<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Holy Spirit &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/holy-spirit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 20:56:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Holy Spirit &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-150/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 11:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pleading for showers of blessing Isaiah 44: I will pour water on the thirsty ground. Spiritually speaking, most of my life has been lived somewhere in the middle. There have been high points, many of them. For this I’m thankful. Also, there have been low points, though not so many. I&#8217;m thankful for that too. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Tip4x5qdBFk/X_JW6TmjruI/AAAAAAABIIc/EU51UhPuBd0SWQ3xIyaw37SIY95K3P24QCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9062314.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Bear Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Pleading for showers of blessing<br />
Isaiah 44: I will pour water on the thirsty ground.<br />
Spiritually speaking, most of my life has been lived somewhere in the middle.  There have been high points, many of them.  For this I’m thankful.  Also, there have been low points, though not so many.  I&#8217;m thankful for that too.  Out here in the middle, where I spend most of my time, things can get rather dry; sometimes with my not even realizing what’s happening.  I go through my routine, focused on the common things of life and don&#8217;t even realize that some of the joy of living in God&#8217;s love has dried up.  The passage before me isn&#8217;t about the spiritual lives of individuals, but a nation of people.  Spiritually, they’ve taken things for granted and the result is that they’re as dry and fragile as the fallen leaves of autumn.  Isaiah&#8217;s word of hope to them is that there’ll be an outpouring of God&#8217;s Spirit on their descendants.  This isn&#8217;t intended to say that they’re doomed to dryness, but to encourage them that something better is coming for them and, even more, for their offspring.  While I know this passage isn&#8217;t specifically about my &#8220;somewhere in the middle&#8221; spiritual dryness I do see a truth here that I can take to heart: God wants to have a vibrant, flowing relationship with his people.  If I’ll trust him and wait for it, he’ll &#8220;pour water&#8221; on my heart&#8217;s &#8220;thirsty ground&#8221; when the time is right.  That’s worth waiting for.  &#8220;Mercy drops &#8217;round us are falling, but for the showers we plead.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord wants to have a vibrant, flowing relationship with us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 17:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The unseen part of life Daniel 10: I was waylaid by the angel-prince of the kingdom of Persia. In general, I&#8217;m not a mystic person. That is, I don&#8217;t see the devil behind every bad thing that happens and I don&#8217;t think most of the events of life are being orchestrated by God. Still, I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 832px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wMvQxjbON2w/YMoQ-vA_nDI/AAAAAAABKfY/WRkqbol4j2gtmvGjWAc21wlq0btMXMS1wCPcBGAsYHg/s1189/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-64.JPG" width="832" height="1189" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; around the city &#8211; Eiffel Tower lit up</figcaption></figure><br />
The unseen part of life<br />
Daniel 10: I was waylaid by the angel-prince of the kingdom of Persia.<br />
In general, I&#8217;m not a mystic person.  That is, I don&#8217;t see the devil behind every bad thing that happens and I don&#8217;t think most of the events of life are being orchestrated by God.  Still, I do believe there&#8217;s an entire part of our existence that&#8217;s very real yet mostly unseen.  That isn&#8217;t really much of a stretch for us anyway.  For instance, a person born blind can be fully convinced of the reality of color even though he&#8217;s never seen it.  However, in that case the blind person has plenty of people around him who do see so he has an abundance of input concerning what is personally beyond his grasp.   When it comes to the spiritual dimension there&#8217;s much less reliable information.  We end up in passages like this one receiving just a fleeting glimpse of events beyond our normal sight.  Even then, the purpose of the passage isn’t to explain all this anyway, so I have to tread very carefully here.  Daniel has an encounter with a messenger of God, an angel.  Others sense this being&#8217;s presence, but can&#8217;t see it.  They flee.  Daniel though, sees and faints at the sight!  The angel is there to talk about future events, but in passing mentions that he was delayed by another angel for three weeks and also mentions he has to go back to fight against that same being when he&#8217;s finished with Daniel.  I know that better educated people than I have worked through this passage, coming to various conclusions about the part of existence we cannot see (or concluded that this passage has nothing to do with that).  For me, I accept the fact that there are realities that I can’t see.  While I don&#8217;t think I go around with a little devil on one shoulder and a little angel on the other, I do believe that this part of existence is just as real as the coffee cup sitting here on the table.  I also believe that there are times when the unseen is very close by and having a direct influence over me and what’s happening in my life.  Finally, I realize that I am, in general, blind to all of this.  I have to trust the Holy Spirit, who can see it all and who was sent to be my Guide to help me navigate through the unseen part of life.<br />
Take Away: We should be thankful for the guidance of the Holy Spirit who sees what we cannot see and helps us avoid that which would do us harm.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Joel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-joel-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Joel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living in the day of the Spirit Joel 2: I will pour out my Spirit on every kind of people. The Hebrew prophets were, in general, positive people. Sometimes they had negative messages to give and sometimes they spoke harshly but they always found a place to promise a better day. In the face of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lQiavjci5zM/YOdqJaykZyI/AAAAAAABKtM/xmCS-sZYNEYto7_6hndCw_7rbMK2EcJyACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/IMG_0695.JPG" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Around Northeastern Ohio &#8211; Lake Erie &#8211; Lake Shore Park Ashtabula</figcaption></figure><br />
Living in the day of the Spirit<br />
Joel 2: I will pour out my Spirit on every kind of people.<br />
The Hebrew prophets were, in general, positive people.  Sometimes they had negative messages to give and sometimes they spoke harshly but they always found a place to promise a better day.  In the face of the natural disaster that has befallen his people, Joel calls for them to take stock of their lives and repent of their sin.  Then he describes a coming better day.  He sees a day when God will “make up for the years of the locust,” restoring what has been destroyed.  He pictures tables full of food and people filled with words of praise and thanksgiving.  Then Joel says, “If you think that stuff sounds good wait till you hear what else is coming!”  He then describes a day of wonderful blessing in which God pours his Spirit out upon, not just one nation, but upon all the nations of the world.  He says that in that day their sons and daughters will prophecy and people from all nations and stations of life will be blessed.  This event, Joel says, will happen before the “Judgment Day of God.”  Years later Peter will quote these words on the Day of Pentecost.  Peter will tell people that they’re literally seeing this “Spirit pouring” promise being fulfilled before their very eyes.  Even today, we live in that “in between” period of history.  We&#8217;re between the outpouring of the Spirit and the Judgment Day of God.  What a wonderful time in which to live!  We&#8217;re in the “day of the Spirit.”  This is the time when, according to Joel, “Whoever calls, ‘Help, God!’ gets help.”<br />
Take Away: What a wonderful thing it is to live in the “day of the Spirit.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 11:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The way to forgiveness Matthew 12: If Satan banishes Satan is there any Satan left? It’s really about the Sabbath. The religious leaders have taken “Remember the Sabbath day” and turned it into a heavy burden laid on the backs of the people. Even picking a piece of fruit to eat is considered to be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15662" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15662" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15662" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029304.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15662" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure>
<p>The way to forgiveness </p>
<p>Matthew 12: If Satan banishes Satan is there any Satan left?</p>
<p>It’s really about the Sabbath.  The religious leaders have taken “Remember the Sabbath day” and turned it into a heavy burden laid on the backs of the people.  Even picking a piece of fruit to eat is considered to be a transgression.  Jesus responds with examples from their own law and history proving that they’re wrong.  He goes on healing people, even on the Sabbath.  When a demon-afflicted woman is set free the critics of Jesus sputter that he must be in cahoots with the devil.  Our Lord responds that if they say that about him what do they say about their own exorcists?  Beyond that, it’s a silly contention anyway.  If Satan casts out Satan there wouldn’t be anything of Satan left.  He then deals with the opposite side of the same coin.  If the Holy Spirit is the One who forgives sins and we cast the Holy Spirit out of lives, how can we ever expect to be forgiven our sins?  Its serious business isn’t it.  We’re sinners in need of forgiveness.  There’s one who forgives.  Throw him out and we’re left without hope.  Stated differently, there’s one road to forgiveness, if I refuse to travel that road, there’s no way I can ever arrive at forgiveness.  The way to God is abundant and grace-filled, offering hope to the worst sinner.  Still, it’s the only way.  I can take it or leave it, but if I leave it, I’m left with nothing.</p>
<p>Take Away: We have, in Christ, hope abundant, but aside from Christ we have no hope at all.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Water Baptizer and the Spirit Baptizer Mark 1: His baptism – a holy baptism by the Holy Spirit – will change you from the inside out. Mark’s gospel is a high speed, breath taking race through the life of Jesus. No “Song of Mary” here and no manger scene. In this story Jesus explodes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15696" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15696" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15696" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15696" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Looking out over Canyonlands NP from Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Water Baptizer and the Spirit Baptizer</p>
<p>Mark 1: His baptism – a holy baptism by the Holy Spirit – will change you from the inside out.</p>
<p>Mark’s gospel is a high speed, breath taking race through the life of Jesus.  No “Song of Mary” here and no manger scene.  In this story Jesus explodes onto the world scene out in the wilderness at one of John the Baptist’s riverside revival meetings.  The “water Baptizer” instantly recognizes Jesus as the Lamb of God, and willingly steps aside for this “Spirit baptizer.”  Jesus changes people, John says, “from the inside out.”  The Gospel writer believes that the promise of real, heart-based change will draw spiritually hungry people like me into his story.  No more playing at religion and hungering for transformation that’s forever beyond my reach.  The one I read about here is the real deal.  Every person who wants something more than what&#8217;s found by following the rules and trying to find God is drawn to the promise of change &#8212; real change &#8212; from the inside out.  This Jesus is worthy of my allegiance.  </p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus is the answer to the great hunger in people’s lives.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 12:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-13/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our secret weapon Mark 13: When the time comes, say what’s on your heart – the Holy Spirit will make his witness in and through you. Big, devastating changes are coming. Their beloved Temple, for instance, will be a pile of ruins. Godly people will be abused, dragged into court. When the pressure’s on and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15738" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15738" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15738" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2812.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15738" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Point Whitehorn Marine Reserve &#8211; near Birch Bay, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Our secret weapon</p>
<p>Mark 13: When the time comes, say what’s on your heart – the Holy Spirit will make his witness in and through you.</p>
<p>Big, devastating changes are coming.  Their beloved Temple, for instance, will be a pile of ruins.  Godly people will be abused, dragged into court.  When the pressure’s on and their enemies have the upper hand the followers of Jesus are to remember these words and turn to the Lord for strength and wisdom to triumph even in the darkest of days.  Specifically, when they stand accused in court they shall do so in confidence.   They’ll have an inner Resource.  They’ll find themselves saying things they haven’t thought of and with a power they never imagined.  That Resource, Jesus says, is the Holy Spirit.  In the decades to come generations of martyrs rise up, each proving the words of Jesus.  When things are the darkest, God’s people stand firmly victorious empowered by the Holy Spirit.  I believe the Holy Spirit is still at work in the world today.  Beyond that, I believe he’s at work in me.  I think I tend to worry too much about what I’m supposed to say and do in difficult situations.  I forget this promise and think it’s all up to me and I fear I’ll blow it.   Surely, those Christians proved this promise to be about a literal enabling of the Holy Spirit for God’s people, especially when they’re under the gun.  I need to be more aware of this promise and of the practical Resource of the Holy Spirit, especially when I need immediate, crisis-level help.</p>
<p>Take Away: The help of the Holy Spirit is more real and immediate than most of us realize.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t leave home without it John 14: Whatever you request along the lines of who I am and what I am doing, I’ll do it. Some of the most empowering words ever spoken are those of our Lord as he prepares his disciples for the soon coming events in these closing days of his earthly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15860" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15860" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15860" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15860" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; La Conner, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Don’t leave home without it</p>
<p>John 14: Whatever you request along the lines of who I am and what I am doing, I’ll do it.</p>
<p>Some of the most empowering words ever spoken are those of our Lord as he prepares his disciples for the soon coming events in these closing days of his earthly ministry.  The clock is ticking and soon their world will be rocked in ways they can’t imagine.  Still, there’s a light at the end of the tunnel.  As a result of all that’s coming they’ll do even greater things than what they’ve seen Jesus do.  I think Jesus is speaking to them as a cooperate group and not as individuals.  They won’t all go out and be messiahs in the world, but together, as the Church, they’ll transform the world in the Name of Jesus.  They won’t be alone in their task.  Jesus is sending the Holy Spirit, his Spirit, who’ll not only be with them but will be in them, empowering them to do his work.  When they run up against impossible situations that threaten to stop them from carrying on his work, all they’ll need to do is call out to him and he’ll make the impossible possible for them.  This “asking in Jesus’ Name” isn’t an open credit card that they can use for doing anything they want.  Rather, this is all about ministry empowerment.  Jesus wants them to carry on his work in this world, bringing the Good News of the Gospel to every nation.  He promises them power for the task and he tells them that he’ll never be more than a prayer away.  This may not be an all-purpose “credit card” but it is, I think, a mighty fine “Master’s Card” that I need to use more often.</p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus has provided us exactly what we need to do his work in this world.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 12:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-20/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Holy Breath John 20: He took a deep breath and breathed into them. The story of the resurrection rightfully dominates the passage. If we don’t quite grasp some of the other things here it’s okay as long as we get that. Still, it’s worthwhile to slow down and, once we’ve freshly soaked in the power [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15877" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15877" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15877" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199497.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15877" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Holy Breath</p>
<p>John 20: He took a deep breath and breathed into them.</p>
<p>The story of the resurrection rightfully dominates the passage.  If we don’t quite grasp some of the other things here it’s okay as long as we get that.  Still, it’s worthwhile to slow down and, once we’ve freshly soaked in the power of the resurrection and look around a bit.  Here we are, still in that first Easter and Jesus arrives inside a locked room where the disciples are gathered.  On his agenda is this “breathing into them” event.  He connects it to their receiving the Holy Spirit, using the word that we translate “breath” or “Spirit” to describe the event.  In this they’re being invited breathe the breath of God.  This is obviously related to the opening pages of our Bibles in which the Lord God makes human beings and then breathes into them the breath of life.  Now, following the resurrection, Jesus symbolically breaths into his disciples the spiritual Breath of Life, the Holy Spirit.  As we know, in the not too distant future, the disciples, likely in this same room, will be filled with “Holy Breath” as the Spirit dramatically comes upon them.  One of the results of the resurrection is the potential of God’s people being filled with the new spiritual empowerment of “Holy Breath.”</p>
<p>Take Away: “Breathe on me, Breath of God.”</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do we do now? Acts 2: Get out of this sick and stupid culture! It’s the Day of Pentecost.  Those in the Upper Room have received the Promise of the Father.  The power of the Holy Spirit flows out of them and they proclaim the Good News of Jesus with authority they’ve never had [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15883" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15883" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-640x1024.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15883" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-640x1024.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-188x300.jpg 188w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-768x1229.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-960x1536.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15883" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>What do we do now?</p>
<p>Acts 2: Get out of this sick and stupid culture!</p>
<p>It’s the Day of Pentecost.  Those in the Upper Room have received the Promise of the Father.  The power of the Holy Spirit flows out of them and they proclaim the Good News of Jesus with authority they’ve never had before and in languages they’ve never spoken before.  Thousands come running to see what’s happening and Peter preaches his Pentecost sermon.  Good people hear this message and are alarmed that the Messiah has come, been executed, and has risen from the grave.  Is it too late for them?  Has the long awaited Messiah come and they missed the boat?  Pleading, they ask, “So now what do we do?”  Peter’s answer is this: “Change your life&#8230;turn to God&#8230;be baptized&#8230;receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.”  A corrupt, Christ-denying culture has brought them to the brink of disaster.  Their only hope, Peter says with Spirit-filled confidence, is to “get out of this sick and stupid culture.”  This message of both warning and hope is still the one people need to hear today.  Our culture of self and materialism is destroying our souls.  We’re on the brink of eternal disaster.  Our hope is in the resurrected Savior of the world.  The message of God to this generation is the same as the one Peter gave to his so long ago: “Repent, turn to God, be baptized, receive the Holy Spirit.”</p>
<p>Take Away: There’s a way through to God and that Way is named Jesus</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[witnessing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pentecost 1b Acts 4: Take care of their threats and give your servants fearless confidence in preaching your Message. The “silver and gold have I none” healing of the lame man gets the attention of everyone, including the religious leaders. Peter and John are arrested for starting a riot, but the city has caught “miracle [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15904" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15904" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-640x1024.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15904" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-640x1024.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-188x300.jpg 188w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-768x1229.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-960x1536.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15904" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pentecost 1b</p>
<p>Acts 4: Take care of their threats and give your servants fearless confidence in preaching your Message.</p>
<p>The “silver and gold have I none” healing of the lame man gets the attention of everyone, including the religious leaders.  Peter and John are arrested for starting a riot, but the city has caught “miracle fever” and the leaders are in danger of having a real riot on their hands if they don’t let the “miracle workers” go.  The disciples are seriously warned to stop talking about Jesus and then let go.  Victoriously, they return to the gathering of believers, telling all that has happened.  Knowing that these leaders don’t make idle threats, the Church goes to prayer.  On one hand, they ask the Lord to deal with their threats.  On the other hand, they ask him to fill them with “fearless confidence in preaching.”  If the Lord will, then, they seek an easy path in proclaiming Jesus.  However, easy or not, they ask for boldness in telling about him.  Luke reports that as they pray there’s a “mini-Pentecost” as the ground trembles and the Holy Spirit re-fills them.  Out the doors they go in Pentecostal power to tell the story of Jesus.  It may be that we go about this “telling” business all wrong.  We tend to focus on the “make it easy for me” part rather than the “make me bold” part.   There’s nothing wrong with asking the Lord to open the way, after all, that’s what happens in this passage.  However, we might just see a more powerful display of the Holy Spirit in our lives if we backed it up by praying the “easy or not, make me more bold” part of the prayer.</p>
<p>Take Away: Maybe we lack boldness because we don’t ask for it.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
