<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>reward &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/reward/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:38:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>reward &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Levites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[missions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rehoboam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leaving everything to follow 2 Chronicles 11: The Levites left their pastures and properties and moved to Judah and Jerusalem. His subjects have requested that Rehoboam back off a bit and give them some breathing room but he foolishly promises more of the same. The result is that he loses half his Kingdom. From now [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-QSM5FXRUmtY/Xr7lpcuACZI/AAAAAAABFCg/uiUzLAurOoUr6E9l7Hf8SEkerQ2SUeDCQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180710_110413.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Bushkill Falls &#8211; PA</figcaption></figure><br />
Leaving everything to follow<br />
2 Chronicles 11: The Levites left their pastures and properties and moved to Judah and Jerusalem.<br />
His subjects have requested that Rehoboam back off a bit and give them some breathing room but he foolishly promises more of the same. The result is that he loses half his Kingdom. From now on we’ll have twin kingdoms: Israel and Judah. Right off Israel enthrones an evil man who shuts down the worship of Jehovah God. However, not everyone in Israel is on his side and several relocate to Judah, not because they like Rehoboam all that much but because they want to worship the Lord. One group, in particular, is mentioned. Traditionally the Levites have served God, first in the Tabernacle and then at the Temple. Now, the Levites living in the new nation of Israel have a decision to make. Will they abandon their calling or will they abandon their property? Many, we’re told, decide for God. They leave home that they can be true to their calling and serve God in Jerusalem. I’m impressed by their decision as I’m impressed by stories of people who leave home to live in some distant place in response to the call of missions. The most many of us can say about following the Lord is that we’ve been inconvenienced at times. Here’s a group of people who abandoned everything to be faithful to God’s call on their lives. People who make that kind of decision are worthy of our admiration. The Lord’s impressed by it too. As Jesus says in Luke 18, “No one who has left home or wife or brothers or parents or children for the sake of the kingdom of God will fail to receive many times as much in this age and, in the age to come, eternal life.”<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for people who are willing to live out their faith even in the face of real personal sacrifice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on the Psalms</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-the-psalms-56/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Psalms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heaven will surely be worth it all Psalm 84: These roads curve up the mountain, and at the last turn &#8212; Zion! The psalmist is thinking about journeying to Jerusalem to worship at the Temple. Oh how the pilgrim looks forward to being in the Temple of God. He can&#8217;t help but think of how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-thkVELmBeOA/X1Ti2KVPGgI/AAAAAAABGIo/DPGmLKbtLMIDiG1IObb-gZubej2WSnuoQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20200820_195801.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2020 &#8211; Lake Conroe, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Heaven will surely be worth it all<br />
Psalm 84: These roads curve up the mountain, and at the last turn &#8212; Zion!<br />
The psalmist is thinking about journeying to Jerusalem to worship at the Temple.  Oh how the pilgrim looks forward to being in the Temple of God.  He can&#8217;t help but think of how blest are those whose serve in that place day by day.  However, there’s more than even that here.  The song writer finds himself thinking about people who are living their lives in the Lord, journeying with him along the dusty roads and through the lonesome valleys of life.  Not that there aren&#8217;t some blest times along the way because there are some &#8220;cool springs&#8221; that refresh the weary traveler.  Then, there’s one last mountain to climb, one last curve to navigate; and then Zion comes into view.   That &#8220;lonesome valley&#8221; journey is quickly forgotten as beautiful Zion is seen.  What a powerful picture he’s painted.  Today, I thank God for walking with me on my life journey.  I thank him for the blessings of cool springs along the way and for his faithfulness to me even in the lonesome valleys.  For me, and for most of us, the blessings far outnumber the trials.  But whether or not that is true for you in particular we all have this hope: one of these days we’ll climb that last mountain and round the final curve and our Zion will come into view.  As the old gospel song says, &#8220;Heaven will surely be worth it all.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: We are a people with hope; hope both in this world and in the world to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
