<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Nahum &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-nahum/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 23:55:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Nahum &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 23:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not thinking too highly of ourselves Nahum 1: A report on the problem of Nineveh. Nahum gets the job Jonah wanted. Around 100 years earlier God sent Jonah to preach condemnation to Nineveh, but in hopes that they would repent and be spared. Jonah would have been happy to preach the message of God’s judgment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-b-FrhNiSpjQ/YRLrelK034I/AAAAAAABLAg/7GKQZiDR9d0wD7eiBXyM_-7L7GuqqCFOQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-036.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains and vicinity &#8211; Lake Toxaway area</figcaption></figure><br />
Not thinking too highly of ourselves<br />
Nahum 1: A report on the problem of Nineveh.<br />
Nahum gets the job Jonah wanted.  Around 100 years earlier God sent Jonah to preach condemnation to Nineveh, but in hopes that they would repent and be spared.  Jonah would have been happy to preach the message of God’s judgment if that was all there was to it.  Now, two generations later Nahum is given that message.  “The problem of Nineveh” is that the Assyrian empire is the superpower of the region.  The tiny nation of Judah is in fearful awe of that empire and behind every move they make is the question, “Will this be okay with the powers that be in the Assyrian capitol of Nineveh?”  Nahum’s call from God is to reorient the priorities of Judah.   He’s to tell his people that God is still God and that Nineveh will be held to the same standards as the other nations of the world.  The prophet goes to work proclaiming his message.  In the first part of his sermon he reminds them that, as mighty as Assyria might be, the Lord is the “All-mighty.”  God’s a patient God, but, in the end, he’s also Judge of the world.  To him, Assyria is just another nation and they’re about to be called to account for their abuse of power.  My nation is on the Assyrian side of things.  We’re the superpower and, to borrow an old saying, “when America sneezes the whole world gets a bad cold.”  As I read from the little Book of Nahum I’m reminded that in God’s eyes we’re not as big a deal as we think we are.<br />
Take Away: It’s important for us as individuals and as a nation to remember that the Lord is the “All-Mighty.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 23:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prodigal son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The God of grace Nahum 1: He recognizes and welcomes anyone looking for help. Even as the prophet prepares to deliver his sermon of condemnation on the mighty nation of Assyria he can’t help but rejoice in the grace and mercy of God. This same God who declares his judgment on those who reject his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JMsPFUHAwL4/YRREUyP1n8I/AAAAAAABLBI/3sGKFEf3qpgF9f5EGlvxdGOhXE3OG12dgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-039.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains and vicinity &#8211; White Water Falls</figcaption></figure><br />
The God of grace<br />
Nahum 1: He recognizes and welcomes anyone looking for help.<br />
Even as the prophet prepares to deliver his sermon of condemnation on the mighty nation of Assyria he can’t help but rejoice in the grace and mercy of God.  This same God who declares his judgment on those who reject his claim on their lives has nothing but good news for those who turn to him for help.  In fact, the Lord is drawn to such people.  I love the fact that even in these portions of the Old Testament that appear to be focused on God as Judge of the World that there are these beautiful word pictures of him as the God of Grace.  Nahum declares that “no matter how desperate the trouble” that God is more than willing to “recognize and welcome” all who come to him.  In an uncertain world I need such a Savior.  I’m reminded in this passage that I don’t have to come to God and convince him that I’m worthy of his help in my life.  Instead, I see that he stands ready to extend his mercy to me.  In the parable of the prodigal son, the returning son expects to have to make concessions, to take a lowly role if he wants to, once again, have a place in the Father’s household.  Instead, the Father runs to him, embraces him, and immediately begins celebrating his return.  Hundreds of years before Jesus ever tells this story, Nahum understands this about God, declaring, “He recognizes and welcomes anyone looking for help.”<br />
Take Away: The Lord stands ready to extend his mercy to us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At just the right time God will speak Nahum 1: And God has something to say about all this. Things don’t look good for God’s purposes in the world. A wicked nation is doing very well. Their capitol city sits at the heart of incredible power and evil. God’s people are small in number and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oKutddGQSJA/YRVzJFGiPbI/AAAAAAABLBY/jWzmwE3k8kQ3kkZ__gY6B-3SHb56_QVtACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-048.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains and vicinity &#8211; &#8220;Dry Falls&#8221; &#8211; Cullasaja Gorge</figcaption></figure><br />
At just the right time God will speak<br />
Nahum 1: And God has something to say about all this.<br />
Things don’t look good for God’s purposes in the world.  A wicked nation is doing very well.  Their capitol city sits at the heart of incredible power and evil.  God’s people are small in number and spirit.  Is this the end of it all?  Will sin and evil win the day?  Nahum calls for calm as he declares good news for all those who love that which is good.  Nineveh appears to be on top of the world, but “God has something to say about all this.”  The “top of the world” position of that wicked city is a mere anthill in the eyes of God and when the Almighty acts, even that anthill will be “mowed down flat.”  Through the centuries there have been many times when it seemed this world was out of God’s control and that the cause of righteousness was lost.  There have been times when God’s people were speechless in the face of overwhelming sin.  That’s okay.  You see, even when we’re at a loss as to what to do or say, at just the right time, God will speak.  What appears to us to be overwhelming circumstances is a mere anthill to the Lord.  My mission in such times is, first, to keep trusting in him even when it seems evil has the upper hand and second, if he can use me, to be a part of God’s remedy for a sin-sick world.<br />
Take Away: At just the right time the Lord will speak.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 23:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No plunger necessary Nahum 2: Nineveh is a tub from which they’ve pulled the plug. If I’m unfortunate enough to find myself in a yard with a pit bull dog, I’ll keep my eye on that dangerous animal as I do whatever it is I need to do. My attention will be divided between the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2L2DN7bL-04/YRbmhomE5tI/AAAAAAABLBs/CaZLkTbwFAwH4OgGyEuDbOrN1SmJ8mfIwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P9199112.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
No plunger necessary<br />
Nahum 2: Nineveh is a tub from which they’ve pulled the plug.<br />
If I’m unfortunate enough to find myself in a yard with a pit bull dog, I’ll keep my eye on that dangerous animal as I do whatever it is I need to do.  My attention will be divided between the task at hand and the big dog.  That’s how it is for Judah.  Nineveh and its empire is an overpowering, frightening evil that dominates the landscape.  Right there in their back yard is the might of Assyria.  Nahum wants to remind them that Nineveh isn’t as big a deal as they think it is.  The description of the end of Nineveh is intended to bring a smile.  When God takes action on that wicked city it will drain away like water draining from a tub once the plug is pulled.  A take away for me today is that some threats demand way too much of my attention.  The Lord can handle that problem.  Anytime he wants he can pull the plug on its entire operation.  My job then, is to keep my eyes on him; to trust him and obey him, and let him handle that which would otherwise scare me half to death.<br />
Take Away: Our job is to keep our eyes on the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 23:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why Nahum preaches to the wrong congregation Nahum 3: You’re past the point of no return. One hundred years earlier the reluctant prophet Jonah had been ordered to go and preach destruction in Nineveh. The result was repentance and God changing his mind about destroying them. Nahum isn’t instructed to go to Nineveh but he&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vn2W18yLKKY/YRg3N2ReVTI/AAAAAAABLCE/_4X5BfzDopkHdtgDdm3fai_iiyqJ9g6oACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-09-12%2B09.50.52.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Advance, NC</figcaption></figure><br />
Why Nahum preaches to the wrong congregation<br />
Nahum 3: You’re past the point of no return.<br />
One hundred years earlier the reluctant prophet Jonah had been ordered to go and preach destruction in Nineveh.  The result was repentance and God changing his mind about destroying them.  Nahum isn’t instructed to go to Nineveh but he&#8217;s given a similar message of destruction.  His sermons appear to be directed to Nineveh but his audience is Judah.  One reason for these anti-Nineveh sermons being preached in Judah is that the people of God are more concerned about what Assyria and its capitol Nineveh is doing than they are with trusting the Lord.  They need to be reminded that, even though they see Assyria as a mountain of power that God sees it as just another anthill.  The second reason for this seeming “preaching to the wrong crowd” is what&#8217;s said in this verse.  In Jonah’s day the Lord hoped to spare Nineveh.  They were great sinners even then, but, according to the Lord, they were more ignorant than rebellious.  Because of that, the Lord was more than willing to change his mind and spare them if they would but turn to him in repentance.  Here in Nahum’s day that has changed.  He preaches about a nation that has pushed God too far and, for them, judgment has come.  Nahum preaches sermons against Nineveh for the sake of Judah.  He doesn’t preach them in Nineveh because it’s too late for them to repent.  I guess the lesson for today is that as long as God speaks to our hearts, even if what he says is guilt producing condemnation, there’s still hope for us.  It’s when we no longer hear from him that it’s too late.  Isaiah put it this way: “Seek the LORD while he may be found; call on him while he is near.” (Isaiah 55:6 )<br />
Take Away: As long as God speaks to our hearts there’s still hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
