<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>gossip &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gossip/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>gossip &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-61/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Running out of wood can be a good thing Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down. As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church. There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-MTTFgHdu11I/X4tVOZuVjqI/AAAAAAABG-E/AXU72ikIuKM_0MSgLcTsQdPeK5gCViOxACPcBGAsYHg/s400/11cripple_creek.JPG" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Cripple Creek, CO</figcaption></figure>Running out of wood can be a good thing<br />
Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down.<br />
As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church.  There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to take control of a church service but that&#8217;s unlikely.  I have the main say concerning the order of worship and, of course, what is said in the sermon.  However, what happens &#8220;out there&#8221; during the week is out of my control.  Because of that, all the efforts on Sunday to create a loving, supportive family of God can be derailed if that same crowd spends the week fanning the flames of division.  Knowing this is humbling to me and it reminds me that I’m not nearly as influential in my own church as I think I am.  However, it also reminds me that my greatest resource is not my leadership ability.  Instead, my greatest Resource is the One I serve.  It’s my desire that the Lord will help me to love people even when they’re behaving in ways that cause pain.  I want to personally set an example of how a sanctified Christian conducts himself, to help people who tend to gossip understand that there’s an underlying spiritual issue, and to pray that the Lord will exhaust their supply of &#8220;wood&#8221; sooner and not later that the church might be united in love for Christ and one another.<br />
Take Away: Some issues will simply die out and go away if we stop fanning the flames.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on James</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-james-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of James]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-james-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taming the tongue James 3: You can tame a tiger, but you can’t tame a tongue. A person can live a good life, honest and sensible, committed to doing good things and yet still have a tendency to say things that aren’t very Christian. One problem is that we see sins of speech as less [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16302" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16302" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16302" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140809_201019.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16302" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Nicolaus, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Taming the tongue</p>
<p>James 3: You can tame a tiger, but you can’t tame a tongue.</p>
<p>A person can live a good life, honest and sensible, committed to doing good things and yet still have a tendency to say things that aren’t very Christian. One problem is that we see sins of speech as less serious than sins of action. People who would never dream of robbing anyone of anything will thoughtlessly gossip about another, thereby robbing them of their reputation. Sins of words are slippery, hard to pin down. A person might say something that’s absolutely innocent. The listener, though, misunderstands the meaning, hearing something that isn’t there at all. Another person might say the same thing but intend it to be hurtful in some way. In one case it’s just a misunderstanding. In the other case it’s sin. James emphasizes the fact that no one can win the battle of the tongue. Try as I might, in and of myself, my words will betray, humiliate, and condemn me. On the surface, it appears James leaves us in this sorry state of affairs. However, a different picture is painted as I read these words in the context of the passage. James says, “My friends this can’t go on.” A few paragraphs later he describes the Christian community as a place where people are treated “with dignity and honor.” On one hand, I can’t control my tongue (or my thoughts, or, sometimes, my actions). The only hope I have is to surrender my tongue to the Lord. As I give it, and my whole self, to him, making him Lord of my life, he goes to work transforming me into the person he wants me to be. It’s a more than one time surrender. In fact, I may have to bring my tongue back to the Lord on a regular basis. As I do that, he takes control doing for me what I can’t do for myself.</p>
<p>Take Away: “I surrender all” is a song that needs to be sung repeatedly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
