<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 1Kings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-1kings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 13:45:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 1Kings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-king-david-37/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Absalom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old age]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Time flies when you’re having fun 1Kings 1: King David grew old. First and Second Samuel have told us the stories of two kings. The first failed miserably and the second became Israel&#8217;s greatest king. Now we come to the stories of all the rest. All fall somewhere between Saul and David. These “king stories” [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Mw61Cja5tjk/XippY8stuFI/AAAAAAABDo0/EP5dRwnxjzg2AouNs6ZLAwT5I2NVrQIowCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129991.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Time flies when you’re having fun<br />
1Kings 1: King David grew old.<br />
First and Second Samuel have told us the stories of two kings. The first failed miserably and the second became Israel&#8217;s greatest king. Now we come to the stories of all the rest. All fall somewhere between Saul and David. These “king stories” start with &#8220;King David grew old.&#8221; It’s interesting to be reminded that even great people grow old. Our days are numbered and, while it’s a blessing to live to old age, it isn&#8217;t really much fun to get there! Physically David&#8217;s wasting away. His circulation isn’t good and he’s cold all the time. His aids come up with an interesting solution for keeping him warm at night. They recruit the young and beautiful Abishag who serves as a sort of &#8220;electric blanket&#8221; for &#8220;poor&#8221; old David. It brings a smile to our faces now, but even the Bible writer notes that David&#8217;s advanced years assure that their relationship is purely platonic. The more serious issue for Israel is that there&#8217;s jostling among his surviving sons as to who will to take the throne. Throughout David&#8217;s 40 years on the throne of Judah and then Israel Absalom&#8217;s effort to take the throne has been the only serious threat to Israel&#8217;s stability. Now, King David grows old and national unity is threatened once again. David has just one more thing to do. He has to name his successor. Once that&#8217;s done the burden of leadership will be lifted from his frail shoulders. I can&#8217;t feel sorry for David. He’s lived a robust life. If anyone ever &#8220;grabs the gusto&#8221; it’s David. Now though, even though he’s bigger than life, it’s life (or maybe better, death) that&#8217;s winning. So it is for all of us. There’s only one alternative to getting old and it isn&#8217;t a very good choice. With that in mind, I want to live as large as I can; to serve God right now with all my strength. Then, when my turn comes I want to be able to look back on a life lived all out for God.<br />
Take Away: We only have one opportunity to live our lives enthusiastically for the Lord, let’s not miss this opportunity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-david-and-solomon-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 12:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The long arm of the law 1Kings 2: Do what God tells you. Walk in the paths he shows you. The transition of the throne from David to Solomon will not be bloodless, but considering the day and age, it comes close to it. David calls for Solomon to come to him and they have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zfyTXZQCssU/XiuuoB7zjjI/AAAAAAABDpE/RwCOceD7630eaL8N7JFTyfQhe22gxx28gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129994.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
The long arm of the law<br />
1Kings 2: Do what God tells you. Walk in the paths he shows you.<br />
The transition of the throne from David to Solomon will not be bloodless, but considering the day and age, it comes close to it. David calls for Solomon to come to him and they have a father-son (or maybe better, a king-king) talk. Some of what David says is lofty, truly uplifting. He encourages Solomon to walk in God&#8217;s ways. If he does that, the Lord will lead and bless him. Some of what David says sounds cold and calculating. There are some people who have acted in ways intended to promote their own agendas rather than his but for various reasons they’ve never been brought to justice. From his deathbed David lists them for the new king. He doesn&#8217;t tell him what to do in each case but he reminds him that he thinks something should be done. At its worst, this is just plain old revenge. At its best, it’s a cold reminder of reality. This, I think sums up David&#8217;s life. On one hand, he’s a hard pragmatist who’ll unflinchingly kill a man he thinks is a threat to the kingdom. On the other hand, he’s a man who loves God with all his heart, who can write soaring poetry and lift the spirits of all those around him. One thing is certain: there&#8217;s nothing lukewarm about David and that’s abundantly clear in this, his final appearance in the Bible.<br />
Take Away: Let’s let David’s unhesitant devotion to the Lord inspire and challenge us in our own relationship with God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-david-and-solomon-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 12:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Seeking a righteous response 1Kings 2: The final verdict is God&#8217;s peace. On his death bed David reminds Solomon of some unfinished issues that need attention. Solomon&#8217;s response is to execute some people. This isn’t pleasant devotional reading but there’s at least an insight into why David sets this agenda for his son. When Joab’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ATLqfblfrf8/XizO0OxoRNI/AAAAAAABDpQ/EHCkrcH9--UGcxyd47jhvVAITh3wBdoSACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129995.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Seeking a righteous response<br />
1Kings 2: The final verdict is God&#8217;s peace.<br />
On his death bed David reminds Solomon of some unfinished issues that need attention. Solomon&#8217;s response is to execute some people. This isn’t pleasant devotional reading but there’s at least an insight into why David sets this agenda for his son. When Joab’s executed we’re reminded that he’s killed some innocent people. Then we read, &#8220;Responsibility for their murders is forever fixed on Joab and his descendants; but for David and his descendants, his family and kingdom, the final verdict is God&#8217;s peace.&#8221; We see that these executions aren’t for revenge but rather are for justice. David believes that if the crimes committed by these people are left without response that he and his descendants will be responsible in part for what happened. The concept here can only be carried so far and it’s important to remember that Solomon isn’t acting here as a vigilante. He’s acting in the capacity of king, head of the government. But let&#8217;s step away from the specific of executions and also lay aside the role of the government here. When I do that I’m still reminded that if I stand by while some wrong is done, declaring, &#8220;It’s none of my business&#8221; I become a part of that wrong. That’s true not only for government but for individual citizens as well.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes doing nothing makes us as guilty in the eyes of the Lord as if we have done something.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/4676/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 12:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/2012/07/05/4676/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good answer! 1Kings 3: God give me a God-listening heart so I can lead your people well, discerning the difference between good and evil. Solomon begins his reign with a great worship celebration that pleases the Lord. Because of this, God asks Solomon what he can do for him. His answer is a life changing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GjydP4ShAug/Xi4wOYZEoRI/AAAAAAABDp4/w6pAM74eGuAUycClfxqf0G5b64zI3mK6ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129996.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Good answer!<br />
1Kings 3: God give me a God-listening heart so I can lead your people well, discerning the difference between good and evil.<br />
Solomon begins his reign with a great worship celebration that pleases the Lord. Because of this, God asks Solomon what he can do for him. His answer is a life changing one. He asks for a &#8220;God-listening heart,&#8221; or &#8220;wisdom.&#8221; Since we’re told elsewhere in the Bible that &#8220;the beginning of wisdom is the fear of the Lord&#8221; describing Solomon&#8217;s request as asking for a &#8220;God-listening heart&#8221; is insightful and reasonable. If wisdom is anything it’s hearing the voice of God, especially in dealing with the gray areas of life. We also see that Solomon&#8217;s request for wisdom is a wise one! The Lord likes his request and agrees to grant it, and, in addition, to bless him in every way possible. This is all interconnected. When I base my life on having a &#8220;God-listening heart&#8221; it opens the way for God to work in my life, blessing me and blessing others through me.<br />
Take Away: Solomon’s request might be a good starting place for us in our walk with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What a wise guy! 1Kings 3: They were all in awe of the king, realizing that it was God&#8217;s wisdom that enabled him to judge truly. The most famous example of the wisdom of Solomon is how he deals with two women claiming to be the mother of the same child. He relies on the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2SFQzlSGJ40/Xi98-Mb8olI/AAAAAAABDqM/Q9pB6KmzxIA0WiPoUaxMTVqUbRUkvYAEQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129999.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
What a wise guy!<br />
1Kings 3: They were all in awe of the king, realizing that it was God&#8217;s wisdom that enabled him to judge truly.<br />
The most famous example of the wisdom of Solomon is how he deals with two women claiming to be the mother of the same child. He relies on the love of a mother for her baby to reveal which of the two women is the baby&#8217;s mother. It’s a pretty impressive display of wisdom, but only the first. In the pages to come we repeatedly see examples of Solomon’s wisdom. Clearly, God keeps his word and gives Solomon the wisdom he so wisely asked for. I like this statement that says people are in awe of Solomon but they also recognize that his wisdom is directly from God. In the New Testament it’s James who talks about wisdom. He says that if I lack wisdom I should ask God who will freely give it. I don&#8217;t know if James is thinking about Solomon or not, but as I put these two things together I conclude that God’s in the wisdom giving business, willingly helping me make good decisions as I cooperate with him. This, my friend, is a pretty good deal. I find myself in need of wisdom and here I’m reminded that there’s a Source of wisdom available.<br />
Take Away: Maybe we should pray for wisdom more often and concerning more things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 13:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The big picture 1Kings 4: People came from far and near to listen to the wisdom of Solomon. Under King Saul Israel becomes a military power. Under David, the nation is united and made secure. Now, under King Solomon Israel becomes an admired, respected nation. It is one thing to be feared and safe and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-B07VQYpWS04/XjECBOXzGdI/AAAAAAABDro/fZyAXRj1zwozXFievxygGR7zDfmVXbtcwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8120001.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
The big picture<br />
1Kings 4: People came from far and near to listen to the wisdom of Solomon.<br />
Under King Saul Israel becomes a military power. Under David, the nation is united and made secure. Now, under King Solomon Israel becomes an admired, respected nation. It is one thing to be feared and safe and secure and something more to be respected, viewed as a positive contributor to the world in general. That’s what happens as Solomon leads Israel. Those who were enemies or at least subdued rivals now come to Israel in peace to sit at the feet of her wise king and to bring goods for trade. It has taken hundreds of years but this nation of slaves has received the inheritance promised to their ancestor Abraham. I know this is the high water mark for the Kingdom of Israel, but what an impressive mark it is. Because of the patience of power of the Almighty the impossible has happened and Abraham’s journey from Ur to the Promised Land is complete. I know I’m supposed to read this story and be impressed with Solomon, but today, I can’t help but be impressed with his God; a God who makes unbelievable promises to unlikely people and then delivers on those promises. If I ever find myself doubting God, I need to step back from the close up snap shots of the Bible and get the big picture. It’s pretty impressive.<br />
Take Away: We too have huge, amazing promises from the Lord. How thrilling it is to remember that he always keeps his promises.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 13:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Keeping first things first 1Kings 5: What&#8217;s important is that you live the way I&#8217;ve set out for you and do what I tell you. Solomon has an aggressive agenda. He’s already built palaces, cataloged information about plants and animals, and amassed an impressive and well-equipped army. His reputation has spread across the face of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Lv--EL6nyeM/XjHu6-Z0UWI/AAAAAAABDsI/e9Cm0J_pjkQdAVEypKLGFIi4YuPIXHcmACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4455.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Along Lake Michigan at Manistique, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Keeping first things first<br />
1Kings 5: What&#8217;s important is that you live the way I&#8217;ve set out for you and do what I tell you.<br />
Solomon has an aggressive agenda. He’s already built palaces, cataloged information about plants and animals, and amassed an impressive and well-equipped army. His reputation has spread across the face of the earth and he’s forged alliances with other nations. Now, he turns his attention to the building of the Temple. You might say that everything else he’s done has been practice for this, his most memorable accomplishment. As construction gets underway Solomon hears a word from the Lord. He’s reminded that living in daily obedience to God is even more important than constructing buildings to the glory of God. For Solomon, and for all those who call on the Name of the Lord, this is a vital concept. It’s so easy to confuse the things we do for the Lord with being in a right relationship with the Lord. More than sacrifices, more than building projects, more than well-organized church programs God desires that I concentrate on having a genuine connection to himself. All the rest is to flow out of that relationship. It’s a vital matter of priorities and, as it’s important in this passage for Solomon it’s important for me.<br />
Take Away: We must be careful we don’t confuse the things we do in the Name of the Lord with our living in a genuine relationship with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appreciation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craftsmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thank God for plumbers and roofers and carpenters 1Kings 7: Hiram was a real artist &#8212; he could do anything with bronze. Solomon presides over some of the most impressive building projects imaginable including the construction of beautiful palaces and the impressive gold-inlaid Temple. He’s the architect, the mastermind, of these great projects. But he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kmSrn5KYQQg/XjWxAAt5bFI/AAAAAAABDsk/yAaMUBU4YEQ7KNDJty8CCbzNksFY9YNAACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4456.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-medium" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Along Lake Michigan at Manistique, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Thank God for plumbers and roofers and carpenters<br />
1Kings 7: Hiram was a real artist &#8212; he could do anything with bronze.<br />
Solomon presides over some of the most impressive building projects imaginable including the construction of beautiful palaces and the impressive gold-inlaid Temple. He’s the architect, the mastermind, of these great projects. But he isn&#8217;t the workman. He recruits a man named Hiram from Tyre to do the bronze work. This guy and some other key people are craftsmen with extraordinary abilities. Under Hiram’s expert guidance durable, functional, and beautiful artifacts are created. I thank God for people like Hiram: people with practical knowledge and skill, people who have God-given gifts willingly given to the work of the Lord. As a person who just barely knows which end of the hammer to use, I’ve come to appreciate those who bring their practical abilities as an offering of love to God and his Church.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for dedicated people who willingly give their skills to the work of God’s Kingdom.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Glory! 1Kings 8: The glory of God filled The Temple of God! The painstaking work of constructing the Temple is complete. It’s a truly impressive structure with every detail perfect. This house of worship is one of the wonders of the world. But that’s the least of the story. What really matters is what happens [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5bCceD-Ixjc/XjdFeFH7WTI/AAAAAAABDsw/-dIe_xQ1ekg51PuZc4tI8Lyq-kebus88gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3912.JPG" width="1600" height="1600" class="size-medium" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Mackinaw Bridge, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Glory!<br />
1Kings 8: The glory of God filled The Temple of God!<br />
The painstaking work of constructing the Temple is complete. It’s a truly impressive structure with every detail perfect. This house of worship is one of the wonders of the world. But that’s the least of the story. What really matters is what happens next. As the dedication service is about to begin God&#8217;s glory falls on the place. His glory is so powerful that it’s tangible. The Presence of God flows into and through the structure to the extent that the priests, who have assumed their assigned positions of service are driven out! Like a cloud, God&#8217;s glory has descended and the people are in reverent awe of the Lord. I’ve been in church services in my life in which God came in glory and majesty. The scale was much smaller, but I’ve tasted just enough to imagine what it’s like on this day. In less public moments God has touched my life and these are my most precious spiritual memories. I thank him for such wonderful encounters with the divine. Beyond that, I hunger for God to pour his glory out on me and on his church. Passages like this both warm my heart and rekindle a hunger for God in the depths of my spirit.<br />
Take Away: There’s nothing like the presence of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 13:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Move right on in 1Kings 8: Can it be that God will actually move into our neighborhood? Solomon’s praying his great prayer of dedication of the newly constructed Temple. He understands that, while the Temple is an impressive house of worship, that God is bigger than any one place, even as beautiful a place as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-j0z_SYEdP3Y/Xjg76Yc6b5I/AAAAAAABDtU/L1iuk0gUB6EVlQkjuN_xAPjD8a7y47vKwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4492.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-medium" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; At Mackinaw City, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Move right on in<br />
1Kings 8: Can it be that God will actually move into our neighborhood?<br />
Solomon’s praying his great prayer of dedication of the newly constructed Temple. He understands that, while the Temple is an impressive house of worship, that God is bigger than any one place, even as beautiful a place as this is. With the thought in mind that God is the God of the universe and can&#8217;t be contained in any one place, Solomon prays that the Almighty will always be attentive to the worship done, and the prayers prayed, at this new Temple. He’s a wise man, after all God’s too big to really live among us, right? Well, not quite! Many years in the future God will do exactly what Solomon imagines being impossible. God will come to us. He’ll indeed move right into our neighborhood. As he does this, human beings will encounter God in a whole new way. And the story won&#8217;t end with the pages of the Gospels. God will come to us in the Person of the Holy Spirit, and in so doing, he’ll move right into the temple that is the heart of every willing person. He’ll not only be &#8220;with us,&#8221; but God, the Holy Spirit, will be &#8220;in us.&#8221; As impressive as the Temple is, and as lofty as Solomon&#8217;s prayer of dedication is, we have the privilege of God actually moving into the neighborhood of our lives today.<br />
Take Away: Have you invited God, the Holy Spirit, to take up residence in your life?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
