<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>overcoming &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/overcoming/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 16:57:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>overcoming &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-144/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 10:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The great Deliverer Isaiah 42: He won&#8217;t be stopped until he&#8217;s finished his work &#8212; to set things right on earth. Even as Isaiah writes words of comfort to those banished from Jerusalem by the crushing might of Babylon, he looks forward to a great day of deliverance. &#8220;One day,&#8221; he promises, &#8220;God will send [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Hw_aCDosO1I/X-pFjAcTBDI/AAAAAAABIEo/faLz05_vrUAJaYS7BdIznVVerr67kxhOQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9092424.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along Colorado Hwy 34</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The great Deliverer<br />
Isaiah 42: He won&#8217;t be stopped until he&#8217;s finished his work &#8212; to set things right on earth.<br />
Even as Isaiah writes words of comfort to those banished from Jerusalem by the crushing might of Babylon, he looks forward to a great day of deliverance.  &#8220;One day,&#8221; he promises, &#8220;God will send the ultimate Deliverer, his prized Servant, to the world.  He’ll do an even greater thing than bringing a scattered people back to their homeland.&#8221;  Isaiah looks to the coming of the Messiah, a man filled with the Spirit who’ll &#8220;set everything right.&#8221;  One day, in Isaiah&#8217;s distant future, a man will be baptized and God&#8217;s voice will be heard proclaiming, &#8220;This is my Son.&#8221;  Here we see that proclamation being foretold as the Lord declares through Isaiah, &#8220;He&#8217;s the one I chose, and I couldn&#8217;t be more pleased with him.&#8221;  The prophet doesn&#8217;t have all the details.  In fact, it’s unlikely that he has a vision of Calvary or of the empty tomb of Easter.  Isaiah doesn&#8217;t see a cross, but he does see a Messiah.  This Promised One will overcome every hindrance to accomplish his work.  That’s just what happens when even a cross can&#8217;t stop this Servant of God.  Know what? Neither can he be stopped by the seeming insurmountable obstacles of the world today.  We Christians need to remember this and join the Messiah&#8217;s mission.  Followers of his don&#8217;t sit around wringing their hands while lamenting the state of things.  This Messiah won&#8217;t quit until things are set &#8220;right on earth.&#8221;  That’s our mission as well as our hope.<br />
Take Away: It’s not that there aren’t any challenges because there are.  Still, the fact remains that the Son of God will, without question accomplish his mission of redemption. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ephesians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ephesians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not a walk in the park Ephesians 6: Be prepared. You’re up against far more than you can handle on your own. Several years ago a popular song included the phrase “I beg your pardon; I never promised you a rose garden.” Know what? That’s life in general and, in light of this passage, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16149" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16149" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-16149" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16149" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; south of Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Not a walk in the park </p>
<p>Ephesians 6: Be prepared. You’re up against far more than you can handle on your own.</p>
<p>Several years ago a popular song included the phrase “I beg your pardon; I never promised you a rose garden.”  Know what?  That’s life in general and, in light of this passage, the Christian life in particular.  Paul writes this passage from jail.  He warns his readers that they have an enemy who&#8217;s intent on destroying them.  Their spiritual journey is no game and how they live in the here and now has eternal consequences.  If a person starts out living for the Lord thinking it’s going to be a stroll in a rose garden they&#8217;re in for some unpleasant surprises.  The Apostle focuses on spiritual adversaries, unseen but real.  It’s not unreasonable to add the common inconveniences and out and out tragedies of life to this mix.  I’m not to be naive about all this.  There are times when it becomes clear that I’m up against far more than I can handle.  Happily, the Lord hasn’t put us out here in real life without some resources. Paul urges us to take advantage of many powerful resources that are at our fingertips.  He reminds us that “Truth, righteousness, peace, faith, and salvation are more than words.”  He directs us to God’s Word and prayer.  It’s no rose garden, but I have everything I need to live a victorious, overcoming life.  </p>
<p>Take Away: Life isn’t always easy but it’s important to remember the Lord’s faithful provision for us.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
