<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Genesis &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-genesis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 09:11:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Genesis &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 06:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eternity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s nature]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The curtain rises and there stands God Genesis 1: First this: God created the Heavens and Earth. Genesis is the book of beginnings. Here I’m told how the world began: light and sky and life. In Genesis I see the first sunrise and meet the first man and woman. Of course, I see the first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16463" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16463" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16463 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/20220530_204025-6-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16463" class="wp-caption-text">2022 &#8211; Dickinson, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>The curtain rises and there stands God<br />
Genesis 1: First this: God created the Heavens and Earth.<br />
Genesis is the book of beginnings. Here I’m told how the world began: light and sky and life. In Genesis I see the first sunrise and meet the first man and woman. Of course, I see the first sin and the first death here, but I also see the first act of redemption, hear the first prayers prayed, and encounter the first man known for his faith and friendship with God. The big omission of a “first” happens in chapter one, verse one. As the curtain lifts I find One Being already standing at center stage. There’s no prelude and no introduction. I start reading and even though there’s nothing to be seen, there He is. It’s staggering isn’t it! The first thing that ever happens is when God steps out into nothingness and begins doing something. Right off I know he’s the Creator and right off I know there’s no hope of my ever fully comprehending him.<br />
Take away: I can know this eternal, Creating Being.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 07:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowing God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Who, How, and What of Creation Genesis 1: It was so good, so very good! The account of Creation is a lot more about “who” than it is about “how.” When the story begins its God who begins it. He speaks and things happen. There’s no doubt that he’s in charge and the account [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16465" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16465" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16465" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P5099457.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16465" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT &#8211; glorious sunset</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Who, How, and What of Creation<br />
Genesis 1: It was so good, so very good!<br />
The account of Creation is a lot more about “who” than it is about “how.” When the story begins its God who begins it. He speaks and things happen. There’s no doubt that he’s in charge and the account of Creation is all about what the Creator does. On the other hand, there’s no more effort made to tell me “how” it happened than there is to explain God, himself. If I want to know the composition of light, I’ll have to look elsewhere because the Bible doesn’t tell me. If this is a poetic description of a “big bang” it’s okay with me so long as I can believe that God is the one who creates and directs the energy of it in the first place. So, as I read these opening pages of the Bible, I immediately encounter the “Who” of it all and I immediately find that this Creator isn’t all that interested in satisfying my curiosity of “how.” However, there is one thing he wants me to know: that’s “what” he has done. He declares to me that it’s “very good.” I know “Who” did it but I don’t know “how” he did it. Still, I know that “what” he did is “so good!” As I read this account I’d better concentrate more on what I’m supposed to know and less on what the Lord doesn’t bother to tell me about it.<br />
Take away: I need to focus on the Creator and not get too wound up in how he created.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 07:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elephants and Monkeys and Kangaroos Genesis 2: Whatever the Man called each living creature, that was its name. God gets the ball rolling: sun, moon, stars, plants, animals, and humans. It’s all his handiwork. The crowning act of creation is humanity. The Lord, himself, breathes life into man, who has been made in his own [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16467" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16467" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16467" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042189.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16467" class="wp-caption-text">Rocky Mountain National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Elephants and Monkeys and Kangaroos<br />
Genesis 2: Whatever the Man called each living creature, that was its name.<br />
God gets the ball rolling: sun, moon, stars, plants, animals, and humans. It’s all his handiwork. The crowning act of creation is humanity. The Lord, himself, breathes life into man, who has been made in his own image. Unlike other elements of creation, this creature has something of God inside. He also has free will. At this point the Creator stands back to watch his masterpiece in action. The Lord wants to see what man will name the animals. Right off the Almighty gives up some of his authority to his Creation. Whatever Man names an animal will stand. It doesn’t sound like much but it’s a significant moment. God, the Decider, decides not to decide. Rather, this new creature, this man, will decide. Also, a theological concept is introduced: God, who has all authority, agrees ahead of time to let decisions made by a human being stand. Will Adam do a good job in naming the animals or will he come up with some stupid names? The Lord, no doubt, is interested in what this unique being will do of his own free will. This pretty much overlooked event is actually filled with drama.<br />
Take away: Having free will is part of my being created in the image of God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 07:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Come out, come out, wherever you are Genesis 3: God called to the Man: “Where are you?” I’m created for fellowship with God. Somehow, in ways beyond my comprehension, God desires a relationship with me. God, you see, is all about relationships. In the Creation he seeks relationships so much that he creates beings with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16470" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16470" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16470" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/04/P9042165.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16470" class="wp-caption-text">Rocky Mountain National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Come out, come out, wherever you are<br />
Genesis 3: God called to the Man: “Where are you?”<br />
I’m created for fellowship with God. Somehow, in ways beyond my comprehension, God desires a relationship with me. God, you see, is all about relationships. In the Creation he seeks relationships so much that he creates beings with free will. Only such creatures can genuinely connect with him. In the Garden Adam and Eve enjoy the fellowship with God, functioning as they&#8217;re created to function. When they sin, they break that fellowship and distance themselves from God. What will he do? Will he press the “reset” button on Creation and give it another try? No, instead, we see the Almighty’s commitment to us. According to the Apostle Paul, that commitment was made before the first act of Creation. Adam and Eve don’t have to sin. They&#8217;re created to live forever and to enjoy constant fellowship with their Maker. However, before the very first “Let there be light” words are spoken the Lord has considered the possibly that if he makes beings with free will that that they might just reject him. What will he do if that happens? Out in pre-creation eternity the Lord decided that, no matter what happens, he’ll remain committed to his Creation. Before the first moment of time, he has a plan to “seek and to save that which was lost.” When we hear him calling “Where are you?” we’re witnessing the very first step in that plan to restore the broken relationship that now exists between God and humanity. It’s the first step, and in the distant future, we see a cross.<br />
Take away: God wants more than obedience from me…more, he wants to be in a relationship with me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 08:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sin, murder, and grace Genesis 4: Sin is lying in wait for you&#8230;you’ve got to master it. The first children are born to the human race, two boys. These boys become men and these men are worshipers of God. One is a dirt farmer and the other raises livestock. These two worshipers of God bring [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FZ7dtAIapvI/XK-Rd32yVFI/AAAAAAAA6fU/AcWx_jhTivMY6Cj1PuHL9R1isiEHTSBdQCKgBGAs/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2Bcamping%2Btrip%2B11-27-2010%2B7-08-14%2BPM.JPG" alt="" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Sin, murder, and grace<br />
Genesis 4: Sin is lying in wait for you&#8230;you’ve got to master it.<br />
The first children are born to the human race, two boys. These boys become men and these men are worshipers of God. One is a dirt farmer and the other raises livestock. These two worshipers of God bring sacrifices to the Lord. To Cain’s dismay God likes his brother’s offering better than his own. I’ve heard a few sermons on the reason why. In fact, I’ve attempted to deal with the topic myself. Some people think it’s the lack of blood in Cain’s offering. Others pounce on the “firstborn” aspect of Abel’s offering and the writer of the book of Hebrews focuses in on the faith aspect of it. Deciding why one offering is more acceptable than the other is a hard call. After all, Cain brought from what he had, just as Abel did. Of course, we know that this passage isn’t here to elevate one type of offering over the other. This account is about sin, murder, and grace. When Cain&#8217;s angry with God about his brother’s offering the Lord warns him that he’s skating on thin ice. Being disappointed with God, apparently, isn’t sin in itself; but such an attitude attracts sin. The Lord speaks to Cain like a father talking to his son, warning him that it’s a dangerous road he’s traveling. This situation has potential for Cain to be humbled. If he responds to the Lord by asking for an explanation concerning why his offering is inferior to Abel’s we won’t have the mystery concerning it. Instead, Cain proves God right by doing the wrong thing. At this point, the score is Sin: one, Cain: nothing.<br />
Take away: Some things that aren’t quite sin, can, if I’m not careful, open that door.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 08:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On being my brother’s keeper Genesis 4: How should I know? Am I his babysitter? An interesting thing about the Lord’s exchange with Cain is that they both know the answer to the question that’s asked. Obviously, the Lord knows what has happened. Of course, Cain knows where Abel is, after all, he’s his murderer. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_13684" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-13684" style="width: 584px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-13684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="438" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2014/12/P9209119.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-13684" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="color: #444444;">On being my brother’s keeper</span></p>
<p>Genesis 4: How should I know? Am I his babysitter?<br />
An interesting thing about the Lord’s exchange with Cain is that they both know the answer to the question that’s asked. Obviously, the Lord knows what has happened. Of course, Cain knows where Abel is, after all, he’s his murderer. Cain’s response: “Am I my brother’s keeper?” has become one of many famous one liners from the Bible. This murderer not only pretends he doesn’t know about Abel, but that, even if he does know, it isn’t his responsibility to take care of him. On a very specific level, I agree with Cain’s statement. As creatures with free will we’re not responsible for what others do. As a pastor of several years of experience, I’ve heard plenty of excuses from people who place the blame for their failure on someone, anyone, else. Because of that, I agree with Cain on at least one level. However, Cain’s suggestion that he operates solo and isn’t accountable for his brother’s whereabouts is a pitiful failure on his part. Even (and that’s a mighty big “even” in this situation) – even had he not killed his brother, and had poor Abel just wandered off in search of one of his sheep and gotten lost, in God’s eyes, Cain has a certain amount of responsibility for him. Our lives are connected at many points and the Lord expects our behavior to reflect this. Many years down the road, Jesus will help me understand this better in the parable of the Good Samaritan and even better when he takes personal responsibility for my lost condition.<br />
Take away: I’m not responsible for what others do of their own free will, but I am accountable before God to show compassion to them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 08:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mercy’s Mark Genesis 3: God put a mark on Cain to protect him. The murderer has been confronted and has confessed. The sentence is banishment to a hostile world. From now on he’ll be an outsider, apart from the family (it’s not a nation yet) God claims as his own. Cain is crushed by this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-SF26kilzHJQ/XLOFpOlXDeI/AAAAAAAA6mI/hxlKw2uyhZQawmKcmhgo1zsMaJX9BXbXwCKgBGAs/s1600/P7268810.JPG" alt="" width="1600" height="1002" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Watkins Glen State Park, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p>Mercy’s Mark<br />
Genesis 3: God put a mark on Cain to protect him.<br />
The murderer has been confronted and has confessed. The sentence is banishment to a hostile world. From now on he’ll be an outsider, apart from the family (it’s not a nation yet) God claims as his own. Cain is crushed by this sentence and already feels the icy grip of loneliness on his life. Not only that, but he knows he’s getting off with a sentence lighter than he deserves. He senses that the proper penalty for murder is death. In addition, he realizes that other people know it too. God may be banishing him, but he imagines other men hunting him down and taking his life that justice might be done. What the Lord does in response is, at the same time, one of the great mysteries of the Bible and also one of many great acts of mercy. Cain&#8217;s marked in some way that says to all he encounters “This man is under God’s protection, leave him alone.” I have no idea of what that mark is, in fact, I can’t imagine how it works. However, I do know it&#8217;s a mark of mercy and I have a very good idea of what mercy looks like. It looks like the Lord forgiving me of my sins rather than condemning me as I deserve. It looks like hope instead of fear. It looks like Jesus on the cross of Calvary.<br />
Take away: Thank God for the “mark of mercy!”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Something new: prayer! Genesis 4: That’s when men and women began praying and worshiping in the name of God. Things are really messed up. The human race is fallen. The Garden is gone. The first murder has taken place. It’s all falling apart. This “free will” thing isn’t working out very well. Eve has another [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MSGrZMnp_1U/XLOGV62G4fI/AAAAAAAA6mQ/5sLkPYPjDDUY3uLZdKwnh71mK1g-5P7iACKgBGAs/s1600/P7268826.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Watkins Glen State Park, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p>Something new: prayer!<br />
Genesis 4: That’s when men and women began praying and worshiping in the name of God.<br />
Things are really messed up. The human race is fallen. The Garden is gone. The first murder has taken place. It’s all falling apart. This “free will” thing isn’t working out very well. Eve has another son and names him Seth. Seth has a son and names him Enosh. Then a wonderful thing happens: people start praying and worshiping. I wonder how that came about. Is Seth so thankful for the gift of a son that he decides to start worshiping God? Is it Enosh who has a hunger for God and introduces praying and worshiping? I don’t know the answer but I do see here a change for the better; one that brought hope to a hopeless situation. So what does it take in my life? Does it take tragedy&#8230;or some great blessing? Does it take someone else finding the way and showing it to me? What does it take to turn me from a life being lived for self to one being lived in fellowship with God?<br />
Take away: Prayer and worship is an “important discovery” for every person to make.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 08:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eternity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[He died before his time Genesis 5: Adam lived a total of 930 years. And he died. I’ve heard that the very long lives of people mentioned in the first pages of Genesis are the result of someone’s counting the seasons as years or something like that. While I have no authority to say it, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/JTxOC7on91WhZhpl13UIA6d32SNNL7Cnhcrzv-0ytCX6RKun77cvdJGgyWp2k_skZSNCNy3KJgpjEwo07in83kLlenv1G3bIN9fsIWN3BHB5rUuukZlQz0BR-xIrbGu4WVtgKQ2NroI=w2400" width="2048" height="1536" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Grand Canyon of Pennsylvania</figcaption></figure>
<p>He died before his time<br />
Genesis 5: Adam lived a total of 930 years. And he died.<br />
I’ve heard that the very long lives of people mentioned in the first pages of Genesis are the result of someone’s counting the seasons as years or something like that. While I have no authority to say it, I’ll say it anyway: I think that’s silly. Based on the Creation story, I think the Lord designed human beings to live forever. It’s their disobedience that brings death into the world. In fact, this very moment the only man already possessing a resurrection body is still alive 2000 years down the road. He’s physically at the right hand of his Father right now. Sin short-circuited the “forever aspect” of human life and it’s Jesus who redeems, not just the souls of people, but our bodies as well. At this point, Jesus is the only man to experience the redeemed body, but judging from his post-resurrection appearances the new body is a fascinating mix of familiar (eating) and unfamiliar (appearing and disappearing). Now, back to Adam. I think his extremely long life is a residue of his original design. If you think about it, his body was designed for eternity and he “only” lived 930 years. Soon, God will move to further limit life spans, not once, but twice. The original limitation, though, is the big one. Because of sin, life expectancy is throttled back from forever to under 1000 years. For a creature intended to live forever that’s like dying in infancy.<br />
Take away: Jesus redeems us entirely, body and spirit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 09:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those mysterious sons of God Genesis 6: The sons of God noticed that the daughters of men were beautiful. What’s going on here? Who on earth (or beyond this earth) are these sons of God? Do we have some angels coming to earth and being attracted to our women? Now that would make for some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/fMrJawZaTVT0dOgXh-b08B3TbmIFHkBufAL8gNWEvRHCH1MUNBV24V13NBJOZiCWo1tc43QzirKeg1F2b2kDKf8xfUCLY91jLhUxlJ-PkHpfNDDFT9aLWbUuCJSMmwUhZB-7Sb4JU78=w2400" width="2048" height="1536" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Watkins Glen State Park, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p>Those mysterious sons of God<br />
Genesis 6: The sons of God noticed that the daughters of men were beautiful.<br />
What’s going on here? Who on earth (or beyond this earth) are these sons of God? Do we have some angels coming to earth and being attracted to our women? Now that would make for some juicy sermon material! Alas, I don’t think it will work. We don’t find any evidence in the Bible of angels being called “sons of God.” Still, the writer of Genesis says that the result of the union of these mysterious sons of God and the daughters of men is a race of giants: big, aggressive, and conquering. I think the best way to work on this passage is to read it backwards. That is, the result of all this is that God concludes that “human evil is out of control.” The rebellion that started with Adam and Eve has gotten progressively worse to the point that humanity is focused on evil all the time. A branch of the human race has sprung up that threatens God’s plan to redeem human beings. The part about sons of God is how the writer introduces this accelerating fall of humanity. Now, having put it into perspective, the identity of these sons of God isn’t quite as important as it was. It’s just the set up describing why God is about to take drastic action against humanity. It may be that the writer is simply giving us a poetic view of how a race of “mighty men” who have no fear of God came dominate the earth. I do have a theory that I’ll share with you, but its pure speculation. I think the sons of God are the descendants of Seth. It’s through him that the Son of God will trace his lineage. It’s Seth’s offspring who are listed as living those extremely long lives in the previous chapter. I also think the “daughters of men” are the offspring of Cain. That murderer was driven out and is no longer counted as one of God’s people. Just because Cain and his descendants are considered to be outsiders doesn’t mean they fade to nothing. In fact, it’s just the opposite. They’re building cities, developing the arts, and bringing the world into the Bronze Age. You might say that humanity has forked into two distinct groups: those who worship God (sons of God) and those who advance humanity apart from God. When the God-worshipers start intermarrying with these humanists the Lord decides he must act aggressively to save humanity. At least that’s my take on it all.<br />
Take away: God will act aggressively to redeem humanity…that’s true in broad terms, but also at the personal level as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
