<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>observations &#8211; Here and There</title>
	<atom:link href="/travel/tag/observations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/travel</link>
	<description>Scott and Jackie&#039;s Travels – Thousand Trails Reviews, Campground Reviews, Fulltime RVing, European Travel</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 21:06:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2023 &#8211; Amsterdam, Netherlands</title>
		<link>/travel/2023/04/28/2023-amsterdam-netherlands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[grscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 20:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Jackie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[observations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sightseeing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pastorscott.com/travel/?p=5098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The primary purpose of our visit to Amsterdam, Netherlands was to see Keukenhof gardens, but, of course, we wanted to see a bit of the city too. We took the train into the city center where we hopped onto one of the many canal cruises that are available. It was a good choice for us [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe title="2023 - Amsterdam, Netherlands" width="960" height="540" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yVZJRwA_saQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The primary purpose of our visit to Amsterdam, Netherlands was to see Keukenhof gardens, but, of course, we wanted to see a bit of the city too.  We took the train into the city center where we hopped onto one of the many canal cruises that are available.  It was a good choice for us as we got to see many of the historic sights of the city while riding on a canal, something Amsterdam is famous for.  It was a relaxing trip and we recommend it.  Afterwards, we just looked around – visiting the &#8220;flower market&#8221; where all kinds of touristy things are sold.  Jackie did a bit of shopping.  Afterward, we headed for the Palace and Dam Square.  This huge town square was full of people.  It is surrounded by government buildings and shops.  For lunch we boarded a tram and worked our way to the Foodhallen – a unique food court in a big mall.  We wandered the city, enjoying the sights.  </p>
<p>Obviously, our short trip didn&#8217;t give us time to visit some of the famous museums.  We opted for getting a general overview instead.</p>
<p>A few observations.  We felt that public transportation, which was quite good, was rather expensive there. It may be that we&#8217;ve just been spoiled by the prices in Manchester which are less than half what they are in Amsterdam.  Our hotel, the Airport Intercity Hotel, was very nice.  We especially appreciated the full, complimentary breakfast that came with our senior adult rates.  I will mention that the 10 minute walk from the bus/train station was complicated by several steps up and over a dike – something we weren&#8217;t prepared for.  </p>
<p>It was, all things considered, a fun, but short, get-away.  We&#8217;re constantly amazed at how close things are in this part of the world.  Our flight from Manchester to Amsterdam was just over one hour.  The negative was that we were supposed to arrive at the airport around two hours early.  It seems strange to sit in the airport for twice as long as we sat on the plane!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
