<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>hope &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/hope/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 16:06:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>hope &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-100/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 02:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reason]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No reboot necessary Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white. If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage. Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals. The Lord says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fOD5LyiXRhA/X7Gv87Av5OI/AAAAAAABHoE/Jjk_2wAXWgwN2cF_RQcN9a5l64zKyU6UACPcBGAsYHg/s400/06garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
No reboot necessary<br />
Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white.<br />
If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage.  Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals.  The Lord says he’s going to put a stop to it.  However, it doesn&#8217;t have to be with defeat, misery, and destruction.  &#8220;Let&#8217;s be reasonable about this,&#8221; the Almighty says, &#8220;we can fix this, and when I’m finished things will be better than before.&#8221;  All it takes is their being sensible and cooperating with God.  This isn&#8217;t about having a sword hanging over their necks.  It&#8217;s about grace and mercy, not justice.  It&#8217;s still true today.  If God wants to do away with us it’s his right and it’s just what we deserve.  However, rather than hitting the &#8220;delete button&#8221; on humanity he offers restoration.  This passage is filled with sunlight and hope.  Plus that, it&#8217;s a genuine offer from Heaven&#8217;s Throne to each of us.  Come on; let&#8217;s be reasonable about this&#8230;God can fix things, making them right between us and Him.  It&#8217;s too good an offer to refuse.<br />
Take Away: Rather than a re-start of humanity the Lord wants to restore us.  That’s grace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-106/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 03:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Moment of truth Isaiah 6: Every word I&#8217;ve ever spoken is tainted&#8230;words that corrupt and desecrate. Isaiah&#8217;s first reaction to seeing the holiness of God isn’t reverence or ecstasy. Rather, it’s horror. In view of a holy God he realizes his own lack of holiness. When compared to his fellow citizens, Isaiah’s a good man, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-h9AP6odBVn4/X7mpRBeq8KI/AAAAAAABHqo/jMy8wjgli0scPcEHoKBId0NliV_IGrjDACPcBGAsYHg/s600/P7110389.JPG" width="600" height="450" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 Caddo Lake, Louisiana</figcaption></figure><br />
Moment of truth<br />
Isaiah 6: Every word I&#8217;ve ever spoken is tainted&#8230;words that corrupt and desecrate.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s first reaction to seeing the holiness of God isn’t reverence or ecstasy.  Rather, it’s horror.  In view of a holy God he realizes his own lack of holiness.  When compared to his fellow citizens, Isaiah’s a good man, even a righteous man.  However, when he finds himself in the presence of God he sees himself as he really is, and that vision brings him to his knees.  Isaiah&#8217;s words are deeply personal and my reaction to this passage, if it’s honest, starts with me and not with what I perceive to be failure in others.  Jesus touches on this in the Sermon on the Mount when he says, &#8220;Be perfect as your Father in heaven is perfect.&#8221;  Also, I note that Isaiah doesn&#8217;t announce that he’s now going to commence a self-improvement campaign.  Instead, it’s honest recognition of his sinful ways and deep sadness as he realizes just how broken his life is.  Isaiah, in just a few words, says it all: &#8220;I’m doomed because everything about me, even my words, is unclean and unholy.  Now that I’ve seen God I realize the depth of my lostness.  In myself I see no hope whatsoever.&#8221;  The hope of Isaiah isn’t found within himself.  He knows it, and the Lord knows it.<br />
Take Away: It’s only as we’re honest with ourselves and with the Lord that the Lord can begin transforming our lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-118/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 05:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Staying connected Isaiah 15: A Message concerning Moab. Lest it appear that Isaiah has it in only for Babylon, we must note that a quick journey through this portion of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy brings to light God&#8217;s displeasure with several other groups. There’s Philistia, Moab, Ethiopia, Egypt, Tyre and others. In other words, not only have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 929px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hofV-wDSOPk/X8lLo-K7oDI/AAAAAAABHwo/GUfwjMwQ6d0aEjEM-8ZgHcb9EAhSWF19gCPcBGAsYHg/s929/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-55-05%2BPM.JPG" width="929" height="743" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Staying connected<br />
Isaiah 15: A Message concerning Moab.<br />
Lest it appear that Isaiah has it in only for Babylon, we must note that a quick journey through this portion of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy brings to light God&#8217;s displeasure with several other groups.  There’s Philistia, Moab, Ethiopia, Egypt, Tyre and others.  In other words, not only have God&#8217;s people gotten themselves in trouble with the Lord for their sin, they’re surrounded by sinful nations that would like nothing better than to wipe Israel off the map.  (Somehow that sounds familiar &#8212; oh yes, we heard something like this on the news this morning!)  Across the centuries God&#8217;s people have survived only by the grace of God.  Their own failures have brought judgment and their enemies have posed a very real threat to their existence.  Today, that’s still true for all of God&#8217;s people.  We Christians believe we’ve been &#8220;grafted in&#8221; and are, by faith, children of Abraham.  As his people, God holds us to a high standard and we must not forget that.  Also, as did they, we live in hostile territory.  For some believers, this is literally true and for all believers it’s spiritually true.  We’re surrounded by that which would destroy our life in the Lord.  Israel&#8217;s only hope is to reconnect with God.  Today, our remaining &#8220;in Christ&#8221; is also our only hope.<br />
Take Away: Our journey through life takes us through some dangerous territory, our only security is in the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-120/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 05:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judgment day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Preaching a message people don’t want to hear Isaiah 22: Don&#8217;t tell me it&#8217;s going to be all right. These people are doomed. It&#8217;s not all right. Have you ever been to a hurricane party? The tamer version of it is that, with the storm knocking out all power, people dig into their freezers and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NdEtAJ4ItwU/X8wTmMlCC-I/AAAAAAABHxM/qdhSPqpcNJ0FTWeR9ZCz97cWIxYJR6PYwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-42-38%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Preaching a message people don’t want to hear<br />
Isaiah 22: Don&#8217;t tell me it&#8217;s going to be all right.  These people are doomed.  It&#8217;s not all right.<br />
Have you ever been to a hurricane party?  The tamer version of it is that, with the storm knocking out all power, people dig into their freezers and have a feast of all the ice cream, etc. that won&#8217;t survive the power outage.  A few years ago, when we fled a hurricane supposedly aimed for our area we took steaks we’d been saving and had a big cookout as we awaited the bad weather.  We might as well enjoy the food; otherwise it’ll be lost when the electricity goes off.  I wonder if that’s the thinking in this portion of Isaiah.  The nation is in trouble, and no victory has been won, but Isaiah complains about the party atmosphere he sees.  Apparently, someone has told him to lighten up, that things will be all right.  His response is that things aren&#8217;t going to be all right.  They live in a doomed nation and everything’s about to fall apart.  Sometimes our message to our society isn’t the message it wants to hear.  Sometimes, it isn&#8217;t going to be all right.  In fact, when we look at things from the largest point of view we know that the world isn&#8217;t going to just go on and on as it is.  A day’s coming with everything we know is going to melt away.  While we can&#8217;t just live there, in doom and gloom, we Christians need to take a good look at the people around us.  Outside of Christ, to use Isaiah&#8217;s words, &#8220;these people are doomed.&#8221;  Ours is a message of hope, but it’s also the only hope of a world that’s doomed.<br />
Take Away: Our message is one of hope, but we need to remember it’s the only hope of an otherwise doomed humanity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-122/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face. Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself. I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bVc5ehr8RoQ/X869s_8TVCI/AAAAAAABHyE/YYt3gG1zx3w_7ioz8H5QaHDZA_YqWHBZACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-27-46%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted<br />
Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself.  I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet is talking to specific people at a specific moment in history or if he’s slipped into &#8220;prophetic perfect tense&#8221; in which he speaks of the future as though it has already happened.  It may be that he’s speaking on multiple levels of a near future and a distant future with the same words.  At times like this, I take the easy way out and focus on my devotional reading, asking, &#8220;What’s this saying to me right now?&#8221;  As I read this part of Isaiah I can&#8217;t help but think of the book of Revelation which contains almost the exact same words.  In fact, I&#8217;m pretty sure the Revelator is reminded of these words even as he promises the glorious &#8220;no tears&#8221; day.  My conclusion is that whether we’re thinking about the broken people of Isaiah&#8217;s day or persecuted Christians of John&#8217;s day or hurting people today that God&#8217;s message is one of comfort and hope.  Some of that hope is contemporary hope: what God is about to do.  At the same time some of that hope is out there in the uncertain future when the Lord wraps up history and brings a new reality into existence.  I’m not sure about just who it is Isaiah is thinking about in this passage, but I do see here a wonderful theme of God&#8217;s mercy and grace.<br />
Take Away: Yesterday, today, and forever the Lord remains merciful and gracious to his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-126/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 06:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sanctification Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives. They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter center center"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tLxpJRYogHU/X9UfaGwBouI/AAAAAAABH2w/0K5sAXq0Ems8aKduLwY10bRqwtcAgNZhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251345.JPG" alt="" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sanctification<br />
Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives.<br />
They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, has no compliments for them. However, the Lord does have words of hope. It will take some doing but God’s going to make them into a holy people. He’s going to have people who worship in holiness, who reverence him as the holy God of Israel. Getting there is going to cost them everything. They’ll lose the land God gave them and, frankly, many in this generation will lose their lives. Out of the destruction, God will begin remaking them into a people worthy of his Name. Today, God’s still in the business of creating holy people. The process is, in some ways, the same. He brings us to the place where we give up everything, dying out to self. Once all else is gone he fills us with himself. This sanctification process is often painful for us as we struggle with the Lord over ownership of our lives. When we do surrender to him, though, the result is holiness; God honoring, wonderfully satisfied lives.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is still in the business of creating holy people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-128/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 06:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’d rather do it myself Isaiah 30: Your salvation requires you to turn back to me and stop your silly efforts to save yourselves. The salvation being spoken of in this passage isn’t &#8220;getting religion.&#8221; Instead, it’s salvation from an enemy that’s threatening to destroy them. Their effort to save themselves includes preparing for war [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RMNRmI50mvE/X9aXiQIHcqI/AAAAAAABH3w/7o1Qjw1AonceGPo0jjEUGsQpPPxPlTiogCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251325.JPG" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</center></figcaption></figure>
<p>I’d rather do it myself<br />
Isaiah 30: Your salvation requires you to turn back to me and stop your silly efforts to save yourselves.<br />
The salvation being spoken of in this passage isn’t &#8220;getting religion.&#8221; Instead, it’s salvation from an enemy that’s threatening to destroy them. Their effort to save themselves includes preparing for war and forming an alliance with a powerful nation that they might defend themselves. Still, there’s a spiritual element here. Their nation&#8217;s existence has always been improbable, a seeming fluke of history. Their ancestors were slaves who never had a chance of calling any land their own. Had it not been for God Almighty acting on their behalf they would have, by now, been one of thousands of forgotten people groups, a mere footnote in history. To forget just who they are how they came to be is a recipe for disaster. However, that’s exactly what they’ve done. They’ve removed from their lives the One who gave them existence in the first place. Now, when everything starts coming apart they’re looking for a &#8220;reasonable&#8221; solution; a solution that excludes God. Through Isaiah the God they’ve ignored tells them that they have only one chance and that chance is in him. What’s true of nations is also true of individuals. I owe my very life to him. The next breath I take is a gift of the God who has loved me and patiently worked in my life. To turn my back on him and fool myself into thinking I can handle life on my own will result in disaster. In Isaiah&#8217;s words: my &#8220;strength will come from settling down in complete dependence&#8221; on the Lord. There&#8217;s plenty of hope here, but also there’s plenty of warning.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is our hope – our only hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-129/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grace as far as the eye can see Isaiah 30: Cry for help and you&#8217;ll find it&#8217;s grace and more grace. Things are a mess for the people of God. They’re living apart from the God who gave them life. Their nation is under considerable threat and they’re looking for help from everywhere but from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 944px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0sXqhNs4SEQ/X9fPDoe5kxI/AAAAAAABH4Q/MACcFtU8BK8p4lKyL6IzD4RJBFdoiPGiACPcBGAsYHg/s944/P4141689.JPG" width="944" height="676" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; near Brennan, TX</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Grace as far as the eye can see<br />
Isaiah 30: Cry for help and you&#8217;ll find it&#8217;s grace and more grace.<br />
Things are a mess for the people of God. They’re living apart from the God who gave them life. Their nation is under considerable threat and they’re looking for help from everywhere but from the Lord. Things look hopeless and, if they continue as they are, that is just the way it is. Still, through Isaiah, the Almighty reaches out to them. Isaiah says &#8220;He&#8217;s waiting around to be gracious to you.&#8221; This is as powerful a vision of God&#8217;s grace as you&#8217;ll ever find apart from the cross. If the Lord is waiting for me to mess up so he can &#8220;get me&#8221; the wait would be long over. Instead, I see here a picture of God Almighty patiently waiting for me to look his way. When I do that, he doesn&#8217;t tell me I&#8217;ve been bad and that I deserve what I’m about to get. Rather, he tells me he loves me and wants to transform my life in wonderful ways. The only thing that stands between me and the grace of God is, well, me! When I bring my messed up life to him he begins to pour grace out: bucketfuls of it! How about you? Have you been afraid to come to God because you think he’s just waiting to send you to hell? If so, this passage contains some of the best news you&#8217;ll ever find. When you turn to the Lord you find an ocean sized portion of grace just for you.<br />
Take Away: The only thing standing between you and grace is you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-130/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 07:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like an eagle circling high above Isaiah 32: Weep and grieve until the Spirit is poured out on us from above. Isaiah is addressing the women of his society, warning them that Judgment is coming and telling them that when it comes their comfortable lives will be disrupted. The coming danger isn’t just that of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-typrpReT6yQ/X9k_qdGni_I/AAAAAAABH4k/wmw0TTvyitkDR8Sn2oIemxJFqHY-99RzACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5291841.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Buffalo River, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Like an eagle circling high above<br />
Isaiah 32: Weep and grieve until the Spirit is poured out on us from above.<br />
Isaiah is addressing the women of his society, warning them that Judgment is coming and telling them that when it comes their comfortable lives will be disrupted. The coming danger isn’t just that of invading armies but of crop failures resulting in famine in the land. Everything will be turned upside down on that day which Isaiah specifically says is just a little over a year away. With such a storm bearing down on them Isaiah says there’s just one thing to do: repent and seek God. The coming disaster isn’t some random event. It’s the Judgment of God. It’s not too late for them to change their ways and seek the Lord. Earlier, the prophet pictured God as a mighty eagle, circling high in the sky, not waiting to pounce upon some unwitting prey, but waiting to deliver. Now, he says that if sinning, God-rejecting people will repent of their sin the Lord will pour his Spirit out upon them from above. We often think of the prophets as having messages of only gloom and doom but that’s only a portion of their work. In this passage we see an abundant measure of hope for even the most God-rejecting life. To this day, the Lord waits for us to look up in repentance and trust that he might pour his Spirit out on our lives.<br />
Take Away: Like a circling eagle, the Lord hovers over us, waiting for an opportunity to dish out abundant mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-137/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second coming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking to the distant mountains Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God. An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range. As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QHj_F29QPmk/X-IZXHRO1-I/AAAAAAABH9U/mCJxOwSoeacenLKkqcw9h_OsO6BQgJuRACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281810.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Looking to the distant mountains<br />
Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God.<br />
An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range.  As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but at the greater distance is yet another taller and even more majestic peak.  Coloradoans call the really big ones, &#8220;fourteeners,&#8221; that is, they’re over 14,000 feet in height.  From my vantage point I can’t tell how far it is between the two mountains.  It’s only as I actually travel through the mountains that I realize there’s a deep valley between the first and the second mountain range.  As the prophets are given a vision of God&#8217;s intentions they sometimes see an act of God that’s close at hand and at the same time see a similar but even greater event more distant than they can imagine.  Here in Isaiah 40 the focus of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecies is on comfort and hope.  These words will become a life line for his people in a few years.  All the terrible things he&#8217;s warned them of will come to pass, and in distant lands the next generation will turn to these words to find comfort in their sorrow.  When I read this passage at the level of the &#8220;front range&#8221; I see that God&#8217;s broken people have hope of restoration.  The Lord’s going to return to their lives as a powerful king might return to his kingdom.  Isaiah&#8217;s command to them is to start preparing for this sure event by making a smooth and straight road into their lives.  However, beyond that &#8220;front range&#8221; is a gigantic &#8220;fourteener,&#8221; the coming of the King of Kings to this world.  Hundreds of years later this prophecy will become John the Baptist&#8217;s text and it’ll be fulfilled in a much greater way by King Jesus.  As a Christian I can identify with the dual nature of this passage.  That &#8220;front range&#8221; view is when I receive Jesus as King in my own heart.  The &#8220;fourteener&#8221; view is when Jesus comes to this world the second time as King and Judge of all.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes the words of the prophets of the Lord cause us to look both to the past and to the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
