<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>murder &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/murder/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 13:13:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>murder &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Numbers</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-numbers-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Come into my heart, Lord Jesus” Numbers 35: Don&#8217;t desecrate the land in which you live. I live here too…. I’ve now worked my way through the &#8220;numbers&#8221; of the book of Numbers. Numbers of people and cattle and cities; who lives where and how many days between various worship events. It isn&#8217;t exactly riveting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Z8Vzs3SqyDM/XVnPrwgXxjI/AAAAAAABAHg/-UwPAfxne5YUqZhoL0XmwcxE_FpM4f_JACKgBGAs/s1600/P6239571.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
“Come into my heart, Lord Jesus”<br />
Numbers 35: Don&#8217;t desecrate the land in which you live.  I live here too….<br />
I’ve now worked my way through the &#8220;numbers&#8221; of the book of Numbers.  Numbers of people and cattle and cities; who lives where and how many days between various worship events.  It isn&#8217;t exactly riveting reading.  In fact, it would have been easy to miss the pure gold at the end of chapter 35.  The issue here is how the people are to deal with murder.  Due to the fact that the laws God gives the Israelites are foundational to our own legal system it seems to be pretty common stuff.  Actually though, it’s groundbreaking material, reshaping human society.  God insists on justice, and adds that if society takes murder lightly the whole land will be polluted.  Then he adds, &#8220;don&#8217;t desecrate the land where you live &#8212; after all, I live here too.&#8221;  In spite of the dreary subject, this is a wonderful phrase of hope.  Their Creator, the Sovereign of the Universe, God Almighty says his address is on their street.  These days, because of the Gift of the Holy Spirit, things are even more personal.  God lives, not just &#8220;in the land&#8221; but &#8220;in my heart.&#8221;  If God&#8217;s presence in the land emphasized the importance of purity there, how much more does his presence in my life call for purity of heart?<br />
Take Away: It’s a wonderful blessing to have the Lord call our lives “home” – at the same time it carries with it a real sense of responsibility.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 08:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those we empower 2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you. It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MjY1xk74qN4/XgUuWqxpnsI/AAAAAAABDFI/rs_ShgebvPs4s2UqyLSuF9BNRQdXh5ZMACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129899.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Those we empower<br />
2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you.<br />
It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants but for one thing: he continues to refuse to lay a hand on Saul&#8217;s descendants. Because of that, things drag on as Ish-Bosheth&#8217;s leadership of Israel slowly unravels on its own. One indication is that his general, Abner, secretly comes to David with an offer of peace. Apparently, David thinks that with Abner&#8217;s help the foregone conclusion of all this can end sooner and not later, and without his raising a hand against Saul&#8217;s son. It doesn’t work out. David&#8217;s own general seizes the opportunity to get revenge for the death of his brother at Abner&#8217;s hand. Before Abner can act Joab kills him. As often happens in life, the greatest damage done is from &#8220;inside&#8221; rather than &#8220;outside.&#8221; In this case, David has one agenda and his general, Joab, has another. One of the challenges of leadership is not only knowing where one is going, but being sure that those we lead &#8212; or even better &#8212; those we empower to lead with us, share in that goal. Otherwise, they’ll take the authority we’ve given them and use it to pursue their own purposes.<br />
Take Away: Real leaders don’t try to do everything themselves. At the same time, though, it’s important that those who work with us are on the same page as we are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 11:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[He’s my friend, but&#8230; 2 Samuel 20: Amasa didn’t notice the sword in Joab’s other hand. Following the defeat and death of Absalom David returns to Jerusalem, victorious but weakened. Soon, there’s another uprising led by Sheba. David realizes that he has to act decisively if he’s to hold Israel together. He shakes up his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-29Tr7X-d5nU/XiUQAXflycI/AAAAAAABDnI/DueFJ6cm30gwpSNFB5DQ_bHi2fjsnLr5ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129983.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
He’s my friend, but&#8230;<br />
2 Samuel 20: Amasa didn’t notice the sword in Joab’s other hand.<br />
Following the defeat and death of Absalom David returns to Jerusalem, victorious but weakened. Soon, there’s another uprising led by Sheba. David realizes that he has to act decisively if he’s to hold Israel together. He shakes up his inner circle, replacing commander Joab with Amasa. The new general is given three days to rally troops to go after Sheba. Time passes and Amasa, for some reason, doesn’t report in and David, feeling time is of the essence bypasses Joab again, this time naming Abishai to lead the force. Being overlooked again angers Joab and with ruthless cunning he acts to regain his position. He, and those loyal to him, joins Abishai’s expedition to root out Sheba. When this group meets Amasa and the force he’s rallied, Joab approaches Amasa as though he’s going to warmly greet him. He then plunges a sword into him, killing him instantly. Amasa is now numbered with Abner and Absalom, all murdered by Joab. Before anyone can respond, he calls for unity in the name of David. In reality, it’s all about him and his power. Joab, though faithful to David, is a ruthless person but David never deals with him. However, he tells his son Solomon that Joab has spilled much innocent blood and that because of him his legacy is stained. I can’t help but wonder why David let Joab get away with it all. He’s David’s nephew but I doubt that has anything to do with it. I think the problem is that Joab serves David’s purposes so well. He’s on David’s side even though his actions aren’t approved of by David. We Christians would do well to study the relationship between David and Joab. Is it possible that we’re too quick to overlook wrong doing by our allies? If someone who’s on “our side” is behaving in an unethical way do we tend to look the other way? Christians are called to a high standard. That should include our reigning in or even disavowing our “friends” when their behavior violates that standard.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately, there’s no right way to do a wrong thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 13:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehoshaphat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The funeral service was poorly attended 2 Chronicles 21: There were no tears shed when he died – it was good riddance! Jehoshaphat fathers five sons and he leaves them each an inheritance of wealth. Additionally each one is given a fortified city to rule, basically setting them up for life. His oldest son, Jehoram, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4uaX9XGTowI/Xsw18As6rtI/AAAAAAABFHg/g89NhDbas_0r6sgVHxh8d407kiOamDbigCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180728_170243.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Lighthouses and coastal area south of Portland, ME</figcaption></figure><br />
The funeral service was poorly attended<br />
2 Chronicles 21: There were no tears shed when he died – it was good riddance!<br />
Jehoshaphat fathers five sons and he leaves them each an inheritance of wealth. Additionally each one is given a fortified city to rule, basically setting them up for life. His oldest son, Jehoram, gets the throne. This could work out as the most successful handoff of power since Solomon took the throne from his father, David. Instead, there’s murder and abandonment of God. This wicked man murders all his brothers and leads his subjects away from God. The Lord, in turn, is disgusted with him. There are rebellions and then a humiliating and destroying illness. After eight years of failure Jehoram is dead. And no one cares. What a pitiful life story. How sobering it is to think that the untimely death of a person is considered a favor of God to those under his influence and authority. What an important reminder to realize it all started when he turned his back on God. Each life journey arrives at key forks in the road. When I arrive at such a place I make a fresh decision concerning the type of person I will be. That decision will impact not only me, but those who are closest to me, and in some cases, even people I’ll never know. Because of the importance of how I handle those big moments in my life, I want to practice for them by dealing with the little stuff in the right way. Little things lead to big things. Big things lead to eternity.<br />
Take Away: We become the people we are by the decisions we make along the way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
