<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Abner &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/abner/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 08:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Abner &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 08:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[War games aren’t fun 2 Samuel 3: The war between the house of Saul and the house of David dragged on and on. Sadly, Saul&#8217;s death and David&#8217;s return to Israel isn’t the end of Saul&#8217;s story. His general, Abner, makes Saul&#8217;s son, Ish-Bosheth king over Israel. Meanwhile, David has moved to Hebron in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zBxZ6S4BQr8/XgQBlEgL-BI/AAAAAAABDE8/vw_u-FrCk0ICb5WzPs85OwAepFvSlf3OgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129891.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
War games aren’t fun<br />
2 Samuel 3: The war between the house of Saul and the house of David dragged on and on.<br />
Sadly, Saul&#8217;s death and David&#8217;s return to Israel isn’t the end of Saul&#8217;s story. His general, Abner, makes Saul&#8217;s son, Ish-Bosheth king over Israel. Meanwhile, David has moved to Hebron in the area of Judah. He’s made king there. Israel’s now divided, with the larger part being ruled by Saul&#8217;s son and the smaller area ruled by David. The result is civil war. David no longer needs to run. He has an army equal to that of Israel. Because of that both sides jealously defend their territory. This is civil war at its ugliest, with relatives battling one another. One major battle takes place at the Pool of Gibeon, where the armies meet face to face. In a deadly game, representatives from each side are pitted against one another in one-on-one fights to the death. As David&#8217;s men win one round after another things escalate to a major battle in which fighters from each side can call one another by name. It is ugly, ugly, ugly. Civil wars are the worst wars in which people who know one another and share common interests and goals fight it out, leaving corpses scattered across the battlefield. There’s nothing more tragic than war within the family. Church people should do everything possible to avoid such wars. The problem is that, as happened at the Pool of Gibeon, such wars start with much smaller barbed &#8220;games&#8221; of saying two edged things to one another or giving or taking offense easily. Oh, how we need the grace of God in our relationships with one another.<br />
Take Away: We can more skillfully hurt those closest to us – so dealing with these precious ones must be especially flavored with grace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 08:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those we empower 2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you. It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MjY1xk74qN4/XgUuWqxpnsI/AAAAAAABDFI/rs_ShgebvPs4s2UqyLSuF9BNRQdXh5ZMACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129899.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Those we empower<br />
2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you.<br />
It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants but for one thing: he continues to refuse to lay a hand on Saul&#8217;s descendants. Because of that, things drag on as Ish-Bosheth&#8217;s leadership of Israel slowly unravels on its own. One indication is that his general, Abner, secretly comes to David with an offer of peace. Apparently, David thinks that with Abner&#8217;s help the foregone conclusion of all this can end sooner and not later, and without his raising a hand against Saul&#8217;s son. It doesn’t work out. David&#8217;s own general seizes the opportunity to get revenge for the death of his brother at Abner&#8217;s hand. Before Abner can act Joab kills him. As often happens in life, the greatest damage done is from &#8220;inside&#8221; rather than &#8220;outside.&#8221; In this case, David has one agenda and his general, Joab, has another. One of the challenges of leadership is not only knowing where one is going, but being sure that those we lead &#8212; or even better &#8212; those we empower to lead with us, share in that goal. Otherwise, they’ll take the authority we’ve given them and use it to pursue their own purposes.<br />
Take Away: Real leaders don’t try to do everything themselves. At the same time, though, it’s important that those who work with us are on the same page as we are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
