<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>reconciliation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/reconciliation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 09:29:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>reconciliation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[division]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reconciliation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-18/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Christian way Matthew 18: If a fellow believer hurts you, go and tell him – work it out between the two of you. We Christians claim to be followers of Jesus but we tend to overlook some of the inconvenient things he teaches. Jesus says that if there’s something going on between me and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15674" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15674" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15674" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029325.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15674" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Christian way</p>
<p>Matthew 18: If a fellow believer hurts you, go and tell him – work it out between the two of you.</p>
<p>We Christians claim to be followers of Jesus but we tend to overlook some of the inconvenient things he teaches.  Jesus says that if there’s something going on between me and you that my first order of business is to go to you and explain to you how I’ve been hurt.  If that doesn’t work out there are further steps I’m to take in seeking reconciliation with you.  The thing is we Christians seldom follow these clear instructions.  We go around with a chip on our shoulder, talk about people (otherwise known as gossip), start lining up our allies and identifying our enemies and, in general, toss aside this teaching of our Lord and Master.  When that’s done, a rift in the church is formed that draws people into the fight and drives people out of the church.  Energies that should be spent in winning the lost are wasted in attempts to win the fight.   Still, for those of us who can’t imagine dealing with a broken relationship like Jesus says, I’m going to offer an alternative approach.  Just forget it.  Stop being hurt, stop “remembering,” stop talking, and forgive from the depths of your heart.  Apologize to Jesus for being so shallow as to be hurt about whatever it is and ask him to forgive you as you’re forgiving them.  This alternative is almost implied by the rest of this passage in which Jesus talks about the unforgiving servant.  So, when I’m hurt and upset about something, as a follower of Jesus, I have a couple of options.  I can go to you and begin the reconciliation process Jesus described or I can stop being so sensitive and let it go, forgiving as I’ve been forgiven.  Responding to hurts in these ways is how Christians do things.</p>
<p>Take Away: A Christian with a chip on his or her shoulder isn’t behaving like a Christian at all.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 09:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Absalom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reconciliation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God provides a way back 2 Samuel 14: God does not take away life. He works out ways to get the exile back. After avenging the terrible thing done to this sister Tamar by murdering his half-brother, Ammon, Absalom has fled, fearing for his own life. Now three years have passed and David&#8217;s general, Joab, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-bogcwMzqNhQ/XheTD_0Oe7I/AAAAAAABDJY/aMY1C66jgLsY5P9cjHToDOPQFxMQqESfQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129947.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
God provides a way back<br />
2 Samuel 14: God does not take away life. He works out ways to get the exile back.<br />
After avenging the terrible thing done to this sister Tamar by murdering his half-brother, Ammon, Absalom has fled, fearing for his own life. Now three years have passed and David&#8217;s general, Joab, thinks it is time for David to reconcile with his son. Earlier, Nathan brought to David a made-up story and confronted him with the memorable words: &#8220;You are the man!&#8221; Now, Joab sends a woman from Tekoa to do a similar thing. She pretends to be the mother of two sons. In her story, one son has killed the other. Now her family is out for revenge by taking the life of her remaining son. David rules compassionately saying he&#8217;ll take care of it. It’s then that the woman challenges David for doing the same thing concerning Absalom. She points out that God seeks ways to bring the exile back and that David should do the same thing. David sees the hand of Joab in this but agrees to at least open the way for his son&#8217;s return. This incident is a mere snapshot taken during a fast moving flow of events, but I’m taken with the wisdom of the woman from Tekoa. Before Jesus ever tells the famous parable, she pictures for us the forgiving mercy of God for the prodigal. She’s one hundred percent correct: &#8220;He works out ways to get the exile back.&#8221; We serve the God of Second Chances.<br />
Take Away: Never give up on God – after all, he never gives up on us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
