<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>enthusiasm &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/enthusiasm/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:36:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>enthusiasm &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enthusiasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of enthusiasm Exodus 35: Then they came back, every one whose heart was roused, whose spirit was freely responsive, bringing offerings to God for building the Tent of Meeting. God gave Moses the plans for the Tabernacle and now Moses has passed them on to the people. A one-of-a-kind of worship center will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-A6msaTYf-Wg/XRrI2WA4lJI/AAAAAAAA8r8/iqZIU55Dx-w7vMt24W3-oLXcx8-udUlBACKgBGAs/s1600/flowers-006.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; In and around the Skagit Valley of Washington</figcaption></figure><br />
The power of enthusiasm<br />
Exodus 35: Then they came back, every one whose heart was roused, whose spirit was freely responsive, bringing offerings to God for building the Tent of Meeting.<br />
God gave Moses the plans for the Tabernacle and now Moses has passed them on to the people.  A one-of-a-kind of worship center will be constructed.  It will be portable but in spite of its portability it will be an elaborate structure, a place reflective of the God they worship.  When Moses tells them what God requires it sparks excitement throughout the congregation.  Now, without any pressure, the people freely give so that the Tent of Meeting can be constructed according to God’s plans.  As I look at the people coming with their gifts, my attention is drawn to those “roused hearts.”  Enthusiasm is a powerful emotion.  As it does for them, it stirs me to action and makes me willing to make sacrifices.  I want to have a “heart that is roused” when it comes to my relationship with God and his Church. There are many things that demand my attention and my support.  Those things may or may not be worthy.  However, doing God’s work is always worth the effort.  Stir my heart, O God, that I might be “roused” to enthusiastic, sacrificial service of you.<br />
Take Away: I serve the Lord, not because I must, but because I may.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enthusiasm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Little deals are sometimes big deals 2Kings 13: The king struck the ground three times and then quit. The old prophet Elisha is nearing the end of life. Unlike his mentor, Elijah, he&#8217;ll not depart this world in a whirlwind. Instead, he’ll die from old age and illness. However, before he goes, he has good [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Bnysz_PXhiU/XnoXEU4Jh3I/AAAAAAABEUs/eVPgwOTn1hM0kWIhR9QR4rQ0CY4JQhTzwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170813_165105.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; KIdder Recreation Area &#8211; Wahpeton, ND &#8211; Red River</figcaption></figure><br />
Little deals are sometimes big deals<br />
2Kings 13: The king struck the ground three times and then quit.<br />
The old prophet Elisha is nearing the end of life. Unlike his mentor, Elijah, he&#8217;ll not depart this world in a whirlwind. Instead, he’ll die from old age and illness. However, before he goes, he has good news for Jehoash, king of Israel. The king is instructed to fire an arrow in the direction of his enemies. Then Elisha instructs him to strike the ground with the remaining arrows. Obviously, this is supposed to be an action related to their struggle with Aram but the king only strikes the ground a few times and stops. Elisha tells him that what he does isn’t good enough and that his minimum cooperation is symbolic of the few times he&#8217;ll defeat Aram. Had he responded with enthusiasm and commitment things could have been different but his token response will result in only a token defeat of Aram. The wise man of Ecclesiastes says, &#8220;Whatever your hand finds to do, do it with all your might&#8221; (Eccl. 9:10). Had Jehoash been ordered to actually go into battle he would have, no doubt, done it with &#8220;all his might&#8221; but since this was merely symbolic he just gave a token effort. With that, Elisha and, apparently God, is displeased. So as I read this story I’m reminded that things that appear to me to be a &#8220;little deal&#8221; are sometimes a &#8220;big deal&#8221; in God&#8217;s eyes.<br />
Take Away: If the Lord says “do it” then do whatever it is with everything you’ve got.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
