<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jesus &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/jesus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Jesus &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-119/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 05:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Missionary outreach Isaiah 19: God will openly show himself to the Egyptians and they&#8217;ll get to know him on that Day. The words of condemnation to Egypt compare what’s coming to a powerful storm, sweeping away everything in its path. Even the mighty Nile, the symbol of life in Egypt, will be dried up and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 510px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-AcM_uCYSKP8/X8q0Sta8KwI/AAAAAAABHw4/mQW-CVI4_f4WMXqmXUIAojcSsV9H2SvbACPcBGAsYHg/s510/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-44-19%2BPM.JPG" width="510" height="408" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Missionary outreach<br />
Isaiah 19: God will openly show himself to the Egyptians and they&#8217;ll get to know him on that Day.<br />
The words of condemnation to Egypt compare what’s coming to a powerful storm, sweeping away everything in its path.  Even the mighty Nile, the symbol of life in Egypt, will be dried up and the nation will be in a hopeless state.  Surprisingly, Isaiah&#8217;s tone suddenly changes.  It’s almost as though the storm ends and the sun breaks through.  God will make an appearance to Egypt and, with all else swept away, the people of that land will turn to him with all their hearts.  Isaiah says, &#8220;Egypt will come back to God.&#8221;  Additionally, we’re told, Assyria will join Egypt in the worship of God and the result will be that they’ll &#8220;share the blessing.&#8221;  In one of his most famous statements Jesus announces that God &#8220;so loved the world.&#8221;  However, here we are back in the Old Testament where a Hebrew prophet has been, just as would be expected, telling how God’s going to destroy all the enemies of the people of Israel.  Then, the tone of his prophecy suddenly changes.  The enemies of God&#8217;s people aren&#8217;t going to be wiped off the face of the earth.  Instead, they’re going to be converted!  Here, then is the heart of every missionary effort.  If God wants to do away with those who reject him, he can do it with just a word.  Instead, he engineers circumstances designed to draw us to him.  Granted, some of those circumstances are stout medicine, but, then again, it isn&#8217;t annihilation, which is what we deserve.  In this somewhat confusing turnabout passage we get a glimpse of what will only become clear through the ministry of Jesus.<br />
Take Away: The Lord wants to save all people – that’s good news for you and me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 11:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Palm Sunday foretold Zechariah 9: Your king is coming! Israel is without a king and under the rule of the Persian King Darius. As the returned exiles accept the call of God to rebuild the Temple, the Lord encourages them through the messages and visions of the prophet Zechariah. God&#8217;s pleased with them and their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15573" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15573" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15573" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309209.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15573" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mesa Verde National Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Palm Sunday foretold<br />
Zechariah 9: Your king is coming!<br />
Israel is without a king and under the rule of the Persian King Darius.  As the returned exiles accept the call of God to rebuild the Temple, the Lord encourages them through the messages and visions of the prophet Zechariah.  God&#8217;s pleased with them and their commitment to the huge Temple project and promises to be with them.  He’ll do for them what they cannot do themselves.  Good days are ahead.  Not only will the Lord help them in the reconstruction project, he’s going to make them into a great nation that will influence all the nations of the earth.  The day will come when they’ll be freed from the rule of Darius and will, instead, be ruled by a King sent from God.  That king will come into Jerusalem, not riding a mount of war, but upon a mount that symbolizes humility and peace, a donkey.  It will be 500 years before that event takes place and then at least 2000 years more before the promise Zechariah gives is totally fulfilled. However, the “donkey riding King” has already ridden into Jerusalem.  It happened when Jesus, the Messiah, rode a borrowed donkey into Jerusalem on the day we call Palm Sunday.  When that took place, the words of long dead Zechariah were proven literally true.<br />
Take Away: The Lord always keeps his promises.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lamb, Lion, King Revelation 5: Look – the Lion from Tribe Judah, the Root of David’s Tree, has conquered. The One who sits on the Throne has a small, sealed scroll full of mysteries to be revealed. However, not just anyone is qualified to open it. In fact, no one can be found and it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16373" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16373" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16373" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16373" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Lamb, Lion, King</p>
<p>Revelation 5: Look – the Lion from Tribe Judah, the Root of David’s Tree, has conquered.</p>
<p>The One who sits on the Throne has a small, sealed scroll full of mysteries to be revealed. However, not just anyone is qualified to open it. In fact, no one can be found and it appears to John as though his “revelation” isn’t going to happen. Then, he sees a Lamb that appears both weak and strong at the same time; bearing marks of death but with traits of unequaled wisdom and strength. John hears one of the Elders call this Lamb “the Lion from Tribe Judah.” We know about Judah. That’s the royal family tree of Israel. King David was of that family; so is Jesus. The One John sees looks like a slain Lamb that&#8217;s very much alive and powerful. This Lamb is also a Lion – a conqueror. He takes the scroll but at that moment no one&#8217;s thinking of the scroll. All heaven bursts forth in praise for the Lamb-Lion. It’s a thrilling moment as “thousand after thousand after thousand” of heavenly beings break forth in a song of praise. That group gets the first verse, then for the next one, all creation joins in. What a scene! There’s more to read, more to be revealed, and more to consider. For the moment though, as happens in this scene of worship I think I’ll just stop and join them in worshiping this Lamb-Lion-King.</p>
<p>Take Away: Worship of Jesus is at the heart of all Creation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
