<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Open Theism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/open-theism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Open Theism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Theism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Take your pick Daniel 4: Make a clean break with your sins&#8230;quit your wicked life&#8230;then you will continue to have a good life. Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s been dreaming again. This time he dreams of a larger-than-life tree that commands the landscape and provides for all around it. In the dream God orders the tree to be cut [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3Ayb8tsdWtI/YL0f5UX8m_I/AAAAAAABKZE/GkLlLW0dcM8Zg-P5h4lDu5c2eOWK8_QUACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA037698.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Windsor Castle, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
Take your pick<br />
Daniel 4: Make a clean break with your sins&#8230;quit your wicked life&#8230;then you will continue to have a good life.<br />
Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s been dreaming again.  This time he dreams of a larger-than-life tree that commands the landscape and provides for all around it.  In the dream God orders the tree to be cut down but the stump be saved.  Nebuchadnezzar wants to know the meaning of the dream and Daniel comes through for him.  The king’s &#8220;statue&#8221; dream was about his kingdom.  His &#8220;tree&#8221; dream is about him personally.  The Lord&#8217;s weary of Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s ignoring him.  When there are miraculous events that declare God Almighty to him Nebuchadnezzar gives God lip service, but goes on living his own way.  This time, the Lord will touch his life directly to humble him enough that he&#8217;ll stop merely declaring the Lord to be God but will start acting as though he believes it.  After explaining the dream to Nebuchadnezzar Daniel pleads with him to respond now and avoid the reality of what he&#8217;s dreamed.  In other words, through the dream and Daniel&#8217;s interpretation of it Nebuchadnezzar is being given a choice.  If he continues as he is the dream will become reality.  If he repents right now and changes his ways he can continue &#8220;to have a good life.&#8221;  I see this as an example of the openness of God.  Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s future isn&#8217;t already set, but based on how he responds to this warning, it&#8217;s already known.  If he heeds this warning from God things will go one way.  If he ignores it, things will go the other.  In this I see the Lord as knowing, not just one set future, but all possible futures.  In this application we see God not only warning Nebuchadnezzar, but offering him a much more desirable alternative.  Still, the Lord won&#8217;t negate his free will&#8230;the ball is in Nebuchadnezzar’s court.<br />
Take Away: The Lord has granted us free will, but he holds us accountable for our exercise of that free will.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jonah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jonah-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Theism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The God of whatever happens Jonah 3: God&#8230;did change his mind about them. What an interesting statement! God intends to do one thing, but then, in response to what they do, he changes his mind and does something else. This view of God challenges our thinking about who he is and how he works in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9kpH25kqDvQ/YQHAgO-TvWI/AAAAAAABK1o/kjFF7jtzSQs6ZVbpxgJsQkSrV8JqBZofgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P8209017.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Shenandoah National Park, VA &#8211; Skyline Drive</figcaption></figure><br />
The God of whatever happens<br />
Jonah 3: God&#8230;did change his mind about them.<br />
What an interesting statement!  God intends to do one thing, but then, in response to what they do, he changes his mind and does something else.  This view of God challenges our thinking about who he is and how he works in this world.  The Lord&#8217;s willing to be influenced by what we say and do.  Of course, in this case, this is what he wanted to have happen.  Had God only wanted to destroy them we&#8217;d have no story of Jonah and the big fish.  Instead, we&#8217;d have another Sodom and Gomorrah story about fire and brimstone wiping out a sinful city.  The reluctant prophet is sent on this mission exactly because God wants their lives to change.  This is a classic Old Testament prophet situation.  The prophet says, “If you do this, God&#8217;s going to do that&#8230;if you do that, God&#8217;s going to do this.”  The Lord’s message to Nineveh is that, because of their sin, destruction is coming.  However, even though it&#8217;s unspoken, they&#8217;re also being given a choice.  If sin is bringing destruction, repentance will bring life.  When the people of Nineveh make the right choice God is happy to change his mind.  This kind of thinking opens up all kinds of possibilities for us.  When I pray, asking for God’s intervention in some matter, I’m not just going through a spiritual discipline.  Rather, I’m actually being allowed to influence God!  My standing in this world is much more than my traveling some predetermined path to some predetermined conclusion.  I’m a partner with God who&#8217;s allowing me to work with him in changing the world.  Here’s a view of a God who&#8217;s never at a loss; who always knows what he&#8217;ll do in response to what I do of my own free will.  Such a view doesn’t make God less.  Instead, it makes him more.  He&#8217;s God whatever happens.<br />
Take Away: As his people we’re partners with the Lord who allows us to work with him in changing the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
