<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Zechariah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-zechariah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 16:36:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Zechariah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 11:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s gracious offer Zechariah 1: Come back to me and I’ll come back to you. Haggai isn’t the only preacher talking about rebuilding the Temple. Zechariah is right there with him calling for the reconstruction of the place of worship. In fact, long after Haggai has disappeared from the world stage we find Zechariah still [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15617" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15617" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15617" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029264.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15617" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s gracious offer<br />
Zechariah 1: Come back to me and I’ll come back to you.<br />
Haggai isn’t the only preacher talking about rebuilding the Temple.  Zechariah is right there with him calling for the reconstruction of the place of worship.  In fact, long after Haggai has disappeared from the world stage we find Zechariah still proclaiming God’s message.  Zechariah is an encourager to his people, reminding them that, as his name means: “The Lord remembers.”  He wants them to know that God remembers the promises he made to their ancestors and that they can depend on him to keep those promises.  His book starts with very good news as the Lord says to them, “Come back to me and I’ll come back to you.”  One doesn’t have to have lived 2500 years ago to be stirred by these words.  The Lord isn’t a hard, unforgiving Judge who&#8217;s out to destroy us.  Instead, he’s compassionate and merciful; patiently inviting us to respond to his message of hope.  Again, I don’t have to be one of the ancient returned exiles to be thrilled with this invitation.  In Christ, that invitation is enhanced and God’s intense desire is made even clearer.  When I turn to the Lord I find that he’s already met me more than half way – that happened on a hill called Calvary.<br />
Take Away: When we come to the Lord we find that, not only is he willing to forgive us, but that he loves showing us mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Legacy of faithfulness Zechariah 1: But the Message&#8230;isn’t dead and buried. Zechariah remembers the stories of the old time prophets of his history. They were spiritual giants like Isaiah and Jeremiah and Ezekiel. These mighty men proclaimed God’s message with, admittedly, limited contemporary success. The people of their day ignored their message and faced the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15620" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15620" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15620" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/P5029265.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15620" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
Legacy of faithfulness<br />
Zechariah 1: But the Message&#8230;isn’t dead and buried.<br />
Zechariah remembers the stories of the old time prophets of his history.  They were spiritual giants like Isaiah and Jeremiah and Ezekiel.  These mighty men proclaimed God’s message with, admittedly, limited contemporary success.  The people of their day ignored their message and faced the consequences.  Now, all that is in the distant past and the people God claimed as his own are back in their home country, reestablishing their lives there.  Zechariah has a new word from the Lord.  Well, the word is new, but the message is old.  The Lord still calls people to an obedient walk with himself.  He still invites those who will to live in his fellowship and to participate in his holiness.  The messengers might have changed, but the purpose of God remains.  It’s humbling to realize that, as a pastor, I have a role in this process today.  I know that someday my voice will be silenced (hopefully, not for a few decades yet) and hope that when the kids (these days, that’s anyone less than thirty) look back on my ministry that they&#8217;ll remember me as one who was faithful in proclaiming the timeless truths of God.<br />
Take Away: As people look back on our lives let them remember us as those who were faithful to God’s call on our lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not acting like a bully Zechariah 1: &#8230;Godless nations that act as if they own the whole world. About half of this book of Zechariah contains descriptions of visions the prophet is given. In the first vision the Lord tells Zechariah that he’s angry with “godless nations that act as if they own the whole [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15546" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15546" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15546" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15546" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Tombigbee State Park &#8211; Tupelo, MS &#8211; road to the park</figcaption></figure><br />
Not acting like a bully<br />
Zechariah 1: &#8230;Godless nations that act as if they own the whole world.<br />
About half of this book of Zechariah contains descriptions of visions the prophet is given.  In the first vision the Lord tells Zechariah that he’s angry with “godless nations that act as if they own the whole world.”  Not only is the Lord angry, he’s about to do something about it.  The Lord had given the mega-powers of the region authority over Israel but they went too far, crushing that tiny nation without any show of mercy.  The Lord says he was angry with Israel, but now he&#8217;s very angry with these nations that acted without mercy.  The vision is intended to condemn those world powers while comforting powerless Israel.  I’m reminded as I read these words that I live in a nation that is a world power.  We have the economic and military might to dominate others.  The vision of the prophet speaks to me, not as one of the oppressed but instead, as one of the powerful.  God has a history of looking out for the needs of the powerless and of holding the powerful accountable.  We aren’t to go around the world flexing our muscles like a bully who always has to get his own way.  The truth is that we don’t own the whole world and we had better remember who does!<br />
Take Away: It’s God’s world and we’re accountable to him for how we live in his world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 11:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's protection]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A wonderful promise Zechariah 2: A wall of fire around&#8230;and a radiant presence within. When the exiles arrived at Jerusalem they found a city in ruins, uninhabitable. They went to work rebuilding their city and its protective wall. In fact, there’s a book of the Bible, Nehemiah, which is almost completely focused on the rebuilding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15548" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15548" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840-1024x589.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="552" class="size-large wp-image-15548" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840-1024x589.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840-300x173.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840-768x442.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840-1536x883.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PHOTO_20151104_092840.jpg 1925w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15548" class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; LeFleur&#8217;s Bluff State Park &#8211; Jackson, MS</figcaption></figure><br />
A wonderful promise<br />
Zechariah 2: A wall of fire around&#8230;and a radiant presence within.<br />
When the exiles arrived at Jerusalem they found a city in ruins, uninhabitable.  They went to work rebuilding their city and its protective wall.  In fact, there’s a book of the Bible, Nehemiah, which is almost completely focused on the rebuilding of the wall of Jerusalem.  Now, Zachariah is told that, due to the Lord’s blessing, Jerusalem&#8217;s going to outgrow its walls.  There’s no need to fear though, because God, himself, is going to be a wall of fire around that city, protecting it from all invaders.  The prophet adds that, even better, God’s presence is going to be burning inside the city as well.  I know that these words are spoken to the Israelites as a nation and not as individuals.  Indeed, it’s a wonderful promise to these exiles as they labor to re-establish themselves in this land that was promised to them centuries earlier.  Still, I can’t help but internalize this promise.  The Lord is with me.  He surrounds me with his presence.  Nothing comes into my life that he doesn’t allow.  Meanwhile, in my heart, I enjoy the “radiant presence” of the Lord.  He protects me and he blesses me.  I know that in a Christian sense, the passage is rightly applied to the bride of Christ, the Church.  Still, it’s a terrific promise to take to heart and I’m thankful for it today.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for his protection and his blessings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 11:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A courtroom scene Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes. In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene. Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation. Their situation is a dire one. Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15626" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15626" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15626" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; LeFleur&#8217;s Bluff State Park, Jackson, MS</figcaption></figure><br />
A courtroom scene<br />
Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes.<br />
In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene.  Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation.  Their situation is a dire one.  Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the consequences of their sin and returned to their homeland, they remain unclean before God.  And that’s what the Accuser comes to declare.  However, there&#8217;s a remedy.  In the vision, the Lord removes the high priest’s uncleanness and outfits him in clean clothes.  Then, the prophet asks that Joshua be given a clean turban as well.  Now, remember that Joshua&#8217;s the high priest.  The clothes he&#8217;s given aren’t just average clothes and the turban isn’t an average turban.  They&#8217;re the robes and turban of the high priest: rich garments reflecting his high position.  That hat, in particular, has meaning.  The turban worn by the high priest has a gold plate on it that’s inscribed with the words “Holiness unto the Lord.”  This is powerful symbolism.  Although the people are redeemed they remain unclean in the sight of the Lord.  Through the mercy and grace of God there’s a remedy.  The Lord purifies their lives and then outfits them in his holiness.  Believers of today can identify with this.  After I put my faith in Jesus as my Savior I come to realize that there remains a basic uncleanness in my heart.  It’s when I throw himself to the mercy of God that he takes action to graciously purify my heart and fill me with his Holy Spirit that I might be holy in his sight.<br />
Take Away: Through the mercy and grace of the Lord there’s a remedy for the stain of sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God powered Zechariah 4: You can’t force these things. They only come about through my Spirit. This statement to governor Zerubbabel is part of one of the most famous portions of Zechariah’s writings. Zerubbabel has already accomplished great things in leading the exiles back to Jerusalem. Now, in response to the urgings of Haggai and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15552" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15552" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15552" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.06.40.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15552" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sumner Lake State Park, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
God powered<br />
Zechariah 4: You can’t force these things.  They only come about through my Spirit.<br />
This statement to governor Zerubbabel is part of one of the most famous portions of Zechariah’s writings.  Zerubbabel has already accomplished great things in leading the exiles back to Jerusalem.  Now, in response to the urgings of Haggai and Zechariah he’s ready to shoulder the task of rebuilding the Temple.  His heart, and the hearts of his people, is in the right place.  God is pleased with them.  The Lord’s words to the good man and his people are wonderfully encouraging: the Temple will be rebuilt not because of some extraordinary human effort, but by the power of God’s Spirit.  This doesn’t mean that the governor and people can sit back and do nothing while a Temple rises from the ashes of destruction, but it does mean that the power for this project is coming from God.  The Lord is with them, not only approving of their actions but empowering them as well.  With that in mind I see here that my efforts to accomplish things in the Name of the Lord aren’t limited by my own initiative, skills, or intelligence.  Every program of the church should be eligible for the label: “God powered.”  If that isn’t an encouraging word I don’t know what is.<br />
Take Away: What we accomplish in the Name of the Lord we accomplish by the power of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 11:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opposition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nothing more needs be said Zechariah 4: So, big mountain, who do you think you are? Zachariah’s well known vision and message continues with a wonderfully encouraging word to governor Zerubbabel. The task before him is a daunting one and there’s real opposition. Zerubbabel is tasked with following in the footsteps of one of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15554" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15554" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15554" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.12.56.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15554" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sumner Lake State Park, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
Nothing more needs be said<br />
Zechariah 4: So, big mountain, who do you think you are?<br />
Zachariah’s well known vision and message continues with a wonderfully encouraging word to governor Zerubbabel.  The task before him is a daunting one and there’s real opposition.  Zerubbabel is tasked with following in the footsteps of one of the most famous kings of Israel, King Solomon, who built the first Temple.  During Solomon’s reign, Israel was a powerful and respected nation.  Now, Zerubbabel leads a relatively small number of returned exiles in a land that has hostile elements.  In the language of this passage he faces a “mountain” of obstacles to his completion of this, the greatest project of his life.  However, even though there’s much to stop him, there is even more to assure his success.  The “even more” is God.  The Lord&#8217;s pleased with his commitment to this task and the Lord’s going to see to it that he succeeds.  My friend, once those words are said there’s nothing more to say and the only thing left to do is to do it.   Through the centuries God’s people have discovered this passage, and many others like it, and have been both challenged and encouraged to do mighty deeds in the name of the Lord.  Not only that, ordinary people like me have applied this “big mountain, who do you think you are?” approach to dealing with the ordinary, everyday circumstances of life.  As Paul writes to the Church at Rome, “What, then, shall we say in response to this? If God is for us, who can be against us?”<br />
Take Away: God’s Spirit, in me, makes the impossible possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 11:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priesthood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prophet, Priest, and King Zechariah 6: Showing that king and priest can coexist in harmony. The prophet has a number of visions, and I&#8217;m not sure even he understands them all. In one vision he sees the high priest, Joshua and is told to fashion a crown for him. Zechariah is also told that Joshua&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15557" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15557" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15557" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-23-10.28.45.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15557" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sumner Lake State Park, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
Prophet, Priest, and King<br />
Zechariah 6: Showing that king and priest can coexist in harmony.<br />
The prophet has a number of visions, and I&#8217;m not sure even he understands them all.  In one vision he sees the high priest, Joshua and is told to fashion a crown for him.  Zechariah is also told that Joshua&#8217;s (which is Hebrew for “Jesus”) name is “Branch” because he will “branch out” and take on the role of royalty, serving as both priest and king.  Now, I&#8217;m pretty lost in the contemporary meaning of this vision.  However, I know that about 500 years from the time these words are written that a man who is Prophet, Priest, and King is going to come to this world.  These offices will be united in him and he&#8217;ll change everything.  I know Zechariah’s words have meaning for the people who have returned from exile and are focused on rebuilding the Temple.  However, I think they&#8217;re also intended to lay a foundation of understanding concerning the coming of the Son of God to this world.  When the writer of Hebrews describes Jesus to us he spends a great deal of time describing his ministry as our Great High Priest.  Then, the Revelator lifts him as King of kings and Lord of lords.<br />
Take Away: In Jesus we have prophet, priest, and King.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 11:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The church calendar of events Zechariah 7: You&#8217;re interested in religion, I&#8217;m interested in you. For seventy years the people of Israel have observed an annual day of mourning in remembrance of the fall of Jerusalem. Now, God&#8217;s promise of restoration has been fulfilled and many have returned to their homeland. A delegation of Jews [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15561" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15561" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15561" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15561" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Petroglyph National Monument &#8211; Albuquerque, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
The church calendar of events<br />
Zechariah 7: You&#8217;re interested in religion, I&#8217;m interested in you.<br />
For seventy years the people of Israel have observed an annual day of mourning in remembrance of the fall of Jerusalem.  Now, God&#8217;s promise of restoration has been fulfilled and many have returned to their homeland.  A delegation of Jews arrives to ask whether or not that day of mourning should be continued.  A committee is formed to make a decision and Zechariah has a word from the Lord for them.  The Almighty says that the annual observance wasn&#8217;t for his sake but for theirs.  If they want to look to the past, they need to look to the unchanging message of God&#8217;s messengers through the years.  When all&#8217;s said and done, the Lord tells them, its people and not God who get all worked up over religious traditions.  His concern is for people and not about annual fasts and feasts.  That, my friends, is a terrific reminder for church folks.  Having annual events isn’t a bad thing but it&#8217;s not the main thing.  God cares about people.  The Lord’s all for it if a yearly homecoming celebration helps us minister to people.  If it&#8217;s an inward-focused, remembering-the-good-old-days event, well, the Lord sees it as a waste of time.  How we go about doing church matters to God, but his concerns are often considerably different than are ours.<br />
Take Away: The Lord cares about people a lot more than he cares about our church calendars.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7800</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s priority list Zechariah 7: The message hasn&#8217;t changed. The question asked concerning the day of fasting in memory of the destruction of Jerusalem opens the way for the Lord to restate what he requires of his people. Through Zechariah the Lord reminds them that his requirements are unchanged. He isn&#8217;t very interested in their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15564" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15564" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" class="size-large wp-image-15564" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2505.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15564" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; In and around Old Town &#8211; Albuquerque, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s priority list<br />
Zechariah 7: The message hasn&#8217;t changed.<br />
The question asked concerning the day of fasting in memory of the destruction of Jerusalem opens the way for the Lord to restate what he requires of his people.  Through Zechariah the Lord reminds them that his requirements are unchanged.  He isn&#8217;t very interested in their traditions but he&#8217;s very interested in how they treat one another.  He&#8217;s always called for them to love their neighbors and be compassionate in their dealings with one another.  Also, the Lord still has a special concern for widows, orphans, outsiders, and the poor.   If these Jews want to please the Lord, they&#8217;ll focus on these things more and on their traditions less.  Zechariah goes on to describe how, when their ancestors ignored these things that the Lord became angry with them and scattered them throughout the world.  Is it possible that we spend too much time worrying about doing church properly and too little time pursuing the things the Lord lists here?  When all is said and done, is the Lord more interested in how capably I can do church than he is in how I treat the poor?  This passage ought to serve as a compass for all who consider themselves to be a people of God.   Here we find a description of how God&#8217;s people ought to live.<br />
Take Away: When all is said and done, the Lord is more interested in how we treat others than in how we do church.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
