<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>needs &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/needs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:27:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>needs &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best laid plans&#8230; Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest. These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples. They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions. The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed. Upon their return, Jesus calls a time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15716" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15716" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15716" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15716" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>The best laid plans&#8230;</p>
<p>Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest.</p>
<p>These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples.  They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions.  The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed.  Upon their return, Jesus calls a time out for a retreat of sorts.  They head for a wilderness spot where he can debrief them and they can be refreshed.  In this case it doesn’t work out.  People find out where they’re going and there’s a big, needy, crowd waiting for them when they arrive.  Jesus’ heart is stirred by their need and he abandons the retreat idea in favor of ministering to these poor, lost sheep.  I know, first hand, of the need to unplug and get away from the day to day responsibilities of life.  In my case, as a pastor, I guess I get just a very small taste of what it is that has zapped the energy of the disciples in this incident.  However, I think the concern is similar for just about everyone who goes out to face the world each day.  There’s a time for unplugging from the stuff of everyday and letting body, soul, and spirit be refreshed.  Still, in light of the entirety of this passage, I’m also reminded that when I love people and have a chance to minister to their need I’m to respond as best I’m able.  In this situation, the opportunity to minister to people trumps the desire of Jesus that the disciples get some rest.  Life is a balancing act.  Here we see Jesus changing his priorities because he’s presented with a great need and opportunity.</p>
<p>Take Away: If we’re to properly represent Jesus in this world we have to remain flexible and responsive to opportunities that come our way.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persistence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-11/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Persisting in prayer Luke 11: Ask and you’ll get; Seek and you’ll find; Knock and the door will open. After teaching the disciples to pray Jesus tells them a story to illustrate how persistence in prayer works. A man goes to his neighbor’s door in the middle of the night asking to borrow some food [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15780" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15780" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15780" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2847.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15780" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Persisting in prayer</p>
<p>Luke 11: Ask and you’ll get; Seek and you’ll find; Knock and the door will open.</p>
<p>After teaching the disciples to pray Jesus tells them a story to illustrate how persistence in prayer works.  A man goes to his neighbor’s door in the middle of the night asking to borrow some food so he can feed an unexpected guest.  However, the neighbor calls out through the closed door that he’s in bed and he doesn’t want to wake up the whole family to answer the request.  The man at the door, though, is persistent and is also somewhat perplexed.   His need is real and his friendship with his neighbor is genuine.  Not only that, but he knows his friend has the resources to meet his need.  Perplexed or not, his faith in the good will and resources of his friend is unshaken.  He doesn’t know why his friend doesn’t respond right off, but he persists, knocking again and again until his neighbor responds.  Now, this story is told by our Lord to teach us to stay with it when we pray.  The minor detail of the reluctant neighbor being in bed, etc. isn’t what this story is about.  Obviously, unanswered prayer isn’t the result of the Lord taking a nap.  The role of the Almighty is not in play here.  This little illustration is about us.  When I have a need, I can go directly to the Lord with that need.  I go in assurance that he welcomes me to do so, and in faith that he has all the resources necessary to meet that need.  With good will and faith I ask.  On those occasions when the answer doesn’t come, Jesus tells me that it’s not against the rules for me to ask again.  After all, like the man in the story, my need is real and I’m certain that my Neighbor can meet that need and that he’s my friend.  I don’t understand why he hasn’t yet responded, but I do understand his good will toward me.  So what do I do?  I ask again: humbly, in faith, and probably with a bit more urgency.  Asking again doesn’t show a lack of faith.  In fact, it’s an affirmation of it.</p>
<p>Take Away: It’s nice when prayers are answered immediately, but when they aren’t it is okay for me to ask again, and again, if necessary.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
