<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ministry &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/ministry/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:41:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>ministry &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-109/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 03:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No guarantee of success Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;. Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness. The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-i_a3YDShAZA/X71OF_Au9hI/AAAAAAABHrc/gzn2cFk2OU8x8X8KgmE4E1tceuPKuEqhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B12-58-18%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
No guarantee of success<br />
Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness.  The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord.  However, the next thing the Lord tells Isaiah must be very difficult to swallow.  In spite of his being a man with &#8220;lips touched with a coal from off the altar&#8221; his ministry won’t bear fruit.  I know it takes commitment to step forward and say &#8220;send me&#8221; but how much more to go on this mission with the promise of failure.  The Lord says that the people Isaiah goes to minister to will not respond.  Why the Lord tells Isaiah this is a mystery to me.  Why not just send him on without telling him of the failure to come?  I have no answer.  However, I do see one important thing here: I belong to the Lord and I have to leave the results of my ministry in his hands.  For Isaiah the important thing is &#8220;going&#8221; &#8212; being faithful.  That’s how it is for all of us who serve him.<br />
Take Away: We’re called to obedient faithfulness.  The results we leave in the hands of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-57/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Giving my best, depending on a dependable God Proverbs 21: Do your best, prepare for the worst &#8212; then trust God to bring victory. At one time Jesus is ministering to thousands of people in a remote place. As the day turns to evening some of the disciples think Jesus ought to dismiss the people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Rz8eXK6EMq8/X4YPSJmFXaI/AAAAAAABG7c/sQwNsKJ_sQENdcp4pZsHlSJYOKtyUCxiQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/2002new_hampshire-05.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2002 &#8211; New Hampshire</figcaption></figure><br />
Giving my best, depending on a dependable God<br />
Proverbs 21: Do your best, prepare for the worst &#8212; then trust God to bring victory.<br />
At one time Jesus is ministering to thousands of people in a remote place.  As the day turns to evening some of the disciples think Jesus ought to dismiss the people so they can go home and get something to eat.  Jesus replies, &#8220;You give them something to eat.&#8221;  How often do I see a need and then go to the Lord with instructions I think he ought to follow to meet that need?  How often does God respond with, &#8220;You do it&#8221;?  My first instinct is to reply, &#8220;Well, Lord, you know this is more than I can do, so it’s up to you.  I&#8217;ll just go find a comfortable spot and watch you in action.&#8221;  That’s never what the Lord wants me to do.  When I see a need, this proverb instructs me to think and plan and make the effort to deal with it.  However, at the same time, I’m to keep my eyes on him.  In the incident from our Lord&#8217;s ministry, it’s actually Jesus who provides the food while the disciples are simply given the responsibility of distributing it.  In light of this proverb, I’m reminded that the Lord expects me to get involved and give my best to the situation.  At the same time though, I’m to remember that if I’m going to make a real difference I need to depend on a dependable God.<br />
Take Away: The Lord expects us to get involved in meeting the needs I see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Joel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-joel-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 19:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Joel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Preaching on current events Joel 1: Have you ever heard of anything like this? There have been a few times when my Sunday sermon was 100% driven by current events. Some were huge, world shaking events like 9/11, hurricane Katrina, and Desert Storm. Others were powerful events on the more local level: the church gym [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-f2r1OrItzWs/YOM13C7TPvI/AAAAAAABKrs/pypmB88UNagGhPul8hO8N1eLbMmjePqXACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-06-13%2B15.19.53.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Covered Bridges in west central Indiana</figcaption></figure><br />
Preaching on current events<br />
Joel 1: Have you ever heard of anything like this?<br />
There have been a few times when my Sunday sermon was 100% driven by current events.  Some were huge, world shaking events like 9/11, hurricane Katrina, and Desert Storm.  Others were powerful events on the more local level: the church gym being destroyed by fire or the death of a beloved member of the church.  There are times when the preacher has to lay aside the sermon schedule and deal with what&#8217;s already on the minds of everyone.  The prophet Joel ministers in such a time.  A horrible plague of locusts has swept through the country devouring everything in its path.  This is a disaster.  Their crops are gone and there&#8217;s nothing to eat or with which to feed their livestock.  Hunger and even starvation is a real danger.  Realizing God has the attention of everyone Joel takes the situation at hand as his text and begins preaching his sermon.  That sermon is the three chapter book of Joel.<br />
Take Away: A sermon schedule can’t be driven by current happenings, but sometimes that’s exactly as it should be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Amos</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-amos-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Amos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amaziah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeroboam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s call Amos 7: I never set up to be a preacher, never had plans to be a preacher. Amos starts out as an unknown, coming out of the fields near a small town to proclaim God’s message. His sermons are rough and tumble, filled with condemnation. They&#8217;re also specific: Amos names names. Now, he’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zGP5tN-z6hs/YPMT6s5yYKI/AAAAAAABKvo/VhLfjJFPADg0wCdEWGxJRKCwcMeFWxarwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/IMG_20130722_152821_487.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Niagara Falls &#8211; Cave of the Winds</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s call<br />
Amos 7: I never set up to be a preacher, never had plans to be a preacher.<br />
Amos starts out as an unknown, coming out of the fields near a small town to proclaim God’s message.  His sermons are rough and tumble, filled with condemnation.  They&#8217;re also specific: Amos names names.  Now, he’s gotten the attention of some people who they don’t like what they’re hearing.  In fact, they see his warning that a pagan army will “make hash of you” to be a threat to national security.  One of the important priests, Amaziah, sends word to king Jeroboam that there’s a traitor in their midst who&#8217;s sowing seeds of fear.  Amaziah then confronts Amos.  He wants this farmer to go back to where he came from and do his preaching in that backwater place.  The context of this confrontation is that Amaziah thinks Amos is just in it for the money and notoriety he’s getting and that he’s come to Bethel with his preaching show for more of the same.  Amos stands up to the powerful priest and declares that he had no desire to preach in the first place.  Unlike Amaziah, Amos has no family tree of ancestors who are clergy.  He’s a mere farmer who&#8217;s heard from God and has been told to proclaim God’s message.  To this day the Lord is still sending people into the ministry.  Some of us heard that call while we were still young children.  Others battled with it as teens, and still others, like Amos, were established in their lives and, in response to the call embarked on a whole new career.  Amos is a poster child for all who are called by God, but he’s especially an example of how God sometimes calls adults who must walk away from one life and obey God in another.<br />
Take Away: To this day the Lord is still sending people into the ministry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 11:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The church calendar of events Zechariah 7: You&#8217;re interested in religion, I&#8217;m interested in you. For seventy years the people of Israel have observed an annual day of mourning in remembrance of the fall of Jerusalem. Now, God&#8217;s promise of restoration has been fulfilled and many have returned to their homeland. A delegation of Jews [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15561" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15561" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15561" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2014-04-25-12.15.25.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15561" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Petroglyph National Monument &#8211; Albuquerque, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
The church calendar of events<br />
Zechariah 7: You&#8217;re interested in religion, I&#8217;m interested in you.<br />
For seventy years the people of Israel have observed an annual day of mourning in remembrance of the fall of Jerusalem.  Now, God&#8217;s promise of restoration has been fulfilled and many have returned to their homeland.  A delegation of Jews arrives to ask whether or not that day of mourning should be continued.  A committee is formed to make a decision and Zechariah has a word from the Lord for them.  The Almighty says that the annual observance wasn&#8217;t for his sake but for theirs.  If they want to look to the past, they need to look to the unchanging message of God&#8217;s messengers through the years.  When all&#8217;s said and done, the Lord tells them, its people and not God who get all worked up over religious traditions.  His concern is for people and not about annual fasts and feasts.  That, my friends, is a terrific reminder for church folks.  Having annual events isn’t a bad thing but it&#8217;s not the main thing.  God cares about people.  The Lord’s all for it if a yearly homecoming celebration helps us minister to people.  If it&#8217;s an inward-focused, remembering-the-good-old-days event, well, the Lord sees it as a waste of time.  How we go about doing church matters to God, but his concerns are often considerably different than are ours.<br />
Take Away: The Lord cares about people a lot more than he cares about our church calendars.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best laid plans&#8230; Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest. These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples. They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions. The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed. Upon their return, Jesus calls a time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15716" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15716" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15716" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15716" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>The best laid plans&#8230;</p>
<p>Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest.</p>
<p>These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples.  They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions.  The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed.  Upon their return, Jesus calls a time out for a retreat of sorts.  They head for a wilderness spot where he can debrief them and they can be refreshed.  In this case it doesn’t work out.  People find out where they’re going and there’s a big, needy, crowd waiting for them when they arrive.  Jesus’ heart is stirred by their need and he abandons the retreat idea in favor of ministering to these poor, lost sheep.  I know, first hand, of the need to unplug and get away from the day to day responsibilities of life.  In my case, as a pastor, I guess I get just a very small taste of what it is that has zapped the energy of the disciples in this incident.  However, I think the concern is similar for just about everyone who goes out to face the world each day.  There’s a time for unplugging from the stuff of everyday and letting body, soul, and spirit be refreshed.  Still, in light of the entirety of this passage, I’m also reminded that when I love people and have a chance to minister to their need I’m to respond as best I’m able.  In this situation, the opportunity to minister to people trumps the desire of Jesus that the disciples get some rest.  Life is a balancing act.  Here we see Jesus changing his priorities because he’s presented with a great need and opportunity.</p>
<p>Take Away: If we’re to properly represent Jesus in this world we have to remain flexible and responsive to opportunities that come our way.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[witnessing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Giving credit where credit is due Acts 3: Faith and nothing but faith put this man healed and whole right before your eyes. Peter and John are on their way to a prayer meeting when they encounter a pitiful lame man at the Temple gate. Peter has no money but he does have faith in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15885" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15885" style="width: 577px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-577x1024.jpg" alt="" width="577" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15885" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-577x1024.jpg 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-169x300.jpg 169w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-768x1364.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-865x1536.jpg 865w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939.jpg 1153w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15885" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Giving credit where credit is due</p>
<p>Acts 3: Faith and nothing but faith put this man healed and whole right before your eyes.</p>
<p>Peter and John are on their way to a prayer meeting when they encounter a pitiful lame man at the Temple gate.  Peter has no money but he does have faith in Jesus’ power to heal.  By that faith the man is wonderfully healed.  This healing causes quite a commotion and a crowd gathers.  It’s now that Peter brings a quick sermon giving Jesus all the glory for the healing and calling on his listeners to put their faith in this Jesus who makes a real difference in people’s lives.  As I watch all this unfold I can’t help but wonder how good a job I do of giving Jesus the credit.  Here’s what I think: Christians do a wonderful job of giving the Lord credit for organized, intentional ministries.  We make sure that people helped through official channels know that we’re ministering to them in Jesus’ name.  On the other hand, I don’t think we do a very good job when we minister in unofficial ways.  I fear that often people just think we’re nice folks because we take it for granted that they know we’re acting as representatives of Jesus.  We need to develop a better strategy along these lines.  I need to come up with a line to say when, for instance, I stop to help my neighbor carry some bit of heavy trash to the curb for pickup.  When he says “thanks” I need to be ready to say something about my being a follower of Jesus and I just try to do stuff I think he’d do.  It may not always be appropriate and it’s probably not a time for me to preach a sermon like Peter does in this passage, but then again, helping carry a worn out clothes dryer to the curb isn’t as big a deal as healing someone like he did.</p>
<p>Take Away: Christians need a strategy for giving Jesus the credit for simple acts of kindness they do it his name.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clergy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pastors and their congregations Acts 6: Choose seven men from among you whom everyone trusts. One of the growth pains of the infant church has to do with the distribution of resources among the church’s own needy. Some women, apparently due to a language barrier, aren’t getting a fair share of the food the church [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15912" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15912" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15912" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15912" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pastors and their congregations</p>
<p>Acts 6: Choose seven men from among you whom everyone trusts.</p>
<p>One of the growth pains of the infant church has to do with the distribution of resources among the church’s own needy.  Some women, apparently due to a language barrier, aren’t getting a fair share of the food the church is providing.  The disciples realize that this is an important concern and willingly share the leadership responsibilities with seven non-apostles.  The result is that the disciples are able to focus on their role in the church while sharing some responsibilities with those who have gifts for that purpose.  The needs of the people are met and the church continues to advance.  As a pastor I’ve read this account again and again trying to understand it in light of the current pastor/congregation scheme that’s generally in place.   I’ve tried to translate it into the 21st century average Protestant church with an average attendance of 70 to 100.  On one hand, I realize that the church of Acts now numbers in the thousands.  Even if the disciples try to handle it all it simply can’t be.  The question that comes to mind is, is that the only reason for the addition of non-clergy leadership?  I think that a lot of church people think so.  In their smaller situations they’re very pastor-centric.  They want the pastor to be the one who visits them when they’re sick and who makes regular nursing home visits.  They expect the pastor to attend every committee meeting and to pray every public prayer.  Then, if the church grows, they’ll take care of things by hiring an assistant pastor.  I can’t help but think this is mistaken because I have the idea that the division of leadership in the Acts church isn’t all about size and work load.  Rather, I believe the leadership and ministry opportunities need to be shared because it’s healthier for the church.  Had the disciples been perfectly capable of caring for the widows while handling the preaching and teaching responsibilities, I still think they would have done, under the Spirit’s leadership, just what they did.  Some church people need to find a place of ministry and plug in, not always looking to the pastor to do it all.  Some pastors need to quit hogging all the ministry opportunities and give others a chance.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord didn’t come to be served, but to serve and we aren’t his followers unless we follow him into lives of service of others.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-20/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking care of God’s people Acts 20: God’s people they are&#8230;God himself thought they were worth dying for. As did Jesus several years earlier, now Paul “sets his face toward Jerusalem” knowing that his arrival there will result in hardship. To speed his journey the Apostle doesn’t go back into Ephesus but, instead, sends word [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15955" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15955" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15955" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15955" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Taking care of God’s people </p>
<p>Acts 20: God’s people they are&#8230;God himself thought they were worth dying for.</p>
<p>As did Jesus several years earlier, now Paul “sets his face toward Jerusalem” knowing that his arrival there will result in hardship.  To speed his journey the Apostle doesn’t go back into Ephesus but, instead, sends word to the church leaders to meet him in Miletus, located about fifty miles south of Ephesus.  Here he has an emotional meeting with his dear friends and co-workers.  He charges them to guard and protect God’s people in Ephesus, reminding them that “God himself thought they were worth dying for.”  Even as this great Apostle is going to go through trials so will this great church.  As I study this passage I can’t help but think of the role of the ministry.  Paul, I see, isn’t worried about the organization and program of the church.  He doesn’t urge the leaders to focus on current worship trends or new technology.  Rather, he reminds them that they’re to guard and protect the “sheep” placed under their watch care.  They’re to value God’s people as God, himself, values them.  Happily, Paul has good news for these leaders of Ephesus and for church leaders across the ages.  He tells them that God “can make you into what he wants you to be and give you everything you could possibly need in this community of holy friends.”  The work of the ministry includes guarding and protecting God’s people from false teaching.  The power for accomplishing that task comes from a gracious God who works in our lives, giving us everything we need to successfully do the work to which we’re called.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord not only calls people to spiritual leadership, he also empowers them for that task.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 12:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-15/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Holy Spirit working through me Romans 15: The wondrously powerful and transformingly present words and deeds of Christ in me. Adventures, Paul’s had some! He’s pioneered the preaching of the Gospel of Jesus Christ throughout the region. He’s been at the forefront of a tidal wave of the work of the Holy Spirit and, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16031" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16031" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16031" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_145450.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16031" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; Dead Man&#8217;s Cove</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Holy Spirit working through me</p>
<p>Romans 15: The wondrously powerful and transformingly present words and deeds of Christ in me.</p>
<p>Adventures, Paul’s had some! He’s pioneered the preaching of the Gospel of Jesus Christ throughout the region. He’s been at the forefront of a tidal wave of the work of the Holy Spirit and, because of that, he’s not only taken plenty of hits, he’s also seen first-hand just what God can do. Paul, though, is quite humble about all that. He doesn’t glorify himself. Rather, he gives glory to the Lord for it all. At times, even though he’s in the middle of it all he’s found himself more bystander than participant as something “wondrously powerful” happens. Paul understands that it isn’t his cleverness or winning personality that’s “triggered a believing response.” The message about Christ is actually delivered by Christ, through Paul. I wish I had a better handle on this. So often I find myself behaving as though it’s all about my performance. I let myself become so focused on how I’m doing that I forget that, actually, I’m not required to do much at all. The Lord wants me to place my full weight of trust on him and allow him to minister through me. My cooperation is required and the Lord will use my personality, education, etc. along the way, but it’s all powered by his Holy Spirit and not by me. There are times when Paul is amazed at the response to his ministry. As I cooperate with the Lord, I, too, will be surprised as lives are touched as the Lord ministers to people through me. Let’s not be guilty of underestimating the ability of the Lord to minister through us.</p>
<p>Take Away: As we cooperate with the Lord he does amazing things through us that surprise us as much as anyone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
