<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>discipleship &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/discipleship/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 15:24:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>discipleship &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipleship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The carried cross Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple. Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel. Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd. On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15789" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15789" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15789" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15789" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Day trip to Vancouver, BC</figcaption></figure>
<p>The carried cross</p>
<p>Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple.</p>
<p>Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel.  Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd.  On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all.  There’s nothing gentle about what he says to them.  If they want to really follow him and not just be tagalongs they have to let go of all else.   Family ties have to be loosed.  Claims to self-sovereignty have to be renounced.  These are hard enough words, but then he adds, “If you won’t shoulder your own cross you can’t be my disciple.”  These Jewish people absolutely hate the cross.  It’s not only the instrument of cruel execution but it’s the symbol of their humiliation under Roman rule.  The cross not only means death for the one who is so unfortunate as to be hung on it, but it’s also the means of grinding to dust the pride of the entire nation.  Those who are following Jesus in hopes of seeing a miracle or at least getting a free meal need to rethink their discipleship.  To this day the decision to follow Jesus should be a thoughtful one.  Long after the memory of seeing a “miracle” fades and the meal has been digested the cross remains.  The occupied cross becomes for Christians the symbol of God’s love for us.  The empty cross becomes the symbol of resurrection and hope.  The carried cross is the mark of our continued sacrifice and commitment to Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: Am I a tagalong or a genuine follower of Jesus?  The answer is found in my willingness or unwillingness to take up the cross.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipleship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-22/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Keeping a safe distance Luke 22: Peter followed, but at a safe distance. It’s the awful night before the crucifixion of Christ. Not long ago Peter and the other disciples promised their loyalty to Jesus. Now, though, he stands before the Chief Priest, alone. The disciples have fled in fear but Luke tells us Peter, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15829" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15829" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="960" class="size-large wp-image-15829" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-150x150.jpg 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-768x768.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2488.jpg 1936w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15829" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Riding the Anacortes Ferry to Friday Harbor, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Keeping a safe distance</p>
<p>Luke 22: Peter followed, but at a safe distance.</p>
<p>It’s the awful night before the crucifixion of Christ.  Not long ago Peter and the other disciples promised their loyalty to Jesus.  Now, though, he stands before the Chief Priest, alone.  The disciples have fled in fear but Luke tells us Peter, under cover of darkness has followed.  He’s close enough to see what’s going on but far enough back as to not be identified as a follower of Jesus.  I fear that this describes many Christians and at certain times, maybe most of us.  We’re following, but not “that” close.  After all, sometimes being a follower of Jesus is just plain unhandy, not to mention possibly dangerous for some.  For instance, someone who doesn’t smell very good needs some personal, up close attention.  If I’m not careful, my revulsion will win out over my discipleship and I won’t even offer a cup of water in Jesus’ Name.  Or, say someone at work isn’t a very nice person.  People tend to give them a wide berth.  Will I get close enough to show them Jesus?  Because of the danger Peter follows, but at a safe distance.  The thing is, before long he isn’t following at all.</p>
<p>Take Away: I want to follow Jesus closely enough that there’s no doubt that I’m with him.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
