<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>baptism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/baptism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:11:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>baptism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Water Baptizer and the Spirit Baptizer Mark 1: His baptism – a holy baptism by the Holy Spirit – will change you from the inside out. Mark’s gospel is a high speed, breath taking race through the life of Jesus. No “Song of Mary” here and no manger scene. In this story Jesus explodes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15696" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15696" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15696" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059352.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15696" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Looking out over Canyonlands NP from Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Water Baptizer and the Spirit Baptizer</p>
<p>Mark 1: His baptism – a holy baptism by the Holy Spirit – will change you from the inside out.</p>
<p>Mark’s gospel is a high speed, breath taking race through the life of Jesus.  No “Song of Mary” here and no manger scene.  In this story Jesus explodes onto the world scene out in the wilderness at one of John the Baptist’s riverside revival meetings.  The “water Baptizer” instantly recognizes Jesus as the Lamb of God, and willingly steps aside for this “Spirit baptizer.”  Jesus changes people, John says, “from the inside out.”  The Gospel writer believes that the promise of real, heart-based change will draw spiritually hungry people like me into his story.  No more playing at religion and hungering for transformation that’s forever beyond my reach.  The one I read about here is the real deal.  Every person who wants something more than what&#8217;s found by following the rules and trying to find God is drawn to the promise of change &#8212; real change &#8212; from the inside out.  This Jesus is worthy of my allegiance.  </p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus is the answer to the great hunger in people’s lives.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-19/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Believers becoming receivers Acts 19: We’ve never heard of that – a Holy Spirit? God within us? They’re a small gathering of believers in the town of Ephesus. They’ve repented of their sins and been baptized with water, believing in the One John the Baptist preached about. When Paul arrives in Ephesus and makes inquiries [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15952" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15952" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15952" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199545.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15952" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Believers becoming receivers </p>
<p>Acts 19: We’ve never heard of that – a Holy Spirit?  God within us?</p>
<p>They’re a small gathering of believers in the town of Ephesus.  They’ve repented of their sins and been baptized with water, believing in the One John the Baptist preached about.  When Paul arrives in Ephesus and makes inquiries as to whether there are any followers of The Way in Ephesus, someone tells him about them.  They welcome him with open arms and soon Paul is updating them on what God&#8217;s doing.  As he brings them up to speed he tells them of the awesome events of the Day of Pentecost.  They’re thrilled at the idea of God’s Holy Spirit living in their lives.  It sounds almost too good to be true.  Soon these believers are receivers.  They’re filled with the Spirit.  Years earlier Jesus so values this infilling that he tells the disciples to remain in Jerusalem until they receive the Holy Spirit.  Now, Paul encounters this group of isolated disciples and almost immediately tells them about the Holy Spirit’s infilling.  This work of God is, apparently, a priority in the Book of Acts and, is, therefore, a priority for all God’s people.  Paul’s focus on the status of their relationship with the Holy Spirit is a good focus for all of God’s people.</p>
<p>Take Away: Have you received the Spirit since you believed?</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Christianity 101 Hebrews 6: The basic foundational truths are in place. There are lots of important things for Christians to know but what are the most important ones? Before moving on to the deeper things of God what are the basics that must be first mastered. Using the lingo of the university, what courses are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16246" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16246" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16246" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16246" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>Christianity 101</p>
<p>Hebrews 6: The basic foundational truths are in place.</p>
<p>There are lots of important things for Christians to know but what are the most important ones? Before moving on to the deeper things of God what are the basics that must be first mastered. Using the lingo of the university, what courses are included in Christianity 101? The writer of Hebrews lists 5 “courses” that must be passed before the believer is ready to deal with more advanced topics. First is trust in God. For me to even be a Christian in the first place I must stop trusting in myself as a source of salvation and start trusting in the Lord. Second is baptism. This entry sacrament is an important part of my becoming a participant in the grace of God and shouldn’t be overlooked. Third is “laying on of hands.” This may be the most challenging of the five, but I think it’s an understanding that God calls people to the ministry and that the church is to recognize that they are called and then to ordain them as set apart for service and leadership by the Lord. Perhaps this needs to be understood early in the Christian life because the Lord often calls people to a life of ministry early on, or even as a part of, their salvation experience. Fourth is “resurrection of the dead.” Believers are, well, believers. We believe Jesus was resurrected from the grave on that first Easter morning. We believe that because of his resurrection all who trust in him share in that same resurrection hope. Fifth is “eternal judgment.” New Christians are to understand that eternity is at stake in their lives and in the lives of all people who will stand before the Lord in final judgment. These five things aren’t all there is to faith. In fact, they aren’t even all there is at the core, but the writer of Hebrews highlights them as a good starting point. Once these things are settled, it’s time to move on. He says, “Let’s get on with it!”</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t want to camp out just inside the gate. At the same time we need to master the basics before we can move on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
