<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>God’s wrath &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gods-wrath/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:20:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>God’s wrath &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s wrath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-15/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s wrath Revelation 15: One of the Four Animals handed the Seven Angels seven gold bowls, brimming with the wrath of God. The revelator hears a song performed by a huge number of overcomers. It’s a song of praise and worship. It’s also a song of fear and judgment. “God is holy,” they proclaim, “all [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16403" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16403" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16403" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259749.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16403" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s wrath</p>
<p>Revelation 15: One of the Four Animals handed the Seven Angels seven gold bowls, brimming with the wrath of God.</p>
<p>The revelator hears a song performed by a huge number of overcomers. It’s a song of praise and worship. It’s also a song of fear and judgment. “God is holy,” they proclaim, “all nations will come and worship you, because they see your judgments are right.” That song ushers in the final set of the Lord’s judgments on the earth. Angels are given the task of delivering those judgments. They&#8217;re given gold bowls, filled to the brim with the wrath of God. Any view of God that ignores his blazing hatred of sin is an incomplete view. He’s merciful and kind and loving and has overflowing grace. He wants nothing more than to save people and his goal is to save every human being. That’s all proven at Calvary. Some though, refuse his offer of salvation, an offer that cost him everything. Now, as time draws to an end we find ourselves face to face with the wrath of God. How dare people spit on his mercy? How dare they treat the crucifixion with distain? Now, in this vision, we’re given a preview of the wrath of God. John sees smoke from God’s glory and power pouring out of the heavenly Temple. It’s a fearful thing to be even this close to the wrath of God.</p>
<p>Take Away: Any view of the Lord that fails to take into account his hatred of sin is an incomplete view.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s wrath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-16/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Muddling my way through, holding fast Revelation 16: Keep watch! I come unannounced, like a thief. You’re blessed if, awake and dressed, you’re ready for me. The seven bowls of God’s wrath bring untold misery to the earth. Some of the miseries remind us of what happened in the limited region of Egypt during the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16406" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16406" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16406" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3341.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16406" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Muddling my way through, holding fast</p>
<p>Revelation 16: Keep watch! I come unannounced, like a thief. You’re blessed if, awake and dressed, you’re ready for me.</p>
<p>The seven bowls of God’s wrath bring untold misery to the earth. Some of the miseries remind us of what happened in the limited region of Egypt during the ten plagues. In this case, though, the suffering is worldwide. When God’s attention specifically turns to the Beast and his unholy trinity they rally the nations of the earth to fight back. Armageddon is at hand. There’s so much here that I don’t understand that I’m ashamed of myself. Here I am in the book called “Revelation” and I’m constantly reminded that I’m missing whatever it is I’m supposed to grasp. Still, once in a while I’m graciously given something to which I can cling. Even if I don’t get it, I’m advised to “Keep watch!” and to be “ready.” Jesus said the same thing during his earthly ministry and now he repeats it. Even as I muddle through these pictures of judgment filled with symbolism that I’m missing more than understanding, I’m encouraged to simply hang in there. I may not understand Armageddon but I understand what it means to stand fast in my relationship with the Lord. Ultimately, it’s that that matters much more than my poor grasp on the precise meaning of passages like this.</p>
<p>Take Away: Even when you don’t understand what’s going on stand fast in the faith. Ultimately, that’s what matters the most anyway.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
