<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>restoration &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/restoration/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 18:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>restoration &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-137/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second coming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking to the distant mountains Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God. An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range. As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QHj_F29QPmk/X-IZXHRO1-I/AAAAAAABH9U/mCJxOwSoeacenLKkqcw9h_OsO6BQgJuRACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281810.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Looking to the distant mountains<br />
Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God.<br />
An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range.  As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but at the greater distance is yet another taller and even more majestic peak.  Coloradoans call the really big ones, &#8220;fourteeners,&#8221; that is, they’re over 14,000 feet in height.  From my vantage point I can’t tell how far it is between the two mountains.  It’s only as I actually travel through the mountains that I realize there’s a deep valley between the first and the second mountain range.  As the prophets are given a vision of God&#8217;s intentions they sometimes see an act of God that’s close at hand and at the same time see a similar but even greater event more distant than they can imagine.  Here in Isaiah 40 the focus of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecies is on comfort and hope.  These words will become a life line for his people in a few years.  All the terrible things he&#8217;s warned them of will come to pass, and in distant lands the next generation will turn to these words to find comfort in their sorrow.  When I read this passage at the level of the &#8220;front range&#8221; I see that God&#8217;s broken people have hope of restoration.  The Lord’s going to return to their lives as a powerful king might return to his kingdom.  Isaiah&#8217;s command to them is to start preparing for this sure event by making a smooth and straight road into their lives.  However, beyond that &#8220;front range&#8221; is a gigantic &#8220;fourteener,&#8221; the coming of the King of Kings to this world.  Hundreds of years later this prophecy will become John the Baptist&#8217;s text and it’ll be fulfilled in a much greater way by King Jesus.  As a Christian I can identify with the dual nature of this passage.  That &#8220;front range&#8221; view is when I receive Jesus as King in my own heart.  The &#8220;fourteener&#8221; view is when Jesus comes to this world the second time as King and Judge of all.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes the words of the prophets of the Lord cause us to look both to the past and to the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-152/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 11:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buried in the deepest sea, yes, that’s good enough for me Isaiah 44: I&#8217;ve wiped the slate of all your wrongdoings. There&#8217;s nothing left of your sins. As I read these words an old Sunday School chorus comes to mind: &#8220;Gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221; As a Sunday School kid to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gJ1uIkMO3fU/X_S2mADvvfI/AAAAAAABII8/5vzhxkRCUP4GF05UrLm1AGC1eEYsmCPaACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9062265.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along the trail to Dream Lake, Rocky Mt Natl Park</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Buried in the deepest sea, yes, that’s good enough for me<br />
Isaiah 44: I&#8217;ve wiped the slate of all your wrongdoings. There&#8217;s nothing left of your sins.<br />
As I read these words an old Sunday School chorus comes to mind: &#8220;Gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221;  As a Sunday School kid to me that was mainly just a catchy tune, although I know that it’s important to &#8220;train up a child in the way he should go&#8230;.&#8221;  The message here is mainly for grownups, especially for those who are troubled by the mess they’ve made of their lives.  They look at their lives and see a disaster that can, in their view, never be cleaned up.  You may have things in your past that are so ugly that you seldom allow yourself to remember them, and when you do, you’re filled with shame.  Or there may be things that everyone knows about: broken promises, failures, and destroyed relationships.  The words of Isaiah are so filled with hope that our hearts cannot hold it all.  The only One who can deal with the mess that is our lives has already acted to do just that.  He cries out, &#8220;Come back to me, come back. I&#8217;ve redeemed you.&#8221;  As I respond to that invitation, the words of the old chorus become mine&#8230;&#8221;gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-160/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prodigal son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The journey home begins with this first step Isaiah 50: It&#8217;s your sins that put you here, your wrongs that got you shipped out. The Lord tells Israel that he didn&#8217;t &#8220;divorce&#8221; them and he didn&#8217;t just kick them out. They’re where they are because of their intentional rejection of him. Even when he reached [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Z2pko0K9iM8/X_9TgRoYKFI/AAAAAAABIMM/36YkCkiiyfEbY3DWz1Ym8NKR1ZIAb7aSQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042172.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The journey home begins with this first step<br />
Isaiah 50: It&#8217;s your sins that put you here, your wrongs that got you shipped out.<br />
The Lord tells Israel that he didn&#8217;t &#8220;divorce&#8221; them and he didn&#8217;t just kick them out.  They’re where they are because of their intentional rejection of him.  Even when he reached out to them, they ignored him.  The disaster didn&#8217;t come because he changed the rules or backed out of his promises to them.  It’s their doing.  Because of that, the road back, as it does for the prodigal son, starts with their coming to their senses and acknowledging their sin.  There&#8217;s hope here, because there is, indeed, a way back; the possibility of restoration even after sin.  It starts with admitting, &#8220;I&#8217;m a sinner.&#8221;  If I think I’ll return to God on my terms I’m only fooling myself.  In this passage the Lord proclaims, &#8220;I’m as powerful as ever.&#8221;  Things don&#8217;t have to stay the same because God has the power to make things right.  It&#8217;s a long road home for these who’ve been exiled to distant lands and that road starts with their repentance.  That&#8217;s true for them, it’s true for the prodigal, and it&#8217;s true for me when my sins have separated me from God.<br />
Take Away: Things don&#8217;t have to stay the same because he Lord has the power to make things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-162/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 13:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two prophecies for the price of one Isaiah 52: He didn&#8217;t even look human. I think this is another of those &#8220;dual prophecies&#8221; in which the prophet speaks of something close at hand, but, maybe without realizing it, speaks words that resonate into the future. On one hand, he’s talking about the restoration of his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-APRjyQ1aiAM/YAJUj_GBhUI/AAAAAAABIM0/ir7n-6fd_4UuAAccd8PFMKZGG7zPAs82QCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042158.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Two prophecies for the price of one<br />
Isaiah 52: He didn&#8217;t even look human.<br />
I think this is another of those &#8220;dual prophecies&#8221; in which the prophet speaks of something close at hand, but, maybe without realizing it, speaks words that resonate into the future.  On one hand, he’s talking about the restoration of his people.  They’re broken, almost to the point of extinction.  If their condition is described as though they are one person, we would say that individual has been beaten to the point that he or she is unrecognizable.  God&#8217;s salvation is coming but at this point things don&#8217;t look very good.  It makes perfect sense to us that the writers of the New Testament are reminded of this passage as they see what happens to Jesus.  The Jews are God&#8217;s people and Jesus is God&#8217;s Man.  Its sin that nearly destroys the Jews and it’s the burden of our sins that takes Jesus to Calvary.  Physically, God’s people are practically destroyed and the same can be said of Jesus.  Yes, it’s easy enough for us to see the connection.   However, we don&#8217;t have to walk away from this passage with a vision of &#8220;a ruined face, disfigured past recognition&#8221; on our minds.  We do need to spend time gazing at that face, absorbing the full impact of what happens at the cross.  Then, we can move on.  Isaiah describes an amazing transformation saying, &#8220;Just watch my servant blossom!” That’s exactly what we see at the garden tomb that first Easter morning. Israel is to be restored by the grace of God. Jesus rises from the grave, victor over sin and death. Praise His Name!<br />
Take Away: The story of salvation doesn’t end at the cross.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-170/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 14:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ll take door number two Isaiah 54: I&#8217;ll see to it that everything works out for the best. The Lord is stepping into their ruined lives and because of that things are going to change for the better. Through him, salvation is coming, restoration is on the way. Their current situation doesn&#8217;t reflect that. If [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ja-ncfl9GPE/YAxQKxJA88I/AAAAAAABIR0/k91-kzDN_d0Ay1aDWc1MZfNwPeMhknNCgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9032108.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along Old Fall River Road &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
I’ll take door number two<br />
Isaiah 54: I&#8217;ll see to it that everything works out for the best.<br />
The Lord is stepping into their ruined lives and because of that things are going to change for the better.  Through him, salvation is coming, restoration is on the way.  Their current situation doesn&#8217;t reflect that.  If their lives were on the stock exchange their value would be plummeting.  However, God has, in his mercy, taken on their case and he’s going to personally see to it that things work out.  I can&#8217;t ask for a finer promise.  I look at the uncertainty of my life and wonder how things will come out.  Not only are there the things I know about, there are likely things headed my way that, if I knew about them I’d be scared to death.  That is, if that’s where I want to focus my attention.  Instead, though, I have the promise of God before me.  I can choose to worry myself to an early grave or I can choose to take God at his word that he&#8217;ll &#8220;see to it that everything works out for the best.&#8221;  As might be heard in the old TV game show, I think I&#8217;ll take door number two.<br />
Take Away: We have the promises of the Lord and it’s there that we take our stand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-177/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hope of restoration Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed. God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it. His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity. This awesome God is a demanding God. He calls me to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 704px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iv0kO_jxD2g/YBWrX4vBb4I/AAAAAAABIX8/BOOAkTIWViItqCIQ8NMxoqCyVIqjKWvzwCPcBGAsYHg/s704/PC253031.JPG" width="704" height="564" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Hope of restoration<br />
Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed.<br />
God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it.  His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity.  This awesome God is a demanding God.  He calls me to live in fellowship with himself and his standard for me is nothing short of holiness.  If I rebel it’s not his purpose that is broken, but me.  However, this God is not untouched by that brokenness.  He not only sits on his throne way up in Heaven, but he also inhabits the world he created.  When my sins have divorced me from the Lord and I begin to realize the awfulness of those sins I find that he&#8217;s been there, reaching out to me all the time.  The same God, this high and towering Being, cares for me even in my ruined state.  He longs to transform my &#8220;spirit-crushed&#8221; life into something wonderful and new.  His language to me is filled with powerful and welcome words: healing, leading, comforting.  As I reach up from the bottom, I realize that God has been there all the time, reaching down from the top.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-184/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 16:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Beulah Land Isaiah 62: You&#8217;ll be called Hephzibah and your land Beulah. The best known song of singer and songwriter Squire Parsons is &#8220;Beulah Land.&#8221; That song is inspired by this passage, in fact those words are found nowhere else in the Bible. Isaiah is describing God&#8217;s love for the people he created, picturing it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XVNT25HpVSU/YB7fE7qhocI/AAAAAAABIaw/MAIdBh1NVts-DlaurAYdSpnXavwsTDqWACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Smoky-mountains-national-park-Elkmont-Campground%2B5-16-2008%2B4-48-12%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Smoky Mountain National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Beulah Land<br />
Isaiah 62: You&#8217;ll be called Hephzibah and your land Beulah.<br />
The best known song of singer and songwriter Squire Parsons is &#8220;Beulah Land.&#8221;  That song is inspired by this passage, in fact those words are found nowhere else in the Bible.  Isaiah is describing God&#8217;s love for the people he created, picturing it as being like the love a groom has for his bride.  Things haven’t gone well for Israel up to this point.  Their sin separated them from God and brought destruction to their land.  As a people they’ve earned the nickname &#8220;Rejected&#8221; and their land can be rightly called &#8220;Ruined.&#8221;  Because of God&#8217;s love and forgiveness everything’s going to change.  The &#8220;Rejected&#8221; people will be restored and the &#8220;Ruined&#8221; land will be brought back under the protection of the Lord.  The new name for God&#8217;s people will be &#8220;Hephzibah&#8221; or &#8220;My Delight&#8221; and the land will be called &#8220;Beulah&#8221; or &#8220;Married&#8221; meaning that the land will reflect its unique connection to the Lord.  Squire Parsons took the idea of a land uniquely the Lord&#8217;s to refer to heaven and his song is that of God&#8217;s people who long to go to that place that’s God&#8217;s very own.<br />
Take Away: The love and forgiveness of the Lord for us changes everything about us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-187/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 16:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise, surprise, surprise! Isaiah 64: Since before time began no one has ever imagined&#8230;a God like you. I know there’s much (and that’s too mild a word) about God that’s beyond my imagination. However, it isn&#8217;t the vastness of God that’s on Isaiah&#8217;s mind here. Isaiah’s talking about what he does know. The Almighty has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DBui6HdajQ/YCMxVSHC0UI/AAAAAAABIek/MOTGQTFsHEA_Aik48iZMy6cq2unecOV8QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5133625.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Blue Ridge Parkway &#8211; Virginia</figcaption></figure><br />
Surprise, surprise, surprise!<br />
Isaiah 64: Since before time began no one has ever imagined&#8230;a God like you.<br />
I know there’s much (and that’s too mild a word) about God that’s beyond my imagination.  However, it isn&#8217;t the vastness of God that’s on Isaiah&#8217;s mind here.  Isaiah’s talking about what he does know.  The Almighty has revealed his intentions concerning his broken people and their enemies.  Isaiah isn&#8217;t saying &#8220;no one knows what God’s going to do.&#8221; Instead, he’s saying &#8220;here&#8217;s what God’s about to do and it’s something no one has ever before imagined.&#8221;  The Lord is about to move in their lives bringing restoration to them.  Everything’s going to change as the Lord works in a never-seen-before way on their behalf.  His plans aren&#8217;t a secret; they’re being announced ahead of time.  This verse reminds me of the passage from the New Testament that’s based on Isaiah&#8217;s words here.  In 1 Corinthians 2:9 Paul says: &#8220;No eye has seen, no ear has heard, no mind has conceived what God has prepared for those who love him.&#8221;  A lot of folks stop right there, thinking Paul’s talking about the future and unknowable plans of God.  However, they need to go right on reading.  Paul continues with: &#8220;but God has revealed it to us by his Spirit.&#8221;  Paul’s saying the very same thing as Isaiah.  No one could ever guess ahead of time how God is going to redeem his people, and now that we know it we stand amazed.  From our point of view, who could ever imagine that a baby born in a barn can save the world?  But God, through his angelic messenger right up front announces that that’s exactly what’s going to happen.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s wonderful plan of salvation is both known by us and amazing to us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-195/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyone a missionary Isaiah 66: I&#8217;ll send them out as missionaries to preach my glory among the nations. The final section of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy has to do with restoration. The Lord’s going to gather his people from the exile and restore them to their beloved homeland. Then, he’ll send them out again. This time, though, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oYQ1sEyYzGs/YC1aJX7UefI/AAAAAAABIoQ/fac9whhIBqUWDZ0lI3VsX6VETFiENFVHwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034519.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Everyone a missionary<br />
Isaiah 66: I&#8217;ll send them out as missionaries to preach my glory among the nations.<br />
The final section of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy has to do with restoration.  The Lord’s going to gather his people from the exile and restore them to their beloved homeland.  Then, he’ll send them out again.  This time, though, it won&#8217;t be as slaves being relocated by a conquering king.  Instead, it’ll be as missionaries spreading throughout the world proclaiming God&#8217;s goodness.  Isaiah pictures them returning with those who’ve responded to the message, presenting these newly found followers of the Lord to the Lord as an offering gladly received by God.  In this I see the heart of God.  His desire is that all his Creation be gathered in love; that we experience unity with one another and with him.  Jesus says the same thing when he talks about us being &#8220;one.&#8221;  As a believer I’m called to participate in that missionary task; to understand the culture of my society and to go out and engage it for the cause of Christ.  The day will come when, as it is in Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy, I’ll stand before God.  I don&#8217;t want to do so empty handed.<br />
Take Away: The Lord uses his people to reach out to all peoples; engaging them, inviting them, and then bringing them to himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-75/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 18:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exhaustion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refreshment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heading for the hills Jeremiah 9: At times I wish I had a&#8230;backwoods cabin. One thing that draws me to Jeremiah is his transparency. He tells us, not only what God’s saying, but also how Jeremiah feels about things. Those feelings range from compassion to anger and from hope to despair. At one point he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QsDJ-xLGCRQ/YD_UB6SXp9I/AAAAAAABI4I/ui8gpsAG6X0ag6KjMmgN1rfYggtK5EriQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-13-2009%2B7-25-17%2BPM.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier National Park, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Heading for the hills<br />
Jeremiah 9: At times I wish I had a&#8230;backwoods cabin.<br />
One thing that draws me to Jeremiah is his transparency.  He tells us, not only what God’s saying, but also how Jeremiah feels about things.  Those feelings range from compassion to anger and from hope to despair.  At one point he says he’s &#8220;heartsick&#8221; over the sins of his people and wonders if there&#8217;s a &#8220;balm in Gilead&#8221; that can be used to heal their brokenness.  He wishes he had the physical ability to weep the rivers of tears because of his sadness over their sin and the coming judgment.  Then, he switches to anger.  They’re worthless people, not worth his effort.  He wishes he could just get away from them and let happen what’s going to happen.  As I say, Jeremiah is a study in transparency and his feelings run the full range of human emotion.  I&#8217;m not wired the same as Jeremiah.  I don&#8217;t dip so low and I don&#8217;t soar as high.  Still, I can identify with him to some extent.  The truth is that, like Jeremiah, I can be filled with loving compassion for someone and be frustrated to death with them at the same time.  His desire to step away from these people for a while and head for the hills isn&#8217;t off the mark at all.  Even the best of people can only carry burdens for so long before a break is needed; a chance to reevaluate and get a fresh grip on things.  That &#8220;backwoods cabin&#8221; experience might actually be the &#8220;balm in Gilead&#8221; that will not only help Jeremiah bring healing to these broken people, but will also bring healing to his spirit as well.<br />
Take Away: We must guard against getting so people-focused that we fail to be God-focused.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
