<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>God&#8217;s sovereignty &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gods-sovereignty/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:45:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>God&#8217;s sovereignty &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 16:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God working in the extreme Daniel 4: The High God rules human kingdoms and puts whomever he wishes in charge. Once Daniel gives the king the meaning of his dream of warning the ball’s in Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s court. He can humbly respond to the Lord&#8217;s overtures to him or not. In the terms of tennis, he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1574px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ETbFn8zNQRI/YL5EUx66HKI/AAAAAAABKZY/hSIWqvuSkiAh3yFMC5jljKAgQs2s7vu0QCPcBGAsYHg/s1575/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B-62.JPG" width="1574" height="1180" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; London &#8211; Windsor Castle</figcaption></figure><br />
God working in the extreme<br />
Daniel 4: The High God rules human kingdoms and puts whomever he wishes in charge.<br />
Once Daniel gives the king the meaning of his dream of warning the ball’s in Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s court.  He can humbly respond to the Lord&#8217;s overtures to him or not.  In the terms of tennis, he &#8220;whiffs it.&#8221;  That is, he totally bungles the opportunity he&#8217;s given.  At the beginning he was ignorant concerning the God Daniel worshiped and could be cut some slack when he didn&#8217;t get it.  Now, he&#8217;s not only seen what this God can do but he&#8217;s also heard from him personally; not once, but twice.  It&#8217;s time for him to respond.  Instead, he chooses to tip his hat to the Lord and then continue as he always has.  As Nebuchadnezzar congratulates himself for all &#8220;he&#8221; has done the Lord moves on his life in one last act of mercy: the Lord grants to him a mental breakdown!  I know it doesn&#8217;t sound much like mercy.  Rather, it seems more like judgment.  However, if dreams and miracles can&#8217;t get this stubborn man’s attention the Lord has only two choices: destroy him or humble him.  It&#8217;s in mercy that the Lord humbles Nebuchadnezzar.  Here’s more evidence that God wants to redeem the lost.  Human wisdom might dictate giving up and moving on to the next candidate.  God says, &#8220;Let&#8217;s give it one more try; this time, maybe some strong medicine will do the trick.&#8221;  I don&#8217;t think God routinely causes mental breakdowns, but I do think he goes to extreme measures in granting mercy to us.  He is, indeed, the God of &#8220;Second Chances.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord goes to extreme measures in granting mercy to us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-41/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 17:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The big picture Daniel 12: It will be a time of trouble, the worst trouble the world has ever seen. Imagine the second part of Daniel as a mural done by a master artist depicting the rise and fall of kingdoms through history. As we examine the mural we see mighty nations rise, then divide, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A43KfvspePk/YMt42BpUMcI/AAAAAAABKgQ/T3peKbySfPYAb9l6gSdY3k9fgPEhulvogCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-29.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; Versailles &#8211; Orangerie</figcaption></figure><br />
The big picture<br />
Daniel 12: It will be a time of trouble, the worst trouble the world has ever seen.<br />
Imagine the second part of Daniel as a mural done by a master artist depicting the rise and fall of kingdoms through history.  As we examine the mural we see mighty nations rise, then divide, and then fall to some new world power.  Some folks have patiently examined Daniel’s “mural,” attaching labels to the various kingdoms he describes.  Those folks might be right and they might be wrong.  Frankly, for me to attempt this is a waste of time.  The least of those who seriously attempt to match nations up with Daniel’s vision is superior to me.  I get lost in it all fairly soon.  I do come away from Daniel’s sweeping picture with certain impressions.  For one thing, I&#8217;m reminded that, even though I firmly believe human beings have free will, there&#8217;s an overarching flow of human history that&#8217;s firmly in the hands of God.  Second, even though it seems some things happen outside of God&#8217;s providence, I’m reminded that the Lord remains Sovereign over all.  Whether or not I think God is orchestrating, down to some detail, the flow of events I need to remember that nothing&#8217;s happening on the world stage that he isn&#8217;t at least allowing to happen.  Finally, I see that there&#8217;s an end to the story.  Things won’t forever continue as they are.  Daniel sums it up with a description of everything coming to a head with &#8220;the worst trouble the world has ever seen.&#8221;  The Lord isn’t a bystander to human history.  He&#8217;s ushering us along to some specific events and, ultimately, to a specific conclusion.  As I watch the world news and see the clashes of world powers, it&#8217;s good to remember that nothing that happens is a surprise to God.  That may not be a very complete view of the nature of prophecy, but it&#8217;s not a bad place to start and, while I may not understand the specifics, I do get the big picture.<br />
Take Away: There&#8217;s an overarching flow of human history that&#8217;s firmly in the hands of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Micah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-micah-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Micah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Open, Under New Management Micah 4: Nations will&#8230;quit learning how to kill one another. Micah’s promise of world peace always sounds good and it’s especially attractive when strife and war are close at hand. Later on, when the Messiah comes his arrival is accompanied with heavenly cheers of “peace on earth.” Every reasonable person is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8Z_x01YOwDI/YQryITcZMFI/AAAAAAABK9g/triV0ze54qYRZEvjqZY3f00iR1dCASXNQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-09-10%2B12.59.27.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Pilot Mountain, North Carolina</figcaption></figure><br />
Open, Under New Management<br />
Micah 4: Nations will&#8230;quit learning how to kill one another.<br />
Micah’s promise of world peace always sounds good and it’s especially attractive when strife and war are close at hand.  Later on, when the Messiah comes his arrival is accompanied with heavenly cheers of “peace on earth.”  Every reasonable person is drawn to the possibility of world peace.  Some have declared the promise of Micah and then of the Gospel writer to be a sham.  And why not: we&#8217;re no closer to world peace than we were when Micah first said these words.  The thing is our world hasn’t cooperated with this promise.  Micah describes this when he says, “Meanwhile, all the other people live however they wish.”  The solution offered in the Bible is a spiritual one.  As people and nations yield to the sovereignty of God, peace reigns.  As people and nations reject God peace becomes more and more distant.   God’s answer is to march onto the world scene and reorder it all.  When that happens we’ll see the equivalent of an “Open, Under New Management” sign placed on the world, and peace will, at least, reign.<br />
Take Away: We can’t expect to receive the promises of the Lord while we, at the same time, refuse to cooperate with him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trusting without understanding Habakkuk 2: Look at that man&#8230;full of himself but soul-empty. The prophet understands that sinful Babylon is God’s chosen instrument for punishing sinful Judah. As bad as Judah is, Habakkuk is having a hard time understanding how God could ever use such an evil nation as his tool against the Children of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15484" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15484" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15484" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15484" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Trusting without understanding<br />
Habakkuk 2: Look at that man&#8230;full of himself but soul-empty.<br />
The prophet understands that sinful Babylon is God’s chosen instrument for punishing sinful Judah.  As bad as Judah is, Habakkuk is having a hard time understanding how God could ever use such an evil nation as his tool against the Children of Abraham.  Habakkuk reverently takes his concern to God and now God answers.  A part of that answer is contained in chapter two of this brief book of the Bible.  The Lord tells Habakkuk he&#8217;s well aware of the sin of Babylon.  Although the language used suggests that the remarks are about only the King of Babylon, the context tells us that it&#8217;s the nation as a whole that&#8217;s being described.  The Lord wants Habakkuk to know that he hasn’t underestimated the sin of Babylon and he isn’t about to overlook it.  Babylon’s self-indulgent pride, its injustice, and its immorality will be dealt with.  Just because God intends to use this nation for his own purpose doesn’t mean that he&#8217;s going to overlook its sin.  The Lord remains sovereign and, in the end, he always has the last word.  This godless empire is, indeed, a tool in the hands of the Almighty.  At some point it may seem that Babylon is getting the benefit of this arraignment, but the real result will only be seen when the final chapter is written.  Today, I’m reminded that all of Creation is in God’s hands.  Anytime he wants, he can use whoever he wants for his purposes.  The Lord doesn’t need for me to explain his actions or to make apologies for them.  He does, however, insist that I trust him even when I don’t understand him.<br />
Take Away: I’m not required to understand the Lord but I am called to trust him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been included Romans 9: They were so absorbed in their “God projects” that they didn’t notice God right in front of them. Big issues are in play here. Paul says that while the descendants of Abraham are the people with the promise of God that promise remains under God’s control. Even among Abraham’s descendants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16017" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16017" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16017" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16017" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Long Beach, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; on the beach a short walk from the campground</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’ve been included</p>
<p>Romans 9: They were so absorbed in their “God projects” that they didn’t notice God right in front of them.</p>
<p>Big issues are in play here. Paul says that while the descendants of Abraham are the people with the promise of God that promise remains under God’s control. Even among Abraham’s descendants some are excluded and have no part in the promise. For instance, twin brothers (Jacob and Esau), before they’re ever born are treated differently from one another by God. One will be part of what God is doing in the world and the other won’t. Some Israelites have the idea that salvation is uniquely theirs because of their lineage. Paul says that’s not how it is. The only real decision maker here is God, so when some of Abraham’s descendants have tried to take the ball and run with it, making salvation their personal property, they’ve run head first into the Almighty who reminds them that this is his doing and not theirs. Israel doesn’t own salvation – God does. This is Good News for those of us who would otherwise be considered outsiders and ineligible for this wonderful plan of salvation.</p>
<p>Take Away: There’s a wideness in God’s mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 21:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Does not work well with others.” Exodus 7: Pharaoh is not going to listen to you For a true blue “free-willer” like me, Pharaoh’s role in the Exodus is somewhat troubling. Before Moses and Aaron ever meet with him the Lord promises that he’s going to be stubborn. The reason for that stubbornness is because [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-y9sa1M8dNLM/XPnVTcaX34I/AAAAAAAA8BQ/AO4VjEjkvGwONI4ubw1EedfEWlunkZY3wCKgBGAs/s1600/100_2551.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mesa Verde National Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
“Does not work well with others.”<br />
Exodus 7: Pharaoh is not going to listen to you<br />
For a true blue “free-willer” like me, Pharaoh’s role in the Exodus is somewhat troubling.  Before Moses and Aaron ever meet with him the Lord promises that he’s going to be stubborn.  The reason for that stubbornness is because the Lord’s going to make him that way.   That’s not how I see God at work in this world.  Instead, I see him supplying sufficient grace to people to respond to his call in their lives if they will.  In the story of the Exodus it appears that God not only sees Pharaoh’s stubbornness but actually stiffens it even more to create conditions for a spectacular deliverance.  So what’s going on here?  On the other side of this “free will” coin is “sovereignty.”  God is God and he holds absolute authority over all Creation.  The reason we have free will is that the Sovereign has granted it.  If I abuse the freedom I&#8217;ve been granted I&#8217;ll answer to him.  In Pharaoh’s case, I don’t think the Lord looked into the future and saw Pharaoh remain resolutely stubborn, but I do think the Lord saw his hard heart and, in his sovereignty declared, “So it shall be.”  The Lord takes what Pharaoh does in his free will and hard wires it.  From that point on he has no other choice.  Pharaoh could have been an example of God’s grace.  Instead, he becomes an instrument for God’s glory.<br />
Take Away: It’s a dangerous thing to challenge the sovereignty of God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plagues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stubbornness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The stubbornness of Pharaoh Exodus 9: But for one reason only I’ve kept you on your feet&#8230; Things continue to go downhill for mighty Egypt. Dead animals and a plague of miserable boils have struck the land. As Goliath will stager before falling many years in the future, Egypt is near the end. All the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9bcbOOBJsdE/XPrRFh9g6jI/AAAAAAAA8Bs/aURQptozP7IGTrFQB_eesAg7CDRXGQrqgCKgBGAs/s1600/100_2648.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
The stubbornness of Pharaoh<br />
Exodus 9: But for one reason only I’ve kept you on your feet&#8230;<br />
Things continue to go downhill for mighty Egypt.  Dead animals and a plague of miserable boils have struck the land.  As Goliath will stager before falling many years in the future, Egypt is near the end.  All the wealth and power Joseph brought to Egypt is draining away.  One has to believe that the people of Egypt and even the advisors of the king are practically begging him to end this by surrendering to the demand from God that the people of Israel be set free.  As Moses promises yet another massive display of God’s power, he explains the absurd stubbornness of Pharaoh.  This is God’s doing.  Pharaoh hasn’t given in because he can’t give in.   After centuries of seeming silence God is making himself known once again.  When he’s finished with Pharaoh the whole world will know about the God of the Israelites.  On one hand I squirm a bit in my spirit as I see Pharaoh stripped of his free will, suffering the consequences of his earlier stubbornness.  On the other hand, though, I’m reminded that it’s the Almighty who’s doing it.  Who has a right to question what the Creator of all things does?  Pharaoh’s life is going to bring glory to God, not only throughout the world of his day, but throughout history as well.  As I read about the plagues I’m reminded that every life will, sooner or later, bring glory to God.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately, God is sovereign and ultimately, every life will yield to that truth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Numbers</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-numbers-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What God intended in the first place Numbers 23: How can I curse whom God has not cursed? Balaam is hired by Balak, king of Moab, to curse the Israelites. After the talking donkey incident, Balaam has had a change of heart. After all, part of that unusual event is that he saw the angel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-jQTychKG7UI/XVHzpbYAfII/AAAAAAAA-YM/5UgcMGz0Gx4Be07tFoRjZVbl_2rAjvFOQCKgBGAs/s1600/P6199557.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 – Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
What God intended in the first place<br />
Numbers 23: How can I curse whom God has not cursed?<br />
Balaam is hired by Balak, king of Moab, to curse the Israelites.  After the talking donkey incident, Balaam has had a change of heart.  After all, part of that unusual event is that he saw the angel of the Lord with sword in hand blocking his way.  Now as he arrives, Balak urges him to go ahead and curse the Israelites.  Balaam agrees to do his thing, but warns Balak that he can only say what the Lord allows him to say.  He enters into his “prophetic trance” and the words that come out of his mouth are a disappointment to Balak.  Right off it’s plain that the pitiful prophet, who’s toying with stuff he would be better off leaving alone, isn’t going to do a very good job of cursing God’s people.  Instead, Balaam hears himself blessing them.  This whole blessing and cursing stuff is off the mark anyway.  God’s people don’t believe in spells and magic.  Rather, we believe in God.  In this case the Lord used Balaam’s hocus pocus for his own purposes, but remember this: God already intends to bless Israel.  That’s what he’s been saying all along.  Even if Balak’s plan had worked and Balaam managed to state a mysterious, mystic curse on Israel it would have just been a lot of hot air.  Beyond that, Balaam’s blessing doesn’t actually mean anything either.  God didn’t hear this silly prophet state a blessing and think he had to obey.  The Lord continued to do what he intended to do all along.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is sovereign and all the hocus pocus in the world isn’t going to force him to do anything.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-43/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 05:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hide and seek 1 Samuel 23: Saul was on one side of the mountain, David and his men on the other. Saul and David are playing a deadly game of hide and seek. In spite of David&#8217;s continuing to be a defender of Israel Saul has made him public enemy number one. David&#8217;s band is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sWimaPtEvXU/XfVbqy2G29I/AAAAAAABDB4/3icPhZQC7mQ2xpvtFLlBWbjeQKDTPKAYgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4468.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Along Lake Michigan at Manistique, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Hide and seek<br />
1 Samuel 23: Saul was on one side of the mountain, David and his men on the other.<br />
Saul and David are playing a deadly game of hide and seek. In spite of David&#8217;s continuing to be a defender of Israel Saul has made him public enemy number one. David&#8217;s band is growing, now numbering over 600, but Saul&#8217;s army vastly outnumbers them. Beyond that, David doesn&#8217;t want to fight Saul or any of his countrymen. The nation of Israel is divided. Some are loyal to Saul and others to David. In fact, one group, the Ziphites, betrays David to Saul. They report David&#8217;s whereabouts to Saul and help set up an ambush. It’s nearly successful. At one point Saul almost has David and his men cornered. If not for word of an attack from a real enemy that forces Saul&#8217;s attention elsewhere, David&#8217;s story would end right here. Because of this, this area is called “Narrow Escape.&#8221; So, was the attack by the Philistines at such a critical moment just good fortune for David? I think not. God&#8217;s fingerprints are all over this. Still, it’s interesting that God used the enemies of Israel, the heathens of the land, to deliver David. The lesson for me is that this is a reminder that God is truly sovereign. Even when godless people act in ways intended to destroy, God can give a gentle push in some particular direction and use their sinful act to accomplish good rather than evil. Even when it seems evil has won the day, God is still God, and he’s working in surprising ways in and through it all.<br />
Take Away: When all is said and done it’s the Lord who has said the last word.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-48/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finding God in unexpected places 1 Samuel 28: There&#8217;s a witch at Endor. Life is terribly dark for Saul. Years ago when he failed God at Gilgal Samuel told him that God was finished with him. However for decades it has looked as though Saul can handle things on his own. He builds a strong [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QinyXvfq48M/XfvZXdLv6cI/AAAAAAABDDQ/dEBrpf3pWvct4i2C6LFVl1mjsmzo21PogCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8119845.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore &#8211; Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Finding God in unexpected places<br />
1 Samuel 28: There&#8217;s a witch at Endor.<br />
Life is terribly dark for Saul. Years ago when he failed God at Gilgal Samuel told him that God was finished with him. However for decades it has looked as though Saul can handle things on his own. He builds a strong army and successfully leads the people of Israel. However, through those years things are always going downhill for Saul. As we near the end of his story, he’s a fear-filled, pitiful man. Thus we come to this strange incident at Endor. Saul&#8217;s afraid of his enemies and with good reason. His past successes against the Philistines are forgotten as a coalition of forces is massing for the biggest battle yet. Saul&#8217;s only connection with God has been through Samuel, but now Samuel is dead. Prayer is an unknown thing for Saul, but in fear, he prays. There’s no answer. Then, with the same denial of God&#8217;s authority that was evident many years earlier when he decided to offer his own sacrifices rather than wait for Samuel at Gilgal, he again takes matters into his own hands. If God won&#8217;t answer, he’ll turn to witchcraft for answers. He knows God strictly forbids this, in fact, as king he’s enforced the abolition of witchcraft in Israel. Now, he goes looking for someone who can contact the dead for him, specifically Samuel. I know some view this as confirmation that witchcraft, mediums, séances, and the like can be genuine. However, I’m not ready to go there based on this passage. The &#8220;witch at Endor&#8221; is probably an old faker who’s told fortunes for years. Now, when she starts her act and Samuel appears she’s more surprised than anyone else: &#8220;When the woman saw Samuel, she cried out&#8230;.&#8221; In other words, she dropped out of her mystic trance when something actually happened. My take on this is that Saul&#8217;s trying to bypass God by moving as far from God&#8217;s &#8220;territory&#8221; as possible. However, he runs headlong into God even there. Here’s the spiritual fact of life: even when a person tries to move out of the light of God into areas where no one is to go they find that God is God even there. This passage is a confirmation of His absolute sovereignty.<br />
Take Away: There’s no way to bypass the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
