<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Samson &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/samson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 22:46:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Samson &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A good story Judges 13: The angel of God appeared to her.&#8212; The set up for the story of Samson begins with the visitation of an angel. Manoah’s wife (unnamed in the Bible) is minding her own business when the angel appears to inform her that she’s going to have a baby boy. The child [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NAdZZgnvP-I/Xa9eA4pUByI/AAAAAAABCK8/OZQysLqyrdw00wzu-_y4636r-0fgmjSOQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3349.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>A good story<br />
Judges 13: The angel of God appeared to her.&#8212;<br />
The set up for the story of Samson begins with the visitation of an angel. Manoah’s wife (unnamed in the Bible) is minding her own business when the angel appears to inform her that she’s going to have a baby boy. The child is to be raised under a strict code including his partaking of no fruit of the vine or ever having his hair cut. While the Nazirite vow was introduced in Numbers 6 this is the first time we hear of anyone actually under that vow and his case is (obviously) extraordinary. Not only does his being under the Nazirite vow set up the unique “haircut” feature of the story of Samson there’s also the fact that in Samson’s case being a Nazirite is not so much a vow as it is a lifetime assignment. His faithfulness to this vow is such a big deal that the angel has arrived early to stop his mother from drinking or doing anything that would constitute a breaking of the vow while Samson is still in his mother’s womb! When Manoah asks the angel his name he’s told that it’s a name beyond his vocabulary and comprehension. Then, as a burnt offering is made, the angel suddenly blends into the flames and ascends heavenward. It’s all very impressive and fun to read and think about. In fact, that’s all I’m doing with this passage because I don’t have a compelling devotional point to make. Sometimes a good story is just a good story!</p>
<p>Take Away: Most of God’s people just live their lives without visions or miracles. When those things happen, though, we have a story worth repeating.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 22:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strength]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Bible’s strong man Judges 14: A young lion came at him, roaring. The Spirit of God came on him powerfully and he ripped it open barehanded. Samson is the &#8220;strong man&#8221; of the Bible. When artists depict him, they always draw him as a muscle man. Frankly, I doubt it. Remember that his enemies [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-K9TzMQiV9Js/XbDYAj_5TaI/AAAAAAABCLg/x2ddzAElFCINEyIk8NZAuqBC_LhE3aSQACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3355.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Bible’s strong man<br />
Judges 14: A young lion came at him, roaring. The Spirit of God came on him powerfully and he ripped it open barehanded.<br />
Samson is the &#8220;strong man&#8221; of the Bible. When artists depict him, they always draw him as a muscle man. Frankly, I doubt it. Remember that his enemies try to discover the secret of his strength. If he’s built like a super hero they wouldn&#8217;t do that. I think he’s of average build and that the only physical characteristic that makes him stand out in a crowd is hair; hair, and lots of it: long, flowing hair on his head and on his face. This guy has never had a razor used on him. His nickname could be &#8220;Harry!&#8221; The key to his strength is tied into his faithfulness to God. And, in his case, the symbol of that faithfulness is uncut hair. Really, I don&#8217;t even see evidence that Samson is always strong. It’s when the &#8220;Spirit of God comes on him&#8221; that he’s strong. The rest of the time, he’s just an ordinary, hairy guy. Thinking devotionally here, I’m reminded that it’s when the Spirit of God moves in my life that I move into the realm of extraordinary possibilities. I may not be “more powerful than a locomotive” but, when the Spirit of God is directing and empowering, I can do whatever it is the Lord wants me to do.<br />
Take Away: The Lord gives us whatever capability he needs for us to have to accomplish his purposes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[selfishness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not exactly the Sermon on the Mount Judges 15: I swear I’ll get even with you. Samson decides to marry a Philistine. Along the way he gets mad and kills thirty men for their clothing to use in paying a lost bet. He gets married, but when he’s absent for a while, her father gives [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-I9JRpDgqdX8/XbJmIQaUoII/AAAAAAABCMc/qv0XvZEHmnE5GFzhDIzT_daUV8AKHXoXwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259759.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Not exactly the Sermon on the Mount<br />
Judges 15: I swear I’ll get even with you.<br />
Samson decides to marry a Philistine. Along the way he gets mad and kills thirty men for their clothing to use in paying a lost bet. He gets married, but when he’s absent for a while, her father gives his bride to the fellow who was best man at the wedding. Once again, Samson gets mad and burns their fields. The Philistines retaliate by killing his bride and her father. True to form, Samson swears to get even. Isn’t this a pleasant story (not!)? Interestingly enough, we’re told at the beginning of this story that “God was behind this.” What’s going on here? How can God be involved in feuds and retaliation and the like? I think I know the answer. Samson is one of the most selfish and self-absorbed people in the Bible. Apparently, his parents are so impressed that the birth of their son was announced by an angel and since he came with special “handling instructions” they have never said “no” to him in his life. The Lord knows that Samson will never consider taking on the Philistines for the good of his people. All he’s interested in is Samson. Therefore, there has to be something in this for Samson and a great motivator in his life is revenge. It’s strange, I know, but it seems God accomplishes his purposes by manipulating Samson into doing what the Lord wants him to do in the first place. Had Samson been a man with some moral integrity the account of his life would be quite different. Still, the Almighty has his way with Samson even though the byword of his life is “revenge.”<br />
Take Away: Better to cooperate with the Lord in doing what he wants done, but, ultimately, God’s purposes will be accomplished either way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 22:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hair today, gone tomorrow Judges 16: Delilah said to Samson, &#8220;Tell me, dear, the secret of your great strength.&#8221; Samson is a one-man army. Other Israelite liberators inspire people to follow them and rally armies to action. Samson does it all by himself. It’s just Samson and God. Well, really it’s just God. Samson&#8217;s unshaved [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Fl2xm8kWswA/XbNG135yVMI/AAAAAAABCM8/efeQWKcAWFYy7tnfyazMyxf1GDv-x4nIwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259765.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Hair today, gone tomorrow<br />
Judges 16: Delilah said to Samson, &#8220;Tell me, dear, the secret of your great strength.&#8221;<br />
Samson is a one-man army. Other Israelite liberators inspire people to follow them and rally armies to action. Samson does it all by himself. It’s just Samson and God. Well, really it’s just God. Samson&#8217;s unshaved head is the symbol of his connection to God and cutting his hair will break that relationship. Subtract God from his life and Samson is a zero. When Samson stupidly tells Delilah his story he breaks that relationship with God. Soon, the wheels come off and all is lost. I’m tempted to say, &#8220;Without his hair Samson’s just an ordinary man.&#8221; Actually, though, it’s, &#8220;Without his God, Samson’s just an ordinary man.&#8221; Subtract the unique features of this story and we’re left with the truth Jesus stated in John 15:5: “apart from me you can do nothing.”<br />
Take Away: Every good thing I accomplish is because of the Lord’s presence in my life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 22:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The God of Second Chances Judges 16: But his hair, though cut off, began to grow again. Samson, lacking both self-control and common sense, has ruined everything. His undisciplined behavior with women and specifically his inability recognize Delilah for the traitor she is has cost him everything. His pride, strength, freedom, and eyesight are gone. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4ClHD9KO4lI/XbT1vIuSl9I/AAAAAAABCSs/Q5T9lhCdZ68V0q9MS3xSweoUHci0CO-kACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259766.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The God of Second Chances<br />
Judges 16: But his hair, though cut off, began to grow again.<br />
Samson, lacking both self-control and common sense, has ruined everything. His undisciplined behavior with women and specifically his inability recognize Delilah for the traitor she is has cost him everything. His pride, strength, freedom, and eyesight are gone. The phrase &#8220;his hair began to grow again&#8221; is powerfully symbolic of what’s happening in Samson&#8217;s heart. As he does the work of an animal, grinding out grain, somehow, through his darkness, he begins to see God. However, a word of clarification is needed here. This isn&#8217;t a Samson story; rather, it’s a God story. We aren&#8217;t to focus on Samson&#8217;s strength or his stupidity, but on the marvelous grace of God. Samson had been raised up to be a deliverer of his people and even in his miserable state the Lord&#8217;s still willing to work in his life to that end. &#8220;His hair began to grow again&#8221; is a hopeful word in a terrible situation. This is a picture of our God of Second Chances at work. Samson&#8217;s end is not the conclusion to the glorious story as it could have been. In the exercise of his free will Samson sabotages his own life. However, even when everything&#8217;s messed up we find God at work salvaging even this destroyed life. That&#8217;s the kind of God I serve.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances, full of grace and mercy, offering us undeserved restoration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
