<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>followers &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/followers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>followers &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Follow the leader Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following. There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers. The Bible has several stories of leadership. Moses led for 40 years. David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GKWZD23715U/X3iy3gUoO3I/AAAAAAABGzw/7uTOofCwLGcYE-Eo4mTLHOuMCXf6CN9CACPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Follow the leader<br />
Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.<br />
There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers.  The Bible has several stories of leadership.  Moses led for 40 years.  David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as well.  His son Solomon led to prosperity.  Here are three things that come to mind when I read about these leaders.  First, each of these men is not only a leader, but is also a follower who accepts the authority of the Lord and spends time with him getting his marching orders.  Second, these men know how to share leadership and to train leaders.  They don&#8217;t try to do everything themselves and surround themselves with capable people to help carry the leadership load.  Third, they lead people to meaningful goals.  These men have God given visions that gives their leadership real purpose.  People believe in them and they believe the goal set out for them is worth their sacrifice.  Leaders such as these have no problem attracting followers.<br />
Take Away: God-called leaders lead with purpose in a God-chosen direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-41/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 04:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My kind of people 1 Samuel 22: All who were down on their luck came around &#8211; losers and vagrants and misfits&#8230;David became their leader. As David hides out at the Cave of Adullam people begin coming to him. These aren&#8217;t influential, comfortable people. Rather, these are those who have nothing left to lose. Seeing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-W8mpTlNYfcI/XfLQWDdlDvI/AAAAAAABDAw/RjhHCZW_hkMOlxgeJC2IhpDGAznnkgS3gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8119835.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Munising Falls, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
My kind of people<br />
1 Samuel 22: All who were down on their luck came around &#8211; losers and vagrants and misfits&#8230;David became their leader.<br />
As David hides out at the Cave of Adullam people begin coming to him. These aren&#8217;t influential, comfortable people. Rather, these are those who have nothing left to lose. Seeing that David has been kicked out they identify with him and become his followers. Hundreds of years later another man will be unfairly mistreated and abused. He’ll be kicked out by the respectable people who are in power. He too will draw &#8220;losers and vagrants and misfits&#8221; to himself. In him they’ll find acceptance, transformation, and purpose. And, thousands of years later I can report to you that I am one of those &#8220;losers&#8221; who has come to Jesus. Those who come to David, the original four hundred, become so devoted to him that they will follow him anywhere. That&#8217;s how I feel about my Lord too.<br />
Take Away: Jesus invites all those who are weary and burdened to come to him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
