<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Jeremiah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-jeremiah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 18:17:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Jeremiah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-62/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking too much for granted Jeremiah 1: The Message of Jeremiah son of Hilkiah&#8230;this is what the Lord said. Jeremiah lives in a time of international upheaval that rivals anything we see in history. His nation is caught in the middle of it all. They’re small players caught between giants and have only one hope [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ciZYQ8SRPq4/YC6pOIwfJpI/AAAAAAABIps/dj8-z7t8i10U9xQZLflaVfqL1njPvyZ4gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034510.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Taking too much for granted<br />
Jeremiah 1: The Message of Jeremiah son of Hilkiah&#8230;this is what the Lord said.<br />
Jeremiah lives in a time of international upheaval that rivals anything we see in history.  His nation is caught in the middle of it all.  They’re small players caught between giants and have only one hope of survival: the supernatural.  Only God can save them from the disaster that’s marching relentlessly through history toward them.  The problem is that his people take God for granted.  After all, God gave their forefathers that land saying it was theirs forever.  They’ve concluded that they don&#8217;t have to do anything to remain under the protection of God.  In fact, they don’t even have to live God&#8217;s way.  Jeremiah is given the task of telling them that they have it all wrong and that God can never be taken for granted.  This message isn&#8217;t preached just once, but repeatedly and in various forms.  Sadly, we know that his message is rejected and Jerusalem falls in 587 B.C.  Since I live in days of unrest and amazing change, and since my nation seems to take a lot for granted, I&#8217;m going to read Jeremiah as not only a historical figure, but as a man who just might have something to say to my society too.<br />
Take Away: The Lord must never be taken for granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 17:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s call Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you. It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage. In fact, I am tempted to do just that. However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives. How does God pick people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ABjXB2vdN0Y/YC_5yGxgLtI/AAAAAAABIqA/6PLptGZ2EWMqzPnBdjXSL2c0i_YdS5SCACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034509.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s call<br />
Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you.<br />
It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage.  In fact, I am tempted to do just that.  However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives.  How does God pick people to speak on his behalf?  What criteria does he use?  Apparently, at least sometimes, he picks people to represent him who have no credentials at all!   In this case Jeremiah looks back on his call to be a prophet and remembers that it was God who picked him, not he who picked God.  Before he had any &#8220;credentials,&#8221; in fact, before he could make any decisions at all, God laid his hand on him, calling him to be his servant.  Clearly, the Almighty has his own agenda and makes decisions based on things totally beyond us.  Now, I have to add that that doesn&#8217;t mean that Jeremiah had no say in the matter.  God&#8217;s call came: that was God&#8217;s role alone.  Jeremiah had to cooperate: that was his role.  In theory at least, Jeremiah could have refused God and walked away and another person&#8217;s ministry would appear in place of this book of the Bible.  Since God called and Jeremiah (howbeit reluctantly) said &#8220;yes&#8221; we have his story here.  I&#8217;m reminded today that when God calls we can&#8217;t always understand why.  We just have to &#8220;trust and obey.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord doesn’t call us to understand everything but he does call us to obey all we understand him to call us to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-64/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testimony]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking God’s Word Jeremiah 1: I&#8217;ve just put my words in your mouth. Jeremiah isn&#8217;t being falsely humble when he hesitates to accept the role of prophet. Frankly, he doesn&#8217;t think he’s up to it. After all, what will he say? He feels inadequate for the task. The Lord understands. In fact, the Lord probably [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cFBdp4KcpS0/YDFTHLGIPyI/AAAAAAABIsE/hDyCfT_shhQw0A5aaXRxy8cVYM7eYZFSwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC024497.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Pedernales Falls State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Speaking God’s Word<br />
Jeremiah 1: I&#8217;ve just put my words in your mouth.<br />
Jeremiah isn&#8217;t being falsely humble when he hesitates to accept the role of prophet.  Frankly, he doesn&#8217;t think he’s up to it.  After all, what will he say?  He feels inadequate for the task.  The Lord understands.  In fact, the Lord probably agrees that Jeremiah’s an unlikely prophet.  However, the Lord isn&#8217;t necessarily looking for the most capable person anyway.  For reasons known only to him, the Lord chose an unlikely person for a very important job.  To encourage Jeremiah, the Lord puts words in his mouth, a demonstration of how it will work.  Today, I very much identify with Jeremiah.  As a young person I felt God&#8217;s call on my life.  Growing up in a small, wonderfully supportive church I marched forward with the confidence of youth.  It was during my first year in college that I realized I&#8217;m, at best, a very average person.  One day, as I faced my inadequacies the Lord took mercy on me as he did for Jeremiah in this passage.  As I read Matthew 10 these words became a personal promise to me: &#8220;Do not worry about what to say or how to say it. At that time you will be given what to say, for it will not be you speaking, but the Spirit of your Father speaking through you.&#8221;  It seemed to me that the Lord said to me, &#8220;If I could give words to the disciples even when they were being abused, I can help you as a preacher to say things I want you to say.&#8221;  That day was a &#8220;Jeremiah 1&#8221; day for me.  It wasn&#8217;t that I now understood all there was to know, but I grasped this promise of God to me.  If he called me to the ministry, he would help me do ministry.  Over 40 years later, I can report that the Lord has been faithful to keep that promise.<br />
Take Away: If the Lord calls you to it he will help you do it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-65/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 17:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confrontation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Walking with God against the flow Jeremiah 1: You&#8217;re a one-man defense system against this culture. Several times in my journeys I’ve had the misfortune of driving along the highway, minding my own business, and coming up on fresh skunk road kill. The stench lingers in the car even after the site of the demise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-32ZhhtJ1LZg/YDLFAZKuZpI/AAAAAAABIsY/f9FCjPFMXpcgKZxhKatY8G050ZFPXt_RACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PB284408.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Campfire</figcaption></figure><br />
Walking with God against the flow<br />
Jeremiah 1: You&#8217;re a one-man defense system against this culture.<br />
Several times in my journeys I’ve had the misfortune of driving along the highway, minding my own business, and coming up on fresh skunk road kill.  The stench lingers in the car even after the site of the demise of the skunk is behind me.  In commissioning Jeremiah to his life&#8217;s work, the Lord says that the culture of his nation stinks.  God’s sick of it and is going to bring in enemies of theirs from the north to do a thorough cleaning.  Jeremiah&#8217;s job is to prepare the way for that event by mounting an offense against that rotten culture.  From the beginning it’s made clear to him that he’ll operate counter to the prevailing culture of that day.  He&#8217;s going to be the focal point of some big explosions and his only hope of surviving them is that God’s going to make him rough and tough, as &#8220;solid as a concrete wall.&#8221;  Jeremiah&#8217;s ministry is to be one of confrontation.  Frankly, I doubt that the culture of my nation is any better than was that of Jeremiah&#8217;s.  If God was sick of the stench of that culture then he must be pretty tired of that of our day too.  Who knows?  Right now God might be rising up a new Jeremiah.  Whether or not that&#8217;s so, I do understand this: we believers have to do more than just go with the flow and feel pleased that we&#8217;re keeping our heads above water.  We need to take a stand for righteousness in our homes and in other places where we have influence.  Can God count on me to be a &#8220;one-man defense system&#8221; at least in those areas?<br />
Take Away: Sometimes Christians have to take a stand for righteousness, even if that stand isn’t well accepted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-66/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have it your way Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running. Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them. They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5hjy4W45ajM/YDQRSicp-ZI/AAAAAAABIs0/KZRzd4xM9PENfeleyEkCY0gkweOPPsSrQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0567.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Big Lagoon State Park, FL</figcaption></figure><br />
Have it your way<br />
Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running.<br />
Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them.  They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t hesitate to run to him for help.  The Lord says, &#8220;You&#8217;ve plenty of gods, let them take care of you; let them save you from the bad times.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve seen it.  I&#8217;ve known people who know God&#8217;s purpose for them but don&#8217;t want any part of it.  When the wheels come off, they “get religion” and want God to rescue them.  I know the Lord is gracious and forgiving and long suffering.  As one of his people I want those qualities to be evident in my life.  At the same time, there’s a fair word of warning in this.  At some point, the Lord yields to our decisions and allows us to have it our way.  We shouldn’t presume on the grace of God.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for his grace – at the same time don’t be so foolish as to see just how far you can push the Almighty.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-67/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 18:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Insulting God Jeremiah 2: But my people forget me. Day after day after day they never give me a thought. Jeremiah says people think about the things that are important to them. Women don&#8217;t forget that they own beautiful jewelry. Guys don&#8217;t forget that the NFL playoffs are on. Political junkies don&#8217;t overlook the New [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VNiiFXAVyBE/YDVSz1qZt5I/AAAAAAABIvM/qbXPluQaRvYIoQJHRvDs8WolqWFhFKK8ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0441.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Big Lagoon State Park, FL</figcaption></figure><br />
Insulting God<br />
Jeremiah 2: But my people forget me.  Day after day after day they never give me a thought.<br />
Jeremiah says people think about the things that are important to them.  Women don&#8217;t forget that they own beautiful jewelry.  Guys don&#8217;t forget that the NFL playoffs are on.  Political junkies don&#8217;t overlook the New Hampshire primaries.  Jeremiah says that God&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’ve forgotten him.  They live their days without giving God much thought, taking him for granted while focusing on things that really do matter to them.  It isn&#8217;t so much that they&#8217;ve made a decision that God doesn&#8217;t matter.  They&#8217;ve just concentrated on other things and neglected the spiritual.  Now, they can go for days without giving the Lord any thought at all.  I imagine that all that can change in an instant.  When trouble comes they can get all &#8220;spiritual&#8221; in a hurry.  God doesn&#8217;t like being treated that way.  He created us to live in constant fellowship with himself.  Apparently, he takes it personally when I can spend a day immersed in other things without giving him a thought.  With that in mind, I must discipline my mind to keep God on my mind.  Lord, let it never be said of me that I can wander through my day without giving you a thought.<br />
Take Away: I must discipline my mind to keep the Lord on my mind.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-68/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prodigal son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s telling the truth to lost people Jeremiah 3: I&#8217;m committed in love to you. The sins of Judah and Israel are described in graphic terms. Their idol worship has a sexual component and the Lord uses that imagery to speak of their betrayal of him in terms of adultery. He’s loved them and been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-b8M3jI-ileU/YDae00PVbEI/AAAAAAABIxE/wSklfcmdrU4TPeFF3ARSnjWdXs7URZjyQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0587.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Fred Hartman Bridge, Houston</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s telling the truth to lost people<br />
Jeremiah 3: I&#8217;m committed in love to you.<br />
The sins of Judah and Israel are described in graphic terms.  Their idol worship has a sexual component and the Lord uses that imagery to speak of their betrayal of him in terms of adultery.   He’s loved them and been faithful to them but they’ve betrayed that love and degraded themselves in the most lewd ways.  If this were a husband and wife relationship no one would question the husband&#8217;s right to kick her out.  It isn&#8217;t that way though.  In spite of their unfaithfulness God calls out to them saying he&#8217;s committed to love them and that all they have to do is admit their sin and return to him.  The imagery changes to that of a parent speaking to a rebellious child as the Lord says, &#8220;Come back wandering children.&#8221;   Before Jesus ever tells the story of the prodigal son Jeremiah pictures for us a loving God reaching out to those who’ve rejected him, wounding his heart.  On one hand, it&#8217;s foolish to presume upon the mercy of God, thinking, &#8220;When I&#8217;m good and ready I&#8217;ll return to him.&#8221;  On the other hand, it&#8217;s an insult to him to say, &#8220;I&#8217;ve sinned in such a terrible way that he won&#8217;t take me back.&#8221;  God says he&#8217;s &#8220;committed in love to&#8221; us.  He promises that if I repent and return he’ll welcome me back.  To doubt that is to think that God doesn&#8217;t tell the truth.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-69/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 18:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weeping]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The weeping prophet Jeremiah 4: My insides are tearing me up. If Jeremiah was a modern film maker this portion of his writings would be rated &#8220;R&#8221; for violence. In one disturbing scene after another he describes the utter destruction that’s coming. Adam Clarke says this is &#8220;imagery scarcely paralleled in the whole Bible.&#8221; Jeremiah’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sCc6-4qrBnA/YDhOu1RVWhI/AAAAAAABIyE/eAzeKkYwb4sv3tFpHIULcpU64V8j9psuQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/sam-houston-jones-state-park-lake-charles-la-2009%2B6-23-2009%2B2-52-22%2BPM%2B7-3-2009%2B10-55-39%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Sam Houston Jones State Park &#8211; Lake Charles, LA</figcaption></figure><br />
The weeping prophet<br />
Jeremiah 4: My insides are tearing me up.<br />
If Jeremiah was a modern film maker this portion of his writings would be rated &#8220;R&#8221; for violence.  In one disturbing scene after another he describes the utter destruction that’s coming.  Adam Clarke says this is &#8220;imagery scarcely paralleled in the whole Bible.&#8221;  Jeremiah’s not untouched by his own prophecy.  We don&#8217;t know exactly how this word of the Lord came to him, but if it was in a dream, it was a nightmare and if it was a vision it was a very disturbing vision indeed.  He reports &#8220;I&#8217;m doubled up with cramps in my belly &#8212; a poker burns in my gut.&#8221;  I can&#8217;t say that Jeremiah is my favorite Hebrew prophet to read, but his humanity does draw me in.  Jeremiah didn&#8217;t want to be God&#8217;s spokesman in the first place.  However, he accepts the Lord&#8217;s appointment and his journey begins.  When he sees the coming destruction he isn&#8217;t a disconnected reporter.  Instead, he’s part of the story.  As wave after wave of visions of destruction wash over him he’s sick to his stomach.  He says to the Lord, &#8220;How long do I have to look at the warning flares, listen to the siren of danger?&#8221;  All he wants is out of this.  As a &#8220;proclaimer&#8221; of God&#8217;s Word in my generation I need some of his spirit.  Otherwise, I (and other Christians) sound hard and hateful and am easily rejected by the very people who must hear the message.  If I can interact with lost people without being moved by their plight something’s wrong with me and I need a spiritual transfusion from this &#8220;weeping prophet.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Judgment, when it must be preached, must be preached with tears in our eyes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-70/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 18:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God takes being ignored personally Jeremiah 5: Why don&#8217;t you honor me? God&#8217;s question to Judah resonates: &#8220;Why don&#8217;t you honor me?&#8221; He’s blessed them, forgiven them, and protected them yet they refuse to look his way. Jeremiah says that the Lord wonders why they don&#8217;t look at all of it and ask, &#8220;How can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_pPfILFnhp8/YDld2tDl5vI/AAAAAAABIy4/KeCqb45mvmws2uJVgi_YfrQAX8YjMTO3QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/sam-houston-jones-state-park-lake-charles-la-2009%2B6-23-2009%2B2-52-22%2BPM%2B7-3-2009%2B10-54-00%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Sam Houston Jones State Park &#8211; Lake Charles, LA</figcaption></figure><br />
God takes being ignored personally<br />
Jeremiah 5: Why don&#8217;t you honor me?<br />
God&#8217;s question to Judah resonates: &#8220;Why don&#8217;t you honor me?&#8221;  He’s blessed them, forgiven them, and protected them yet they refuse to look his way.  Jeremiah says that the Lord wonders why they don&#8217;t look at all of it and ask, &#8220;How can we honor our God with our lives?&#8221;  However, that doesn&#8217;t happen.  Instead, we see God-insulting sin and rebellion.  It’s no wonder the Lord’s sick of them!  After all he&#8217;s done for them they’ve turned their backs on him and walked away.  God&#8217;s response is to do the same.  He’ll be the one walking away and they’ll pay a terrible price for their insulting attitude toward him.  Frankly, this passage troubles me.  It would be easier to skip ahead to more sunshine and bypass this gloom and doom.  That, though, is the problem.  I&#8217;d better listen to Jeremiah.  God takes being ignored personally.  He blesses us in many wonderful ways but he expects us to respond to that blessing by honoring him in our lives.  I may not be able to influence the larger culture but I’d better take this stuff to heart.  Beyond that, I need to use what influence I do have to remind people that God expects us to respond to his blessings and never take him, or them, for granted.<br />
Take Away: The Lord takes being ignored personally.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-71/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 18:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new heart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Visiting ICU Jeremiah 6: My people are broken &#8212; shattered! &#8212; and they put on band-aids! To be apart from God is serious business. The solution isn’t to turn over a new leaf or to try to be a nicer person. Outside of God is death. A doctor doesn’t put a band-aid on a person [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1063px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VGlV9M0iI7I/YDqP2tBsI7I/AAAAAAABIzg/kQcSZ-tcywA-bU1nhzuEHLSDalMHB0ZYACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-12-2009%2B4-51-30%2BPM.JPG" width="1063" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier National Park, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Visiting ICU<br />
Jeremiah 6: My people are broken &#8212; shattered! &#8212; and they put on band-aids!<br />
To be apart from God is serious business.  The solution isn’t to turn over a new leaf or to try to be a nicer person.  Outside of God is death.  A doctor doesn’t put a band-aid on a person who needs a heart transplant.  The treatment is major surgery by a skilled surgeon.  As a Christian I ought to understand this because I&#8217;ve been through the spiritual version of that process.  However, I tend to forget it.  Lost people aren&#8217;t simply making mistakes and facing a troublesome future.  Spiritually speaking they’re in ICU with worse things yet to come.  Jeremiah realizes that the sins of his nation have brought them to the brink of absolute catastrophe.   I need to deal with those who are apart from God with the seriousness Jeremiah shows here.<br />
Take Away: Lost people are really lost &#8212; condemned and without hope unless they allow the Lord to do a major, life changing work in their lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
