<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>loss &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/loss/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 01:06:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>loss &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-47/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 22:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The death of Ezekiel’s wife Ezekiel 24: Get dressed as usual and go about your work &#8212; none of the usual funeral rituals. The final part of Ezekiel 24 is one of the most painful passages one can read. The Lord tells his prophet that his wife is about to die but as an object [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oz9SkvM29tQ/YJ70MCmLEPI/AAAAAAABKKU/Jrar0gZxF0U9bDgLw66ZweX7m5K8W8F2wCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2Bcamping%2Bat%2BGoose%2BIsland%2BState%2BPark%2B11-29-2010%2B6-41-55.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
The death of Ezekiel’s wife<br />
Ezekiel 24: Get dressed as usual and go about your work &#8212; none of the usual funeral rituals.<br />
The final part of Ezekiel 24 is one of the most painful passages one can read.  The Lord tells his prophet that his wife is about to die but as an object lesson for the people he&#8217;s not to publicly mourn her death.  By the time of this event Ezekiel is well known for his messages of God&#8217;s anger with his people.  He&#8217;s also known for &#8220;acting out&#8221; some event as an object lesson.  When his wife dies and Ezekiel just goes on with his preaching everyone knows there&#8217;s an object lesson in it.  They gather round this broken man and ask him why he isn&#8217;t mourning the loss of the love of his life.  It&#8217;s then that he warns them that even as his beloved has been taken from him their beloved city and Temple are going to be taken and, even as he&#8217;s not gone through a mourning process their enemies won&#8217;t give them even a moment to mourn the loss of it all.  I can hardly imagine what it was like for Ezekiel that day as God&#8217;s message had to take precedence over his personal loss.  Earlier in his ministry the Lord promised to stiffen Ezekiel that he could face all the rejection that was coming, so maybe that&#8217;s in play here.  Another thing I can hardly imagine is how God could love these hard people so much as to keep reaching out to them, calling them to himself in such drastic ways.  Finally, I don&#8217;t think Ezekiel&#8217;s situation can be viewed as typical of God&#8217;s servants.  On one hand, I&#8217;m reminded of what it means to be surrendered to the Lord; that it can take us to places we never would go otherwise.  On the other hand, I remember that this is a very unique situation in the Bible and can&#8217;t be viewed as how the Lord usually deals with us.  Of course, the Lord asks noting of Ezekiel that he doesn&#8217;t require of himself.  Even as God&#8217;s Only Begotten Son dies on the cross, he&#8217;ll have to turn his back on him.<br />
Take Away: The Lord loves lost people so much that he’ll act in extreme ways to redeem them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ruth</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ruth-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 23:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ruth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Full commitment Ruth 1: Where you go, I go; and where you live, I&#8217;ll live. Your people are my people, your God is my god. A family of refugees moves into her neighborhood and over time she falls in love with and marries one of the sons. Her in-laws often surprise Ruth. Their ways are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-20lk34yv4b0/XboaCRWHs-I/AAAAAAABCWU/fsVLfHAeJdI18v4McRNoBVoq7oBehkoRACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9299772.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Full commitment<br />
Ruth 1: Where you go, I go; and where you live, I&#8217;ll live. Your people are my people, your God is my god.<br />
A family of refugees moves into her neighborhood and over time she falls in love with and marries one of the sons. Her in-laws often surprise Ruth. Their ways are different than hers. Most unique is their religion. They have but one God and they tell many stories of his deliverance of their people and his love for them. Their laws are just and intended to protect the weak. Even as Ruth is becoming a part of this family, the family begins coming apart. First, her father-in-law dies. Then her brother-in-law passes away and soon after that her own husband dies. In time, her broken-hearted mother-in-law declares that she&#8217;s releasing the wives of her two deceased sons. The young women can marry again and start life anew. As for her, it&#8217;s time she returns home. How sad: she left her homeland with a husband and two fine sons. Now she&#8217;ll return alone. Ruth is having none of this. In Naomi she has not only a mother-in-law but also a friend. Beyond that, going back to her old life, now that she’s had had a glimpse of something better, is unthinkable. So we come to her beautiful statement of commitment. She will cast her lot with Naomi. She will be her friend and she will make Naomi&#8217;s values and Naomi&#8217;s God her own. I wonder if my life, even in the face of heartache, has the potential to cause anyone to say, &#8220;I will serve and love the God you serve and love.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: There’s something attractive about a God-centered life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 01:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mrs. Job Job 2: Curse God and be done with it! I&#8217;m not sure how far one can go in thinking about Mrs. Job. Obviously this story isn’t about her. It’s Job&#8217;s faithfulness to God even when he’s getting nothing out of it that drives this story. Still, I feel sorry for Job&#8217;s wife. She’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-XdhKFnHoJyA/XxuA8WmXFgI/AAAAAAABFmk/lyJmuvq8BOc5LhVTP0vsOHge47BOpd1ZgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_130409.jpg" width="1600" height="796" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Mrs. Job<br />
Job 2: Curse God and be done with it!<br />
I&#8217;m not sure how far one can go in thinking about Mrs. Job.  Obviously this story isn’t about her.  It’s Job&#8217;s faithfulness to God even when he’s getting nothing out of it that drives this story.  Still, I feel sorry for Job&#8217;s wife.  She’s suffered all the same losses he has.  She’s lost everything, including her family.  Now her husband sits before her, quivering in agony.  Her life is ruined.  When she advises Job to give up on God it’s because she already has.  Her response is what Satan predicted Job&#8217;s would be: if the blessings of God are withdrawn human beings will no longer serve him.  Job&#8217;s reply is that this is a foolish approach.  God grants us life and we enjoy the good days that come.  When things turn sour we go on trusting and serving him.  That doesn&#8217;t mean we’re happy about things or that we don&#8217;t change them if we can.  It does mean that we’ve chosen to trust God with both the good and bad that life brings.  Job is angry with God, as we shall see, but he refuses to turn away from Him, even when serving God has resulted in so much pain.<br />
Take Away: Faith is a matter of the will and not a product of circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
