<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>faithfulness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/faithfulness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:37:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>faithfulness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good theology from Johnny Cash Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom. The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen. At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-E_1VkmdhITE/X6MTYEsK8zI/AAAAAAABHew/MSgFGd12GEQ69iWj9UBv0nsDUHrDw8ehgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/22rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Good theology from Johnny Cash<br />
Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom.<br />
The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen.  At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so I just smiled and moved on.  A person can say and do a lot of wise things in their life, but one blunder can pretty much ruin it all.  I&#8217;ve seen that happen with presidents and pastors; with CEO&#8217;s and secretaries.  When my son got his first driver&#8217;s license I commented to him that many drivers only make one mistake in their lives, and it&#8217;s their last.  Car wrecks can be unforgiving.  It’s true of other life situations too.  A man can be a good husband and father for 30 years and then get involved with someone for a brief fling that ruins all those years of faithfulness.  While I’m a big believer in second chances and grace I also know that a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; can ruin a lot of godly living.  Johnny Cash wasn&#8217;t singing a hymn when he sang, &#8220;I keep a close watch on this heart of mine&#8230;because you&#8217;re mine I walk the line&#8221; but his words do apply in that sense.  I don&#8217;t want a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; to ruin a lifetime of faithfulness.<br />
Take Away: Watch out for “dead flies” in your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-109/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 03:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No guarantee of success Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;. Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness. The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-i_a3YDShAZA/X71OF_Au9hI/AAAAAAABHrc/gzn2cFk2OU8x8X8KgmE4E1tceuPKuEqhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B12-58-18%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
No guarantee of success<br />
Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness.  The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord.  However, the next thing the Lord tells Isaiah must be very difficult to swallow.  In spite of his being a man with &#8220;lips touched with a coal from off the altar&#8221; his ministry won’t bear fruit.  I know it takes commitment to step forward and say &#8220;send me&#8221; but how much more to go on this mission with the promise of failure.  The Lord says that the people Isaiah goes to minister to will not respond.  Why the Lord tells Isaiah this is a mystery to me.  Why not just send him on without telling him of the failure to come?  I have no answer.  However, I do see one important thing here: I belong to the Lord and I have to leave the results of my ministry in his hands.  For Isaiah the important thing is &#8220;going&#8221; &#8212; being faithful.  That’s how it is for all of us who serve him.<br />
Take Away: We’re called to obedient faithfulness.  The results we leave in the hands of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-50/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 08:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[support]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Friends and family Proverbs 17: Friends love through all kinds of weather, and families stick together in all kinds of trouble. I&#8217;ve lived long enough to know that &#8220;all kinds of trouble&#8221; comes to every life. Sooner or later its each person&#8217;s turn to face disappointment and be let down by people and circumstances or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iJuEGHdXI4c/X3y83nkUBEI/AAAAAAABG1A/Jcn9HM6KzUANbwyePUVmA748RyaToktgQCPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Friends and family<br />
Proverbs 17: Friends love through all kinds of weather, and families stick together in all kinds of trouble.<br />
I&#8217;ve lived long enough to know that &#8220;all kinds of trouble&#8221; comes to every life.  Sooner or later its each person&#8217;s turn to face disappointment and be let down by people and circumstances or be betrayed by their own humanity.  At such times it becomes easier to see what and who matters the most to us.  I&#8217;m thankful today for family of both the &#8220;blood line&#8221; and the &#8220;relationship&#8221; variety.  There’s power in positive relationships.  Even when we’re at the end of ourselves, we can draw strength from those dear ones who stand with us.  I&#8217;m reminded today that, first, I need to appreciate precious friends and family and not take them for granted even though they love me enough that I could probably get away with it.  Also, I remember that I’m privileged to be such a friend to some.  It&#8217;s an honor, but it’s also a responsibility that I must take seriously no matter what the &#8220;weather.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for friends and family and, thank the Lord for the privilege of being friend and family to others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-72/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our incense from Sheba Jeremiah 6: Your religious rituals mean nothing to me. They have church services and follow the time honored traditions handed down from generation to generation. It&#8217;s pretty impressive: robed priests, burning incense, sacrifices and prayers and songs. In fact, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with any of it. The problem isn&#8217;t in how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rSs4I_YZqnM/YDwZAFv2YHI/AAAAAAABI0o/Hpaw68PWHdoZFo4Te_wUvVsDjbI5K3eqQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-12-2009%2B3-32-40%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1063" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Our incense from Sheba<br />
Jeremiah 6: Your religious rituals mean nothing to me.<br />
They have church services and follow the time honored traditions handed down from generation to generation.  It&#8217;s pretty impressive: robed priests, burning incense, sacrifices and prayers and songs.  In fact, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with any of it.  The problem isn&#8217;t in how they worship, it&#8217;s in how they live the rest of the time.  God says they&#8217;ve just been &#8220;playing games&#8221; and &#8220;ignoring everything&#8221; he says.  They respond by trying to jazz up their worship by bringing in some exotic incense from Sheba.  Can&#8217;t you hear it: &#8220;the worship service seems a bit down lately, let&#8217;s get some of that really good incense from Sheba, that&#8217;ll give us just the spark we need.&#8221;   However, it doesn&#8217;t work.  God isn&#8217;t impressed and their worship services remain as empty as before.  Listen, I&#8217;m all for fixing things up and I&#8217;m a firm believer in presenting a well ordered, prepared worship service.  Adding our version of “incense from Sheba” isn’t necessarily a bad thing.  However, that stuff only makes a difference if the worshipers are backing up their wonderfully choreographed and innovative church services with faithful day to day living.  Otherwise, the new &#8220;incense&#8221; won&#8217;t please us or the God we worship.<br />
Take Away: Being a worshipper of the Lord includes a lot more than just going to church.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 21:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust and obey for there’s no other way Ezekiel 3: &#8230;but you won&#8217;t die. You&#8217;ll have saved your life. As the prophet is commissioned he&#8217;s told that his job is to warn people. If they refuse his warning, then they&#8217;re responsible to God for that refusal. Ezekiel&#8217;s job is to issue God&#8217;s message. His salvation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1vEENiscTRs/YIxkjAD5NNI/AAAAAAABKB4/8UENIpghjfo_IlbLQQG_AHFSlKxRpWFpACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-47-18%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Trust and obey for there’s no other way<br />
Ezekiel 3: &#8230;but you won&#8217;t die.  You&#8217;ll have saved your life.<br />
As the prophet is commissioned he&#8217;s told that his job is to warn people.  If they refuse his warning, then they&#8217;re responsible to God for that refusal.  Ezekiel&#8217;s job is to issue God&#8217;s message.  His salvation is contingent on his faithfulness in doing so.  My first reaction to this passage is one of caution.  I read this from a New Testament point of view and immediately respond that my hope of salvation isn’t in my performance but in my faith in the Savior, Jesus.  Does that, in some way nullify this passage for me today?  Upon reflection, I think not.  Old or New Testament, preacher or listener, the requirement of God is the same: obedience.  The Lord calls Ezekiel to preach his message and that&#8217;s what&#8217;s required of him.  He&#8217;s called to obedience even as he calls his listeners to obedience.  It&#8217;s the same for me.  As I understand that Jesus is the Savior of the world I must obey his call to yield my life to him and follow him.  Anything else is disobedience.  So, Ezekiel obeyed by preaching God&#8217;s message.  His listeners were to obey by forsaking their sin and worshiping the Lord.  I obey by trusting in Jesus as my Lord and Savior and living in a relationship with him.  People may refuse Ezekiel&#8217;s message, but he&#8217;ll be saved in his obedience in preaching it anyway.<br />
Take Away: No matter where a person is on their spiritual journey, the Lord’s requirement is this: obey.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-51/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 22:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s messenger]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Faithful watchman Ezekiel 33: You, son of man, are the watchman. Ezekiel&#8217;s job, the Lord says, is that of a watchman. He&#8217;s to cry out, warning people of impending danger. If he does that, he&#8217;s done his job. If he fails, then part of the blame for the loss is his own. Ezekiel has done [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6E2uxnsZZvk/YKPwpi3fNGI/AAAAAAABKMg/lVtF5bMadtUjOdUdoUyLQVUCuQ18pTA7wCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BBlanco%2BState%2BPark%2B-%2B%2B5-23-2011%2B5-19-14%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1279" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Blanco State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Faithful watchman<br />
Ezekiel 33: You, son of man, are the watchman.<br />
Ezekiel&#8217;s job, the Lord says, is that of a watchman.  He&#8217;s to cry out, warning people of impending danger.  If he does that, he&#8217;s done his job.  If he fails, then part of the blame for the loss is his own.  Ezekiel has done his job.  The book bearing his name contains page after page of his warnings which are given, sometimes, at considerable personal cost.  Had he failed in doing his part the story would be considerably different, in fact, I doubt we would have a book of Ezekiel at all.  God would have sought out another spokesman and it would be his name that would appear as the title of a book of the Bible. It could be that Ezekiel wasn&#8217;t God&#8217;s first choice, that he started by calling someone who&#8217;s unknown to us today.  Also, there&#8217;s the record of massive failure here that we do know about.  The failure is that of those who heard the warning and rejected it.  Ezekiel is God&#8217;s watchman for Israel and his faithfulness to that task is impressive.  I pray not only that the Lord will send a faithful watchman for my nation but that his or her message will be heard and heeded.<br />
Take Away: All a person can do is be faithful to do what the Lord directs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winning in little ways first Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food. The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation. There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lJE1XjaSU48/YLQVqR4_jqI/AAAAAAABKVk/CYDNktkWgasEd-apehJEqrnPTJjj-OCJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-29-2011%2B12-19-09%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Hyde Park &#8211; the Serpentine &#8211; London, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
Winning in little ways first<br />
Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food.<br />
The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation.  There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what happens on vacation stays on vacation.&#8221;  One &#8220;off diet&#8221; meal leads to another and I end up bringing home, not just pleasant memories and photos of all the places we saw, but a few extra pounds too.  Of course, Daniel and his companions aren&#8217;t on vacation.  They&#8217;ve been taken against their will to a distant land with little hope of returning home.  Even if they could go back, things are very different than when they left.  Still, they&#8217;re in very pleasant surroundings.  They&#8217;re part of the household of the most powerful king on earth and they&#8217;re being groomed to serve in the royal court.  Their rations aren’t bread and water but, instead, are the richest of foods and the finest of wines.  The thing is that their religion has strict dietary rules.  That pork chop might look quite tasty, but it&#8217;s forbidden to them by their God.  If we struggle with our diets just because we’re a few hundred miles from home, think of their struggle.  The Temple, Jerusalem, and their family ties are all in their past.  Do the rules even apply anymore?  If they do just go along with what is being asked of them where will it take them next?  Does saying &#8220;yes&#8221; here mean they&#8217;ll be expected to say &#8220;yes&#8221; somewhere else, like, for instance, the worship of an idol?  Daniel decides to draw the line right where he is.  He&#8217;s a follower of God and God has given him some dietary rules.  He&#8217;ll be respectful, but he&#8217;ll hold steady at this minor point.  If he never starts down the path away from God he&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.  I don&#8217;t know if this passage will help me stay on my diet or not, but it certainly can help me remember that spiritual failure doesn&#8217;t start with my rejecting God in some big way.  Rather, it starts with little things.  If I win there, I&#8217;m much more likely to conquer the &#8220;biggie&#8221; when it shows up.<br />
Take Away: If we never start down the path away from God we&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 16:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At least they know what Daniel stands for Daniel 6: We&#8217;re never going to find anything against this Daniel unless we can cook up something religious. At the end of chapter five we find a simple statement that Darius the Mede is made king. Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of history loaded into that statement. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P8hPZkwGH7U/YMJMgreWK-I/AAAAAAABKaY/d5sFwzFtB-U96oYCZwpsUg3SuW-SKPC-ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA057783.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Arc de Triomphe, Paris, France</figcaption></figure><br />
At least they know what Daniel stands for<br />
Daniel 6: We&#8217;re never going to find anything against this Daniel unless we can cook up something religious.<br />
At the end of chapter five we find a simple statement that Darius the Mede is made king.  Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of history loaded into that statement.  The handwriting on the wall informed the now dead Belshazzar that his kingdom was going to be handed over to the &#8220;Medes and Persians,&#8221; a confederacy that rose to challenge the power of Babylonia.  Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of historical push and shove concerning all that happened in that takeover.  Daniel spares us all that, barely mentioning his own rise to authority in the reorganized kingdom, now under the rule of Darius.  This king recognizes leadership capability when he sees it and makes Daniel, first, one of his three vice-regents, and then moves to make Daniel the man in charge.  Of course, there are those who oppose this elevation of Daniel and they scramble to find some way to discredit him.  When they can&#8217;t come up with anything bad about him they focus in on his religion.  They conclude that his devotion to his God is his weakest point and decide to attack there.  I know it isn&#8217;t intended, but what a compliment to Daniel!  After living among the Babylonians for many years he&#8217;s still known for his devotion to the Lord.  It all started many years earlier when he decided to keep the dietary laws of his religion.  Now, we see him untouched by the pagan culture.  Things are about to get dicey for Daniel, but for now, he can say &#8220;thanks&#8221; to his enemies for the compliment.<br />
Take Away: Live in such a way even our enemies recognize our devotion and commitment to the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-35/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Keep up the good work Daniel 6: He continued to pray just as he had always done. The king has been duped by Daniel&#8217;s political enemies into banning prayer. They&#8217;re sure Daniel will &#8220;break the law&#8221; and pray anyway&#8230;and they&#8217;re right. I like the phrase &#8220;he continued to pray just as he had always done.&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7TkRLMe1vCQ/YMPD1FJn2rI/AAAAAAABKb0/T1OKlocc54kxpBR7f6r30j9vBMXpF_QLgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA057809.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; L&#8217;église de la Madeleine Catholic church &#8211; Paris</figcaption></figure><br />
Keep up the good work<br />
Daniel 6: He continued to pray just as he had always done.<br />
The king has been duped by Daniel&#8217;s political enemies into banning prayer.  They&#8217;re sure Daniel will &#8220;break the law&#8221; and pray anyway&#8230;and they&#8217;re right.  I like the phrase &#8220;he continued to pray just as he had always done.&#8221;  One can&#8217;t &#8220;continue&#8221; to pray unless he&#8217;s in the habit of praying in the first place.  Daniel has lived in a pagan culture for a long time but he&#8217;s found an anchor in prayer.  Three times each day he retreats to a place of prayer, keeping his connection with his God intact.  Through the years he&#8217;s risen to a powerful position in multiple administrations.  He&#8217;s been an explainer of dreams and a solver of mysteries.  Now we see the key to it all.  Daniel prays.  I don&#8217;t think I can overestimate the importance of my &#8220;continuing to pray.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Nothing takes the place of prayer in the lives of the people of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Amos</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-amos-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 20:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Amos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Car shopping Amos 5: You talk about God&#8230;being your best friend. I was talking to a car salesperson about a car. He was a friendly guy, a bit rough around the edges, using a few words I don’t have in my vocabulary. Then, he asked me what I did for a living. I told him [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GV-q-Pp_MOI/YPCbBTwOMsI/AAAAAAABKvA/-ZSseLi5Pswnrl9rCvBgWfUMqDac8_fAACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P7228790.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Niagara Falls</figcaption></figure><br />
Car shopping<br />
Amos 5: You talk about God&#8230;being your best friend.<br />
I was talking to a car salesperson about a car.  He was a friendly guy, a bit rough around the edges, using a few words I don’t have in my vocabulary.  Then, he asked me what I did for a living.  I told him I was the pastor of a church.  Guess what happened?  Suddenly, he was a very faithful Christian man.  He told me about his church and his pastor and some words disappeared from the conversation.  Amos complains about people who claim God as their best friend but live very different lives than what the Lord demands.  The big issue to Amos is how the poor are treated.  He says that in his society “justice is a lost cause” and people are “kicking the poor when they’re down.”   God’s man says that won’t cut it.  I can’t expect to get away with giving the Almighty lip service while ignoring his directions on how I&#8217;m to live.  Amos says, “You talk about God, the God-of-the-Angel-Armies, being your best friend.  Well, live like it, and maybe it will happen.”  By, the way, I bought my car elsewhere.<br />
Take Away: Live like it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
