<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Romans &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-romans/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 15:43:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Romans &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A theology book Romans 1: I write this letter to all the Christians in Rome, God’s friends. No one knows who it was who took the Gospel message to Rome. Some think Peter, but that’s due to a particular theological agenda that isn’t supported by the historical commentary of the book of Acts. I do [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15982" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15982" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15982" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239581.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15982" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>A theology book </p>
<p>Romans 1: I write this letter to all the Christians in Rome, God’s friends.</p>
<p>No one knows who it was who took the Gospel message to Rome.  Some think Peter, but that’s due to a particular theological agenda that isn’t supported by the historical commentary of the book of Acts.  I do have the idea that some who heard Peter’s great message on the Day of Pentecost were from Rome and were among the 3000 who became believers.  Perhaps they returned home and established Christianity in Rome.  If I understand the chronology right, as Paul writes this letter he’s about three years from the events recorded in the closing chapters of Acts that will bring him to Rome.  In his other letters, he deals with specific concerns because he&#8217;s had personal contact with the churches.  When he writes to the church at Rome he takes a different approach.  The result is the finest book of theology ever written.  I don’t know what the original readers thought of this letter but can only guess that they were as blown away by its depth and complexity as I am.  Happily for me, I’m not committed to write a commentary on Romans, just some devotionals.  Humanity, Paul says, has ignored God resulting in a sort of downward spiral into more and more outrageous and destructive sin.  This book of theology describes how it is God has acted to remedy that situation.</p>
<p>Take Away: If you like to read theology you can do no better than to commit yourself to becoming an expert on the book of Romans.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 12:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God at work here Romans 2: There is something deep within them that echoes God’s yes and no, right and wrong. Paul hasn’t spent his time locked up in some ivory tower thinking about hypothetical situations. Rather, more than anyone else, he’s gone out into the real world dealing with people from all walks of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15985" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15985" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15985" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239582.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15985" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>God at work here </p>
<p>Romans 2: There is something deep within them that echoes God’s yes and no, right and wrong.</p>
<p>Paul hasn’t spent his time locked up in some ivory tower thinking about hypothetical situations.  Rather, more than anyone else, he’s gone out into the real world dealing with people from all walks of life and a variety of religious beliefs.  We think that if we have a spirited exchange with a friend who’s a Catholic or a Pentecostal or a Baptist that we’ve been debating religion.  Paul has encountered a variety of religious views that reveal our denominational differences to be as trivial as they really are.  He’s worked with idol worshipers and with a wide variety of pagans.  In all that, Paul has never backed away from his faith in Jesus Christ and he’s proclaimed that faith at considerable personal cost.  Still, even in the most non-Christian settings he’s discovered in people the image of God.  He’s seen in those who’ve never heard of the Ten Commandments or the Sermon on the Mount an innate understanding of the concepts taught to God’s people by them.  This, Paul says, is a proof of God’s hand in their lives and a reminder that their coming to Christ isn’t as distant a journey as one might think.  On one hand, I don’t want to drift into the dangerous waters of universalism.  Among other things, that diminishes the sacrifice our Lord made on the cross.  On the other hand, I want to appreciate the good things I see in people who haven’t yet come to the Lord.  On every human heart, follower of Jesus or not, a sign can be hung declaring “God at work here.”</p>
<p>Take Away: Before I ever think of God he thinks of me and before I ever respond to him, he’s already at work in my life.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 12:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grace extended to both insiders and outsiders Romans 3: Out of sheer generosity he put us in right standing with himself. The Jews, Paul says, have a special relationship with God. They’re the writers of Scripture, introducing God to the world. That’s a place of great honor, but it’s no guarantee of salvation. Not only [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15988" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15988" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15988" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239591.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15988" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Grace extended to both insiders and outsiders </p>
<p>Romans 3: Out of sheer generosity he put us in right standing with himself.</p>
<p>The Jews, Paul says, have a special relationship with God.  They’re the writers of Scripture, introducing God to the world.  That’s a place of great honor, but it’s no guarantee of salvation.  Not only that, but these custodians of God’s Word have, themselves, failed to live according to it.  Meanwhile, the outsiders have gone their own way.  Ignorant of God’s commands, uninterested in his ways, they too have failed.  The result is “that we’re sinners, every one of us, in the same sinking boat with everybody else.”  So now what?  Those with the inside path to God haven’t followed it and those on the outside haven’t found it.  Hope for salvation has to come from, not within, but from outside of humanity.  Enter Jesus.  Through him the remedy for failure and sin is offered.  The Jews need him because they’ve rejected what they knew God wanted.  The outsiders need him because they’ve never started down God’s path in the first place.  The generous provision of God is his making a way to life for all people, Jews and non-Jews alike.  The hope of salvation, then, is in this wonderful expression of God’s grace to a lost human race.</p>
<p>Take Away: For those who know the law but haven’t kept it and for those who never kept it because they never knew it, that is, for all of us, our only hope is God’s grace.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 12:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A “me-story” or a God-story? Romans 4: The story we’re given is a God-story, not an Abraham-story. The Old Testament story of Abraham doesn’t start with “Abraham sought God” or “Abraham was a righteous man.” Rather, the focus is on God who approaches Abraham, makes promises to him, and calls him to follow. Obviously, without [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15991" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15991" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15991" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6239592.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15991" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>A “me-story” or a God-story? </p>
<p>Romans 4: The story we’re given is a God-story, not an Abraham-story.</p>
<p>The Old Testament story of Abraham doesn’t start with “Abraham sought God” or “Abraham was a righteous man.”  Rather, the focus is on God who approaches Abraham, makes promises to him, and calls him to follow.  Obviously, without Abraham’s response there would be no story.  However, it’s even truer that without God’s first call, Abraham would have had no opportunity to obey in the first place.  In the book of Romans, Paul wants us to understand the route to righteousness.  We don’t arrive at a certain place where the Almighty is impressed by us and decides to take us under his wing.  Rather, even when we’re hopelessly lost the Lord seeks us out, calls to us, makes promises to us and then awaits our response.  The greatest thing Abraham ever does is to respond to what God does.  As I apply that to my life I find all the rules being rewritten.  If it’s just me doing stuff, even things that impress others, it’s not worth much.  However, if I respond to God’s grace in my life, and then live my life in him, things happen that would have never otherwise been accomplished.  My life becomes, not a “me-story,” but becomes a God-story.</p>
<p>Take Away: It all starts with the grace of God.  I plug into that grace by faith.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 12:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grace wins Romans 5: When it’s sin verses grace, grace wins hands down. Obviously, it all starts with Adam, the first human being. This first man’s failure puts in motion a whole string of failures. Humanity is in a death spiral. One man’s sin results in the sins of many. One man’s sin results in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15994" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15994" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-1024x641.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="601" class="size-large wp-image-15994" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-1024x641.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-1536x961.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15994" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Grace wins </p>
<p>Romans 5: When it’s sin verses grace, grace wins hands down.</p>
<p>Obviously, it all starts with Adam, the first human being.  This first man’s failure puts in motion a whole string of failures.  Humanity is in a death spiral.  One man’s sin results in the sins of many.  One man’s sin results in the deaths of many.  Without an intervention this story is going to end badly.  Then, God’s own Son, Jesus, Son of God and Son of Man, steps into history.  Adam’s disobedience brings death.  Jesus’ obedience brings life.  For humanity it’s a gift beyond understanding.  Our sin: our crushing, destroying, death dealing sin seems insurmountable.  Now, through Jesus, the remedy is given.  Sin, as powerful as it is, meets its match.  Grace wins. </p>
<p>Take Away: No matter how great the sin, it meets it match in God’s matchless grace.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 12:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freedom Romans 6: You are dead to sin and alive to God. The topic is freedom. When I was bound in sin, living a dead end life without hope Jesus came to rescue me. Taking my sin as his own, he carried it to death, stripping it of its grip on me. Then, in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15996" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15996" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15996" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140620_193632.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15996" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Chehalis, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; chapel</figcaption></figure>
<p>Freedom </p>
<p>Romans 6: You are dead to sin and alive to God.</p>
<p>The topic is freedom.  When I was bound in sin, living a dead end life without hope Jesus came to rescue me.  Taking my sin as his own, he carried it to death, stripping it of its grip on me.  Then, in the resurrection, the possibility of new life came to me.  When I join Christ at the cross I die to sin.  When I join him at the tomb on resurrection morning, that resurrection life becomes mine.  Now, I stand a free man, made new by the work of Christ.  I’m filled with thanksgiving and forever indebted to the One who has made it all possible.  The freedom I’ve received is a cherished possession, one that I guard carefully, realizing that some acts are out of bounds for me because to do them would place me back in bondage from whence I came.  Instead, I willingly serve the One who gave me freedom, bound, not by sin and death, but by love.  </p>
<p>Take Away: I’m bound…not by sin, but by God’s love.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 12:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The greatest need of the believer Romans 7: But I need something more. In this passage the Apostle describes the frustration of many of God’s people. He’s been set free from sin’s prison and now wants to live God’s way. He understands that God’s ways are right but under the influence of sin even the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15994" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15994" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140623_140803-1-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="601" class="size-large wp-image-15994" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15994" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>The greatest need of the believer </p>
<p>Romans 7: But I need something more.</p>
<p>In this passage the Apostle describes the frustration of many of God’s people.  He’s been set free from sin’s prison and now wants to live God’s way.  He understands that God’s ways are right but under the influence of sin even the purity of the Law becomes a tool of temptation and failure.  He’s been freed from prison but some of that prison remains in him.  He declares “I need something more.”  A believer doesn’t have to attend a particular brand of church to identify with this statement.  Having been forgiven of sins I set out to live a new life of righteousness in fellowship with the Lord.  However, I come to the conclusion that this isn’t as easy as it appears.  In fact, the harder I try to live that life of righteousness the clearer it becomes that, in Paul’s words: “I obviously need help!”  Is this passage a pitiful surrender to sin?  When all is said and done, is the Christian life all about grimly holding on through repeated spiritual failure?  The Apostle will more fully answer these questions as he continues writing in what we call chapter eight, but he tips his hand when he says, “The answer, thank God, is&#8230;Jesus Christ.”</p>
<p>Take Away: Without the deeper work of God the Christian life is one of constant struggle.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s answer to sin-in-me Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved. What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16014" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16014" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16014" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-768x482.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1536x963.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16014" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Long Beach, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; on the beach a short walk from the campground</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s answer to sin-in-me</p>
<p>Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved.</p>
<p>What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown away by the opening words of Romans 8. Before Christ, Romans 7 was the norm, but it’s the norm no more. In Christ “a new power is in operation” and everything’s changed. When I cry out to God for relief from sin he responds in Christ to defeat sin-in-me once and for all. The blood of Christ is applied to my life to bring about a “deep healing” and sin-as-a-condition is defeated. Now, a new day dawns in my spiritual life. I’m led “out into the open, into a spacious, free life.” I’ve been “delivered from that dead life” and the Spirit is now living in me. As a child of God who struggles with sin, I cry out to my Heavenly Father for help. He responds by doing a work in me as “God’s Spirit touches” my spirit resulting in a deeper relationship with God and a level of spiritual living I never before dreamed possible.</p>
<p>Take Away: In God, there’s wonderful freedom from self and sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been included Romans 9: They were so absorbed in their “God projects” that they didn’t notice God right in front of them. Big issues are in play here. Paul says that while the descendants of Abraham are the people with the promise of God that promise remains under God’s control. Even among Abraham’s descendants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16017" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16017" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16017" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140629_144640.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16017" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Long Beach, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; on the beach a short walk from the campground</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’ve been included</p>
<p>Romans 9: They were so absorbed in their “God projects” that they didn’t notice God right in front of them.</p>
<p>Big issues are in play here. Paul says that while the descendants of Abraham are the people with the promise of God that promise remains under God’s control. Even among Abraham’s descendants some are excluded and have no part in the promise. For instance, twin brothers (Jacob and Esau), before they’re ever born are treated differently from one another by God. One will be part of what God is doing in the world and the other won’t. Some Israelites have the idea that salvation is uniquely theirs because of their lineage. Paul says that’s not how it is. The only real decision maker here is God, so when some of Abraham’s descendants have tried to take the ball and run with it, making salvation their personal property, they’ve run head first into the Almighty who reminds them that this is his doing and not theirs. Israel doesn’t own salvation – God does. This is Good News for those of us who would otherwise be considered outsiders and ineligible for this wonderful plan of salvation.</p>
<p>Take Away: There’s a wideness in God’s mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Message-proclaimers Romans 10: Grand processions of people telling all the good things of God! Paul quotes the prophet Isaiah all through this passage. In his day, Isaiah extolled the value of messengers who went from place to place proclaiming the message of hope to their generation. That, he says, is a beautiful thing. Paul is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16019" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16019" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16019" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/P6309594.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16019" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment</figcaption></figure>
<p>Message-proclaimers</p>
<p>Romans 10: Grand processions of people telling all the good things of God!</p>
<p>Paul quotes the prophet Isaiah all through this passage. In his day, Isaiah extolled the value of messengers who went from place to place proclaiming the message of hope to their generation. That, he says, is a beautiful thing. Paul is sorry that the people of Israel of his day aren’t the “message-proclaimers.” They’ve had every opportunity to play that role but instead insist on doing things their own way. They’re the losers in that. Now, I read this scenario and think about my own generation. Like the messengers of Isaiah’s day, the Church has Good News. We should be happily “telling all the good things of God.” All too often though, like the people of Israel of Paul’s day, we’ve retreated to our church buildings and busied ourselves with committees and programs, hanging our shingle outside inviting those want to know more to come on in. Beyond that, we’ve divided up into different camps, drawing lines and building walls. We’d rather argue over finer points of the Bible than go next door to offer a cup of cold water in Jesus’ name. Isaiah reminds us that it’s a beautiful thing when God’s people take the Good News to those who need it so desperately. Paul, though, reminds us that it’s possible for those with the Good News to fumble and fail. Does this kind of thinking alarm us? It should.</p>
<p>Take Away: Who do I know who needs the Good News?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
