<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Luke &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-luke/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 15:09:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Luke &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 15:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's purposes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Exactly, what prayer was that? Luke 1: Your prayer has been heard. For Zechariah it’s an once-in-a-lifetime event. He’s the priest who’ll enter the sanctuary and burn incense before the Lord. As he carefully and reverently goes about this task he sees movement to the right of the altar, then, out of nowhere an angel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15811" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15811" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15811" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/100_2826.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15811" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Point Whitehorn Marine Reserve &#8211; near Birch Bay, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Exactly, what prayer was that?</p>
<p>Luke 1: Your prayer has been heard.</p>
<p>For Zechariah it’s an once-in-a-lifetime event. He’s the priest who’ll enter the sanctuary and burn incense before the Lord. As he carefully and reverently goes about this task he sees movement to the right of the altar, then, out of nowhere an angel of the Lord appears. Zechariah would run if he could, but instead just stands there, eyes wide, mouth open, face to face with an archangel. The angel speaks reassuringly, and, to the old priest’s surprise, calls him by name. Then this angel adds, “Your prayer has been heard.” I wonder what thoughts raced through Zechariah’s mind in that instant. Here’s what I think: I imagine the old priest thinking, “What prayer is that?” You see, there was a time in his and Elizabeth’s lives when they prayed for a child most every day. They were young then and all the other couples they knew were having babies. However, time was passing and they remained childless. The years passed and they were no longer a young couple. They prayed about this less and then they gave up, disappointed but trusting God with their emptiness. Now, years later, when Gabriel says, “Your prayer has been answered” my guess is that the “baby prayer” is the farthest thing from Zechariah’s mind. Zachariah might have forgotten the prayer, but God hasn’t. Now, at the time that seems way too late for this senior adult couple, God is about to move. Once again I’m reminded that God’s ways aren’t my ways and his schedule isn’t my schedule. Beyond that, I see that God’s ways are the right ways and his time is always the right time. This realization has plenty of practical applications in my life today.</p>
<p>Take Away: Never doubt the power of prayer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 12:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior adults]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hats off to those who are “very old” Luke 2: She was by now a very old woman. Jesus is now eight days old and his parents take their newborn to the nearby Temple in Jerusalem for the rite of passage for every Jewish boy. Lots of people spend their days at the Temple. Some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15813" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15813" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15813" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_175449.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15813" class="wp-caption-text"></p>
<p>2014 &#8211; Point Whitehorn Marine Reserve &#8211; near Birch Bay, WA &#8211; cottonwood trees are blooming</figcaption></figure>
<p>Hats off to those who are “very old”</p>
<p>Luke 2: She was by now a very old woman.</p>
<p>Jesus is now eight days old and his parents take their newborn to the nearby Temple in Jerusalem for the rite of passage for every Jewish boy.  Lots of people spend their days at the Temple.  Some are there as doing jobs and others are simply devout people who’d rather be there than anywhere else.  On this day we meet two senior citizens who are Temple regulars.  One is a kindly old gentleman who loves baby dedications.  He spends his time hanging out in the area where that takes place congratulating parents and asking if he can take a peek at their eight day old boys.  The other is a sweet but reclusive woman who spends her days in the Court of Women.  Lots of people see her there because this is where the offerings are given, but she’s generally off to the side and out of the flow, head bowed in prayer.  When Joseph and Mary bring baby Jesus to the Temple, Simeon heads straight to them.  There’s purpose in his walk and he gently asks if he can hold the baby.  With tears in his eyes he praises God.  Joseph and Mary are speechless and thrilled with this event.  Then, the other senior saint shows up.  Aged Anna joins them and starts singing a wonderful song of praise to God.  The official baby dedication by the priest hasn’t yet happened, but these two senior adults who are so in tune with God do the most important part of the dedication on this day.  As I look back over my life and think of folks who are best connected to the Lord I’m not surprised to find that they&#8217;re all older people.  I’m a strong believer in God’s transforming works of grace in our lives but I also understand that maturity and spiritual depth only comes over time.  When a person who’s faithfully walked with the Lord for 80 years has something to say we’re smart to listen.</p>
<p>Take Away: The only way to become a mature Christian is to be a faithful Christian for a long time. </p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 12:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One tough man Luke 3: The main character in this drama&#8230;will ignite the kingdom life, a fire, the Holy Spirit within you. John the Baptist storms onto the world stage as “Thunder in the desert.” This is one tough man. He preaches a radical repentance. He calls some of his congregation “snakes” and tells everyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15756" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15756" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15756" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-768x573.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1536x1147.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15756" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Park at Blaine, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>One tough man </p>
<p>Luke 3: The main character in this drama&#8230;will ignite the kingdom life, a fire, the Holy Spirit within you.</p>
<p>John the Baptist storms onto the world stage as “Thunder in the desert.”  This is one tough man.  He preaches a radical repentance.  He calls some of his congregation “snakes” and tells everyone to straighten out their lives.  When people begin to speculate that he might be the Messiah of God he points to the precious Lamb of God who’s soon to be revealed.  John says that water baptism is the best he can offer.  The coming Messiah, he declares, will baptize with the fire of the Holy Spirit, changing people from the inside out.  John’s approach to life change is to take a hard line against sin.  Those who claim a righteousness of their own he calls “snakes.”  It’s a hard message, one intended to draw attention, and of course it’s true.  However, John’s message is of only limited value.  The tax collector who repents and commits himself to do the right thing is still the same person he was before.  The real need of his life will never be met in this manner.  The need is for him to be changed, transformed into a new person.  John’s method creates skin deep believers.  Jesus’ method creates saints of God.  Any time I’m tempted to come down hard on people, challenging them to straighten up and fly right I need to remember that the finest, most anointed practitioner of that kind of preaching ever says that he’s a mere stage hand compared to the real Star, Jesus.  His method isn’t to “tell it like it is.”  Rather, it’s to be a loving, humble servant of God and man. Lord, make me more like your Son, Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: More than reformation people need transformation.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 12:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temptation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The kingdom of darkness Luke 4: He shut them up, refusing to let them speak because they knew too much. Following his baptism Jesus is led by the Spirit out to the wilderness where he faces intense testing by the Devil. From this opening act of his ministry it’s clear that Jesus isn’t going to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15759" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15759" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15759" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-4a.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15759" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Blaine, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>The kingdom of darkness</p>
<p>Luke 4: He shut them up, refusing to let them speak because they knew too much.</p>
<p>Following his baptism Jesus is led by the Spirit out to the wilderness where he faces intense testing by the Devil.  From this opening act of his ministry it’s clear that Jesus isn’t going to have an easy time of it.  Right off he’s severely tested, both spiritually and physically.  Obviously, the Tempter knows who Jesus is and he makes every effort to derail the work of Christ before it ever gets underway.  The Devil then retreats for a time, waiting for another opportunity.  Now Jesus begins his work in earnest.  Luke begins the story of our Lord’s ministry in his home town of Nazareth but tells us Jesus is rejected there.  Then it’s off to Capernaum, a place that will be blessed by many miracles of Jesus.  When our Lord confronts a demon possessed man it’s the demon who speaks, apparently surprised at being confronted by Jesus, God’s Son.  Other possessed people are brought to Jesus and he drives the unclean spirits out as they protest their unexpected encounters with the Son of God.  Jesus isn’t ready for all this “Son of God” talk and orders them quiet, but Luke reports it to us.  I find myself thinking of the nature of what might be thought of as the “kingdom of darkness.”  When Jesus goes to the wilderness, the Devil comes to confront him.  Clearly, the Devil knows the identity of our Lord.  Then, just a short time later, when Jesus begins to challenge demons, they appear surprised by Jesus.  Sometimes we tend to think of Satan as the evil opposite of God, but that’s nothing close to the truth.  Satan has nothing like the power and authority of God Almighty.  He’s isn’t always present and he isn’t in control of anything.  In the case of this passage, we see that the demons aren’t like soldiers in his army, taking commands from him.  The Devil knows Jesus is beginning his ministry as Son of God, but the demons don’t know it and are surprised when they found themselves face to face with him.  I’m not sure what to make of this aside from being reminded that we tend to give Satan more power and authority than he actually has.  Beyond that, we see here the absolute authority of the Son of God over all the kingdom of darkness.  The Devil and the demons aren’t as big a deal as some think they are.  Still, seeing what happens when Jesus confronts this dark kingdom causes me to want to cozy up as close to him as possible.</p>
<p>Take Away: I want to be aware of the kingdom of darkness but not be focused on it.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So where’s Jesus now? Luke 5: As often as possible Jesus withdrew to out-of-the-way places for prayer. This statement about the prayer habit of Jesus sticks out like a sore thumb in this passage. It feels as if it was just tossed in after the fact, maybe written while Luke was thinking of what to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15762" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15762" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15762" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135813.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15762" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>So where’s Jesus now?</p>
<p>Luke 5: As often as possible Jesus withdrew to out-of-the-way places for prayer.</p>
<p>This statement about the prayer habit of Jesus sticks out like a sore thumb in this passage.  It feels as if it was just tossed in after the fact, maybe written while Luke was thinking of what to next tell us about the ministry of Jesus.  We’ve just heard Jesus preach while sitting in Simon’s boat and then watched as, under the command of Jesus, Simon and partners have caught a huge haul of fish.  Now Jesus is healing a man with leprosy and soon he’ll be surrounded by people seeking healing and with Pharisees seeking arguments.  Right in the middle of all this action is this one liner about Jesus slipping away for prayer.  Obviously, this is more than random filler from Luke.  He wants me to connect the mighty acts of Jesus with his secret prayer life.  As he teaches and heals God’s power flows out of him.  In his secret prayer life God’s power is replenished in him.  This is no chance thought of Luke’s.  Rather, he’s providing me with insight into the power source of our Lord.  Another devotional thought here is that in spite of the fact that Jesus is a busy man he makes time for prayer.  When the last needy person has been satisfied and these new disciples find themselves and Jesus finally alone they expect to enjoy some quality time with their Lord, or at least some down time before it all starts again in the morning.  James and John look around and realize Jesus isn’t there.  “Where’s Jesus?” they ask.  “He’s down by the lake,” Peter answers, adding, “He said something about needing some time alone.”  This is to become a daily pattern that the disciples will come to expect.  If it’s good for Jesus it’s good for me too.</p>
<p>Take Away: There’s always time, and the necessity, for prayer.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 13:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enemies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Drinking from a fire hose Luke 6: Our Father is kind; you be kind. Reading the Sermon on the Mount is like trying to get a drink from a fire hose. It’s not like the parables in which there’s a story followed by the lesson. Instead, there’s one wonderful, challenging, powerful concept after another. As [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15765" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15765" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15765" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_135939.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15765" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Drinking from a fire hose</p>
<p>Luke 6: Our Father is kind; you be kind.</p>
<p>Reading the Sermon on the Mount is like trying to get a drink from a fire hose.  It’s not like the parables in which there’s a story followed by the lesson.  Instead, there’s one wonderful, challenging, powerful concept after another.  As I try to write a devotional for each chapter of the New Testament the challenge is not finding something to write about.  Rather, it’s trying to dip into the huge stream of material and grab just one concept out of all the concepts and get my mind and heart around it.  Right now I’m focusing in on how our Lord says we’re to relate to our enemies.  I can’t help but note that Jesus doesn’t talk about how we’re to respond “if” we have enemies.  He apparently takes it for granted that some folks aren’t going to like us and some will go so far as to wish us harm.  What am I to do about such people?  First, Jesus says, I’m to pray for them (“respond with the energies of prayer”).  Second, I’m to return good for evil (“practice the servant life”).  Third, I’m to have genuine love for them (“love your enemies”).  Fourth, I’m to go easy on them (“be easy on people”).  Fifth, I’m to realize I’m not so wonderful myself (“wipe that ugly sneer off your own face”).   The key to my relationship to my enemy, according to Jesus is “kindness.”  The measure of that kindness is the kindness our Father shows to us.  “Oh Lord, let me live a life that reflects your kindness to me, even when I deal with people who aren’t very kind to me.”</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord is quite interested in how we treat people who don’t treat us well.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pharisees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A ruined dinner party Luke 7: I forgive your sins. It’s intended to be a formal dinner in the home of a community leader. However, some of the formality is waved off. After all, Simon thinks Jesus ought to be impressed and humbled that a common person like Jesus is even invited to the home [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15768" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15768" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15768" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15768" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>A ruined dinner party</p>
<p>Luke 7: I forgive your sins.</p>
<p>It’s intended to be a formal dinner in the home of a community leader.  However, some of the formality is waved off.  After all, Simon thinks Jesus ought to be impressed and humbled that a common person like Jesus is even invited to the home of a Pharisee.  Then, to Simon’s surprise this disgusting woman has managed to slip into the room.  Some servant will pay the price for that!  She ruins Simon’s nice dinner party.  Not only is he scandalized that such a person would dare enter his very house, but she’s dominating the moment.  With all this foolishness going on how can he properly impress his guests?  Jesus is obviously uncomfortable with her groveling at his feet, but he’s clearly moved by her sorrow.  Maybe Jesus doesn’t know her story?  Its then that Jesus speaks first as a teacher and then as a Savior.  This woman is overwhelmed by her sins.  Simon has missed the point because he doesn’t see himself as a sinner.  Jesus then turns his attention to this poor, grieving woman and says the greatest words she’s ever heard: “I forgive your sins.”  Simon hears blasphemy, she hears salvation.  In this story, do I best identify with Simon or with this miserable sinner?</p>
<p>Take Away: We tend to see ourselves as the “good people” in Gospel stories, maybe, though, we’re supposed to recognize ourselves as those who aren’t so good.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 12:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disciples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How much I have and how much does what I have have me Luke 8: There were also some women in their company. The ministry of Jesus is in full swing here in the North. Jesus teaches, heals, and performs other miracles. He’s now traveling from place to place leading a large band of dedicated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15771" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15771" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15771" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2831.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15771" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>How much I have and how much does what I have have me</p>
<p>Luke 8: There were also some women in their company.</p>
<p>The ministry of Jesus is in full swing here in the North.  Jesus teaches, heals, and performs other miracles.  He’s now traveling from place to place leading a large band of dedicated followers.  Of course, we see the disciples in that number but also several women are in his entourage.  These women, we’re told, have stories of deliverance to tell.  They&#8217;re also major financial supporters of this ministry.  I think it’s instructive to remember this as I read later on of Jesus telling the rich young ruler to give it all away and then follow.  Apparently, these women are, at the same time, wealthy and followers of Jesus.  They haven’t been instructed to give it all away.  As I think about this I realize that the problem isn’t how much money the young man has, but is, rather, how much the money has the young man.  These women who accompany Jesus use their resources for his work.  I think it’s important to realize the balance that’s required of us who follow the Lord.  Anything that comes between him and me needs to be cast off.  All else is to be laid at the feet of Jesus, a part of my living my life in him.</p>
<p>Take Away: Having money isn’t the big deal.  The big deal is when my money has me.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transfiguration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The other view of Jesus Luke 9: The appearance of his face changed and his clothes became blinding white. In Jesus we see God and man. He is, at the same time fully God and fully man. As he goes about his ministry he does so as man. Here’s humanity as the Lord intended. Jesus [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15774" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15774" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15774" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2839.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15774" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>The other view of Jesus</p>
<p>Luke 9: The appearance of his face changed and his clothes became blinding white.</p>
<p>In Jesus we see God and man.  He is, at the same time fully God and fully man.  As he goes about his ministry he does so as man.  Here’s humanity as the Lord intended.  Jesus trusts and obeys his Father implicitly.  He performs miracles, not by drawing from his power and authority as God, but as a man who relies on his Heavenly Father and is thus empowered to do miracles.  Then, we arrive at the Mount of Transfiguration.  For a short time it’s God in this God-man who&#8217;s evident.  There’s light such as the disciples have never seen.  Then, there’s fellowship with two spiritual giants of the past, Moses and Elijah.  The Lord God in the person of Jesus discusses the coming events in Jerusalem with two great men of the past.  I’m not saying I understand all that’s going on here.  Still, it’s my feeling that throughout most of our Lord’s ministry I see, in Jesus, humanity as was intended at Creation.  In this case though, I see God breaking through in such a way that skin and bones can hardly contain him.  The disciples experiencing this are speechless.  Now, more than 2000 years later I read of this event and struggle to find words to describe what I see happening.</p>
<p>Take Away:  The Jesus I see on the Mount of Transfiguration is the same Jesus he always is, but here, I see him in a way I haven’t seen him before.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 12:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gentle rebukes Luke 10: Martha, dear Martha, you’re fussing far too much and getting yourself worked up over nothing. When their friend Jesus arrives everyone at Martha’s house is excited. They love Jesus and they can’t think of anything better than spending some quality time with him. Mary is quite literal about that. She stays [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15817" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15817" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15817" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/11/PHOTO_20140526_182220.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15817" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Point Whitehorn Marine Reserve &#8211; near Birch Bay, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Gentle rebukes</p>
<p>Luke 10: Martha, dear Martha, you’re fussing far too much and getting yourself worked up over nothing.</p>
<p>When their friend Jesus arrives everyone at Martha’s house is excited.  They love Jesus and they can’t think of anything better than spending some quality time with him.  Mary is quite literal about that.  She stays in the room where Jesus is, hanging on his every word.  Martha, though, feels a sense of responsibility to make her guest comfortable.  In fact, she’s frustrated with her sister for not pitching in and helping with the meal Martha’s preparing in honor of Jesus and his disciples.  It’s as she busies herself with these practical matters that frustration grows to the point that having Jesus there becomes secondary to her feeling of aggravation.   I can just imagine it: many people, including Mary, are in the living room listening to Jesus when the door bursts open and there stands Martha.  Without meaning to, she interrupts Jesus, demanding that he order Mary to help her.  Our Lord responds to her with an ever so gentle rebuke.  I’m so glad that his rebuke is a gentle one because I identify with Martha.  Don’t get me wrong, I’m no cook and I’m certainly not known for having the gift of hospitality.  However, I do sometimes get so focused on the nuts and bolts of things that I miss the big picture.  Maybe you’re like that too.  Maybe you can’t give yourself fully to the worship service because the guy running the video keeps getting the words out of sync.  Maybe you spot cobwebs under a pew or notice that one light bulb in the chandler is still burned out.  If you tend to focus on stuff like that you have to join me in appreciating the fact that the rebuke Jesus gives to Martha is, at least, a mild one.</p>
<p>Take Away: Sometimes it takes a bit of self-discipline to focus on Jesus rather than some of the minor distractions of life.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
