<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bildad &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/bildad/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 04:03:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Bildad &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 01:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bildad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eliphaz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Enter the friends Job 2: They went together to Job to keep him company and comfort him. Eliphaz, Bildad, and Zophar, and later on Eliju come to visit poor, miserable Job. I think these guys get a bad rap from most people. The first three, at least, are friends of Job and when they arrive [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 999px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-54sD1GCvRm8/XxxySEFXyeI/AAAAAAABFm0/djdqYaH3UZECSayZ7w9fvcZ9wQyKPudigCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_130605.jpg" width="999" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Enter the friends<br />
Job 2: They went together to Job to keep him company and comfort him.<br />
Eliphaz, Bildad, and Zophar, and later on Eliju come to visit poor, miserable Job.  I think these guys get a bad rap from most people.  The first three, at least, are friends of Job and when they arrive and see the pitiful shape he’s in they’re shocked, speechless and broken hearted.  They can hardly bear seeing their friend like this.  When they do speak, they do so in response to Job&#8217;s complaint and the things they say are the same sort of things Job might have said to them had their places been reversed.  The debate that follows isn’t based on Job believing one thing and them believing another.  Instead it’s about Job&#8217;s insistence that things aren’t working as he and his friends always believed they worked.  They say, &#8220;Bad things don&#8217;t happen to good people, therefore, as surprising as it is, Job must be a bad person.&#8221;   Job says, &#8220;I agree that bad things don&#8217;t happen to good people, but I’ve remained faithful to God and bad things have happened to me.  Therefore, God isn&#8217;t following the rules.&#8221;  The thing about Eliphaz, Bildad, and Zophar that needs to catch our attention is that they say all the same things we’ve said at one time or another.<br />
Take Away: Do we trust God even when we don&#8217;t understand him?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 02:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bildad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Caution: big issues in play Job 8: Does God mess up? We’re still at the beginning of the debate that makes up the most of the book of Job but the battle lines are already drawn. Job doesn&#8217;t really disagree with what his friends believe; he just sees himself as an innocent victim of some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FuQ0WuksVfY/XyMd16a7KtI/AAAAAAABFps/4p_XHIjpXi8P-pGHfOWJsYt6nPsW2zrkwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_133617.jpg" width="1600" height="946" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Caution: big issues in play<br />
Job 8: Does God mess up?<br />
We’re still at the beginning of the debate that makes up the most of the book of Job but the battle lines are already drawn.  Job doesn&#8217;t really disagree with what his friends believe; he just sees himself as an innocent victim of some cosmic mistake.  Bildad&#8217;s comment that &#8220;God doesn&#8217;t mess up&#8221; is at the heart of all this.  Job and his friends believe that when a person has something bad happen to them that it’s because they’re being punished by God.  Bildad doesn&#8217;t need any other evidence of Job&#8217;s children&#8217;s sin than the fact that they all died in a tornado.  Since he can&#8217;t imagine a horrible thing like that &#8220;just happening&#8221; it has to be that God did it.  And, if God did it, he did it for a reason.  After all, everyone knows God doesn&#8217;t make mistakes.  As I’ve said, the purpose of this book to answer the question, &#8220;Will a man serve God for nothing?&#8221;  However, there are other issues in play and the majority of the book is taken up with those issues.  This is one of the big ones: how does the reality of bad things happening to good people fit a theology of a wise, loving, and all knowing God?<br />
Take Away: One result of reading this book of the Bible is that the reader has to think about big issues.  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 04:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bildad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The difference between imperfection and unrighteousness Job 25: Even the stars aren&#8217;t perfect in God&#8217;s eyes. The final statement from one of Job&#8217;s three friends (although the fourth speaker, Elihu, is still to come), is a short one and it causes us to wonder if maybe Job has argued them to a standstill. However, Bildad [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-B62TqpU8jtA/XzL3Jc98DoI/AAAAAAABFu8/IAoLwaFwxv8dM07SwZ68CtZ3yIId82CLgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190815_130912.jpg" width="1600" height="909" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Niagara Falls, NY</figcaption></figure><br />
The difference between imperfection and unrighteousness<br />
Job 25: Even the stars aren&#8217;t perfect in God&#8217;s eyes.<br />
The final statement from one of Job&#8217;s three friends (although the fourth speaker, Elihu, is still to come), is a short one and it causes us to wonder if maybe Job has argued them to a standstill.  However, Bildad does take us down a bit different track. He argues that only God is truly perfect, and next to him, everything else comes up short.  Even the stars of the sky are lacking in God&#8217;s eyes.  Since that’s true (according to Bildad) God is justified in bringing calamity on anybody, including Job.  After all, we’re all less than insects when compared to God.  That&#8217;s his argument, but it isn&#8217;t a very good one.  Job replies that he maintains his integrity even in the midst of what he sees as an unjust trial.  His argument isn’t that he’s perfect.  Rather, it’s that he’s just.  Job understands something that many modern Christians fail to grasp.  There’s a difference between imperfection and unrighteousness.  God looks, not on our performance, but on our intent.  My humanity guarantees that I’ll have a sub-par performance.  However, by God&#8217;s grace, I can live for God and maintain my integrity before him even in the worst of times.  Samuel learned this truth before anointing David King of Israel: &#8220;Man looks at the outward appearance, but the LORD looks at the heart.&#8221; (1 Samuel 16:7)  Job may be struggling with several theological concepts, but he has this one down pat.<br />
Take Away: By the grace of the Lord it is, indeed, possible to have a pure heart in his sight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
