<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>moses &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/moses/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>moses &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Follow the leader Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following. There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers. The Bible has several stories of leadership. Moses led for 40 years. David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GKWZD23715U/X3iy3gUoO3I/AAAAAAABGzw/7uTOofCwLGcYE-Eo4mTLHOuMCXf6CN9CACPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Follow the leader<br />
Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.<br />
There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers.  The Bible has several stories of leadership.  Moses led for 40 years.  David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as well.  His son Solomon led to prosperity.  Here are three things that come to mind when I read about these leaders.  First, each of these men is not only a leader, but is also a follower who accepts the authority of the Lord and spends time with him getting his marching orders.  Second, these men know how to share leadership and to train leaders.  They don&#8217;t try to do everything themselves and surround themselves with capable people to help carry the leadership load.  Third, they lead people to meaningful goals.  These men have God given visions that gives their leadership real purpose.  People believe in them and they believe the goal set out for them is worth their sacrifice.  Leaders such as these have no problem attracting followers.<br />
Take Away: God-called leaders lead with purpose in a God-chosen direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s easy to miss 1Kings 19: &#8230;a gentle and quiet whisper. After hearing the voice of God Elijah’s told that he’s to prepare himself for a personal encounter with the Lord. As Elijah sits inside the mouth of the cave things start happening outside. There’s a great wind, then an earthquake, and then a fire. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dAut5IEq-Bg/Xlf07ldTTrI/AAAAAAABD3I/slb1wuICwZ8IV-vooyCuRiR3gk9uvK5DwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4850.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Twin Dikes Park, Lake Sam Rayburn &#8211; Jasper, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
It’s easy to miss<br />
1Kings 19: &#8230;a gentle and quiet whisper.<br />
After hearing the voice of God Elijah’s told that he’s to prepare himself for a personal encounter with the Lord. As Elijah sits inside the mouth of the cave things start happening outside. There’s a great wind, then an earthquake, and then a fire. We’re told that God isn&#8217;t in these things. In other words, while they’re sent by God he doesn’t inhabit them. What the Lord has for Elijah is yet to come and it’s only after the wind, earthquake, and fire that the Lord comes to Elijah in the gentle, quiet whisper. When Moses met God on this same mountain it was the same way. There was thunder and lightning and earthquakes followed by a face to face meeting with the Lord. We see this pattern repeated throughout the Bible. For instance, on the Day of Pentecost it won’t be about the sound of wind, the tongues of fire, or other languages being spoken. Rather, it will be about God, the Holy Spirit, filling their lives with himself. As I see this repeated spiritual fact of life I’m reminded to dial back my love of the spectacular and pay more attention to the “gentle quiet whisper” of God in my life.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately it’s not the fireworks but is, instead, the personal presence of the Lord that counts in my life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
