<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>leprosy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/leprosy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 13:57:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>leprosy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leprosy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4778</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Making it harder than it really is 2Kings 5: If the prophet had asked you to do something hard and heroic, wouldn&#8217;t you have done it? It’s one of our favorite stories from 2 Kings. Naaman is the General of the Army of Aram, a nation that has a long and contentious relationship with Israel. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dINGix7ZnRI/XmzpSFi16XI/AAAAAAABEBE/bAmWHl15gbg96dzykRIGRYXdXbi6JwwWgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170425_124948.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Making it harder than it really is<br />
2Kings 5: If the prophet had asked you to do something hard and heroic, wouldn&#8217;t you have done it?<br />
It’s one of our favorite stories from 2 Kings. Naaman is the General of the Army of Aram, a nation that has a long and contentious relationship with Israel. He’s a brave and capable warrior who’s well respected in his homeland. Yet there’s one terrible affliction that not only haunts him, but is probably killing him. Naaman has leprosy. When he hears that there’s a man of God in Israel who heals people of this terrible disease he travels there, prepared to pay handsomely to be cured. To his dismay, Elisha doesn&#8217;t even meet him in person, but instead sends a mere servant with what sounds like a silly command: take seven baths in the muddy Jordan to be healed. Furious and humiliated, he turns on his heel to leave, but an old family servant gives the great general the best advice of his life. If Elisha had told him to do some great thing (for instance, pay a king&#8217;s ransom) to be healed, he’s prepared to do that. Why not, then, do some simple thing like, &#8220;take a bath and be clean.&#8221; Naaman listens and the result is a miracle of God and a happy ending to the story. I think I need to pay careful attention to Naaman’s story in my dealings with God. I’m ready to do the great thing like following some demanding course of action or making some big sacrifice as I follow the Lord. While stuff like this is sometimes a part of being a disciple more often than not it’s much less spectacular. &#8220;If you want to be my disciple follow me,&#8221; the Lord says. I respond, &#8220;You&#8217;ve got it Lord – I’ll serve you to the ends of the earth, I’ll make great sacrifices for you, I’ll be an example of total surrender to God.&#8221; The Lord says, &#8220;Tell you what, if I want you to do that stuff, I&#8217;ll tell you. For now, how about just walking with me?&#8221;<br />
Take Away: What little thing is the Lord calling you to do today?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 23:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leprosy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A tale of four lepers 2Kings 7: Let&#8217;s go tell the good news. The capital city, Samaria, is under siege and the result is a terrible famine. Things can&#8217;t get much worse there and people are being driven to horrible acts of desperation. Four lepers decide they have nothing else to lose. They’ll throw themselves [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sztFR00vLG0/Xm-mkKjd2lI/AAAAAAABECI/7B56VM49FEEsNcp8_oMcKB3zdPZCoWXIgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170530_113924.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Clifton Mill, OH</figcaption></figure><br />
A tale of four lepers<br />
2Kings 7: Let&#8217;s go tell the good news.<br />
The capital city, Samaria, is under siege and the result is a terrible famine. Things can&#8217;t get much worse there and people are being driven to horrible acts of desperation. Four lepers decide they have nothing else to lose. They’ll throw themselves on the mercy of the invaders. If they’re executed, they’ll die a quicker death than they would die by starvation anyway. When they arrive at the camp they’re surprised to find that there’s no one there! God has moved bringing terror to their camp. The mighty army has fled in panic not even knowing why they were running. The lepers have the time of their lives, eating their fill and ransacking the place. It’s at that point that one of them says to his friends, &#8220;We aren&#8217;t doing right. Back in Samaria people are starving to death while we’re enjoying all this bounty.&#8221; This real life story is also a parable for Christians everywhere. Like the lepers we’ve discovered something wonderful. Meanwhile there’s a world that desperately needs to know what we know. Like those lepers, if we aren&#8217;t telling we aren&#8217;t doing the right thing.<br />
Take Away: I found it, but I’m glad to share it with you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leprosy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uzziah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pride goes before a fall 2 Chronicles 26: Arrogant and proud, he fell. Uzziah is just a teen when he becomes king of Judah. By and large, he does a good job as king and his long reign is a good one for his nation. From the beginning he seeks God. The Lord is pleased [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--3UTAZxHqbg/XtFv5BDwYzI/AAAAAAABFJQ/fb3EHuusR5kscgOjSeJ5pksE6KTHE1EmgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20180731_153016.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing Acadia National Park and area</figcaption></figure><br />
Pride goes before a fall<br />
2 Chronicles 26: Arrogant and proud, he fell.<br />
Uzziah is just a teen when he becomes king of Judah. By and large, he does a good job as king and his long reign is a good one for his nation. From the beginning he seeks God. The Lord is pleased with him and blesses his life with successful building projects and a strong army. Then, when it seems Uzziah will be one of the rare kings who have nothing but positive things on their record something ugly happens. His successes go to Uzziah’s head. We don’t know the full story but Uzziah decides, like Saul did many generations earlier, to take over the worship activities. He takes the one role in the nation that&#8217;s denied him – going into the Temple and acting as priest of God. The legitimate priests, descendants of Aaron, try to stop Uzziah, but he ignores them. With the holy censor in hand, he refuses to hear the objections of the priests. Then, God objects, and when he objects, he can’t be ignored. The dreaded disease of leprosy breaks out on Uzziah’s hand as he holds the censor. This is God’s judgment. It’s too bad isn’t it. Uzziah comes so far and does so many things right. His downfall comes, not as a result of some big temptation or some great threat. Instead, it’s brought about by his success. When things are going right and it’s clear that God is blessing us we need to remember Uzziah. Here we see a lesson in how success can lead to failure.<br />
Take Away: The distance from impressive success to dismal failure is shorter than we might think.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
