<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>betrayal &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/betrayal/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 09:56:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>betrayal &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 18:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[betrayal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A love that never gives up Hosea 2: Then I&#8217;ll marry you for good &#8211; forever! The book of Hosea is a book of extremes. There&#8217;s nothing mundane or middle of the road here as everything is at one end or the other end of the spectrum. Here we see powerful love and painful betrayal. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m7BCXoIFWM8/YNOLdVDkodI/AAAAAAABKkE/0fiOlmaiTbIV3f8V8UJkUsSYrWNpasIYwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-88.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; Eiffel Tower</figcaption></figure><br />
A love that never gives up<br />
Hosea 2: Then I&#8217;ll marry you for good &#8211; forever!<br />
The book of Hosea is a book of extremes.  There&#8217;s nothing mundane or middle of the road here as everything is at one end or the other end of the spectrum.  Here we see powerful love and painful betrayal.  We see the beauty of tender, marital sex and we also see the brutal, cheapening side of sex in the market place.  In one place we see the anger of God as he declares the coming destruction as a result of their sin but we also see God&#8217;s mercy as he promises restoration.  There&#8217;s nothing in Hosea that lends itself to a relaxing late night read before sleep.  This book is an emotional rollercoaster.  God&#8217;s people have betrayed him and, because of that betrayal he&#8217;s rejected them, kicking them out.  Israel has committed spiritual adultery against God and God has issued a decree of divorce against them.  Then as we&#8217;re emotionally ready to close the book on this relationship the tone of the Lord changes.  He&#8217;s kicked them out and declared his anger with them and judgment on them.   Just as I get my mind around that the landscape suddenly changes.  The Lord declares his intentions to clean them up, to romance them again and ultimately to reinstate his marriage to them.  The sweep of all this is stunning and I realize I&#8217;m reading about a love that never gives up.  God is truly the God of Second Chances.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 09:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Absalom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[betrayal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Simply doing the right thing 2 Samuel 15: Absalom&#8230;stole the hearts of everyone in Israel. Permitted back into Israel and King David&#8217;s presence should have humbled Absalom. He should be grateful for the kindness of his father in restoring him after had murdered one of his own brothers. It doesn&#8217;t work that way though. Absalom [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-8RliLZDcIs0/Xhj6aw5eDGI/AAAAAAABDJs/98UC0zx7FwE0lgQPOxUBsOMoWRv-k1rnwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129949.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Simply doing the right thing<br />
2 Samuel 15: Absalom&#8230;stole the hearts of everyone in Israel.<br />
Permitted back into Israel and King David&#8217;s presence should have humbled Absalom. He should be grateful for the kindness of his father in restoring him after had murdered one of his own brothers. It doesn&#8217;t work that way though. Absalom wants more. To be exact, he wants the throne of Israel. With that in mind, he implements a patient plan. First, he begins to play the part of the king, making a regal procession wherever he goes. Then, he sets up shop at the city gate, the place where the community leaders meet to deal with issues under their jurisdiction. Absalom plays the part of the kind, caring friend to all who come. He suggests, ever so gently, that his father, the King, doesn’t care about the common man enough to grant justice. The impact isn&#8217;t immediate, but over time Absalom rises in popularity to the point that he can challenge his father for the throne of Israel. It shouldn&#8217;t be this way. Absalom ought to be the greatest and most committed supporter of David. Instead, he sets himself up to be his father&#8217;s greatest enemy. Sadly, this is how life is sometimes. We befriend people, forgive them, and make ourselves vulnerable to them and then they let us down. It happened to David, and, with Judas, it happened to Jesus too. Frankly, I can&#8217;t control what other people do, right or wrong. All I can do is the right thing and demonstrate the gentleness and mercy of God in my life. It would be better if the result of that were blessed and solid relationships. Sometimes, though, I have to settle for knowing that the Lord is pleased with me for trying. That, of course, is extremely valuable in itself.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes we do the right thing and the results are everything we hoped for. Other times, it doesn’t work out, but there’s still great value in doing the right thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 09:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Absalom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[betrayal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outsiders and insiders 2 Samuel 15: Where my master is, that&#8217;s where I&#8217;ll be &#8212; whether it means life or death. Absalom has patiently prepared to betray his father, King David, and he decides the time has come to act. With the skill of a big business publicist he orchestrates things to make it appear [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zMqoLgsi2VM/XhqBHXBzNkI/AAAAAAABDKQ/q6wrdDpip0g0q_t9dpt2_07-uIraOhl0QCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4437.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Outsiders and insiders<br />
2 Samuel 15: Where my master is, that&#8217;s where I&#8217;ll be &#8212; whether it means life or death.<br />
Absalom has patiently prepared to betray his father, King David, and he decides the time has come to act. With the skill of a big business publicist he orchestrates things to make it appear that the public and the leaders of Israel have made him king. Earlier, David could have easily stopped all this. In fact, he could have kept Absalom in exile in the first place. Instead, David has believed the best in Absalom and turned a blind eye to his scheming. When word of the power grab reaches David he immediately retreats, believing that Absalom has the upper hand. It’s as he flees Jerusalem that we hear the pledge Ittai makes to David. Ittai is from the city of Gath, which means he’s a Philistine. Apparently, he’s deserted his native land to follow David. When David sees him he tells him to go home to Gath, but Ittai will have none of it. He’s committed to David and pledges to follow him even to death. This warrior&#8217;s words to David shine in the darkness of an otherwise bleak day. In a spiritual view of things, I am a Philistine, an outsider in the family of God. Like Ittai, the King, himself, has made me welcome. And like Ittai, I cast my lot with my King, all the way, life or death.<br />
Take Away: What an honor it is for an outsider to be invited to the inside by none other than the King, himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
