<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Christmas &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/christmas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:16:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Christmas &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-187/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 16:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surprise, surprise, surprise! Isaiah 64: Since before time began no one has ever imagined&#8230;a God like you. I know there’s much (and that’s too mild a word) about God that’s beyond my imagination. However, it isn&#8217;t the vastness of God that’s on Isaiah&#8217;s mind here. Isaiah’s talking about what he does know. The Almighty has [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7DBui6HdajQ/YCMxVSHC0UI/AAAAAAABIek/MOTGQTFsHEA_Aik48iZMy6cq2unecOV8QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5133625.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Blue Ridge Parkway &#8211; Virginia</figcaption></figure><br />
Surprise, surprise, surprise!<br />
Isaiah 64: Since before time began no one has ever imagined&#8230;a God like you.<br />
I know there’s much (and that’s too mild a word) about God that’s beyond my imagination.  However, it isn&#8217;t the vastness of God that’s on Isaiah&#8217;s mind here.  Isaiah’s talking about what he does know.  The Almighty has revealed his intentions concerning his broken people and their enemies.  Isaiah isn&#8217;t saying &#8220;no one knows what God’s going to do.&#8221; Instead, he’s saying &#8220;here&#8217;s what God’s about to do and it’s something no one has ever before imagined.&#8221;  The Lord is about to move in their lives bringing restoration to them.  Everything’s going to change as the Lord works in a never-seen-before way on their behalf.  His plans aren&#8217;t a secret; they’re being announced ahead of time.  This verse reminds me of the passage from the New Testament that’s based on Isaiah&#8217;s words here.  In 1 Corinthians 2:9 Paul says: &#8220;No eye has seen, no ear has heard, no mind has conceived what God has prepared for those who love him.&#8221;  A lot of folks stop right there, thinking Paul’s talking about the future and unknowable plans of God.  However, they need to go right on reading.  Paul continues with: &#8220;but God has revealed it to us by his Spirit.&#8221;  Paul’s saying the very same thing as Isaiah.  No one could ever guess ahead of time how God is going to redeem his people, and now that we know it we stand amazed.  From our point of view, who could ever imagine that a baby born in a barn can save the world?  But God, through his angelic messenger right up front announces that that’s exactly what’s going to happen.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s wonderful plan of salvation is both known by us and amazing to us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-193/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A given life Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say. I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus. The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones. Beyond those [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7ly2NAezS9s/YCrg7H5D4oI/AAAAAAABImc/oAPwqqgH9ngaXn1QXNFEwMtEI9o-rhQhACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034534.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
A given life<br />
Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say.<br />
I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus.  The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones.  Beyond those material things, though, the important thing is that they bring themselves.  In this passage Isaiah reminds me that God made it all and he owns it all.  He&#8217;s not depending on me to bring him gold, frankincense, and myrrh or anything else for that matter.  He is, though, counting on me to bring him my reverent obedience.  I believe a person ought to practice their faith in Christ in practical ways, including being a good steward of all that has been placed in his or her hands.  However, the offering I give is simply an outflow of a given life.  That&#8217;s a gift that’s guaranteed to please the Lord.<br />
Take Away: Our offerings are an outflow of our given lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 11:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living in the present Matthew 6: Give your entire attention to what God is doing right now. I don’t think there’s anything wrong with anticipation. Part of the joy of Christmas is the “longing with hope” aspect of it that we highlight on the first Sunday of Advent each year. Still, there’s a danger of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15650" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15650" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15650" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029293.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15650" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure>
<p>Living in the present</p>
<p>Matthew 6: Give your entire attention to what God is doing right now.</p>
<p>I don’t think there’s anything wrong with anticipation.  Part of the joy of Christmas is the “longing with hope” aspect of it that we highlight on the first Sunday of Advent each year.  Still, there’s a danger of so looking forward to something in the future that we forget to live in the present.  Life isn’t all about tomorrow, for good or bad.  Life is lived in the present.  It has no rewind or fast forward buttons.  In this passage Jesus reminds us that God is with us “right now.”  We remember wonderful blessings in the past and appreciate what the Lord did for us then.  We also look to the future with confidence in faith that the same good, gracious God will be with us in that day.  Still, it’s right now that’s most under my control.  Not that I control the circumstances of right now, but I have some say about how I will live in those circumstances.  So, one thing I gain from this passage is the reminder to live in this present moment; to appreciate the good things and to trust God with the not-so-good things.  The other thing that comes to mind is the calm, certain assurance that God is, indeed, doing something “right now.”  I may be praying for a great revival to come to my church, longing for that day to come.  I may be looking forward to some major life event like the birth of a grandchild or some special anniversary.  However, Jesus tells me that God is also doing things right here and right now.  He’s working in my life, walking with me in these ordinary days of life.  After all, the great mystery of Christmas is the incarnation, Emmanuel, God with us.</p>
<p>Take Away: I need to be more aware of the blessings of life right now and not always focusing on some future blessing.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merry Christmas…maybe Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child. John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16394" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16394" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16394" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16394" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Merry Christmas…maybe</p>
<p>Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child.</p>
<p>John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written to be read by first century Christians I lean toward understandings of it that keep their perspective in mind. Also, there’s such a strong parallel to the story of the birth of Christ that I tend to think that John’s using that well known story to illustrate something more. Mary, the most blessed of women, gives birth to the Son of God. Immediately, Satan tries to have him killed but, being warned in a dream, his earthly father, Joseph, takes them and flees to the desert, Egypt. Throughout his ministry there’s a war for the hearts of men, women, boys, and girls. Ultimately, though, Satan&#8217;s defeated as Jesus goes to the cross, winning the ultimate victory for all who will come to him. It all fits, kind of. The question for Bible scholars is “What does it illustrate?” Most say that the woman represents the Church and that the battle represents the war waged by the enemy of our souls in an attempt to defeat the Church. If that’s right the message here is one of divine protection and ultimate victory. Even readers like me, in spite of my struggles in understanding the passage, can conclude that, whatever the exact meaning here, God will protect his people and that ultimately, in Christ, victory is ours. I know I don’t get everything that’s going on here, but that’s a pretty good place to start.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to have a firm grasp on the fact of the Lord’s provision for, and protection of, us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
