<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>righteousness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/righteousness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 16:26:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>righteousness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-107/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 03:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s response to my need Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out. Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart. In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away. His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for. Immediately, the Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Pq33Oxxh4nc/X7sbikt2k1I/AAAAAAABHq4/BwxFxow0j_o3OkzzULmD5QIHj1d0iY0fgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B5-46-04%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s response to my need<br />
Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.<br />
Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart.  In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away.  His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for.  Immediately, the Lord takes action to cleanse him of his sin.  Since this is a vision, there’s a lot of symbolism here.  We have an altar of sacrifice with fire, which speaks to us of surrender and purification.  There’s Isaiah’s direct reference to his “unclean lips” which refer to, not just a tendency to say the wrong thing, but his whole life, which he sees as speaking in ways that reflect a deep level of spiritual need.  The thrilling thing is how the Lord responds to Isaiah’s cry of repentance.  A heavenly being touches his lips with the burning coal from the altar declaring the wonderful truth that his sin is “wiped out” and his guilt is gone.  Listen, I don’t have to pull some surprising insight out of this passage.  In fact, it’s surprising enough just as it is.  When I realize the purity of God and see my own deep failure…when I confess it, throwing myself on the mercy God…when I do that, I place myself in the only place where the Lord can help me.  I can’t forgive my own sin and I can’t purify my own life, but when I “repent and turn” he immediately does for me what I can never do for myself.  There’s no better word from the Lord than “gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.”<br />
Take Away: As I confess my need the Lord does for me what I can never do for myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-131/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To do list Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right. The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one. Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda. Who can survive such a purging? How does a person prepare for it? Isaiah has a list for all who will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6lieSoE49o/X9pXgBBGPBI/AAAAAAABH48/E9zKMFyWXN8_ama67n-b-yXf2dZap3JqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5291839.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Buffalo River, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
To do list<br />
Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right.<br />
The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one.  Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda.  Who can survive such a purging?  How does a person prepare for it?  Isaiah has a list for all who will listen: &#8220;live right, speak the truth, despise exploitation, refuse bribes, reject violence, and avoid evil amusements.&#8221;  This, he says, is the way through the storm, the way to stability and satisfaction.  I know that some things about God are complicated and it takes a lifetime of serious study and application to master them.  However, some things are pretty straight forward and this list is an example of that.  The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;  That is, we can drop the excuses and commit ourselves to, as best we can, doing the things we know we should do.  That isn&#8217;t all there is to it, but it’s a pretty good start.  Soon enough we&#8217;ll realize that our best isn&#8217;t good enough, but it does turn us in the right direction and with that done, we&#8217;ll find ourselves aligned with God&#8217;s grace which is freely extended to us.<br />
Take Away: The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-180/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 15:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calvary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The battle of the ages Isaiah 59: So he did it himself, took on the work of Salvation. The Lord God looks out to the horizon and sees the ugly advance of sin. Before him is a sea of lies and hate and evil and death. He looks to his right and left and sees [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Zi0fejD3Ez8/YBnGSbA-lqI/AAAAAAABIZY/YWmb-PFplVoJL64UVCxu75JOusT8_iFIQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/GSMNP-Cades-Cove%2B5-23-2008%2B9-46-50%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2008 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; Cades Cove &#8211; Abrams Falls</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The battle of the ages<br />
Isaiah 59: So he did it himself, took on the work of Salvation.<br />
The Lord God looks out to the horizon and sees the ugly advance of sin.  Before him is a sea of lies and hate and evil and death.  He looks to his right and left and sees no one who can raise the standard of righteousness.  He comes to a decision.  He, himself, puts on armor for battle: Salvation, Judgment, and Passion. There’s no one else who can take on the rising tide of evil; all others are tainted and overrun by this enemy. He, alone, will go into the battle with Righteousness as his strength. Two millennia ago that battle took place, not in the heart of God’s prophet but at a place called Calvary. There, God, the Son, does what no one else can do. On that old rugged cross the battle for righteousness is fought and won. With the fate of humanity in the balance this hero enters the conflict and defeats the enemy once and for all.<br />
Take Away: Jesus fought and won the battle for humanity on the old rugged cross.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-65/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 17:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confrontation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Walking with God against the flow Jeremiah 1: You&#8217;re a one-man defense system against this culture. Several times in my journeys I’ve had the misfortune of driving along the highway, minding my own business, and coming up on fresh skunk road kill. The stench lingers in the car even after the site of the demise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-32ZhhtJ1LZg/YDLFAZKuZpI/AAAAAAABIsY/f9FCjPFMXpcgKZxhKatY8G050ZFPXt_RACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PB284408.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Campfire</figcaption></figure><br />
Walking with God against the flow<br />
Jeremiah 1: You&#8217;re a one-man defense system against this culture.<br />
Several times in my journeys I’ve had the misfortune of driving along the highway, minding my own business, and coming up on fresh skunk road kill.  The stench lingers in the car even after the site of the demise of the skunk is behind me.  In commissioning Jeremiah to his life&#8217;s work, the Lord says that the culture of his nation stinks.  God’s sick of it and is going to bring in enemies of theirs from the north to do a thorough cleaning.  Jeremiah&#8217;s job is to prepare the way for that event by mounting an offense against that rotten culture.  From the beginning it’s made clear to him that he’ll operate counter to the prevailing culture of that day.  He&#8217;s going to be the focal point of some big explosions and his only hope of surviving them is that God’s going to make him rough and tough, as &#8220;solid as a concrete wall.&#8221;  Jeremiah&#8217;s ministry is to be one of confrontation.  Frankly, I doubt that the culture of my nation is any better than was that of Jeremiah&#8217;s.  If God was sick of the stench of that culture then he must be pretty tired of that of our day too.  Who knows?  Right now God might be rising up a new Jeremiah.  Whether or not that&#8217;s so, I do understand this: we believers have to do more than just go with the flow and feel pleased that we&#8217;re keeping our heads above water.  We need to take a stand for righteousness in our homes and in other places where we have influence.  Can God count on me to be a &#8220;one-man defense system&#8221; at least in those areas?<br />
Take Away: Sometimes Christians have to take a stand for righteousness, even if that stand isn’t well accepted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-36/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mark of God’s people Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark. In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem. The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there. The sin is outrageous and disgusting. Anyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TruL9SmdBfo/YI8fidWJRVI/AAAAAAABKC8/Il7o9gOsHrc3t3gLmi5P1b0FrYDED1XqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-28-28%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The mark of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark.<br />
In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem.  The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there.  The sin is outrageous and disgusting.  Anyone who loves the Lord and worships him would be broken hearted to see their precious Temple desecrated in this way.  Then, Ezekiel sees a man on a mission.  He&#8217;s to walk the streets of Jerusalem, putting a mark on the foreheads of those who are distressed at the sin of their nation.  All others will be wiped out.  I find it interesting that in Revelation we find the &#8220;mark of the beast.&#8221;  In that case, it&#8217;s those who refuse the mark who are saved.  Here in Ezekiel, we see the reverse.  It is those with the mark who are spared from the judgment that comes.  Comparing the two &#8220;marks&#8221; ought to cause some who subscribe to a &#8220;Left Behind&#8221; brand theology to pause and consider!  I think of the mark of Ezekiel as the &#8220;mark of caring.&#8221;  You see, God cares about people and righteousness and holiness.  He&#8217;s always on the lookout for people who&#8217;ll join him in that concern.  If that fellow with the writing kit passed by my life today I wonder if I would receive that mark.<br />
Take Away: The sin of our society should break our hearts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-45/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Key people Ezekiel 22: I looked for someone to&#8230;stand in the gap to protect this land. The Lord&#8217;s on the lookout for people who&#8217;ll take a stand for righteousness. The reason he seeks such people is not so churches can build nicer buildings or even so that more people will attend their services. God knows [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c2vV7SiBzrM/YJw0bbo9DiI/AAAAAAABKJw/hD08AbNGcGoG-b3c_ZFlsdVLZXHUj0wJgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2BCamping%2BTrip%2B-%2BGoose%2BIsland%2Band%2BVicinity%2B12-2-2010%2B11-47-14%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Key people<br />
Ezekiel 22: I looked for someone to&#8230;stand in the gap to protect this land.<br />
The Lord&#8217;s on the lookout for people who&#8217;ll take a stand for righteousness.  The reason he seeks such people is not so churches can build nicer buildings or even so that more people will attend their services.  God knows it&#8217;s &#8220;repent or perish.&#8221;  When a nation stubbornly disregards righteousness and persists in following a God-ignoring road that nation is in serious jeopardy.  We&#8217;re not talking about such a nation getting a slap on the wrist for being &#8220;bad.&#8221;  This is a life and death situation.  The Lord says that when he sees a nation on this road he desperately seeks people who&#8217;ll stand up for what&#8217;s right.  He doesn&#8217;t want to destroy that nation.  Instead, he wants to redeem it and make its people into a people his very own.  With that in mind, he looks everywhere for some key person in some key situation who&#8217;ll declare their loyalty to him and his ways.  In Ezekiel&#8217;s day that person is never found.  I may not be able to influence nations for righteousness, but maybe I can influence someone.  With that in mind I step into the gap to stand for God even as I pray that that “big player” will step up to stand in the gap for my nation.<br />
Take Away: “Here I am, send me.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nahum</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nahum-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nahum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At just the right time God will speak Nahum 1: And God has something to say about all this. Things don’t look good for God’s purposes in the world. A wicked nation is doing very well. Their capitol city sits at the heart of incredible power and evil. God’s people are small in number and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oKutddGQSJA/YRVzJFGiPbI/AAAAAAABLBY/jWzmwE3k8kQ3kkZ__gY6B-3SHb56_QVtACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-048.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains and vicinity &#8211; &#8220;Dry Falls&#8221; &#8211; Cullasaja Gorge</figcaption></figure><br />
At just the right time God will speak<br />
Nahum 1: And God has something to say about all this.<br />
Things don’t look good for God’s purposes in the world.  A wicked nation is doing very well.  Their capitol city sits at the heart of incredible power and evil.  God’s people are small in number and spirit.  Is this the end of it all?  Will sin and evil win the day?  Nahum calls for calm as he declares good news for all those who love that which is good.  Nineveh appears to be on top of the world, but “God has something to say about all this.”  The “top of the world” position of that wicked city is a mere anthill in the eyes of God and when the Almighty acts, even that anthill will be “mowed down flat.”  Through the centuries there have been many times when it seemed this world was out of God’s control and that the cause of righteousness was lost.  There have been times when God’s people were speechless in the face of overwhelming sin.  That’s okay.  You see, even when we’re at a loss as to what to do or say, at just the right time, God will speak.  What appears to us to be overwhelming circumstances is a mere anthill to the Lord.  My mission in such times is, first, to keep trusting in him even when it seems evil has the upper hand and second, if he can use me, to be a part of God’s remedy for a sin-sick world.<br />
Take Away: At just the right time the Lord will speak.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zephaniah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zephaniah-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 11:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zephaniah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[values]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We need to make up our minds Zephaniah 2: You’re a nation without a clue about what it wants. The prophet describes a coming day of God’s Judgment. The Lord&#8217;s about to demand an accounting from them and it’s clear that they aren’t ready for such a confrontation. Zephaniah tells people that they need to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15504" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15504" style="width: 768px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15504 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279144.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15504" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Burgess Falls State Park, TN</figcaption></figure>
<p>We need to make up our minds<br />
Zephaniah 2: You’re a nation without a clue about what it wants.<br />
The prophet describes a coming day of God’s Judgment. The Lord&#8217;s about to demand an accounting from them and it’s clear that they aren’t ready for such a confrontation. Zephaniah tells people that they need to get their act together. They need to stop letting other nations be their primary influence and they need to start living as people who are going to face God. They’ve lost their bearings and are now at the mercy of whatever fad happens to come along. For a little known, mostly ignored, minor book of the Bible, Zephaniah has pretty much nailed my society. My nation has lost its bearings. It doesn’t want all those “Christian hang ups” but it can’t decide what values are worth pursuing. Instead, we’ve become a shallow people, more concerned about being politically correct than we are with being morally righteous. Zephaniah’s warning of Judgment Day needs to be heard here and now. Otherwise, our story is likely to end like that of clueless Judah.<br />
Take Away: Zephaniah’s warning needs to be heard here and now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zephaniah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zephaniah-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 11:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zephaniah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Standing alone if necessary Zephaniah 2: Seek God, all you quietly disciplined people. The nation the prophet addresses is filled with sinful, guilty people. However, there&#8217;s another, much smaller group. Zephaniah knows that there&#8217;s a minority that has humbled themselves before the Lord. They&#8217;ve been meek when chastised by God and have quietly accepted his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15506" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15506" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15506 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049177.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15506" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Along Natchez Trace &#8211; Fall Hollow</figcaption></figure>
<p>Standing alone if necessary<br />
Zephaniah 2: Seek God, all you quietly disciplined people.<br />
The nation the prophet addresses is filled with sinful, guilty people. However, there&#8217;s another, much smaller group. Zephaniah knows that there&#8217;s a minority that has humbled themselves before the Lord. They&#8217;ve been meek when chastised by God and have quietly accepted his discipline. They&#8217;ve been an oasis of justice in an unjust land. Now, Zephaniah says, the Lord is about to bring an end to all the rebellion. God’s man advises those who have swam against the tide to focus their attention on the Lord and center their lives on doing the right thing even if they’re alone in doing it. In this day, I can’t force everyone to do the right thing but that doesn’t stop me from righteous living. I want to influence everyone I can for Christ, but whether or not I&#8217;m successful in that, I can commit myself to walk in the ways of the Lord. Zephaniah is certain that the “Day of God’s anger” is coming but he’s also convinced that there is a way of living that prepares us for that sure day.<br />
Take Away: As Joshua of old says: “As for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zephaniah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zephaniah-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 11:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zephaniah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We don’t clean house to punish dust Zephaniah 3: I’ll leave a core of people among you. The prophet first turns his attention to other nations surrounding Judah. They’re not the chosen people, but they’ve refused the light they’ve been given. Because of that, the Day of Judgment that is such a driving force in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15508" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15508" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15508 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/PA049187.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15508" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Along Natchez Trace &#8211; Fall Hollow</figcaption></figure>
<p>We don’t clean house to punish dust<br />
Zephaniah 3: I’ll leave a core of people among you.<br />
The prophet first turns his attention to other nations surrounding Judah. They’re not the chosen people, but they’ve refused the light they’ve been given. Because of that, the Day of Judgment that is such a driving force in Zephaniah’s preaching is coming to them too. When I read of Judgment in the Old Testament I sometimes come away thinking of God as punishing those who reject him. However, this passage takes me in a different direction. Zephaniah says that when God&#8217;s finished, he’ll leave a core of people who “will not do wrong.” If a person cleans house, wiping everything clean, they aren’t punishing the dust. Instead, they&#8217;re just cleaning things up like they ought to be. Through his prophets, the Lord cautions, warns, and pleads with people to repent and align themselves with his purpose for their lives. In the end, the Judgment that falls on those who refuse this patient call of the Lord is the result of their own refusal to connect to their Creator. I know that there’s a place to think about an angry God but I’m reminded today that a God who loves righteousness is bound by his own nature to take action when his creatures reject his righteousness. When the Lord&#8217;s finished, things will be drastically different and one of those changes will be that we&#8217;ll see core of previously unnoticed people still standing. “Blessed are the poor in spirit for theirs is the Kingdom of Heaven.”<br />
Take Away: A God who loves righteous must, ultimately, deal decisively with sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
