<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>seeing God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/seeing-god/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:56:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>seeing God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeing God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stillness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Questions answered Habakkuk 2: God is in his holy Temple! Quiet everyone – a holy silence. Listen! Chapter two is mostly a listing of the sins of Babylon. The Lord may intend to use this godless nation in his dealings with Judah but that doesn’t mean its despicable evil will be overlooked. As a series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15489" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15489" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15489 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15489" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Questions answered<br />
Habakkuk 2: God is in his holy Temple! Quiet everyone – a holy silence. Listen!<br />
Chapter two is mostly a listing of the sins of Babylon. The Lord may intend to use this godless nation in his dealings with Judah but that doesn’t mean its despicable evil will be overlooked. As a series of “Who do you think you are?” judgments is being listed, the prophet suddenly has a vision of God. Immediately, the prophet calls for “holy silence.” This isn’t the time to preach sermons of condemnation. The only thing a human being can do at this point is to bow in silence before the Lord. This, I think is God’s second answer to Habakkuk. The prophet has asked how a holy God can use a sinful nation to punish Judah. One answer is that God is well aware of the sin of Babylon and that he will decisively deal with it. The other answer is heard as the Almighty reveals himself to Habakkuk. This is similar to what happens in the Book of Job. Job has asked for an audience with God that he might plead his case. However, when God appears, Job is speechless and all he can do is bow in worship and adoration. When I see God my questions are answered. My need is not for the Lord to explain to me everything I think I want to know. The need in my life is a fresh vision of God.<br />
Take Away: All our questions are answered when we genuinely experience the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on the Psalms</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-the-psalms-53/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Psalms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeing God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Helping God be God Psalm 73: I nearly missed it&#8230;I was looking the other way, looking up to the people. Asaph is one of David&#8217;s choir directors and the writer of eleven of the psalms. The Bible also mentions the &#8220;sons of Asaph.&#8221; These are probably people who are disciples of this talented worship leader. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_16550" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16550" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-scaled.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="540" class="size-large wp-image-16550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-1536x864.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/09/20221015_171235-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16550" class="wp-caption-text">2022 &#8211; Pontcysyllte Aqueduct, Wales</figcaption></figure><br />
Helping God be God<br />
Psalm 73: I nearly missed it&#8230;I was looking the other way, looking up to the people.<br />
Asaph is one of David&#8217;s choir directors and the writer of eleven of the psalms.  The Bible also mentions the &#8220;sons of Asaph.&#8221;  These are probably people who are disciples of this talented worship leader.  Asaph and David are kindred spirits and the themes of their psalms are similar.  In this song Asaph declares the goodness of God and talks about how the Lord patiently led him even when he was &#8220;totally ignorant&#8221; of what was going on.  It’s the opening part of this psalm, though, that gets my attention today.  He declares the goodness of God but then confesses that he nearly missed seeing that goodness.  Why?  He was too busy looking at people to see God.  Asaph&#8217;s attention was drawn to the seeming success of others, then, as he considered their success he saw that some were wicked people and he began to question God as to how it could be that wicked people enjoy such success.  The truth is that I can fail to see God because I’m enamored with the success of others.  I can also fail to see him because I am too busy telling him what I think he should do.  In trying to help God out I place myself in danger of losing sight of him altogether.  I need to remember who God is and that he can handle the inconsistencies of life.  My main job is to keep my eyes on him and live in obedience to him.  It’s not my job to point out things I think he may have overlooked.<br />
Take Away: Always remember that the Lord can handle the seeming inconsistencies of life – we can leave such things in his hands and keep our eyes on him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
