<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>personal responsibility &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/personal-responsibility/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 02:35:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>personal responsibility &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-179/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 15:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Admitting personal failure Isaiah 59: There&#8217;s nothing wrong with God; the wrong is in you. Ever since Adam blamed Eve, and in reality, blamed God, people have tried to pass the buck for their sin. &#8220;God’s too strict&#8221; or &#8220;the temptation is too great&#8221; or some other lame excuse is used as a defense for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vGIx3Q6GAtU/YBhLIZHubpI/AAAAAAABIY4/cZU9cMnom_gFHFYdUL-eMy53xvjdyXx-QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/GSMNP-Cades-Cove%2B5-23-2008%2B9-47-48%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2008 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; Cades Cove &#8211; Abrams Falls</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Admitting personal failure<br />
Isaiah 59: There&#8217;s nothing wrong with God; the wrong is in you.<br />
Ever since Adam blamed Eve, and in reality, blamed God, people have tried to pass the buck for their sin.  &#8220;God’s too strict&#8221; or &#8220;the temptation is too great&#8221; or some other lame excuse is used as a defense for spiritual failure.  As a pastor I&#8217;ve probably heard more than most.  I immediately think of lines like: &#8220;I was absent from church for two weeks and no one called me&#8221; or &#8220;the church just isn&#8217;t as spiritual as it ought to be.&#8221;  Isaiah has heard enough and he reacts especially to excuses that place the blame for spiritual failure on the Lord.  He tells his people that the thing that has come between them and God is none other than themselves.  It’s their sin that has messed things up and until they admit that things are only going to get worse.  Listen, I know that the church has a responsibility to reach out to people; even people who know better than what they’re doing.   The church is accountable before God when it fails along this line.  However, Isaiah&#8217;s message places the blame for personal failure directly on the shoulders of the one who willfully sins against God.  Don&#8217;t blame God, the church, your spouse, your boss, or your friends for your sin.  Take responsibility for your own actions, confess, and make it right.   You&#8217;ll find that the grace of God is sufficient and that brings a whole lot more peace than making excuses does!<br />
Take Away: Take responsibility and make things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-119/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johanan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zedekiah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking into the future Jeremiah 43: He&#8217;ll set up his throne on the very stones I&#8217;ve had buried here. I don&#8217;t believe that the future is mapped out in detail because I firmly believe God has given us the gift, and responsibility, of free will. However, I certainly believe that some things about the future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PLe2riXuIPU/YHhuyk9OIEI/AAAAAAABJ2g/9riyD9YTYJoWDuPSC_gHDliyy08hQFtCACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PB285810.JPG" width="1600" height="1280" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Brazos Bend State Park &#8211; TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Looking into the future<br />
Jeremiah 43: He&#8217;ll set up his throne on the very stones I&#8217;ve had buried here.<br />
I don&#8217;t believe that the future is mapped out in detail because I firmly believe God has given us the gift, and responsibility, of free will.  However, I certainly believe that some things about the future are preordained.  It isn&#8217;t that the Lord has looked into the future and seen things happening; it&#8217;s just that he&#8217;s Sovereign and he&#8217;s declared he&#8217;s going to bring certain things to pass.  When the Almighty says he&#8217;s going to do something, that&#8217;s just as sure as if it already happened.  In this passage we find Jeremiah in Egypt.  I&#8217;m not sure why Johanan and the others brought him along.  Apparently, it&#8217;s similar to why King Zedekiah kept Jeremiah locked up but couldn&#8217;t resist going to him for the latest word from the Lord.  Jeremiah&#8217;s message to them is unwavering.  The Lord said, &#8220;Don&#8217;t go to Egypt&#8221; and they&#8217;ve gone to Egypt anyway.  The Lord said, &#8220;If you go to Egypt you&#8217;ll find the death and destruction you&#8217;re fleeing.&#8221;  Now, Jeremiah drives that point home by having some stones laid along the walkway that leads to one of Pharaoh&#8217;s palaces.  He says that the day&#8217;s coming when King Nebuchadnezzar of Babylon will sit his throne right on top of those stones as he claims the gem of Egypt for Babylon.  Again, I don&#8217;t see every detail of the future as predetermined.  Still, there&#8217;s plenty that God has already declared to be certain.  For instance, Jesus is coming back, Judgment day is sure, and everyone will spend forever somewhere.  I have the freedom to prepare for those certainties or not, as my future isn’t predetermined.  By the grace of God that much is up to me and my eternity hangs in the balance based on that decision.<br />
Take Away: Certain things about the future are sure but how I respond to the grace of God in preparing for that future he leaves to me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/2011/11/11/devotional-on-exodus-16/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cooperating with God Exodus 12: The Israelites then went and did what God had commanded Moses and Aaron. They did it all. Emancipation day is coming. After generations of slavery God is about to keep his promise to “rescue and redeem” them from the bondage of Egypt. The deciding event will be one of fearsome [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-o2ZiH0rHezE/XP1a2rQTHyI/AAAAAAAA8G0/7B0_oOeoUTETGblJS0r6pPLly10SS6CDQCKgBGAs/s1600/P5029262.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
Cooperating with God<br />
Exodus 12: The Israelites then went and did what God had commanded Moses and Aaron.  They did it all.<br />
Emancipation day is coming.  After generations of slavery God is about to keep his promise to “rescue and redeem” them from the bondage of Egypt.  The deciding event will be one of fearsome judgment.  Death is coming.  However, death will not visit every home in the land.  The Israelites must to follow explicit instructions if they’re to escape the terrible events of that night.  A lamb is to be slaughtered, cooked, and eaten.  Some of the blood, mixed with hyssop is to be smeared on the door posts of their homes.  As a result, the death angel will “pass over” their dwellings.  They listen and obey – “they did it all.”  In so doing they become a part on their own deliverance.  Most of what needs to be done is accomplished by the Lord but they must cooperate by taking this action.  Well, you know where this is going by now.  God has acted to deliver me from slavery to freedom.  He has done the vast majority of what must be done.  Still, he has instructions for me to follow.  I must respond by cooperating with the Almighty if his perfect will is to be accomplished in my life.<br />
Take Away: How can I best cooperate with God today?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Leviticus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-leviticus-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 02:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Leviticus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fan the flames Leviticus 6: Keep the fire burning on the Altar continuously. It must not go out. Instructions for worship continue, and will throughout the book. The command to keep the Altar fire burning stands out. The fire is representative of God. It was fire that Moses encountered in the desert; it’s a pillar [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zy02c15CKRQ/XSetUHjybLI/AAAAAAAA9SM/fg2Q6tQbsEcohpDZnvzLZRl62QGLAA2SgCKgBGAs/s1600/PB284409.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="aligncenter size-large" /><br />
Fan the flames<br />
Leviticus 6: Keep the fire burning on the Altar continuously.  It must not go out.<br />
Instructions for worship continue, and will throughout the book.  The command to keep the Altar fire burning stands out.  The fire is representative of God.  It was fire that Moses encountered in the desert; it’s a pillar of fire that leads them at night.  The fire of the Altar also symbolizes the presence and work of Jehovah in their midst.  Because of that, the command is that it never be allowed to go out.  The application is pretty easy to understand and not so easy to apply.  I want the fire of God’s presence in my life to burn freely – and, like that of the burning bush: never go out.  It was the work of those who tended to the Tent of Meeting to assure the perpetuity of the flame, and it’s my responsibility to keep that flame burning in my life.  I pray, read the Word, and live in fellowship with God and his people.  In the midst of my busyness, this is my priority.  The fire of God must keep burning.<br />
Take Away: God’s fire in my life must be tended and never taken for granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
