<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Habakkuk &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-habakkuk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 16:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Habakkuk &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Silent God Habakkuk 1: God, how long do I have to cry out for help? Most of the Old Testament prophets have messages from God and usually those messages are calls to repentance with a heaping helping of “or else” on the side. Habakkuk, who lives 600 years before Jesus is born, brings a different [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yaZqNr_bxVA/YRmJZS-L5lI/AAAAAAABLCU/qLe_B3Pz5MgIN0gMJuFx5eOe-99nSrKFwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-034.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains and vicinity &#8211; Lake Toxaway area</figcaption></figure><br />
Silent God<br />
Habakkuk 1: God, how long do I have to cry out for help?<br />
Most of the Old Testament prophets have messages from God and usually those messages are calls to repentance with a heaping helping of “or else” on the side.  Habakkuk, who lives 600 years before Jesus is born, brings a different perspective to the ministry of the prophets.  His messages start, not with a word from the Lord, but with questions for the Lord.  While Habakkuk isn’t the only one to follow this path (we see it a lot in the Psalms) it does set him apart from the average approach of his fellow minor prophets.  There’s some complaining to God in his writings.  Habakkuk speaks from his heart as he tries to understand how a righteous God could possibly use an unrighteousness people like the Babylonians to do his will in punishing Israel.  This little book is a good one to read when it appears that bad people are getting away with their sin.  It’s also a good one to help us work through the unwelcome “silent God” times of life.<br />
Take Away: It’s okay to be absolutely honest with the Lord in expressing our disappointment or confusion to him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 11:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disappointment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeking God]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Telling it like it is Habakkuk 1: Why are you silent now? The complaint of the prophet to God is startling. He comes to the Lord and lays it all on the table, confessing his confusion and disappointment. He knows God to be righteous and loving but what he sees happening has none of that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15475" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15475" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15475" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15475" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Telling it like it is<br />
Habakkuk 1: Why are you silent now?<br />
The complaint of the prophet to God is startling.  He comes to the Lord and lays it all on the table, confessing his confusion and disappointment.  He knows God to be righteous and loving but what he sees happening has none of that in it.  The godless army of Babylon is destroying God’s chosen people and that doesn’t make sense to Habakkuk.  Not only that, but his prayers go unanswered.  Why, of all times, does the Almighty choose this dark hour to go silent?  Where is God when evil is winning the day?  Does God’s use of unrighteous people to achieve his purposes make God, himself, unrighteous?  Habakkuk writes more on this topic, including a report on how God finally responds to his questions.  However, today I’m taken with how he goes into the presence of the Lord to state his fear and disappointment.  There’s something refreshing about Habakkuk’s approach to the Lord here.  Habakkuk isn’t irreverent toward the Almighty, but he openly expresses his disappointment in how the Lord is doing (maybe better, isn’t doing) things at this point.  I know I’m called to trust the Lord no matter what, but if I’m having doubts the Lord wants me to bring them to him.  To pretend I believe when I don’t does me no good and is dissatisfying to the Lord as well.<br />
Take Away: Better to victoriously march on in overcoming faith but when there is doubt we can be frankly honest with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 11:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waiting for God’s response Habakkuk 2: If it seems slow in coming wait&#8230;it will come right on time. The prophet has stated his concerns to the Almighty. He’s troubled that a holy God would use such unholy people as his workers in the world. Having asked his questions of God, Habakkuk braces himself for God’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15482" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15482" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" class="size-large wp-image-15482" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IMG_1540.jpg 1227w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15482" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; wild turkey</figcaption></figure><br />
Waiting for God’s response<br />
Habakkuk 2: If it seems slow in coming wait&#8230;it will come right on time.<br />
The prophet has stated his concerns to the Almighty.  He’s troubled that a holy God would use such unholy people as his workers in the world.  Having asked his questions of God, Habakkuk braces himself for God’s answer.  The first thing he hears from God is that the Lord does, indeed, have an answer for him.  The second message he receives is that sometimes God’s answers appear to be slow in coming but they’re worth waiting for, and when they do come, it&#8217;s plain that God not only answered well, but the answer came at just the right time.  This passage is a wonderful blessing to all who have dealt with hard things in their lives; who have asked God for help in understanding them but haven’t yet received an answer.  At such times God’s word to Habakkuk is also his word to us: “wait.”  I’m not a big fan of waiting but in this passage I’m reminded that God hasn’t forgotten me and he isn’t ignoring me.  At just the right time – in God’s time – the answer will come.  When it does, it will have been well worth the wait.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes the Lord’s answers appear to be slow in coming but they’re worth waiting for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trusting without understanding Habakkuk 2: Look at that man&#8230;full of himself but soul-empty. The prophet understands that sinful Babylon is God’s chosen instrument for punishing sinful Judah. As bad as Judah is, Habakkuk is having a hard time understanding how God could ever use such an evil nation as his tool against the Children of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15484" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15484" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15484" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/IMG_1546.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15484" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Trusting without understanding<br />
Habakkuk 2: Look at that man&#8230;full of himself but soul-empty.<br />
The prophet understands that sinful Babylon is God’s chosen instrument for punishing sinful Judah.  As bad as Judah is, Habakkuk is having a hard time understanding how God could ever use such an evil nation as his tool against the Children of Abraham.  Habakkuk reverently takes his concern to God and now God answers.  A part of that answer is contained in chapter two of this brief book of the Bible.  The Lord tells Habakkuk he&#8217;s well aware of the sin of Babylon.  Although the language used suggests that the remarks are about only the King of Babylon, the context tells us that it&#8217;s the nation as a whole that&#8217;s being described.  The Lord wants Habakkuk to know that he hasn’t underestimated the sin of Babylon and he isn’t about to overlook it.  Babylon’s self-indulgent pride, its injustice, and its immorality will be dealt with.  Just because God intends to use this nation for his own purpose doesn’t mean that he&#8217;s going to overlook its sin.  The Lord remains sovereign and, in the end, he always has the last word.  This godless empire is, indeed, a tool in the hands of the Almighty.  At some point it may seem that Babylon is getting the benefit of this arraignment, but the real result will only be seen when the final chapter is written.  Today, I’m reminded that all of Creation is in God’s hands.  Anytime he wants, he can use whoever he wants for his purposes.  The Lord doesn’t need for me to explain his actions or to make apologies for them.  He does, however, insist that I trust him even when I don’t understand him.<br />
Take Away: I’m not required to understand the Lord but I am called to trust him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quiet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeing God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stillness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Questions answered Habakkuk 2: God is in his holy Temple! Quiet everyone – a holy silence. Listen! Chapter two is mostly a listing of the sins of Babylon. The Lord may intend to use this godless nation in his dealings with Judah but that doesn’t mean its despicable evil will be overlooked. As a series [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15489" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15489" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15489 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209120.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15489" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Questions answered<br />
Habakkuk 2: God is in his holy Temple! Quiet everyone – a holy silence. Listen!<br />
Chapter two is mostly a listing of the sins of Babylon. The Lord may intend to use this godless nation in his dealings with Judah but that doesn’t mean its despicable evil will be overlooked. As a series of “Who do you think you are?” judgments is being listed, the prophet suddenly has a vision of God. Immediately, the prophet calls for “holy silence.” This isn’t the time to preach sermons of condemnation. The only thing a human being can do at this point is to bow in silence before the Lord. This, I think is God’s second answer to Habakkuk. The prophet has asked how a holy God can use a sinful nation to punish Judah. One answer is that God is well aware of the sin of Babylon and that he will decisively deal with it. The other answer is heard as the Almighty reveals himself to Habakkuk. This is similar to what happens in the Book of Job. Job has asked for an audience with God that he might plead his case. However, when God appears, Job is speechless and all he can do is bow in worship and adoration. When I see God my questions are answered. My need is not for the Lord to explain to me everything I think I want to know. The need in my life is a fresh vision of God.<br />
Take Away: All our questions are answered when we genuinely experience the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 11:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do it again, Lord Habakkuk 3: Do among us what you did among them. The prophet of God has the heart of a psalmist. As I started reading Habakkuk and saw his reverent complaint to God I was reminded of the Psalms of complaint in which the writer pours his heart out before the Lord. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15492" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15492" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15492 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9209126.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15492" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Do it again, Lord<br />
Habakkuk 3: Do among us what you did among them.<br />
The prophet of God has the heart of a psalmist. As I started reading Habakkuk and saw his reverent complaint to God I was reminded of the Psalms of complaint in which the writer pours his heart out before the Lord. Now, as Habakkuk experiences God in a fresh way, his words remind me of the Psalms again. He pens a psalm of his own in which he recounts God’s past deliverance and looks to a day of restoration. His opening lines: “Do among us what you did among them. Work among us as you worked among them” is the prayer of many of God’s people through the ages. In this case, Habakkuk is specifically thinking of the deliverance of his ancestors from Egyptian bondage. However, through the centuries, many have looked back to great movements of God: revivals, healings, and other times of special blessing and prayed this prayer. In my life there have been times of extraordinary blessing, some so private and precious that I seldom speak of them. However, I mention them to the Lord, thanking him for what he did and marveling at his grace to me and, in the spirit of Habakkuk, ask the Lord to “do it again.” It’s unhealthy to spend our lives talking about the “good old days” but we should allow those times of special blessing to remind us of what God can do and to encourage us to seek his best for in our lives in this day and in these circumstances.<br />
Take Away: There are times when we do well to revisit past blessings and allow those blessings to encourage us to expect renewed blessings of God in our lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 11:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The God who never fails Habakkuk 3: Counting on God’s Rule to prevail, I take heart and gain strength. The little book of Habakkuk is all about the prophet’s concern with how God works in the world. How can a holy God use such an unrighteousness people as those of Babylon to accomplish his purposes? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15496" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15496" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15496 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279154.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15496" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Burgess Falls State Park, TN</figcaption></figure>
<p>The God who never fails<br />
Habakkuk 3: Counting on God’s Rule to prevail, I take heart and gain strength.<br />
The little book of Habakkuk is all about the prophet’s concern with how God works in the world. How can a holy God use such an unrighteousness people as those of Babylon to accomplish his purposes? The Lord answers his question, first, by assuring Habakkuk that he&#8217;s aware of sin and rebellion and that it will be judged. The second answer, I think, is when the prophet sees God, in his holiness, enter his Temple. Such a vision of God produces an awed silence and an undeniable assurance that God is God. Because of that, whatever happens will be the right thing. Habakkuk breaks out in praise, writing what might be called a “displaced psalm.” The final chorus, in particular, states an unshakable trust in the Lord. “Though the cherry trees don’t blossom and the strawberries don’t ripen&#8230;I’m singing joyful praise to God&#8230;counting on God’s Rule to prevail.” This hymn is a powerful expression of trust in God. Even when the enemy attacks, even when life takes an unwelcome turn, even when all else fails&#8230;even then I rejoice in the One who never fails.<br />
Take Away: Even when live is confusing and painful…even then, God is God and God never fails.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
