<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Colossians &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-colossians/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 15:55:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Colossians &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Colossians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-colossians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Colossians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-colossians/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The heart of it all Colossians 1: We preach Christ. The Apostle sits in a jail as he writes this letter to the Christians in the city of Colossi, located in what is now the nation of Turkey. He wants his readers to stand firm for Jesus over the long haul, not in some grim, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16166" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16166" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16166" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140715_104310.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16166" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR Thousand Trails</figcaption></figure>
<p>The heart of it all </p>
<p>Colossians 1: We preach Christ.</p>
<p>The Apostle sits in a jail as he writes this letter to the Christians in the city of Colossi, located in what is now the nation of Turkey.  He wants his readers to stand firm for Jesus over the long haul, not in some grim, miserable, “unto death” sort of a way, but with joy and confidence and strength.  In fact, Paul wants them to be absolutely focused on Jesus and not allow themselves to journey down “dead-end alleys.”  They’re to be so in love with Jesus, so impressed with him, that they can’t imagine anything but living in him and for him.  Actually, all Paul wants for them is what he has for himself.  He’s bought into Jesus, “hook, line, and sinker.”  In his mind Jesus towers above all else; always has – always will.  He tells them, and us, that the world exists only by Jesus.  He’s “supreme,” “God’s original purpose,” and gives everything in creation “its proper place.”  When Paul preaches, he has only one subject: Jesus.  When his ministry is finished, the result, he hopes, will be many mature, settled followers of Jesus.  How important this message is today.  We’re pulled this way and that.  Decisions are demanded of us.  The circumstances of life threaten to erode our souls.  At the end of the day – at the end of life – what’s going to matter?  In Paul’s words I find the answer: “Christ! No more, no less.”</p>
<p>Take Away: I want the compass of my life to always point to Jesus.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Colossians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Colossians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secrets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mystery has been solved Colossians 2: We’ve been shown the mystery! A new church has started down the block and old First Church seems dull in comparison. New Church not only offers a different style of music, but there’s a lot of talk about amazing spiritual experiences and hitherto unknown secrets being revealed. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16169" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16169" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16169" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mystery has been solved </p>
<p>Colossians 2: We’ve been shown the mystery!</p>
<p>A new church has started down the block and old First Church seems dull in comparison.  New Church not only offers a different style of music, but there’s a lot of talk about amazing spiritual experiences and hitherto unknown secrets being revealed.  The folks at First Church can’t help but notice what’s going on down the street.  How come their pastor never tells them some of these secrets to success?  Why doesn’t he lead them into the mysteries of the spiritual?  Something like that is happening at Colossi and Laodicea.  Those with a different approach to God have come to town claiming that their way unlocks doors that have before been locked.  If the Christians listen to them they can go beyond where they are and press on to spiritual power and authority beyond what they&#8217;ve ever imagined.  The Apostle tells them that that’s completely wrong.  The great mystery, the wonderful secret to spiritual power and success has already been explained to them.  It can all be summed up in one name: “Jesus.”  To be connected to him is to be connected to all there is of God.  He warns them that to rush off down some other road is a “wild-goose chase.”  Paul urges them to focus only on Jesus and, in him to be dominated by the love of God.  The mystery has been solved and the secret has been revealed.  His name is Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: Our religion isn’t bound up in mysteries.  Rather it’s all about relationship: knowing Jesus as Savior, Lord, and Friend.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Colossians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Colossians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dressing like a Christian Colossians 3: Dress in the wardrobe God picked out for you. For many people the phrase “dressing like a Christian” dredges up a lot of old guilt and maybe resentment. We were raised in church traditions that stressed externals and the weight of that emphasis fell especially on the girls and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16172" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16172" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16172" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163145.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16172" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along Oregon Hwy 101 &#8211; north of Florence</figcaption></figure>
<p>Dressing like a Christian</p>
<p>Colossians 3: Dress in the wardrobe God picked out for you.</p>
<p>For many people the phrase “dressing like a Christian” dredges up a lot of old guilt and maybe resentment.  We were raised in church traditions that stressed externals and the weight of that emphasis fell especially on the girls and young women.  Looking back, I feel somewhat charitable toward those who stressed such things.  I think, by and large, their hearts were in the right place.  After all, they wanted to live holy, clean lives and our personal holiness ought to be evident even in the clothing we choose to wear.  However, the years have pretty much proven that traveling that road leads to the city of legalism which is quite distant from the city of love and grace.  In this passage we’re told that there&#8217;s a wardrobe that&#8217;s appropriate for God’s people but it has nothing to do with how much or little skin is shown.  God’s people are to be characterized &#8212; “clothed in” &#8212; “compassion, kindness, humility, quiet strength, discipline.”  We’re to be known as “even-tempered, content…quick to forgive.”  The absolute necessity for all followers of Jesus, Paul says, is the “basic, all-purpose garment” of love.  He emphasizes love by saying, “don’t leave home without it.”  So, there I have it.  My Christianity isn’t seen in what I wear, but it is seen as these positive characteristics are on display in my life.  It was easier to focus on “covering up” but such an emphasis totally misses what it really means to dress like a Christian.</p>
<p>Take Away: Christ should be seen in our lives, not so much by what we wear, but by the display of Christ-like characteristics. </p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Colossians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 10:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Colossians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The secret to evangelism Colossians 4: Make the most of every opportunity. Believers aren’t supposed to create closed communities of the faithful. Rather, we’re to live right out in the open, rubbing shoulders with those outside the faith, making friends, sharing in their lives. I don’t think this means that believers are never to “retreat.” [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16175" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16175" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16175" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_163453.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16175" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>The secret to evangelism </p>
<p>Colossians 4: Make the most of every opportunity.</p>
<p>Believers aren’t supposed to create closed communities of the faithful.  Rather, we’re to live right out in the open, rubbing shoulders with those outside the faith, making friends, sharing in their lives.  I don’t think this means that believers are never to “retreat.”  After all, Jesus at least attempted to get the disciples away from the crowds sometimes.  Still, he always went back to them, loving them, and, apparently, liking those who weren’t his followers.  Paul urges the Colossian Christians to not only stay involved in their community but to make the most of that involvement.  Interestingly, his directions for them aren’t as evangelistic as you might think.  He describes “making the most” as being “gracious in your speech” and tells them that their “goal is to bring out the best in others in a conversation.”  Apparently, our influencing others for Christ doesn’t necessarily start with a “spiritual conversation” at all.  Instead, it starts with friendship, respect, genuine interest.  In fact, Paul specifically warns them not to “put them down” or “cut them out.”  In light of these instructions, becoming a “friend” to someone just so we can tell them about Jesus is off the table.  My seizing the moment starts, instead, with my making some genuine friends outside the body of believers.  Then, I make sure I’m always gracious in my conversations with them, wanting the best for them.  Real friendships are the secret to evangelism.</p>
<p>Take Away: For church people it’s a big challenge to make good friends who are outside the church.  Still, it’s a key component to evangelism.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
