<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>victory &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/victory/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 22:40:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>victory &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-144/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 10:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The great Deliverer Isaiah 42: He won&#8217;t be stopped until he&#8217;s finished his work &#8212; to set things right on earth. Even as Isaiah writes words of comfort to those banished from Jerusalem by the crushing might of Babylon, he looks forward to a great day of deliverance. &#8220;One day,&#8221; he promises, &#8220;God will send [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Hw_aCDosO1I/X-pFjAcTBDI/AAAAAAABIEo/faLz05_vrUAJaYS7BdIznVVerr67kxhOQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9092424.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along Colorado Hwy 34</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The great Deliverer<br />
Isaiah 42: He won&#8217;t be stopped until he&#8217;s finished his work &#8212; to set things right on earth.<br />
Even as Isaiah writes words of comfort to those banished from Jerusalem by the crushing might of Babylon, he looks forward to a great day of deliverance.  &#8220;One day,&#8221; he promises, &#8220;God will send the ultimate Deliverer, his prized Servant, to the world.  He’ll do an even greater thing than bringing a scattered people back to their homeland.&#8221;  Isaiah looks to the coming of the Messiah, a man filled with the Spirit who’ll &#8220;set everything right.&#8221;  One day, in Isaiah&#8217;s distant future, a man will be baptized and God&#8217;s voice will be heard proclaiming, &#8220;This is my Son.&#8221;  Here we see that proclamation being foretold as the Lord declares through Isaiah, &#8220;He&#8217;s the one I chose, and I couldn&#8217;t be more pleased with him.&#8221;  The prophet doesn&#8217;t have all the details.  In fact, it’s unlikely that he has a vision of Calvary or of the empty tomb of Easter.  Isaiah doesn&#8217;t see a cross, but he does see a Messiah.  This Promised One will overcome every hindrance to accomplish his work.  That’s just what happens when even a cross can&#8217;t stop this Servant of God.  Know what? Neither can he be stopped by the seeming insurmountable obstacles of the world today.  We Christians need to remember this and join the Messiah&#8217;s mission.  Followers of his don&#8217;t sit around wringing their hands while lamenting the state of things.  This Messiah won&#8217;t quit until things are set &#8220;right on earth.&#8221;  That’s our mission as well as our hope.<br />
Take Away: It’s not that there aren’t any challenges because there are.  Still, the fact remains that the Son of God will, without question accomplish his mission of redemption. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 12:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-11/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Its Jesus verses death John 11: Lazarus, come out! I’ve heard it said that Jesus specified that Lazarus “come out” of the grave because, had he just given the command to “come out” that there would have been a general resurrection. Personally, I think that’s more of a poetical take on this remarkable event than [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15866" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15866" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" class="size-large wp-image-15866" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1536x960.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15866" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Its Jesus verses death</p>
<p>John 11: Lazarus, come out!</p>
<p>I’ve heard it said that Jesus specified that Lazarus “come out” of the grave because, had he just given the command to “come out” that there would have been a general resurrection.  Personally, I think that’s more of a poetical take on this remarkable event than a realistic one.  Still, I understand the statement of faith in that concept.  This is an act of absolute authority over death.  Jesus doesn’t even touch the dead body.  He, in fact, never enters the tomb.  From outside, after a public prayer, Jesus merely shouts out the command and Lazarus is resurrected.  I can’t imagine any more powerful demonstration of authority over death than this one.  Well, almost.  Soon, an even more convincing event will take place.  For now though, I’m happy to be reminded of this wonderful truth.  Any time Jesus faces death, Jesus wins.  Glory!</p>
<p>Take Away: One hope of all Christians is the hope of life after death.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s answer to sin-in-me Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved. What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16014" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16014" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16014" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-768x482.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1536x963.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16014" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Long Beach, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; on the beach a short walk from the campground</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s answer to sin-in-me</p>
<p>Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved.</p>
<p>What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown away by the opening words of Romans 8. Before Christ, Romans 7 was the norm, but it’s the norm no more. In Christ “a new power is in operation” and everything’s changed. When I cry out to God for relief from sin he responds in Christ to defeat sin-in-me once and for all. The blood of Christ is applied to my life to bring about a “deep healing” and sin-as-a-condition is defeated. Now, a new day dawns in my spiritual life. I’m led “out into the open, into a spacious, free life.” I’ve been “delivered from that dead life” and the Spirit is now living in me. As a child of God who struggles with sin, I cry out to my Heavenly Father for help. He responds by doing a work in me as “God’s Spirit touches” my spirit resulting in a deeper relationship with God and a level of spiritual living I never before dreamed possible.</p>
<p>Take Away: In God, there’s wonderful freedom from self and sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ephesians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ephesians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not a walk in the park Ephesians 6: Be prepared. You’re up against far more than you can handle on your own. Several years ago a popular song included the phrase “I beg your pardon; I never promised you a rose garden.” Know what? That’s life in general and, in light of this passage, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16149" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16149" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-16149" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259636.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16149" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; south of Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Not a walk in the park </p>
<p>Ephesians 6: Be prepared. You’re up against far more than you can handle on your own.</p>
<p>Several years ago a popular song included the phrase “I beg your pardon; I never promised you a rose garden.”  Know what?  That’s life in general and, in light of this passage, the Christian life in particular.  Paul writes this passage from jail.  He warns his readers that they have an enemy who&#8217;s intent on destroying them.  Their spiritual journey is no game and how they live in the here and now has eternal consequences.  If a person starts out living for the Lord thinking it’s going to be a stroll in a rose garden they&#8217;re in for some unpleasant surprises.  The Apostle focuses on spiritual adversaries, unseen but real.  It’s not unreasonable to add the common inconveniences and out and out tragedies of life to this mix.  I’m not to be naive about all this.  There are times when it becomes clear that I’m up against far more than I can handle.  Happily, the Lord hasn’t put us out here in real life without some resources. Paul urges us to take advantage of many powerful resources that are at our fingertips.  He reminds us that “Truth, righteousness, peace, faith, and salvation are more than words.”  He directs us to God’s Word and prayer.  It’s no rose garden, but I have everything I need to live a victorious, overcoming life.  </p>
<p>Take Away: Life isn’t always easy but it’s important to remember the Lord’s faithful provision for us.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Victory in Jesus Revelation 7: Who are these dressed in white robes, and where did they come from? As the worship scene in heaven unfolds John sees more and more worshipers. First, there are 144,000 people from the family trees of Israel. Then, he sees thousands and thousands from “all nations and tribes.” The number [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16379" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16379" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16379" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16379" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Victory in Jesus</p>
<p>Revelation 7: Who are these dressed in white robes, and where did they come from?</p>
<p>As the worship scene in heaven unfolds John sees more and more worshipers. First, there are 144,000 people from the family trees of Israel. Then, he sees thousands and thousands from “all nations and tribes.” The number is too vast to count and they all begin singing praise to God and to the Lamb. John is transfixed by the scene but his focus is interrupted when one of the Elders asks him a question. He asks John who they are, this white robed, too-vast-to-be-counted throng of worshipers. John doesn’t know, but the Elder answers his own question. These are those who have come through the great tribulation. This huge multitude isn’t made up of everyone in heaven, just of those who faithfully serve Christ right at the end, as earth’s history is being wrapped up. A couple of things come to mind at this point. First, heaven won’t be a lonely place. In spite of “many called, few chosen” the “few” comprise a huge number. Second, as bad as the time of tribulation might be, by God’s power his people can overcome, not just surviving, barely limping in, but thriving in numbers too great to count, coming through clean and rejoicing. This is a testimony, not to human perseverance, but to God’s power at work in the lives of his people.</p>
<p>Take Away: By the grace of the Lord, by his power in our lives…by the Lord, we can hold fast in our faith and receive a glorious entrance into the place he’s prepared for us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merry Christmas…maybe Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child. John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16394" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16394" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16394" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16394" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Merry Christmas…maybe</p>
<p>Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child.</p>
<p>John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written to be read by first century Christians I lean toward understandings of it that keep their perspective in mind. Also, there’s such a strong parallel to the story of the birth of Christ that I tend to think that John’s using that well known story to illustrate something more. Mary, the most blessed of women, gives birth to the Son of God. Immediately, Satan tries to have him killed but, being warned in a dream, his earthly father, Joseph, takes them and flees to the desert, Egypt. Throughout his ministry there’s a war for the hearts of men, women, boys, and girls. Ultimately, though, Satan&#8217;s defeated as Jesus goes to the cross, winning the ultimate victory for all who will come to him. It all fits, kind of. The question for Bible scholars is “What does it illustrate?” Most say that the woman represents the Church and that the battle represents the war waged by the enemy of our souls in an attempt to defeat the Church. If that’s right the message here is one of divine protection and ultimate victory. Even readers like me, in spite of my struggles in understanding the passage, can conclude that, whatever the exact meaning here, God will protect his people and that ultimately, in Christ, victory is ours. I know I don’t get everything that’s going on here, but that’s a pretty good place to start.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to have a firm grasp on the fact of the Lord’s provision for, and protection of, us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The way to die Revelation 14: Blessed are those who die in the Master from now on; how blessed to die that way! In this passage the harvest of the world is about to be described but prior to that there’s another description of God’s people standing “passionately patient, keeping God’s commands, staying faithful to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16400" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16400" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16400" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259748.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16400" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The way to die</p>
<p>Revelation 14: Blessed are those who die in the Master from now on; how blessed to die that way!</p>
<p>In this passage the harvest of the world is about to be described but prior to that there’s another description of God’s people standing “passionately patient, keeping God’s commands, staying faithful to Jesus.” Then John is told specifically to write about those who finish their lives while being “passionately patient.” They serve God through their lives, looking for Jesus to return, overcoming the hardships and trials of their journey. In the specific case of this passage there’s considerable pressure on them to follow the general population in worship of the Beast. These saints resist and at personal cost persist in being “faithful to Jesus.” Now, for them, the battle ends. Their “hard, hard work” is over and “God blesses them for it all in the end.” I’ve known people such as these described in this passage. They loved the Lord and served him through their lives. When hard times came, they wished for a way out, but way out or not, they continued to trust God. Physically, they were ultimately defeated. Spiritually though, they were victorious. John is told to remind God’s people that those who “die in the Master” are blessed. Unless Jesus comes back first, my turn&#8217;s coming. I want the same kind of passionate patience, the same faithfulness to God’s commands, to be the hallmark of my life. As this passage says: “how blessed to die that way!”</p>
<p>Take Away: Live the right way so you can die the right way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The end is at hand, the end is at hand! Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings. John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16409" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16409" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16409" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16409" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The end is at hand, the end is at hand!</p>
<p>Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings.</p>
<p>John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told that that, too, is a riddle name, and the city, Rome, is described. In John’s day, seeing Rome as the seat of evil in the world makes a lot of sense. Some continue to take the woman, Babylon, and description of the riddle to add up to the literal Rome, carrying with it lots of religious overtones. Frankly, it’s beyond me (seems I’ve been saying that a lot lately). If it isn’t to be taken literally, it may be that the “Babylon” represents a current world power that dominants the world as Rome did in John’s day. All of this is the set up for the big battle. This world power will rally the nations of the world to battle against the Lamb of God. Then, before the battle is even described, we’re told the outcome of it. The Lamb wins. In the end, there will be no doubt as to his high standing: Lord over all lords, King over all kings. The descriptions of judgment, war, and destruction are soon to give way to victory, worship, and the exaltation of the Lamb of God.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to understand this: in the end, the Lamb reigns.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/2011/09/26/4064/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mystery man of the Bible Genesis 14: Melchizedek, king of Salem&#8230;blessed him. I’ve always thought of Abraham’s rescue of Lot as a fairly localized situation and that their enemy was a neighboring warlord. However, I’ve just realized that Kedorlaomer and his allies were a big deal: a conquering army from Babylon; a world power. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dVWPC31TshU/XL-QKPUT2vI/AAAAAAAA6xM/_GcGeM9WI18UfIHmvpWJY1ByaFAcjxnzwCKgBGAs/s1600/P7268805.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Watkins Glen State Park, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mystery man of the Bible<br />
Genesis 14: Melchizedek, king of Salem&#8230;blessed him.<br />
I’ve always thought of Abraham’s rescue of Lot as a fairly localized situation and that their enemy was a neighboring warlord. However, I’ve just realized that Kedorlaomer and his allies were a big deal: a conquering army from Babylon; a world power. The Canaanite rulers didn’t have a chance against them. When Abram hears what&#8217;s happened, he mounts a rescue effort with just 318 people. Years before Gideon’s 300 will win a battle against an insurmountable force Abraham mounts an amazing rescue by the authority of God. As he returns from that battle the Canaanite kings salute him and tell him to keep the spoils of his unprecedented victory, but Abraham turns them down, commenting that he doesn’t want people to think it was the Canaanites who made him rich. Then, out of nowhere, the mysterious Melchizedek, King of the town named Peace (or Salem) makes an appearance. He comes to bless Abraham and to praise God for what he&#8217;s done. In turn, Abraham recognizes this hitherto unknown man as a spiritual authority and gives him a tithe of all the plunder. I’m sure we’re talking about wagon loads of stuff here. In centuries to come both the Psalmist and the writer of Hebrews revisit this incident. They remind us that, even for the Jewish people, not all spiritual authority is based on lineage. In fact, the highest authority is when the Lord grants it in a direct way. I’m not ready to get bound up in whether or not Melchizedek is Jesus making an Old Testament appearance, but he does become the poster boy for God’s granting direct authority to the person of his choosing, credentials or not. That’s real important in our understanding how Jesus is the High Priest of Christians through the ages.<br />
Take away: As we read our Old Testaments it isn’t unusual to find God preparing the way for his Son, Jesus, to come to the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 22:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having a small role in a big deal Exodus 17: But Moses’ hands got tired. The first of what will be a seeming unending number of battles is taking place. Their background as slaves affords these Israelites little preparation of combat. King Amalek, on the other hand, is a fighter with a trained and disciplined [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uJ9dUoCQx0w/XQgDlFkq08I/AAAAAAAA8PM/fT-ePTWhg88bNcRannMOpPPdkWylBAt0ACKgBGAs/s1600/P5029291.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
Having a small role in a big deal<br />
Exodus 17: But Moses’ hands got tired.<br />
The first of what will be a seeming unending number of battles is taking place.  Their background as slaves affords these Israelites little preparation of combat.  King Amalek, on the other hand, is a fighter with a trained and disciplined army.  He sees the Israelites as easy prey and attacks them.  The thing he doesn’t know is that Israel is under the protection of God Almighty.  God’s man, Moses, climbs to a high point and raises that famous staff to the Lord.  When he does, it’s almost as though God’s power flows from heaven, through that staff, into Moses, and then out to those defending the nation.  These slaves fight like soldiers.  However, Moses’ arms grow weary and he lowers the staff.  When he does, the tide of the battle turns and Amalek’s forces begin to gain the advantage.  Two men, Aaron and Hur, come to the rescue.  They provide Moses a place to sit and then they hold up his arms and staff.  Victory is theirs.  As I read this story I see that God&#8217;s teaching them that (in the words of Jesus) “Apart from me you can do nothing.”  Their victory on this day is clearly linked to Moses, the staff, and the action of Aaron and Hur.  It’s a great victory, the first of many, but there’s no way they can take credit for it.  Also, I can’t help but comment on the support of Aaron and Hur.  Neither is God’s man for this moment.  Clearly, that’s Moses.  However, they become literal “supporters” of God’s man, lifting him when he can’t go on.  Generally speaking, that’s our role in life too.  We lend our support to those God is using in unique ways.  In so doing, we play a small role in the big deal of God’s work in this world.<br />
Take Away: It’s nice to have a part to play, even when it’s mainly just supportive of others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
