<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>secrets &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/secrets/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 15:55:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>secrets &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secrets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve got a secret Mark 4: We’re not keeping secrets, we’re telling them. The theme here is parable telling. Mark tells us some of Jesus’ stories and then remarks that Jesus is “never without a story.” The reason for this approach, according to Jesus, is that he’s in the “secret revealing” business. No hidden, mystic [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15710" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15710" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-15710" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15710" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’ve got a secret</p>
<p>Mark 4: We’re not keeping secrets, we’re telling them.</p>
<p>The theme here is parable telling. Mark tells us some of Jesus’ stories and then remarks that Jesus is “never without a story.” The reason for this approach, according to Jesus, is that he’s in the “secret revealing” business. No hidden, mystic religion of riddles here. Jesus’ purpose is to open wide the doors to the Kingdom of God. People who never understood before now get a crystal clear picture of God at work. Now we understand how the gospel takes root in some lives but not in others. We see what happens when the gospel does take root, starting small but becoming a huge, transforming force in life. And, we see God’s purpose in all this. Those who receive the gospel are to let the light of that gospel shine in their lives. We aren’t to be “keepers of the flame.” Instead, we’re “givers of the flame.” We don’t take the gospel into our lives and hide it. Instead, it’s to be the noticeable thing about us. So, how’s it going? Do people see the light of the gospel in my life? If I’m one of those who has received the gospel and if it has taken root and become the number one thing in my life, is it what others see in me? At the very core of my life, I’m to be a “secret teller” letting others in on the best news in the world. If not, maybe it’s because I’m not the kind of “soil” I think I am!</p>
<p>Take Away: Some secrets are best told.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Colossians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Colossians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secrets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-colossians-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mystery has been solved Colossians 2: We’ve been shown the mystery! A new church has started down the block and old First Church seems dull in comparison. New Church not only offers a different style of music, but there’s a lot of talk about amazing spiritual experiences and hitherto unknown secrets being revealed. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16169" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16169" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/PHOTO_20140724_145653.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16169" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mystery has been solved </p>
<p>Colossians 2: We’ve been shown the mystery!</p>
<p>A new church has started down the block and old First Church seems dull in comparison.  New Church not only offers a different style of music, but there’s a lot of talk about amazing spiritual experiences and hitherto unknown secrets being revealed.  The folks at First Church can’t help but notice what’s going on down the street.  How come their pastor never tells them some of these secrets to success?  Why doesn’t he lead them into the mysteries of the spiritual?  Something like that is happening at Colossi and Laodicea.  Those with a different approach to God have come to town claiming that their way unlocks doors that have before been locked.  If the Christians listen to them they can go beyond where they are and press on to spiritual power and authority beyond what they&#8217;ve ever imagined.  The Apostle tells them that that’s completely wrong.  The great mystery, the wonderful secret to spiritual power and success has already been explained to them.  It can all be summed up in one name: “Jesus.”  To be connected to him is to be connected to all there is of God.  He warns them that to rush off down some other road is a “wild-goose chase.”  Paul urges them to focus only on Jesus and, in him to be dominated by the love of God.  The mystery has been solved and the secret has been revealed.  His name is Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: Our religion isn’t bound up in mysteries.  Rather it’s all about relationship: knowing Jesus as Savior, Lord, and Friend.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
