<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>salvation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/salvation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>salvation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Return on investment Ecclesiastes 11: Be generous: Invest in acts of charity. Charity yields high returns. The Lord is wonderfully generous to us. He’s given us the world and all its beauty and life itself. His greatest gift to us is salvation. This gift cost him everything as is seen at the cross. This is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TWUm43NL6v0/X6RoskaJ8pI/AAAAAAABHfc/ju3WLSkLKPMtZXDgJDML7FihZfPWjak9QCPcBGAsYHg/s400/16rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Return on investment<br />
Ecclesiastes 11: Be generous: Invest in acts of charity.  Charity yields high returns.<br />
The Lord is wonderfully generous to us.  He’s given us the world and all its beauty and life itself.  His greatest gift to us is salvation.  This gift cost him everything as is seen at the cross.  This is God&#8217;s investment in us and his charity toward us.  Solomon says &#8220;charity yields high returns.&#8221;  God gave everything and he has every right to expect big returns on his investment.  What is the return he expects?  He expects human beings to respond to his great act of charity by giving their hearts to him in loving devotion.  From the very beginning God has desired willing fellowship from us.  That relationship is so valuable to the Lord that he gave everything (invested everything) that that relationship might be restored.  It&#8217;s my positive response to that sacrifice; my responding in love and thanksgiving, and my walking in continued fellowship with the Lord that he considers to be a &#8220;high return.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Am I giving the Lord a “high return” on his investment in me?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-115/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 04:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thirst]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living Water Isaiah 12: Joyfully you&#8217;ll pull up buckets of water from the wells of salvation. As I read this statement from Isaiah about drawing &#8220;buckets of water from the wells of salvation&#8221; I can’t help but think of Jesus and the woman at the well. Jesus offers the Samaritan woman &#8220;living water&#8221; that she [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Bwq6rgf7dR4/X8VH9HIAq0I/AAAAAAABHuU/MPB3xAsUUoIsKqvFbeFUPPKyX8rP5vpTACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Lost%2BMaples%2BSt.%2BPark%2Bvicinity%2B%2B11-28-2006%2B10-17-56%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>Living Water<br />
Isaiah 12: Joyfully you&#8217;ll pull up buckets of water from the wells of salvation.<br />
As I read this statement from Isaiah about drawing &#8220;buckets of water from the wells of salvation&#8221; I can’t help but think of Jesus and the woman at the well.  Jesus offers the Samaritan woman &#8220;living water&#8221; that she might &#8220;never thirst again.&#8221;  As I see Isaiah promising a day when abundant &#8220;salvation water&#8221; will be available and remember Jesus offering just such water, well, I can&#8217;t help but focus in on this wonderful offer.  I&#8217;m glad today that Jesus didn&#8217;t just offer a philosophy of life or a new approach to religion.  Instead, his &#8220;well of salvation&#8221; contains that which is &#8220;living&#8221; and fully satisfying.  Whether Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy really applies here or not, it does remind me of all Jesus has made available.   In the words of the woman at the well, &#8220;Give me that living water that I might never thirst again.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The “living water” is nothing other than an abiding relationship with the Lord, himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-128/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 06:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’d rather do it myself Isaiah 30: Your salvation requires you to turn back to me and stop your silly efforts to save yourselves. The salvation being spoken of in this passage isn’t &#8220;getting religion.&#8221; Instead, it’s salvation from an enemy that’s threatening to destroy them. Their effort to save themselves includes preparing for war [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RMNRmI50mvE/X9aXiQIHcqI/AAAAAAABH3w/7o1Qjw1AonceGPo0jjEUGsQpPPxPlTiogCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251325.JPG" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</center></figcaption></figure>
<p>I’d rather do it myself<br />
Isaiah 30: Your salvation requires you to turn back to me and stop your silly efforts to save yourselves.<br />
The salvation being spoken of in this passage isn’t &#8220;getting religion.&#8221; Instead, it’s salvation from an enemy that’s threatening to destroy them. Their effort to save themselves includes preparing for war and forming an alliance with a powerful nation that they might defend themselves. Still, there’s a spiritual element here. Their nation&#8217;s existence has always been improbable, a seeming fluke of history. Their ancestors were slaves who never had a chance of calling any land their own. Had it not been for God Almighty acting on their behalf they would have, by now, been one of thousands of forgotten people groups, a mere footnote in history. To forget just who they are how they came to be is a recipe for disaster. However, that’s exactly what they’ve done. They’ve removed from their lives the One who gave them existence in the first place. Now, when everything starts coming apart they’re looking for a &#8220;reasonable&#8221; solution; a solution that excludes God. Through Isaiah the God they’ve ignored tells them that they have only one chance and that chance is in him. What’s true of nations is also true of individuals. I owe my very life to him. The next breath I take is a gift of the God who has loved me and patiently worked in my life. To turn my back on him and fool myself into thinking I can handle life on my own will result in disaster. In Isaiah&#8217;s words: my &#8220;strength will come from settling down in complete dependence&#8221; on the Lord. There&#8217;s plenty of hope here, but also there’s plenty of warning.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is our hope – our only hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-59/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rescue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5252</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rescue the perishing Proverbs 24: Rescue the perishing; don&#8217;t hesitate to step in and help. Fanny Crosby wrote the missionary song that’s based on this proverb. Many a missionary service of years gone by has featured her song &#8220;Rescue the Perishing.&#8221; Would that the lives of God&#8217;s people feature it’s message in this day! The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FZiq9QHEJRw/X4ifIoz8JhI/AAAAAAABG8Q/rYSe-zbN2Jodo01I3KkI4qr0qm1BtHZ4QCPcBGAsYHg/s400/2002maine-1.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2002 &#8211; Maine</figcaption></figure><br />
Rescue the perishing<br />
Proverbs 24: Rescue the perishing; don&#8217;t hesitate to step in and help.<br />
Fanny Crosby wrote the missionary song that’s based on this proverb.  Many a missionary service of years gone by has featured her song &#8220;Rescue the Perishing.&#8221;  Would that the lives of God&#8217;s people feature it’s message in this day!  The immediate assumption of the proverb is that there are those who are, indeed, perishing.  In some cases it’s quite clear that people are in trouble.  Their lives are unraveling and it’s plain that things can&#8217;t continue as they are.  In other cases it takes insight to see what’s happening.  People are living ordinary lives and pretty much keeping things together.  However, spiritually speaking, they too are perishing.  When Jesus stated his mission he gave it in terms of &#8220;rescue&#8221; saying he came to &#8220;seek and to save that which was lost.&#8221;  As I consider this proverb, I’m challenged to join Jesus in that mission.  &#8220;Rescue the perishing, care for the dying.  Jesus is merciful, Jesus will save.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: As followers of Jesus we need to join him in his mission to rescue the perishing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-145/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2007 &#8211; Elk in Rocky Mtn National Park, CO Such Good News! Isaiah 42: I am God. I have called you to live right and well. As Isaiah celebrates the ministry of the Messiah it seems that God, Himself, steps onto center stage. He, too, comes to rejoice in the promise of a &#8220;new salvation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-U3QZeBcZAqg/X-ubkVHhWlI/AAAAAAABIE8/PzwvvC0S1Y4IiTamQwi9qIwEmj7AOqIVQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9082396.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /> <center>2007 &#8211; Elk in Rocky Mtn National Park, CO</center></p>
<p>Such Good News!<br />
Isaiah 42: I am God. I have called you to live right and well.<br />
As Isaiah celebrates the ministry of the Messiah it seems that God, Himself, steps onto center stage.  He, too, comes to rejoice in the promise of a &#8220;new salvation work.&#8221;  This Salvation-Bringer is coming, not because people have earned it but because the Lord has &#8220;taken responsibility&#8221; for them and is going to act in their behalf.  The result of that ministry will be that God&#8217;s people will &#8220;live right and well.&#8221;  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that Jesus didn&#8217;t come to the world to condemn us for living poorly; instead, he came to enable us to live well in the sight of God.  Jesus put it this way: &#8220;I have come that they may have life, and have it to the full.&#8221; (John 10:10)<br />
Take Away: Jesus came to enable us to live well in the sight of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-147/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 10:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tolerance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only One Savior Isaiah 43: I’m the only Savior there is. I know that pluralism and tolerance are in, and, truthfully, I agree that these are a positive step away from bigotry and narrowness. I also know that we Americans have a lot to learn from other nations and cultures. Just my limited relationships with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DHyBwvPq3ww/X-4YuoCv1vI/AAAAAAABIF8/QPmU8pqpIH84ukMD3FY-JPhJkTmgVIS1ACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9072336.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Lake Irene, Colorado</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Only One Savior<br />
Isaiah 43: I’m the only Savior there is.<br />
I know that pluralism and tolerance are in, and, truthfully, I agree that these are a positive step away from bigotry and narrowness. I also know that we Americans have a lot to learn from other nations and cultures. Just my limited relationships with friends of Mexican heritage has both broadened my perspective and deepened my life. This passage, however, underscores the other side this issue. If there’s a place for open-mindedness, there’s also a time and place for narrowness and exclusivity. In this passage I hear the Lord speaking words of hope and comfort through his man Isaiah. I see that God offers us the gift of salvation. I also am told he’s the only one qualified to make that offer. I can walk down the aisle of Wal-Mart and decide which brand of peanut butter I prefer. I can listen to presidential candidates and pick which one I want to support. I can realize that the Oriental culture has something to offer that’s just as good as or maybe even better than what my own culture offers. However, when it comes to salvation, there’s only one place to go, and that’s to the God Isaiah’s talking about. The salvation he offers is abundant and sufficient for me and for every other person. Still, I need to know that it’s also the only salvation that actually saves. He’s the only Savior there is.<br />
Take Away: When it comes to salvation, there’s only one place to go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-151/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 11:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God keeps his word Isaiah 44: From the beginning, who else has always announced what&#8217;s coming? These pages of Isaiah are some of the most encouraging in the whole Bible. God has such good news for his people. Salvation is coming to their spiritually dry lives like streams flowing into a parched desert. This promise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2WwQ52km_0A/X_Nver6aB6I/AAAAAAABIIs/OsrymXU94mU_5YwrmSnVWhnLltutBgudgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9062273.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Dream Lake, RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God keeps his word<br />
Isaiah 44: From the beginning, who else has always announced what&#8217;s coming?<br />
These pages of Isaiah are some of the most encouraging in the whole Bible.  God has such good news for his people.  Salvation is coming to their spiritually dry lives like streams flowing into a parched desert.  This promise is so great that people can hardly get their minds and hearts around it.  To help them do that, the Lord puts his credentials on display.  He says he&#8217;s the first and the last and &#8220;everything in between.&#8221;  He’s always trustworthy and he&#8217;s the one who can speak about his future actions with absolute certainty.  I know some see this passage as ammunition for &#8220;God&#8217;s knowledge of the future&#8221; discussions but it’s more correctly seen as &#8220;God keeps his word&#8221; material.  The Lord isn’t passively watching events unfold and he’s not letting history proceed in whatever direction it happens to find.  This God is on purpose in his dealings with Creation.  As he speaks to a fallen Israel he has promises to make.  Salvation will come because he’ll keep his word.  How does God know salvation will come?  He knows it because he’s going to do it.  Generations later, God&#8217;s promise is kept in a stable in Bethlehem.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is the only one who can speak of the future with absolute certainty.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-159/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 12:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global Salvation Isaiah 49: Even if mothers forget, I&#8217;d never forget you &#8212; never. The prophet describes the glorious reign of the Messiah, looking not only to his distant future, but to ours as well. The work of the Messiah isn’t only to provide salvation to the people of Israel, but to bring, in his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Q6krwNSpB7A/X_4j8RHtmcI/AAAAAAABIL8/3GKNCpWyIbgG1R5MItwZTccatBb3Igm0ACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042173.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Global Salvation<br />
Isaiah 49: Even if mothers forget, I&#8217;d never forget you &#8212; never.<br />
The prophet describes the glorious reign of the Messiah, looking not only to his distant future, but to ours as well.  The work of the Messiah isn’t only to provide salvation to the people of Israel, but to bring, in his words, &#8220;global salvation.&#8221;  Of course, that’s good news for me, since I&#8217;m on the &#8220;global&#8221; side of the equation.  Isaiah envisions some of his fellow Israelites looking at their current situation and thinking that God has forgotten them.  Their lives are anything but glorious and, while they want to hear this good news, they can&#8217;t get their hearts around it.  To them, Isaiah says, &#8220;Can a mother forget her own child?  God has been Father and Mother to us and he hasn&#8217;t forgotten us.&#8221;  Israel has messed up in every way and her sin has had real, and painful, consequences.  In the darkness of those consequences she feels forsaken and forgotten.  But it isn&#8217;t so.  God reaches out to them with the compassion of a mother nursing her infant.  Israel isn&#8217;t the only one who’s messed up.  The world is filled with people who’ve had far more failures than successes in their moral lives.  Does this describe you?  If so, the message of this passage isn&#8217;t just for ancient Israelites; it&#8217;s God&#8217;s word to you, today.<br />
Take Away: The Lord reaches out to us with the compassion of a mother reaching out for her infant child.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-161/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[darkness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God reigns! Isaiah 52: How beautiful on the mountains are the feet of the messenger bringing good news. They live in darkness, separated from God and without hope. Then, off in the distance a light is shining. At first, it’s barely visible, but in time bright enough to create excitement in all who’ve longed for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XBOS52zydu0/YACMcxlILmI/AAAAAAABIMc/UkA18tN_mygvZhPz777ojkpp5EY-oPf6wCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042165.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake, Rocky Mountain National Park, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God reigns!<br />
Isaiah 52: How beautiful on the mountains are the feet of the messenger bringing good news.<br />
They live in darkness, separated from God and without hope.  Then, off in the distance a light is shining.  At first, it’s barely visible, but in time bright enough to create excitement in all who’ve longed for this darkness to end.  Then, coming out of that light is a runner, silhouetted by the glow behind him.  He advances toward them and the crowd gathers, wondering what’s going on.  They then hear him shouting something and the broken people strain to hear his words.  He’s shouting, &#8220;Good news, good news.&#8221;  With the light brightening behind him the runner races into their still-darkened camp.  The people are quiet as everyone gathers around the runner who shouts out &#8220;Good news&#8221; one last time.  He then catches his breath and cries out at the top of his lungs: &#8220;God reigns!&#8221;   At first the people are stunned, and quietly speak these words among themselves, &#8220;God reigns.  God reigns.&#8221;  Then, without really thinking about it, they begin saying those words in unison: &#8220;God reigns. God reigns.&#8221;  The chat becomes a shout as hands and voices are raised, &#8220;GOD REIGNS, GOD REIGNS.&#8221;  Their sins have separated them from God.  It seems that all that’s left is darkness and hopeless death.  Now, a new day is dawning, a day of salvation.  God is once again stepping into their lives. &#8220;God reigns.&#8221;  Thank God for messengers of Good News.  Praise God, who is God, reigning in our lives.<br />
Take Away: God reigns!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-163/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A strange way to save the world Isaiah 53: Who would have thought God&#8217;s saving power would look like this? If the pages leading up to this portion of Isaiah contain &#8220;dual prophecy&#8221; &#8212; that is, messages that apply to Isaiah&#8217;s current situation but will also speak to some future event as well &#8212; this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BVmRktk-5HI/YANA7qM-SiI/AAAAAAABINY/O1e5m-lW1uECg_vg92aTMKIXl8Hy9oavQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042156.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Alberta Falls &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
A strange way to save the world<br />
Isaiah 53: Who would have thought God&#8217;s saving power would look like this?<br />
If the pages leading up to this portion of Isaiah contain &#8220;dual prophecy&#8221; &#8212; that is, messages that apply to Isaiah&#8217;s current situation but will also speak to some future event as well &#8212; this portion of his writings abandon all but the future.  It’s the Messiah who’s clearly before the prophet now.  What he sees amazes him.  He knows God is showing him the promised Savior but in this vision the Savior looks nothing like anyone thinks he should look.  The Man he sees writhes in agony and suffers a horrible death.  Knowing the hearts of sinful man, the Lord shows Isaiah how a perfectly holy Man will be rejected and mistreated.  Even with that knowledge, the Messiah will be sent to save us, not by crushing our enemies, but by allowing himself to be crushed.  The words of Mark Lowry&#8217;s Christmas classic echo the words of Isaiah, &#8220;this is such a strange way to save the world.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Christ conquers sin, not by crushing enemies, but by being crushed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
