<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Easter &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/easter/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 02:43:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Easter &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-168/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 14:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering Servant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Life after death – what a concept! Isaiah 53: Life, life, and more life. Isaiah prophetically sees the Suffering Servant, the man born to die for the sins of the world. He also sees, maybe not with total clarity, life after death for the Messiah. From our common point of view following death there’s deterioration. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RRMrm1j80eY/YApg7vWSteI/AAAAAAABIPw/VvF8ZVQUwOIlVyjxbf2YJDVObOvPMYdLQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9032124.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Near Alpine Visitor Center &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Life after death – what a concept!<br />
Isaiah 53: Life, life, and more life.<br />
Isaiah prophetically sees the Suffering Servant, the man born to die for the sins of the world.  He also sees, maybe not with total clarity, life after death for the Messiah.  From our common point of view following death there’s deterioration.  Even as Isaiah describes the terrible destruction of the Suffering Servant, he finds himself talking about abundant life.  Our understanding of what happened at, and after, Calvary isn’t superior to Isaiah&#8217;s but we do have a clearer knowledge of those events.  Jesus goes to the cross and there suffers and dies for the sins of the human race.  His lifeless body is then placed in a tomb.  Then, early on Sunday morning, the after-death process is abruptly halted.  Rather than deterioration, life, new life, springs forth.  Resurrection!  That&#8217;s reason enough for Isaiah to conclude his mourning over the death of the Messiah with a surprising &#8220;life oriented&#8221; twist.  However, there’s even more.  As the suffering and death of Jesus is for us, so is his resurrection.  We have hope of spiritual and physical life beyond this world because of what happens at that tomb.  At one point Jesus says that he came that we might have abundant life.  That promise is made sure the first Easter morning.  Isaiah&#8217;s vision of &#8220;life, life, and more life&#8221; not only tells the story of the Suffering Servant, it’s our story too.<br />
Take Away: As the suffering and death of Jesus is for us, so is his resurrection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-186/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 16:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second coming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking back and looking forward Isaiah 64: Oh, that you would rip open the heavens and descend. Isaiah longs for God to move and bring salvation to his people. He envisions the sky splitting apart as the Lord comes in dramatic, powerful fashion bringing hope to their hopelessness and healing to their brokenness. Hundreds of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_km9Cd9SLJk/YCFfYYobWjI/AAAAAAABIcs/A_zrp50BQvcBM_FmuihCND_GQI89CtDqACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Smoky-mountains-national-park-Newfound-gap%2B5-16-2008%2B12-30-15%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Looking back and looking forward<br />
Isaiah 64: Oh, that you would rip open the heavens and descend.<br />
Isaiah longs for God to move and bring salvation to his people.  He envisions the sky splitting apart as the Lord comes in dramatic, powerful fashion bringing hope to their hopelessness and healing to their brokenness.  Hundreds of years later when that coming takes place its earthshaking indeed.   The Gospels tell us of that powerful event, especially at the crucifixion and the resurrection of our Lord.  However, this passage causes me to look forward as much as it causes me to look back to the first Easter.  Even as Isaiah anticipates the coming salvation of the Lord, I anticipate his Second Coming.  What an event it will be as Jesus splits the eastern sky and causes the mountains to tremble.  &#8220;What a day that will be, when my Jesus I shall see.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Never doubt it – Jesus is coming back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-28/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 11:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-28/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This angel got the job all the angels wanted Matthew 28: He rolled back the stone and then sat on it. This angel is pretty cool. He’s supernatural, coming down out of heaven. He’s majestic with shafts of light blazing out of him. He’s powerful, rolling away the stone. Then, what does he do? He [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15694" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15694" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15694" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5059350.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15694" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Looking out over Canyonlands NP from Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>This angel got the job all the angels wanted</p>
<p>Matthew 28: He rolled back the stone and then sat on it.</p>
<p>This angel is pretty cool.  He’s supernatural, coming down out of heaven.  He’s majestic with shafts of light blazing out of him.  He’s powerful, rolling away the stone.  Then, what does he do?  He has a seat on the stone he speaks calmly and reassuringly and matter-of-factly to the women.  It’s almost as though they don’t know whether to bow down to him or invite him out for breakfast.  Then the resurrected Jesus makes his appearance.  It’s the same way.  Here’s the victor over death, freshly raised from the grave; yet he greats them with a cheery “good morning” as though they are just old friends who happen to meet at the mall.  The women, though, know just what to do in this case.  They bow before him.  Jesus, still in an apparent light hearted mood tells them not to be afraid, but to go and tell the disciples that “plan A” is still in order and they&#8217;re to meet him at the designated spot in Galilee.  This first Easter morning is awesome &#8212; holy.  It’s also happy, joyous, and just a little light hearted.  It’s an interesting balance and the Church should do all it can to capture this wonderful mixture as it proclaims the resurrection of Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: It’s the resurrection that makes Christianity the happy, hope-filled religion that it is.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 02:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zophar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Life after death? Job 13: How many sins have been charged against me? In response to Zophar&#8217;s counsel, Job replies with some choice insults. He doesn&#8217;t need Zophar to lecture him. In fact Job already believes all the things his friend has said. Beyond that, Job assures him that everyone believes that stuff. Since Zophar [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hDUwvCQ7CYg/XycOKkYVsEI/AAAAAAABFrk/y_pCp-VHl3wSGedhiwpF6ifIa9bYGVLgwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_134900.jpg" width="1600" height="983" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Life after death?<br />
Job 13: How many sins have been charged against me?<br />
In response to Zophar&#8217;s counsel, Job replies with some choice insults.  He doesn&#8217;t need Zophar to lecture him.  In fact Job already believes all the things his friend has said.  Beyond that, Job assures him that everyone believes that stuff.  Since Zophar and Job believe the same thing (that bad things only happen to bad people) Job again turns his attention to God.  He wants to know exactly what sins have been charged against him.  Perhaps there needs to be an audit of God’s bookkeeping system so the error against Job can be found.  Still, even as he pleads with God to tell him what he’s done wrong, Job&#8217;s reminded of the uncomfortable fact of the unfairness of life in general.  It may be that Job has never admitted this to himself before.  It’s only as he sits here in absolute misery listening to his friends saying all the same things he’s said many times that he acknowledges that life isn&#8217;t as neatly ordered as he has believed.  Both good and bad people alike have plenty of trouble come to their lives.  It seems to Job that even a lowly ditch digger gets a day off once in a while.  Shouldn&#8217;t God make life easy for human beings who only have a short life anyway?  And, since our lives are so limited, is there something more, beyond this life?  Job has no Easter story to draw from, but even in this distant day, he’s considering the possibility of life after death as a way God might &#8220;balance the books&#8221; of life.<br />
Take Away: We know more about this than Job does; that ultimately the Lord will set all things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
