<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>glory &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/glory/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:36:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>glory &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-48/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 08:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satisfaction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learning humility Proverbs 15: First you learn humility, then you experience glory. Humility has to be learned because we’re all born thinking the world revolves around us. Unless I learn humility I spend my life, not necessarily thinking I’m better than others, but thinking that everything that happens should happen the way I want it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PyB4WtL8FvY/X3oyTvo8pSI/AAAAAAABG0Q/lT8Ngn6uykIuZBVQ2-X-HtuV9ewoTKj3ACPcBGAsYHg/s400/normal_rainbow%2Bfalls.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Learning humility<br />
Proverbs 15: First you learn humility, then you experience glory.<br />
Humility has to be learned because we’re all born thinking the world revolves around us.  Unless I learn humility I spend my life, not necessarily thinking I’m better than others, but thinking that everything that happens should happen the way I want it to.  For me to be humble is for me to realize that I’m not the center of the universe and that the world has no obligation to please me.  Beyond that, to be humble is for me to come to the realization the most satisfying life is not all about my getting my own way about things, but is, instead, found as I live with others in mind.  Jesus said that I’m to &#8220;love my neighbor as myself.&#8221;  The result of such a life, according to the wise man of the Proverbs, is &#8220;glory.&#8221;  That is, others will be irresistibly drawn to me and my life will influence them in positive ways.  Not only that, but God will be pleased with me for patterning my life after that of his own Son who humbly lived and died for others.  This proverb reminds me that the route to glory isn’t by my taking power and trying to shape the world to suit me.  Instead, it’s achieved by loving others and placing their needs at a level equal to my own.<br />
Take Away: Contrary to what we may think, humble people are some of the most influential people there are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-17/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Listening to Jesus pray John 17: Father, it’s time. This great prayer of Jesus has three parts. The first section concerns our Lord’s relationship with his Father. All that has happened and will happen is done for the purpose of displaying the glory of God, a glory shared by Father and Son; a glory that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15871" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15871" style="width: 768px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15871" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/P6199492.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15871" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Listening to Jesus pray </p>
<p>John 17: Father, it’s time.</p>
<p>This great prayer of Jesus has three parts.  The first section concerns our Lord’s relationship with his Father.  All that has happened and will happen is done for the purpose of displaying the glory of God, a glory shared by Father and Son; a glory that has existed since before the world began.  Second, Jesus prays for his disciples.  He’s going to depart, but they’re going to stay.  His purpose of bringing glory to the Father will now be their purpose.  Jesus prays that everything about his disciples will accomplish that purpose and that they’ll be protected from all that might distract from their mission.  Third, Jesus prays for future believers.  Again, there’s a prayer for unity of heart and purpose.  Our Lord prays that the believers will give evidence that Jesus is the one sent from God because of his love for us.  Jesus concludes his prayer by asking the Father to gather all believers to himself, where they can bask in the glory of the Lord, united in love for God and for one another.  This passage, my friend, is holy ground.  We’re allowed to listen in to a conversation within the Godhead.  We witness the Son’s communion with the Father and then, we’re invited into the conversation.  It’s humbling to be allowed in this place today.</p>
<p>Take Away: God’s people are considered “insiders.”  What an honor!</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love it when God moves in 2 Chronicles 5: Then a billowing cloud filled The Temple of God. Solomon’s building project is complete and it’s a great success. An impressive Temple is now the official place of worship for the people of Israel and all others who will come. The building is complete with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QEOzkzOYOB8/Xrc-uk8V4kI/AAAAAAABFAs/B3LGa6outb0Xsf7AAQhzS-JKHj7aqlINgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180706_112723.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Woodland, PA Campground</figcaption></figure><br />
I love it when God moves in<br />
2 Chronicles 5: Then a billowing cloud filled The Temple of God.<br />
Solomon’s building project is complete and it’s a great success. An impressive Temple is now the official place of worship for the people of Israel and all others who will come. The building is complete with the fixtures in place, the offerings ready, and the personnel standing ready to serve. Then God moves in. In a display of glory that hasn’t been seen since Moses climbed the mountain to meet the Almighty, the Glory of the Lord fills the Temple. The Presence of the Lord is so great, so real, that the priests can’t even carry out their assigned duties. Outside the Temple Solomon does the only reasonable thing: he begins to call on God in prayer. Today, I long for God’s glory to fall on his Church, for Him to come in such majesty that the order of worship is set aside and people begin to simply call on the Name of the Lord. Oh God, we seek, not so much the “billowing cloud” as we seek you. Pour yourself out upon your Church as you did upon the Temple so long ago.<br />
Take Away: The people of the Lord need to seek and, yes, expect, the Lord to fill our worship services with himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
