<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Worship &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/worship/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:38:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Worship &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-125/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 06:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Genuine Worship Isaiah 29: They act like they&#8217;re worshipping me but don&#8217;t mean it. Generally speaking, we know how to have church. While it’s true that there are various &#8220;flavors&#8221; of worship ranging from high church with rich liturgy to “low church” filled with individual expression, there’s beauty and impressive worship services across Christianity. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter center"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ISlPrYct-VI/X9KoVeP7cjI/AAAAAAABH2U/T2b2P1HAMVcE9C08SRqIjjWT9dJDx-8rACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB261367.JPG" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>
<p>Genuine Worship<br />
Isaiah 29: They act like they&#8217;re worshipping me but don&#8217;t mean it.<br />
Generally speaking, we know how to have church. While it’s true that there are various &#8220;flavors&#8221; of worship ranging from high church with rich liturgy to “low church” filled with individual expression, there’s beauty and impressive worship services across Christianity. The issue isn’t that some need to abandon their worship tradition and adopt that of someone else. Isaiah complains about how his contemporaries worship, but his complaint isn&#8217;t that they don&#8217;t know how to organize a worship event. They’re doing fine in that department. The problem is on the inside, not the outside. An impressive, well done worship service is meaningless unless the worshippers pour themselves into their worship. This is no excuse for shoddy planning, but it does force us to concentrate on what really matters. Isaiah says the solution is God doing a &#8220;shock and awe&#8221; operation on the worshippers. Is that what it takes for us to move beyond &#8220;worship wars&#8221; and get about the business of worshipping from the heart?<br />
Take Away: The Lord still looks for people who worship in spirit and in truth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-138/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 09:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God of Creation Isaiah 40: God sits high above the round ball of earth. The people look like mere ants. In this passage Isaiah pictures for us the God of Creation. This is the God who &#8220;scooped up the ocean in his two hands&#8221; and measured out the mountains. This God calls the stars by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P2FrNn3Y0U0/X-IaLK1tblI/AAAAAAABH9g/DXbKoLsKZCAJKqYe7z6Fx_8W4NNubNv3ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281805.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God of Creation<br />
Isaiah 40: God sits high above the round ball of earth.  The people look like mere ants.<br />
In this passage Isaiah pictures for us the God of Creation.  This is the God who &#8220;scooped up the ocean in his two hands&#8221; and measured out the mountains.  This God calls the stars by name and sits high above the earth, so distant that the inhabitants of this world look like &#8220;mere ants.&#8221;  The purpose of this passage isn’t to teach what I’ve heard called &#8220;worm theology&#8221; in which the human race is viewed as insignificant and worthless.  After all, once those oceans are created and the mountains put in place, God turns his attention to making us, and when he finishes he’s pleased with the results.  This portion of this passage isn&#8217;t about putting humanity in its place.  Instead, it’s about lifting our Creator to his place!  We aren&#8217;t talking about a tin god here; this is the God of the Universe, Maker of all.  This King isn’t the ruler of some little country off in some forgotten part of the world.  No king or idol holds a candle to this Creator-God.  I can never fully comprehend him but I can worship him.  This passage is a reminder of the greatness of God and a call to humbly bow before him.<br />
Take Away:  I can never fully comprehend him but I can worship him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-149/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[praise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve experienced an extreme make-over Isaiah 43: &#8230;a people custom-made to praise me. God has good news for his people. The destruction of the past is ending and a wonderful plan of salvation is being put in place. Things are going to change for the better as the dry times end and times of refreshing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/--BD6WF11zdk/X_EyFZZ0w-I/AAAAAAABIHU/Fxye6wRxOic8M5yzroM1NfRz2KrYvFFCQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9072320.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Old Fall Creek Road &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
We’ve experienced an extreme make-over<br />
Isaiah 43: &#8230;a people custom-made to praise me.<br />
God has good news for his people.  The destruction of the past is ending and a wonderful plan of salvation is being put in place.  Things are going to change for the better as the dry times end and times of refreshing come.  God will bless his people who, in the words of this passage are, &#8220;a people custom-made to praise me.&#8221;  Those who first heard these words never considered the possibility that those &#8220;custom-made&#8221; people could include anyone but their own nation.  We, though, have the whole story; how God&#8217;s Son came to us to remake us into new people, a people who are his very own.  If it can be said that Israel was a &#8220;custom-made&#8221; people it might be added that, through Christ, we’ve undergone an &#8220;extreme make-over&#8221; in which everything about us has been transformed by the work of Jesus.  The result of this &#8220;customizing&#8221; encounter with the Lord is that we become enthusiastic worshipers of God.  Our new native language is the language of praise.  For us, life isn&#8217;t a daily struggle in which we whimper words of complaint and need.  Our first thoughts and the words we most easily say are those of praise to God.  Israel was custom-made for that purpose and we&#8217;ve been made-over for the same thing.  We’re redesigned to praise the Lord.<br />
Take Away: My purpose is to bring praise, glory, and honor to the Lord</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-194/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Old Testament worship wars Isaiah 66: You choose self-serving worship, you delight in self-centered worship &#8212; disgusting! And all this time I thought that the &#8220;worship wars&#8221; started in my generation with battles between &#8220;traditionalists&#8221; and &#8220;contemporaries.&#8221; In Isaiah&#8217;s case the Lord is weary of all the &#8220;I like it this way&#8221; approaches to worship. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-no6gyVM05Wg/YCw3dM_ENJI/AAAAAAABIm4/6hegQf-6f6sIefN8yG9c8_YCwKXnWYHGACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034530.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Old Testament worship wars<br />
Isaiah 66: You choose self-serving worship, you delight in self-centered worship &#8212; disgusting!<br />
And all this time I thought that the &#8220;worship wars&#8221; started in my generation with battles between &#8220;traditionalists&#8221; and &#8220;contemporaries.&#8221;  In Isaiah&#8217;s case the Lord is weary of all the &#8220;I like it this way&#8221; approaches to worship.  He says that when I insist on worshiping &#8220;my way&#8221; that, no matter &#8220;what way&#8221; might be, it isn&#8217;t &#8220;his way.&#8221;  The Lord tells them that they can do worship in technically correct ways but because of their attitude, it’ll be seen as an act of sin rather than an act of worship.  What does the Lord think of my approach to worship?   As a pastor am I so wrapped up in keeping the program on track that I fail to give myself over to the act of worship?  It’s likely that only a pastor or worship leader will understand this, but I find myself in services wondering why the sound person doesn&#8217;t adjust the volume down a bit or if the head usher is aware that one of the regular ushers is out of town or if anyone has greeted the guests who’ve just slipped into the back row.  While I&#8217;m worrying about such things, the &#8220;worship&#8221; service is proceeding without me.  If I’m giving more energy to organizing and running the service according to my standards, whatever standard that might be, than I am in surrendering myself to worship, then my worship experience is self-centered rather than God-centered.   Isaiah reminds me today that that isn&#8217;t a good thing!<br />
Take Away: When I insist on worshiping &#8220;my way&#8221; that, no matter &#8220;what way&#8221; might be, it isn&#8217;t &#8220;his way.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-72/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 18:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our incense from Sheba Jeremiah 6: Your religious rituals mean nothing to me. They have church services and follow the time honored traditions handed down from generation to generation. It&#8217;s pretty impressive: robed priests, burning incense, sacrifices and prayers and songs. In fact, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with any of it. The problem isn&#8217;t in how [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rSs4I_YZqnM/YDwZAFv2YHI/AAAAAAABI0o/Hpaw68PWHdoZFo4Te_wUvVsDjbI5K3eqQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-12-2009%2B3-32-40%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1063" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Our incense from Sheba<br />
Jeremiah 6: Your religious rituals mean nothing to me.<br />
They have church services and follow the time honored traditions handed down from generation to generation.  It&#8217;s pretty impressive: robed priests, burning incense, sacrifices and prayers and songs.  In fact, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with any of it.  The problem isn&#8217;t in how they worship, it&#8217;s in how they live the rest of the time.  God says they&#8217;ve just been &#8220;playing games&#8221; and &#8220;ignoring everything&#8221; he says.  They respond by trying to jazz up their worship by bringing in some exotic incense from Sheba.  Can&#8217;t you hear it: &#8220;the worship service seems a bit down lately, let&#8217;s get some of that really good incense from Sheba, that&#8217;ll give us just the spark we need.&#8221;   However, it doesn&#8217;t work.  God isn&#8217;t impressed and their worship services remain as empty as before.  Listen, I&#8217;m all for fixing things up and I&#8217;m a firm believer in presenting a well ordered, prepared worship service.  Adding our version of “incense from Sheba” isn’t necessarily a bad thing.  However, that stuff only makes a difference if the worshipers are backing up their wonderfully choreographed and innovative church services with faithful day to day living.  Otherwise, the new &#8220;incense&#8221; won&#8217;t please us or the God we worship.<br />
Take Away: Being a worshipper of the Lord includes a lot more than just going to church.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-82/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 19:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The harsh reality Jeremiah 14: Preachers and priest going about their business as if nothing&#8217;s happened! Jeremiah is known as the &#8220;weeping prophet&#8221; because he speaks of his tears for his people so often. In this passage he says he cries &#8220;day and night&#8221; over their sin and the resulting destruction it will bring to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CGTrME1AmZo/YEk2A6E-KGI/AAAAAAABJeg/ujBpwUzr7KAlV9gVqztmaaJJCUvEvF_HQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bjuneau%2B-%2B%2B8-16-2009%2B6-50-16%2BPM.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; at Mendenhall Glacier &#8211; Juneau, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
The harsh reality<br />
Jeremiah 14: Preachers and priest going about their business as if nothing&#8217;s happened!<br />
Jeremiah is known as the &#8220;weeping prophet&#8221; because he speaks of his tears for his people so often.  In this passage he says he cries &#8220;day and night&#8221; over their sin and the resulting destruction it will bring to them.  He’s shocked and dismayed by all he sees: so much pain and suffering, so much sin and evil.  Now, another thing shocks him.  It&#8217;s the reaction of the church people to all this.  He expects at least for them to share in his tears over it all.  However, it isn&#8217;t that way.  Church services go on as usual.  &#8220;Wasn&#8217;t that an interesting illustration the pastor used in the sermon?&#8221;  &#8220;Yes, but he preached a bit long for my taste, however, that special in song was lovely, wasn&#8217;t it?&#8221;  Off we all go to our favorite restaurant for lunch, hopefully, we&#8217;ll get there before the Baptists.  Oh, I&#8217;m not really against good church services or Christians enjoying fellowship after the service.  However, Jeremiah&#8217;s heartbreak over lost people does speak to my heart today.  We&#8217;ve got to stop doing business as usual and find ways to impact our society for Christ.  Our church growth model is often more about getting people to switch to our church than it is about seeing people saved.  We simply can&#8217;t think we&#8217;re doing what the Lord commanded us to do by just having good worship services while so many are headed out to eternity without Jesus.<br />
Take Away: We&#8217;ve got to stop doing business as usual and find ways to impact our society for Christ.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-92/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 19:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preachers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Which church would you attend? Jeremiah 23: They preach&#8230;their &#8220;Nothing Bad Will Ever Happen to You&#8221; sermon. Jeremiah isn&#8217;t the only preacher of his generation. In fact, he has plenty of competition from preachers who enjoy large followings and enthusiastic support. Folks love their positive, uplifting, and encouraging sermons. No doubt, these preachers find some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HQKtJaDaiz0/YFZDWGeeWfI/AAAAAAABJnM/6WSHq0KnvQQnmwWgJgn3fyhNPHa-fdbMQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B4-37-00%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Which church would you attend?<br />
Jeremiah 23: They preach&#8230;their &#8220;Nothing Bad Will Ever Happen to You&#8221; sermon.<br />
Jeremiah isn&#8217;t the only preacher of his generation.  In fact, he has plenty of competition from preachers who enjoy large followings and enthusiastic support.  Folks love their positive, uplifting, and encouraging sermons.  No doubt, these preachers find some really good texts that proclaim God&#8217;s love for and protection of his people.  The problem is that their sermons are, in Jeremiah&#8217;s words, just so much &#8220;hot air.&#8221;  The people in their congregations need to repent and return to God.  The truth is that everything’s not going to turn out fine and bad things are coming, whether or not these preachers will admit it.  Can&#8217;t you imagine a family getting ready to go to worship services? &#8220;Where are we going to church today, dear?&#8221; the wife asks.  &#8220;I don&#8217;t know.  Jeremiah’s preaching nearby, but you know he specializes in telling it like it is.  I hear that the &#8216;Things are Great and Getting Better&#8217; church has big things planned for today and they have a terrific praise band.  Shall we go there?&#8221;  So, where would I go to church?  How entertainment oriented am I when it comes to worship?  I&#8217;m not suggesting that &#8220;gloom and doom&#8221; is always God&#8217;s message while &#8220;happiness and security&#8221; is always just hot air.  Still, I see here a reminder that there’s more to worship than a main course of an entertaining sermon with large helping of great music on the side.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes God-directed preaching isn’t all that fun to hear.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-44/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 22:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reverence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Lord is much more than a Friend Ezekiel 22: They can&#8217;t tell the difference between sacred and secular. It&#8217;s a horrible time for the people of Jerusalem. There&#8217;s threatening war, a devastating drought, and a collapse of civil authority. Down at the Temple the priests continue in a God-ignoring pattern, treating sacred things as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rF_uwJxpWYQ/YJrOODYEUmI/AAAAAAABKJk/fO0b--oFxjclZqcnlN9UASyAMFHERdLawCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2BCamping%2BTrip%2B-%2BGoose%2BIsland%2Band%2BVicinity%2B12-2-2010%2B11-47-35%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
The Lord is much more than a Friend<br />
Ezekiel 22: They can&#8217;t tell the difference between sacred and secular.<br />
It&#8217;s a horrible time for the people of Jerusalem.  There&#8217;s threatening war, a devastating drought, and a collapse of civil authority.  Down at the Temple the priests continue in a God-ignoring pattern, treating sacred things as common.  The Almighty complains that they profane him by trying to &#8220;pull me down to their level.&#8221;  I like to sing &#8220;What a Friend we have in Jesus&#8221; and feel humbled and honored at the thought that the Lord is willing to be my Friend.  However, I can&#8217;t help but think that the &#8220;friendship&#8221; model only works at one level.  This Friend is the King of Kings.  He&#8217;s holy and eternal.  My relationship with him starts with my bowing before him.  It&#8217;s he who takes my hand and gives me permission to stand in his presence.  If I call him &#8220;Friend&#8221; it&#8217;s only because he allows me to.  The priests of Ezekiel&#8217;s day treat the holy as common.  Today, in my blessings and comfort, I don&#8217;t want to make the same mistake.<br />
Take Away: I call the Lord my friend only because he has graciously allowed me to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shopping for religion Hosea 7: They turn&#8230;here, then there, like a weather vane. &#8220;Welcome to WorshipMart, your one stop shop for religion. Please keep an eye out for our blue light specials, you may find a very nice accessory to your faith for a low price.&#8221; You head over to the New Age aisle. Maybe [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vpozPUqf4Kw/YNtTAXNHppI/AAAAAAABKoI/lU9eeq15p-MxM7ABTguuytxwwLDzHsgowCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-05-28%2B20.27.46.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Saylorville Lake &#8211; near Des Moines, IA</figcaption></figure><br />
Shopping for religion<br />
Hosea 7: They turn&#8230;here, then there, like a weather vane.<br />
&#8220;Welcome to WorshipMart, your one stop shop for religion.  Please keep an eye out for our blue light specials, you may find a very nice accessory to your faith for a low price.&#8221;  You head over to the New Age aisle.  Maybe a new crystal will help you pray better.  The Politically Correct section has some interesting items, some of that &#8220;what works for you may not work for me&#8221; might come in handy when dealing with some of the more narrow people you know.  The Hedonism section makes you feel somewhat uncomfortable but you can&#8217;t resist some of the &#8220;it can&#8217;t be all that bad if it feels right.&#8221;  And then you head over to the staples section.  After all, when all else fails you might just want some help from God Almighty.  At the checkout counter the salesperson asks if you found everything you wanted.  You answer &#8220;yes&#8221; but you think, &#8220;I&#8217;ll probably be back in here before long, somehow this stuff doesn&#8217;t seem to last like it should.&#8221;  As you check out, you can&#8217;t find the last item.  That&#8217;s happened before.  Everything else is there though; you&#8217;ll just have to make it without God.  Anyway, your religion is no one&#8217;s business but your own.  Right?<br />
Take Away: He’ll either be Lord of all or he won’t be Lord at all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Amos</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-amos-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Amos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intentional worship Amos 4: But you never got hungry for me. You continued to ignore me. The people Amos preaches to are religious people. They&#8217;re faithful to attend worship services, to make the correct sacrifices, and to pay their tithes. The casual observer might conclude that they&#8217;re just the sort of people God wants. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BWJW_iFjbBA/YO3BMSS2xnI/AAAAAAABKuk/zo34wdcv0dY9cjQRHy8TNR_zaSCcGs06wCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P7228759.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Niagara Falls &#8211; Rainbow Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
Intentional worship<br />
Amos 4: But you never got hungry for me. You continued to ignore me.<br />
The people Amos preaches to are religious people.  They&#8217;re faithful to attend worship services, to make the correct sacrifices, and to pay their tithes.  The casual observer might conclude that they&#8217;re just the sort of people God wants.  However, that isn’t the case.  Amos complains that all they&#8217;re doing is putting on a religious show.  At the core of all their religious activities is, not God, but themselves.  Even as Amos delivers his sermons the Lord is acting to bring a stop to it all.  The fact is that God won’t be ignored!  He, who created me, demands that I focus my life on him.  That&#8217;s true in all of my life, and it&#8217;s especially true in my religious life.  The issue of what I “like” or “don’t like” is, ultimately, unimportant.  God isn’t looking at the show I put on.  Instead, he&#8217;s looking at my heart.  The issue in play in my worship activities is whether or not I hunger for him.  I want to do church “right.”  I want the worship services I attend to be well thought out and intentional.  However, beyond all of that, I want the Lord to see that more than anything else, my worship activities are a reflection of my hunger for him and of my rejoicing in his presence.  God won’t be ignored and a God-ignoring worship experience is a waste of time.<br />
Take Away: The Lord isn’t looking so much at how we do church as he is looking at our hearts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
