<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Song of Songs &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-song-of-songs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 01:26:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Song of Songs &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 01:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Night at the opera Song of Songs 1: The Song &#8212; best of all &#8212; Solomon&#8217;s song! I confess here and now that I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to do with Song of Songs. I can tell you this; my devotional journey through these eight chapters isn&#8217;t going to take long! As my beloved [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N0lknVi1RIo/X6mbUuRbSpI/AAAAAAABHjc/hPATGfho9KMci2CQEqYc5VUV4Nykp7XzgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/20garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Garden of the Gods, Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>Night at the opera<br />
Song of Songs 1: The Song &#8212; best of all &#8212; Solomon&#8217;s song!<br />
I confess here and now that I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to do with Song of Songs. I can tell you this; my devotional journey through these eight chapters isn&#8217;t going to take long! As my beloved wife will tell you I’m not the most romantic fellow in the world so this portion of Scripture doesn&#8217;t really resonate very well with me. I can write about the technical side of things though. Song of Songs is, basically, an opera. There are different characters and they interact in telling of the passion of two lovers. The woman, the man, and a chorus sing to one another all through the opera. The KJV doesn&#8217;t make this very clear, so, for us who were introduced to this book by that translation, this was a very confusing book. The Message, and most current translations tell us who is singing when and that helps a bit. Some have &#8220;Christianized&#8221; Song of Songs by making it an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. I’m not knowledgeable enough to debate the point but it seems to me that it&#8217;s more of a celebration of God&#8217;s gift of human sexuality than anything else. To be honest about it, I&#8217;m a lot more comfortable with the sexuality of Song of Songs when it’s left in that realm and not made into a spiritual allegory so I intend to leave it at that. Finally, Solomon is the writer and apparently the male character in the opera is based on him. Because of that, this book is also called Song of Solomon. When I remember how many wives Solomon had I have to smile and wonder which of his wives inspired this opera. However, I do understand that many of his marriages were political in nature, basically arraigned to seal some treaty between Israel and a neighboring nation. The actual identity of the woman is, so far as I can see, unknown to us.<br />
Take Away: We believe this book of the Bible is the inspired Word of God, so we read it and consider it even when we don’t fully understand it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t just fall in love with being in love Song of Songs 2: Don&#8217;t excite love, don&#8217;t stir it up, until the time is ripe &#8212; and you&#8217;re ready. The woman, who co-stars in the opera, is speaking to her &#8220;sisters in Jerusalem&#8221; and she has some good advice for them. She tells them to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jBZb-7H42RY/X6r3fb4wl-I/AAAAAAABHkM/a3Q89p4hnHoy-Csrb7mEJQWcKOoG1SkIQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/16garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>Don’t just fall in love with being in love<br />
Song of Songs 2: Don&#8217;t excite love, don&#8217;t stir it up, until the time is ripe &#8212; and you&#8217;re ready.<br />
The woman, who co-stars in the opera, is speaking to her &#8220;sisters in Jerusalem&#8221; and she has some good advice for them. She tells them to wait for the right time and for the right person to be sent into their lives before falling in love. Sometimes young women are more in love with the idea of being in love than they are actually in love. They get emotionally involved with someone who has a very different agenda than they do and the result is, at best, disappointment and a feeling of having been used and cheapened. Song of Songs is a celebration of human love and sexuality &#8212; and the two are very much linked. The woman who is loved by the King says, &#8220;The real thing is worth waiting for &#8212; don&#8217;t sell out too soon.&#8221; Young women across the ages have faced the temptation to do otherwise but to do so is to accept a cheap imitation that won&#8217;t last. In Song of Songs, the opera about love, we’re told: &#8220;wait, you&#8217;ll be glad you did!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The real thing is worth waiting for &#8212; don&#8217;t sell out too soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 01:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Real romance Song of Songs 8: Love can&#8217;t be bought, love can&#8217;t be sold. Romantic love is one of the highest of human emotions. The Song of Songs is a testimony to the power of romantic love plus sexual attraction. The opera pictures a man and woman who are irresistibly drawn to one another. She [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QjxtAaXKjYg/X6xcJ0p0-4I/AAAAAAABHlE/P7YxNN5dIYoASq3aLz5sSbLXc3dNzyjHgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/14garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>Real romance<br />
Song of Songs 8: Love can&#8217;t be bought, love can&#8217;t be sold.<br />
Romantic love is one of the highest of human emotions. The Song of Songs is a testimony to the power of romantic love plus sexual attraction. The opera pictures a man and woman who are irresistibly drawn to one another. She can&#8217;t sleep for thinking about him and he daydreams only of her. The imagery here is compelling and sometimes &#8220;R-rated.&#8221; The woman observes that love like this can&#8217;t be found in the marketplace. That is, it doesn&#8217;t come along every day. Our society has separated sexual attraction from real love and has, in fact, mislabeled it alone as &#8220;love.&#8221; The truth is that sex without love and commitment cheapens rather than elevates life. Song of Songs gives us the whole package. Since it&#8217;s all dressed up as an opera we might be tempted to dismiss it as unrealistic. It probably is unrealistic to envision the average guy and gal singing opera to one another; at least it doesn&#8217;t happen at our house! However, it’s right on in its depiction of the power of love, romance, and sex as God intended it.<br />
Take Away: Sex without love and commitment cheapens rather than elevates life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 01:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of love Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love! Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kcF20kAoXS4/X62rvAEuytI/AAAAAAABHls/P8eM6_KmFEM7VfaEIMzvY5K5TvOXHV4JgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/11garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>The power of love<br />
Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love!<br />
Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, although passages like this do remind me of scriptures like Ephesians 4 where I’m told that: &#8220;Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her to make her holy&#8230;and to present her to himself as a radiant church&#8230; holy and blameless.&#8221; That passage describes Christ&#8217;s passionate love for the Church, a love that takes him to the cross. In the portion of Song of Songs that&#8217;s before me today, the man describes the power of his love for the woman. In Ephesians I see the power of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. Whether or not Song of Songs is intended to connect me to Christ and his love for us, I’m reminded in this passage of the power of love and the sacrifice one who loves is willing to make for his beloved.<br />
Take Away: “Love” is, ultimately, an action word…real love takes action on behalf of the one who is loved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 10:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[talents]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Psychoanalyzing Solomon 2 Chronicles 8: Solomon built impulsively and extravagantly. From other passages we know that Solomon built other things, including his palace before he built the Temple. Some think that’s a bad thing. I think it was just practice. Still, once he started building things David’s son could hardly stop himself. In fact, Solomon’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HPs15i0HRB8/XrrhWJWrbII/AAAAAAABFBk/7wtSBCDgPPUGltmtUzeAYF5j-vwXJE6WgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_7144.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing the Pennsylvania Wilds &#8211; Parker Dam State Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Psychoanalyzing Solomon<br />
2 Chronicles 8: Solomon built impulsively and extravagantly.<br />
From other passages we know that Solomon built other things, including his palace before he built the Temple. Some think that’s a bad thing. I think it was just practice. Still, once he started building things David’s son could hardly stop himself. In fact, Solomon’s psychology is that of an impulsive overachiever. From the rest of his story, especially from the Book of Ecclesiastes and Song of Songs I see Solomon being consumed by one thing after another. At the beginning of his story he asks for and receives the gift of wisdom, now he can’t rest until he has mastered whatever it is that catches his attention. In fact, the same thirst for understanding that causes him to be a great builder and king will become his downfall as he becomes infatuated with the women he marries and then their various gods. I don’t think the Lord sat Solomon up for a fall in granting him wisdom, but I do think that the seed of failure was in it. In fact, I think that all gifts granted to us: natural ability, attributes, and talents have the potential of being a great blessing or the source of great failure for us. In Solomon, even as we celebrate his wisdom and understanding of an encyclopedia of things, we see a red flag of warning that there’s danger in natural abilities. These things must be continually balanced by an honest admission that we’re incomplete without God, who brings balance to even the most gifted life.<br />
Take Away: When the Lord gifts us in any way the wise course of action is to bring those gifts right back to him and place them under his authority.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
