<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>messengers &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/messengers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 15:55:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>messengers &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-161/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[darkness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God reigns! Isaiah 52: How beautiful on the mountains are the feet of the messenger bringing good news. They live in darkness, separated from God and without hope. Then, off in the distance a light is shining. At first, it’s barely visible, but in time bright enough to create excitement in all who’ve longed for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XBOS52zydu0/YACMcxlILmI/AAAAAAABIMc/UkA18tN_mygvZhPz777ojkpp5EY-oPf6wCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042165.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake, Rocky Mountain National Park, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God reigns!<br />
Isaiah 52: How beautiful on the mountains are the feet of the messenger bringing good news.<br />
They live in darkness, separated from God and without hope.  Then, off in the distance a light is shining.  At first, it’s barely visible, but in time bright enough to create excitement in all who’ve longed for this darkness to end.  Then, coming out of that light is a runner, silhouetted by the glow behind him.  He advances toward them and the crowd gathers, wondering what’s going on.  They then hear him shouting something and the broken people strain to hear his words.  He’s shouting, &#8220;Good news, good news.&#8221;  With the light brightening behind him the runner races into their still-darkened camp.  The people are quiet as everyone gathers around the runner who shouts out &#8220;Good news&#8221; one last time.  He then catches his breath and cries out at the top of his lungs: &#8220;God reigns!&#8221;   At first the people are stunned, and quietly speak these words among themselves, &#8220;God reigns.  God reigns.&#8221;  Then, without really thinking about it, they begin saying those words in unison: &#8220;God reigns. God reigns.&#8221;  The chat becomes a shout as hands and voices are raised, &#8220;GOD REIGNS, GOD REIGNS.&#8221;  Their sins have separated them from God.  It seems that all that’s left is darkness and hopeless death.  Now, a new day is dawning, a day of salvation.  God is once again stepping into their lives. &#8220;God reigns.&#8221;  Thank God for messengers of Good News.  Praise God, who is God, reigning in our lives.<br />
Take Away: God reigns!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[messengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m just an old lump of clay 2Corinthians 4: All we are is messengers, errand runners from Jesus for you. I wonder what Paul actually looked like. He describes himself as unimpressive, the kind of person you meet at a party but don’t remember the next day. Maybe he’s just being honestly humble here. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16087" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16087" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16087" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2627.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16087" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Meares, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’m just an old lump of clay</p>
<p>2Corinthians 4: All we are is messengers, errand runners from Jesus for you.</p>
<p>I wonder what Paul actually looked like. He describes himself as unimpressive, the kind of person you meet at a party but don’t remember the next day. Maybe he’s just being honestly humble here. However, he wants his readers to know that it’s his message that matters and not the power (or lack thereof) of his personal presence. He imagines himself to be a plain clay jar that holds a treasure of unimaginable value. To look at the outside no one would ever guess what’s on the inside. Here he is: a plain sort of fellow sharing an extraordinary gift with all who will receive it. This is such an important concept and one that resonates with me. It’s the message that matters. Other servants have other gifts, some quite impressive and often well used of the Lord. The bottom line, though, is that we’re all mere messengers, “errand runners.” On the surface, we’re ordinary or less. What we have to give is a gift beyond imagination. For my part it’s good to be reminded of my place in this grand scheme. I’m honored to be a “plain clay jar” used in the service of the Master. As I realize that the message is bigger than this messenger I’m reminded of my responsibility to never let my life get in the way of my message.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Message of God is more important than the messenger.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
