<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Zophar &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/zophar/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 03:43:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Zophar &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 02:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zophar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not a very pious prayer Job 11: Should this kind of loose talk be permitted? When Job finishes responding to Bildad he addresses the Almighty, Himself. His words in chapter 10 are that prayer, but it isn&#8217;t a very pious one. Job, in his misery, cries out to God, demanding to know why his life [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kDmuE9WOkJc/XyW16gYME9I/AAAAAAABFrU/qphBveHIC1UNPER-aeVlb7OyVIgNzNtJACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_134018.jpg" width="1600" height="902" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Not a very pious prayer<br />
Job 11: Should this kind of loose talk be permitted?<br />
When Job finishes responding to Bildad he addresses the Almighty, Himself.  His words in chapter 10 are that prayer, but it isn&#8217;t a very pious one.  Job, in his misery, cries out to God, demanding to know why his life has taken such a terrible turn.  He complains that, apparently, he’s accidentally missed some step and is being punished for it even though he has no idea of why.  If this is how things are, Job decides, it would be better to never live at all.  Zophar, but not God, responds to this prayer of complaint.  He’s scandalized; maybe backing away lest the bolt of lightning he’s sure is coming doesn&#8217;t hit him too.  In his thinking bad things happen to us because we deserve it.  This is no time to complain to God, it’s a time to repent and admit wrong doing so God will let up.  Listen, Job&#8217;s prayer is the right prayer here because it’s his heart&#8217;s cry.  God doesn&#8217;t want to hear us pray little fake prayers that pretend things about ourselves and our relationship with him.  He’d rather hear an honest prayer of complaint than a dishonest prayer of contrition.  It may be that we Christians have so narrowly defined how prayer should sound that we’ve defused it of much of its power.<br />
Take Away: A dishonest prayer is more posturing than it is praying.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 02:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zophar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Life after death? Job 13: How many sins have been charged against me? In response to Zophar&#8217;s counsel, Job replies with some choice insults. He doesn&#8217;t need Zophar to lecture him. In fact Job already believes all the things his friend has said. Beyond that, Job assures him that everyone believes that stuff. Since Zophar [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hDUwvCQ7CYg/XycOKkYVsEI/AAAAAAABFrk/y_pCp-VHl3wSGedhiwpF6ifIa9bYGVLgwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_134900.jpg" width="1600" height="983" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Life after death?<br />
Job 13: How many sins have been charged against me?<br />
In response to Zophar&#8217;s counsel, Job replies with some choice insults.  He doesn&#8217;t need Zophar to lecture him.  In fact Job already believes all the things his friend has said.  Beyond that, Job assures him that everyone believes that stuff.  Since Zophar and Job believe the same thing (that bad things only happen to bad people) Job again turns his attention to God.  He wants to know exactly what sins have been charged against him.  Perhaps there needs to be an audit of God’s bookkeeping system so the error against Job can be found.  Still, even as he pleads with God to tell him what he’s done wrong, Job&#8217;s reminded of the uncomfortable fact of the unfairness of life in general.  It may be that Job has never admitted this to himself before.  It’s only as he sits here in absolute misery listening to his friends saying all the same things he’s said many times that he acknowledges that life isn&#8217;t as neatly ordered as he has believed.  Both good and bad people alike have plenty of trouble come to their lives.  It seems to Job that even a lowly ditch digger gets a day off once in a while.  Shouldn&#8217;t God make life easy for human beings who only have a short life anyway?  And, since our lives are so limited, is there something more, beyond this life?  Job has no Easter story to draw from, but even in this distant day, he’s considering the possibility of life after death as a way God might &#8220;balance the books&#8221; of life.<br />
Take Away: We know more about this than Job does; that ultimately the Lord will set all things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 03:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zophar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getting away with it Job 21: They&#8217;re given fancy funerals with all the trimmings. Zophar admits that, for a while, evil people get away with it. However, he says, their good times are always short-lived and then everything falls apart for them. Job is having none of it. He replies that he’s watched things too, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F0Ni7_NZBII/Xy7BNnL5NJI/AAAAAAABFto/tNTPTrLvOVEJk1ygLkBo4bypTENXBeohwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/68679964_10156874716223717_9043602843491106816_o.jpg" width="1600" height="926" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Lake Ontario &#8211; Wilson, NY</figcaption></figure><br />
Getting away with it<br />
Job 21: They&#8217;re given fancy funerals with all the trimmings.<br />
Zophar admits that, for a while, evil people get away with it.  However, he says, their good times are always short-lived and then everything falls apart for them.  Job is having none of it.  He replies that he’s watched things too, and it isn&#8217;t very often that such people get their just deserts.  In fact, he&#8217;s attended their funerals and heard the lies said about them even as their bodies were lowered into the ground.  The big theme of Job&#8217;s story is &#8220;will a man serve God for nothing.&#8221;  Then, as things play out, we’re confronted with the issue of human suffering.  Is it possible that people suffer and it isn&#8217;t because God is angry with them?  Now, we meet yet another theme.  It’s the reverse concern.  If it’s true, as Job contends, that sometimes people suffer through no fault of their own, is it also true that sometimes evil people get away with it?  Is it possible that some enjoy all the pleasures of sin all the way to old age and never hit the brick wall of God&#8217;s judgment?  I think that before this ordeal Job was fairly comfortable with Zophar&#8217;s philosophy.  At least he hadn’t given it much thought.  Now, he finds himself dealing with the issue of how unjust life can be.  All the time God remains silent, allowing Job and his friends to grapple with it all.  For most of us, reading through these discussions is more philosophical than anything else.  Once in a while though, these issues become quite serious and they did for Job so long ago.<br />
Take Away: Some people live their entire lives believing things to be true that aren’t.  Once in a while though, we’re given the opportunity (or maybe “forced” is a better word) to get a fresh grip on “truth.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
