<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 1Samuel &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-1samuel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 1Samuel &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 23:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiloh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When God says “yes” 1 Samuel 1: Crushed in soul, Hannah prayed to God and cried and cried &#8212; inconsolably. As I begin reading the books of Samuel the first thing I hear is the prayer of a broken hearted woman named Hannah. Young women across the ages have longed for children and that desire [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-R-_tuJ9KqSY/Xb877HsByYI/AAAAAAABCkk/bVUw-yH2fmkLE5tfCo2vxzjA1voLBY1GgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3031.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oak Creek Canyon near Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>When God says “yes”<br />
1 Samuel 1: Crushed in soul, Hannah prayed to God and cried and cried &#8212; inconsolably.<br />
As I begin reading the books of Samuel the first thing I hear is the prayer of a broken hearted woman named Hannah. Young women across the ages have longed for children and that desire is especially true in this age, 3000 years ago. In her society much of Hannah&#8217;s worth as a human being is dependent on her ability to have offspring. Even her good husband&#8217;s efforts to make her feel better about herself fail. On a trip to Shiloh everything comes to a head. In her misery Hannah pours out her heart to God at this place of worship. The Lord hears her prayer and answers, bringing not only relief to this good woman, but the beginning of restoration to Israel which has fallen far from God. I wish I understood why God hears and responds to Hannah&#8217;s prayer and not similar prayers prayed by people just as good and just as miserable as she. I know that God cares for hurting people and provides strength and comfort for them, and, sometimes he says &#8220;yes.&#8221; The rest of the time, we do the only thing we know to do: we trust him with that which we don&#8217;t understand.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for the times when the answer is “yes” – trust him in the times when the answer isn’t the one we want.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiloh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Making the most of what God has given 1 Samuel 2: I’ll establish for myself a true priest. He’ll do what I want him to do, and be what I want him to be. The priest Eli is an interesting person in the story of Samuel. He presides over the worship activities at Shiloh but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L4ft7LaoFmc/XcDNis0oMYI/AAAAAAABCmo/aLg_gp481Y0V8jxUoDlP43N2mycoheb1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3037.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oak Creek Canyon near Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Making the most of what God has given<br />
1 Samuel 2: I’ll establish for myself a true priest. He’ll do what I want him to do, and be what I want him to be.<br />
The priest Eli is an interesting person in the story of Samuel. He presides over the worship activities at Shiloh but is a deeply flawed individual. He has some spiritual insights, but won’t control his own sons who make a mockery of spiritual things. At the same time, he’s entrusted with the young Samuel who&#8217;ll usher in a new day in Israel’s relationship with God. I want to cut him some slack because he lives in these days of transition but it’s plain that the Lord holds him accountable for his failure. I don’t have to judge him because the Lord already has. Eli is, I think, a person who has great potential that’s never realized. He has position, insight, and opportunity to make a real impact for God. Instead, he shows only occasional flashes of that and is ultimately told by the Lord that he and his family will be replaced by someone more worthy. Frankly, I think one reason I want to go easy on Eli is that I fear my life also sometimes fails to measure up. God has been good to me and blessed me in many ways. I don’t want to someday look back and see years of wasted opportunity.<br />
Take Away: Make the most of opportunities the Lord gives you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God moves first 1 Samuel 3: This was at a time when the revelation of God was rarely heard or seen. The negative momentum of the book of Judges reaches beyond its pages to the books of Samuel. Although there are a few positive pictures: Ruth and Boaz and now Hannah, in general, the nature [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OFOrSvvZwaM/XcIoFRcZ4DI/AAAAAAABCnE/YrVPeWf3HncxdK2UY0OXSHvRgyM_HqamgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9299781.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Chapel of the Holy Cross &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God moves first<br />
1 Samuel 3: This was at a time when the revelation of God was rarely heard or seen.<br />
The negative momentum of the book of Judges reaches beyond its pages to the books of Samuel. Although there are a few positive pictures: Ruth and Boaz and now Hannah, in general, the nature of spiritual life is in terrible condition. There’s a central place of worship, Shiloh, but the way in which things are done there is more discouraging than encouraging. Eli is the priest, assisted by his two sons. Eli is permissive and disconnected. His sons are dishonest and immoral. The fact that the people of Israel have a place of worship and that people are coming to worship there is somewhat positive. The fact that worship is led by the likes of these men tells us that things are still in a pitiful condition. But that’s about to change. The change isn’t coming because key people are deciding to seek and find God. It isn&#8217;t coming because someone is pushing the right religious buttons to bring fresh life to a dead worship experience. The reason that the spiritual sun is about to rise is because God is about to move and, in fact, is already moving. God is always the First Mover. He doesn&#8217;t respond to what we do. Rather, we respond to what he does. Revival will come to Israel because God&#8217;s going to bring it, and then, Samuel and others will respond in obedience.<br />
Take Away: It’s a wonderful thing when the Lord begins to move in new ways in a life, church, or nation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can you hear me now? 1 Samuel 3: Then God came and stood before him exactly as before calling out, &#8220;Samuel, Samuel!&#8221; It&#8217;s as Samuel sleeps that God first calls him. The lad hears the Voice of God but doesn&#8217;t recognize it as the Lord&#8217;s call. The old priest, Eli, (in spite of his failings) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nkdeVj0_oEw/XcOWFNEKIcI/AAAAAAABCoI/HOBTHhFl-OIFRoqYbEmoLSnvroYbmuw9ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3078.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Chapel of the Holy Cross &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Can you hear me now?<br />
1 Samuel 3: Then God came and stood before him exactly as before calling out, &#8220;Samuel, Samuel!&#8221;<br />
It&#8217;s as Samuel sleeps that God first calls him. The lad hears the Voice of God but doesn&#8217;t recognize it as the Lord&#8217;s call. The old priest, Eli, (in spite of his failings) solves the riddle. Something unexpected is happening. God is calling. I wonder how often God speaks to me and I mistake his Voice for something else? &#8220;Now, there&#8217;s an unusual idea&#8221; or &#8220;Where did that come from?&#8221; Samuel mistook the call of God to be the call of Eli. Have I misidentified his voice to be my own rambling thoughts? I&#8217;ve learned something about God&#8217;s Voice in my own life. While God speaks fairly often I don&#8217;t listen very often. It’s as Samuel sleeps, unencumbered with the thoughts of everyday life that God calls his name. Could it be that my prayers are so full of my own wants and wishes that I drown out God&#8217;s Voice? It’s as I pray with a listening heart that I’m most likely to hear the Divine Voice in my own life.<br />
Take Away: Prayer is as much about listening as it is about talking.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiloh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spiritual Springtime 1 Samuel 3: God continued to show up at Shiloh. God&#8217;s presence has been rare and, as a result, even those who desire righteousness have blindly stumbled through life. At our best humans are still pretty pitiful and, in this distant day, most people have no interest in striving for anything close to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-abIx4tEZa04/XcR9DyLMppI/AAAAAAABCoU/nERhjblgCgIX8wRuNfOW5DyQjGi-IpWtgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3081.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Chapel of the Holy Cross &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Spiritual Springtime<br />
1 Samuel 3: God continued to show up at Shiloh.<br />
God&#8217;s presence has been rare and, as a result, even those who desire righteousness have blindly stumbled through life. At our best humans are still pretty pitiful and, in this distant day, most people have no interest in striving for anything close to &#8220;the best&#8221; anyway. Because of that spiritual darkness dominates. Then, in the figurative and literal night God speaks to young Samuel. Even better than that: God speaks and then continues to speak. There’s something wonderful about the phrase, &#8220;God continued to show up at Shiloh.&#8221; It has the feel of springtime in it. After the long, cold winter, the sun is shining and new life is breaking out everywhere. I’ve journeyed through my share of spiritual winters: times when God seemed far away and unreachable. But I’ve also enjoyed spiritual springtime. Frankly, my experience was more like Samuel&#8217;s than I care to admit, because in my case, like his, I didn&#8217;t have much to do with the dawning of the new day in my heart. All I know is that, after the night, God showed up and then continued to show up. By his grace, I will be faithful when spiritual winter comes, but, oh, how I love the spiritual springtime!<br />
Take Away: Spiritual winter comes to just about everyone. How good to be reminded that after the winter season, springtime arrives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God won’t be manipulated 1 Samuel 4: When the Chest of the Covenant of God was brought into the camp, everyone gave a huge cheer. There’s war between the Israelites and the Philistines and the Philistines have the upper hand. In one battle 4,000 men of Israel are killed. What can they do to turn [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8QLvuPmGN2A/XcXyLYNi96I/AAAAAAABCwk/OByf8ZSCHOc26O1HlpB6eSo2_LMxH3ChgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3088.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Chapel of the Holy Cross &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God won’t be manipulated<br />
1 Samuel 4: When the Chest of the Covenant of God was brought into the camp, everyone gave a huge cheer.<br />
There’s war between the Israelites and the Philistines and the Philistines have the upper hand. In one battle 4,000 men of Israel are killed. What can they do to turn the tide? Someone has the idea of bringing the sacred Ark of the Covenant to the battle lines. Like the fictional German officers in the Indiana Jones movie these ancient Israelites think the Ark has power of its own that can be controlled by whoever possesses it. As the Chest arrives at the camp everyone cheers. Now they have the Power of God at their disposal and nothing will stop them. However, it doesn’t work out that way. On one hand, the Almighty clearly has an interest in the Ark of the Covenant. As the story continues that becomes abundantly clear. On the other hand, God is in authority over the Ark rather than the other way around. Bringing the Ark to battle doesn’t guarantee victory. They need God much more than they need the Chest. Today, as I read this story I’m reminded that in spite of the Indiana Jones movie, the Ark hasn’t been located and even if it was there’s not much chance that it could be used as a secret weapon now any more than it was in this story from the Bible. In my life, the key to spiritual power isn’t in my waving my Bible around or in my wearing a cross on a string around my neck or in my being anointed with oil. As it was with the Ark, those things may have value, but they’re nothing in and of themselves. It’s God who I need and I’m wise to remember that no matter how many props I come up with he won’t be manipulated.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is real and he insists I treat him as something other than some unseen force to manipulate to get my own way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dagon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Poor old Dagon didn’t have a chance 1 Samuel 5: They were shocked to find Dagon toppled from his place, flat on his face before the Chest of God. The people of Israel aren&#8217;t much more spiritually aware than are the Philistines. When the Israelites get into a difficult battle they think that bringing out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Cu0owVScIks/XcdywPJs7yI/AAAAAAABCw0/9xcFO4tzs0sg_u7sI3HQxvctGajU7onXACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3092.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Chapel of the Holy Cross &#8211; Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Poor old Dagon didn’t have a chance<br />
1 Samuel 5: They were shocked to find Dagon toppled from his place, flat on his face before the Chest of God.<br />
The people of Israel aren&#8217;t much more spiritually aware than are the Philistines. When the Israelites get into a difficult battle they think that bringing out the Ark of the Covenant will bring them luck. However, it doesn&#8217;t work out that way. They’re soundly defeated and their enemies take the Ark, their most holy relic. Now, the story shifts to the Philistine city of Ashdod, the shrine of the idol Dagon. Someone has the bright idea of putting their new religious prize on display there with their idol. After a bit of rearranging the Ark is in its new place. To their surprise, when they visit the shrine the next morning their Dagon idol has toppled face down before the Ark. &#8220;I wonder how that happened?&#8221; someone asks in an unsteady voice. Dagon is stood up again. The following morning the priest of Dagon peeks around the corner and it’s happened again! This time, though, poor old Dagon&#8217;s in bad shape. His head and arms are broken off and he’s once again bowing before the Ark. Something has to be done and the decision is made, not to start worshipping the God of the Ark, but to get rid of it so that they can patch up poor old Dagon and prop him up back in his place again. It sounds dumb and in a sense it is. Still, they believe in national gods and the God of Israel, in their thinking, can never be theirs. The Chest has to go. As I read this interesting account I’m reminded that everything in my life must ultimately yield to God Almighty. Also, God isn&#8217;t a good luck charm. He’s the real deal and he insists that I live in a relationship with him.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately everything in my life must bow before the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dagon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yuck, yuck, yuck! 1 Samuel 6: Five gold tumors and five gold rats Not only is the Ark causing problems for the Philistine idol Dagon some bad things are happening in their cities and in the very personal lives of their citizens as well. First, and reminiscent of the plagues of Egypt many years earlier, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zqXPjyDPT-Y/XchzdFkx9ZI/AAAAAAABCxQ/0X4pSZQn7D81G1Vw7lPkgvQ7jGut8XHWACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9299790.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Near Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Yuck, yuck, yuck!<br />
1 Samuel 6: Five gold tumors and five gold rats<br />
Not only is the Ark causing problems for the Philistine idol Dagon some bad things are happening in their cities and in the very personal lives of their citizens as well. First, and reminiscent of the plagues of Egypt many years earlier, there’s a rat infestation in the land. These nasty rodents are showing up everywhere and getting into everything. Second, there’s an outbreak of (ahem) hemorrhoids among the population. Knowing what happened to poor old Dagon, and having heard the story of the plagues of Egypt, the leaders of the cities of the Philistines want to let the Chest of God go even as Pharaoh let the Israelites go. Their priests come up with a plan that includes sending a peace offering along with the Ark. What an offering it is: golden replicas of the rats and (get this) the (politely called) “tumors.” Can’t you imagine the look on the faces of the people of Beth Shemesh when they open the bag containing those replicas! It all sounds weird to us, but from the Philistine’s point of view it’s a desperate effort to make peace with the God of Israel. I think people today still do some strange things in an attempt to get on the good side of God. However, it’s unnecessary. God has already built that bridge and all we have to do is “cross it.” (Get it? “Cross” it). No golden rats or tumors are necessary.<br />
Take Away: It doesn’t take golden rats to make peace with God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revival]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Caution, God at work here 1 Samuel 7: Throughout Israel there was a widespread, fearful movement toward God. The enemies of Israel, the Philistines, have had enough of the Ark of the Covenant. Not only have they had to repair their idol Dagon, things are not going well at all throughout their territory. There’s general [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zUYrfhU--oo/XcnESlL0RJI/AAAAAAABCxc/fVAYObUuye4DFCOntvEkr3sK0fLkSM_cACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3402.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Jerome, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Caution, God at work here<br />
1 Samuel 7: Throughout Israel there was a widespread, fearful movement toward God.<br />
The enemies of Israel, the Philistines, have had enough of the Ark of the Covenant. Not only have they had to repair their idol Dagon, things are not going well at all throughout their territory. There’s general sickness and death and they know that it’s related to the captured Chest. They decide to send it back and be rid of it once and for all. It ends up at the town of Beth Shemesh, but not without incident. Some of the locals look inside this holy relic and are struck dead for their irreverence. This causes the fear of the Lord to fall on that place. It also reminds them that God is real and not just the product of old stories. The Ark is moved to Kiriath Jearim, where it remains for 20 years. It&#8217;s during that time that people become more and more &#8220;God aware.&#8221; It’s been a long journey from the dark ages of the book of Judges to this point, but, once again, these people are becoming a people of God. The words, &#8220;there was a widespread, fearful movement toward God&#8221; are the result of God&#8217;s faithfulness to a people who don&#8217;t deserve it. Even though they’re far from God, he’s at work and the boy Samuel is part of his plan. When they use the Ark as a good luck charm, and thus lose it, God is working. Even when the men at Beth Shemesh treat the Ark in an inappropriate way and lose their lives, God is working, setting things in motion to change the attitude of the nation. I pray that God is working in my nation too. I pray that he’s doing things in places and in ways that I don’t even see, changing attitudes, preparing the way for a &#8220;widespread, fearful movement toward&#8221; himself. And, if he can use me in any of that I want to be available to him, a willing partner in his gracious work in my society.<br />
Take Away: The Lord sometimes works in ways unseen by us and only recognized after the fact.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not famous, but faithful 1 Samuel 7 They ordained his son, Eleazar, to take responsibility for the Chest of God. The Ark of the Covenant ends up in Kiriath Jearim, the house of Abinadab. Someone needs to be responsible for the Ark. After all, during the seven years that it was in the hands of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FxqdHlVW3bM/Xct5hyfeClI/AAAAAAABCyo/RcSzL7coRW4qRCUJetfQPy6BkR7NRVLoQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3404.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Jerome, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Not famous, but faithful<br />
1 Samuel 7 They ordained his son, Eleazar, to take responsibility for the Chest of God.<br />
The Ark of the Covenant ends up in Kiriath Jearim, the house of Abinadab. Someone needs to be responsible for the Ark. After all, during the seven years that it was in the hands of the Philistines tumors broke out among the population and when the men of Beth Shemesh treated it in an irreverent way they were struck dead. They can&#8217;t have the Ark just sitting around. Someone has to care for it. Abinadab&#8217;s son, Eleazar, takes the job. For the next twenty years Eleazar takes care of the Chest of God. We know nothing else about him. Not a single word from him is recorded in Scripture and he’s associated with none of the adventures of the Bible. He just takes care of the Ark. During that time a spiritual change for the better is taking place. Samuel is growing too &#8212; in spirit and in body. Soon, this spiritual giant will take center stage and will be the spiritual leader of Israel for decades to come. But, for now, God just needs someone to look after the Ark; to be a &#8220;place holder&#8221; for Samuel until he’s ready to assume leadership. Not many of us are &#8220;Samuels.&#8221; No doubt, God calls some to do the big stuff, and I thank God for them. Most of us are called to simply be faithful, serving the Lord every day, doing what he’s placed before us. It’s nice to be reminded though, that in this small way Eleazar kept things going for the good. His faithfulness held things together while God prepared the &#8220;big player&#8221; to come on the scene. I think that is pretty impressive.<br />
Take Away: What an honor it is to be used of the Lord, even in some small, unnoticed way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
