<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Temple &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/temple/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 08:07:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Temple &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-60/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sacred Space Ezekiel 43: Draw a picture&#8230; As a casual reader, one of the bewildering portions of Ezekiel has been, to me, all the measuring that takes place in the final chapters of the book. In his vision Ezekiel crawls all over the Temple measuring every nook and cranny, carefully taking note of every inch. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15295" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15295" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15295" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15295" class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Thames Cruise &#8211; the real London Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
Sacred Space<br />
Ezekiel 43: Draw a picture&#8230;<br />
As a casual reader, one of the bewildering portions of Ezekiel has been, to me, all the measuring that takes place in the final chapters of the book.  In his vision Ezekiel crawls all over the Temple measuring every nook and cranny, carefully taking note of every inch.  If I thought about it at all I thought maybe these were the plans for the promised rebuilding of the Temple.  However, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s the actual intent.  The Lord tells Ezekiel, &#8220;Draw a picture so they can see the design and meaning and live by its design and intent.&#8221;  Concerning the Temple the prophet is told, &#8220;Everything around it becomes holy ground.&#8221;  God had called the people of Israel to be his own, holy nation.  All the laws, rituals, and even the construction of the Temple had the purpose of helping to bring that to pass.  In this case Ezekiel is to rediscover the power of the architecture of that place of worship.  Ezekiel&#8217;s vision of the Temple is to remind his people of how far they&#8217;ve fallen from the holiness to which they were called.  It&#8217;s also intended to give them hope and call them back to God.  Ezekiel&#8217;s going to go right on with his vision, talking about the rituals and the work of the priests and the feasts, all with that same intent.  However, I&#8217;m still thinking about the purpose of sacred space.  The Temple wasn’t just built to be a functional place of worship.  It was to call people to holiness &#8212; a place set apart for the worship of a God set apart by a people set apart.  The layout and the furnishings weren’t just for practical use.  Just looking at the building was to create longing for holiness.  I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;m deep enough to fully grasp this, but I&#8217;m reminded today that as I read of Ezekiel with his tape measure that there&#8217;s more going on than just the drawing of blueprints.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for those gifted in the design of buildings set apart for the purpose of worship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Haggai</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-haggai-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 11:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Haggai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Changing priorities Haggai 1: The people procrastinate. The land of Judah reels from a drought: no rain means no crops means no food. It’s a serious situation. Governor Zerubbabel feels a shred of hope as he sees prophet Haggai coming to meet him. Maybe the prophet has prevailed upon the Lord to send some rain. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15514" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15514" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-15514 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57-1568x884.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/2013-10-09-13.08.57.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15514" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; David Crockett State Park, Lawrenceburg, TN</figcaption></figure>
<p>Changing priorities<br />
Haggai 1: The people procrastinate.<br />
The land of Judah reels from a drought: no rain means no crops means no food. It’s a serious situation. Governor Zerubbabel feels a shred of hope as he sees prophet Haggai coming to meet him. Maybe the prophet has prevailed upon the Lord to send some rain. However, Haggai disappoints the governor. He&#8217;s heard from the Lord God and what he&#8217;s heard isn’t about rain. God’s man says that God&#8217;s displeased with them because they’ve settled in to their homeland but haven’t yet rebuilt the Temple. The Lord’s complaint is that they’ve found time to make their homes comfortable but they haven’t found time to repair the Temple which lies in ruins. Now, this charge of God doesn’t come the first day they arrive in Jerusalem. It’s likely that Haggai arrived with that first group of 50,000 people who returned from exile around 16 years earlier. At that time there was considerable emphasis on rebuilding the Temple. However, other needs were pressing so the Temple project was suspended as the city of Jerusalem was secured, permanent homes were constructed, and agricultural concerns were addressed. Along the way people got used to seeing the Temple as it was. Now, a serious drought threatens their welfare. Haggai says the lack of rain is God’s doing. The Lord&#8217;s getting their attention. There was a time for them to deal with the necessities of life but when the time came for them to take care of the Temple they put it off. This little book of our Old Testament is all about priorities. Apparently, the Lord didn’t mind their focusing on dealing with housing and food needed for survival. However, their place of worship was also a necessity and the Lord expected that matter to become a priority to them when the time was right. Today, I’m reminded that the priorities of my life are in constant flux. What I need to do at 8:00 in the morning gives way to what needs to be done at 11:00. Like a river, life flows along. Because of that, I have to keep up with the current priorities of my life.<br />
Take Away: We have to keep up with the current priorities of our lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 12:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gospel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How not to win friends and influence people Acts 7: And you continue, so bullheaded. The ragged transition in righteous Stephen’s sermon feels so out of place. He’s been debating with the religious leaders, and winning, so they come up with a scheme to lie about him and get him arrested. The charge is that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15915" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15915" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15915" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15915" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>How not to win friends and influence people</p>
<p>Acts 7: And you continue, so bullheaded.  </p>
<p>The ragged transition in righteous Stephen’s sermon feels so out of place.  He’s been debating with the religious leaders, and winning, so they come up with a scheme to lie about him and get him arrested.  The charge is that Stephen claims Jesus of Nazareth is going to destroy the Temple and toss out the customs of Moses.  Stephen’s defense begins innocently enough.  For some reason he decides to recount the history of their people, from Abraham on.  Everything he says is plain vanilla, middle of the road facts that every Jew knows.  After several minutes of this walk through history Stephen arrives at the story of the building of the Temple.  Now those who have made the charge that Stephen says the Temple is going to be destroyed by Jesus sit up and take notice.  When Stephen reminds them that their own Scriptures state that God doesn’t live in any building made by man they, I think, decide he’s about to say the Temple isn’t important at all.  Although it isn’t recorded in this passage, I believe that people start shouting Stephen down.  That’s when he drops out of his sermon and responds by calling them “bullheaded,” “traitors,” and “murderers.”  His enemies don’t take kindly to being thus accused and the result is that the mob lives down to Stephen’s description of them as murderers.  I know I’m not anything close to being worthy of making a judgment call on this good man who, even as he’s being murdered prays for those doing the horrible deed.  Still, I can’t help but wonder if things might have turned out differently had Stephen responded differently.  It seems to me that when he gets into a shouting match with his adversaries that his opportunity to make any case at all is lost.  Again, I know I’m not in a position to judge here but I think Christians are almost always more effective in spreading the Good News of Jesus when they live servant-lives, humble and kind.  After all, Jesus said that when we’re rejected we’re to shake the dust off our feet and meekly move on.  That feels a lot different to me than telling people they’re bullheaded murderers.</p>
<p>Take Away: Likely the best way to influence people for Christ is to take on the role of a servant while avoiding calling them names! </p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 07:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m part of this story 2 Samuel 7: God himself will build you a house! For David, the sun&#8217;s finally beginning to shine. His long struggle with Saul has come to an end. The promise made to him when he was a mere shepherd has come to pass and he sits securely on the throne [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zgDaAlCFN4w/XgwJnR0H0vI/AAAAAAABDG8/QbW0Q_1bkbg0q1zFBYw0dPn1jll9nzrswCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129910.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
I’m part of this story<br />
2 Samuel 7: God himself will build you a house!<br />
For David, the sun&#8217;s finally beginning to shine. His long struggle with Saul has come to an end. The promise made to him when he was a mere shepherd has come to pass and he sits securely on the throne of Israel. Even the Ark of the Covenant is now at rest in the city called the &#8220;City of David.&#8221; David&#8217;s comfortable and settled and he wants the same for the precious Chest of God, so he proposes the first ever permanent worship structure, a Temple, for Israel. To his surprise God says &#8220;no.&#8221; It isn&#8217;t that the Lord&#8217;s against the building of such a place but this is not the time. Still, God&#8217;s pleased with David and he tells him so. David will become one of the most famous people in the world. He’ll reign in peace and when his days on earth are over it will be one of his own offspring who will rule Israel. Even as the Lord fully rejected Saul he now fully accepts David. His family will rule Israel forever. David doesn&#8217;t know it, but he’s just heard the promise of the Messiah. One of his descendants will be King of kings and Lord of lords. He’ll rule, not only Israel, but all of Creation &#8212; forever! I’m not a part of the people of Israel but, today, I’m a beneficiary of the promise God makes to David. That ultimate Ruler only hinted at in this passage is the Ruler of my life. How wonderful to read about an event that happened thousands of years ago and to suddenly find myself a part of the story!<br />
Take Away: All those who live by faith have a place in the story of the people of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 13:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Move right on in 1Kings 8: Can it be that God will actually move into our neighborhood? Solomon’s praying his great prayer of dedication of the newly constructed Temple. He understands that, while the Temple is an impressive house of worship, that God is bigger than any one place, even as beautiful a place as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-j0z_SYEdP3Y/Xjg76Yc6b5I/AAAAAAABDtU/L1iuk0gUB6EVlQkjuN_xAPjD8a7y47vKwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4492.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-medium" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; At Mackinaw City, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Move right on in<br />
1Kings 8: Can it be that God will actually move into our neighborhood?<br />
Solomon’s praying his great prayer of dedication of the newly constructed Temple. He understands that, while the Temple is an impressive house of worship, that God is bigger than any one place, even as beautiful a place as this is. With the thought in mind that God is the God of the universe and can&#8217;t be contained in any one place, Solomon prays that the Almighty will always be attentive to the worship done, and the prayers prayed, at this new Temple. He’s a wise man, after all God’s too big to really live among us, right? Well, not quite! Many years in the future God will do exactly what Solomon imagines being impossible. God will come to us. He’ll indeed move right into our neighborhood. As he does this, human beings will encounter God in a whole new way. And the story won&#8217;t end with the pages of the Gospels. God will come to us in the Person of the Holy Spirit, and in so doing, he’ll move right into the temple that is the heart of every willing person. He’ll not only be &#8220;with us,&#8221; but God, the Holy Spirit, will be &#8220;in us.&#8221; As impressive as the Temple is, and as lofty as Solomon&#8217;s prayer of dedication is, we have the privilege of God actually moving into the neighborhood of our lives today.<br />
Take Away: Have you invited God, the Holy Spirit, to take up residence in your life?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 06:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preparation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vision]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Passing the vision along 1 Chronicles 22: I wanted in the worst way to build a sanctuary to honor my God. But God prevented me. It was years earlier that David envisioned building a great House of Worship. The Lord blessed David for having that vision but he told David, “no.” David obediently yielded but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-oGG4GOs1ubY/XqnNeOyi3PI/AAAAAAABE8w/u4pt_xUG644L-k-NoHXkkXb0NKoG2I8TACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170628_103526.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Horseshoe Lakes Thousand Trails &#8211; Clinton, IN</figcaption></figure><br />
Passing the vision along<br />
1 Chronicles 22: I wanted in the worst way to build a sanctuary to honor my God.  But God prevented me.<br />
It was years earlier that David envisioned building a great House of Worship.  The Lord blessed David for having that vision but he told David, “no.”  David obediently yielded but the vision never faded.  Now, late in his life David begins stockpiling materials for the great Temple project.  There’s now a huge store of gold and silver and other precious building materials.  David has also identified gifted stonecutters, masons, carpenters, and artisans.  He’s still on the throne but he’s preparing for the day when his son Solomon ascends to leadership in Israel.  The King has a father-son chat with his son, expressing his great disappointment in not being allowed to build the Temple, but also describing for Solomon all the preparations he’s made for its construction.  Obviously, David wants Solomon to be infected with his vision.  Worthwhile visions are, indeed, infectious.  My enthusiasm is passed on to others who may actually accomplish more with it than I ever could.  Also, David’s preparation efforts did a lot to assure that it would come to pass.  David did more than dream of a Temple; he also did everything he could to prepare for its construction.  Without that key ingredient all we have is good intentions.  Visionary thinking includes not only thinking big, it includes real life preparation, and an intentional effort at vision casting.<br />
Take Away: All the vision in the world is worthless without real life application.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 07:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Levites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[servants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Modern day Levites 1 Chronicles 23: The Levites no longer have to carry the Tabernacle. Centuries earlier when Moses organized their ancestors the descendants of Levi were given the task of moving the Tabernacle and all its furnishings from place to place. It was a big job and it was their job. As Israel fell [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-94FIV3cFa2M/XqsyZgQ_QeI/AAAAAAABE9k/u9dVBsYQQ_0d2qaf2r7po4XDxEKQh6YswCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180604_192415.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Bear Cave Thousand Trails &#8211; Buchanan, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Modern day Levites<br />
1 Chronicles 23: The Levites no longer have to carry the Tabernacle.<br />
Centuries earlier when Moses organized their ancestors the descendants of Levi were given the task of moving the Tabernacle and all its furnishings from place to place.  It was a big job and it was their job.  As Israel fell into the idol worship of the Book of Judges the Levites were still considered holy men, although the application of that position was a pitiful distortion of “holy.”  Now things are coming together.  Israel’s in possession of the Promised Land.  They have a King who wants nothing more than to serve and please God.  Their days of wandering in both the physical and spiritual wilderness are past.  And the days of moving the Tabernacle, including the precious Ark of the Covenant are also over.  David, displaying his organizational genius, counts the Levites and finds that there are 38,000 men of age of service.  He divides them into subgroups and begins handing out assignments in keeping with the spirit of their original assignment generations earlier.  From now on they may not have to carry the Tabernacle from place to place, but they’ll be the overseers of the Tabernacle and, once it’s built, the Temple.  The priests, descendants of Aaron, will handle the sacrifices and such.  These sons of Levi will take care of everything else associated with the Temple.  As I realize how much David loves the yet-to-be-built Temple and watch as he puts these Levites in charge of it I see what a compliment he’s paying them.  I know it’s not the same but I’m reminded of the people who accept responsibilities associated with the Church.  Thank God for church treasurers, Sunday Superintendents, teachers, volunteer janitors, and many others who love the Church and faithfully give of their time, talent, and treasure.  These, I think, are the modern day Levites.<br />
Take Away: Never take faithful servants for granted.  They serve the Lord just a significantly as the preachers and singers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 07:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Levites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Security guards 1 Chronicles 26: The teams of security guards were from the family of Korah. I’ve read this passage several times in various versions of the Bible, but since the sons of Korah were called “gatekeepers” it didn’t catch my attention. Now I see them being described as “security guards.” I guess that’s what [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0dYqvtXFqBg/XqxsxN3cR2I/AAAAAAABE9w/TgNcJnsUoM86GZYy1L6eGPOhFSwG0iilQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180604_192722.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Bear Cave Thousand Trails &#8211; Buchanan, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Security guards<br />
1 Chronicles 26:  The teams of security guards were from the family of Korah.<br />
I’ve read this passage several times in various versions of the Bible, but since the sons of Korah were called “gatekeepers” it didn’t catch my attention.  Now I see them being described as “security guards.”  I guess that’s what gatekeepers are supposed to do: they provide security, seeing to it that all who enter are there for legitimate purposes.  King David is such a multifaceted person.  He’s a singer and songwriter and harp player, a skilled leader, and he’s a warrior who’s won countless battles.  In this case, I see him drawing from his “warrior” skills in organizing the Levites.  In spite of the peaceful conditions of the day David prepares for possible trouble.  Now, it might be that the sons of Korah are basically ushers who tell people where the corral is for their soon to be sacrificed lamb but I’m guessing that David also wants them there “just in case.”  I wonder to what extent, if any, this applies to the Church today.  There have been some horror stories in the news, and, obviously, a church full of people is probably viewed as an easy target by some very bad people.  I’m not seeing this as some kind of mandate, but there is, at least to some extent, a precedent here for a church to have at least some unofficial security.<br />
Take Away: Leadership involves, in addition to having a vision and sense of direction, the ability to think through the practical concerns of the organization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 07:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacred space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than a meeting house 1 Chronicles 29: This is not just a place for people to meet each other, but a house for God to meet us. David is raising funds for the construction of the Temple, which will be built by his son, Solomon. It’ll be an extravagant place of worship and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yNvk7xdL6zg/XrBss3H6tTI/AAAAAAABE_E/466fHKqY25MhPEFdDVmPzmreMheYzeTUACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180608_164339.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Silver Beach &#8211; St. Joseph, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
More than a meeting house<br />
1 Chronicles 29: This is not just a place for people to meet each other, but a house for God to meet us.<br />
David is raising funds for the construction of the Temple, which will be built by his son, Solomon. It’ll be an extravagant place of worship and the hub of the life of the nation. It’ll also be the place where God will meet with man. As the people of Israel grasp this lofty concept they begin to joyfully and generously give. “Sacred space” has always been important to the people of God. It isn&#8217;t that God can’t meet us out in the common places of life because he certainly does. It remains though, that setting aside times and places for the express purpose of encountering the Lord is not only biblical, but is spiritually beneficial too. Note that this passage doesn&#8217;t describe the creation of personal, private spiritual hide-a-ways. This passage reminds us of the value of having a place set aside for the purpose of cooperate meetings with the Almighty. As the people of God, we have much to gain by creating sacred space in which we wait upon the Lord together.<br />
Take Away: We aren’t intended to be “Lone Ranger” Christians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 08:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generosity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The children of good stewardship 1 Chronicles 29: It was all yours in the first place! Centuries before Paul ever writes to Corinth, encouraging them to give selflessly and stating stewardship principles, David lays out some giving concepts for the people of Israel. They’re raising an offering for the construction of the Temple and David’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5WYe7Qi4xhw/XrG8HFvkuxI/AAAAAAABE_U/oNUHO4104WEETeHels5eTdXYeUL97_WPwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180621_200215.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Kenisee Lake Thousand Trails &#8211; Jefferson, OH</figcaption></figure><br />
The children of good stewardship<br />
1 Chronicles 29: It was all yours in the first place!<br />
Centuries before Paul ever writes to Corinth, encouraging them to give selflessly and stating stewardship principles, David lays out some giving concepts for the people of Israel.  They’re raising an offering for the construction of the Temple and David’s addressing the Almighty in prayer.  He’s reminded that this nation began as pitiful slaves in Egypt, without a square inch of land to call their own.  Over the years God blessed them and now they can no longer say, “Silver and gold have I none.”  Still, in a real sense they continue to have nothing of their own.  All that they have has been graciously provided to them by the Lord.  As plans are being made to build a House of Worship it only makes sense that they return a portion of that which has been entrusted to them that the planned building might be constructed.  The people come through with wonderful generosity and David prays that this giving spirit might always be seen in their lives.  The result of all this is the Temple.  Also, there’s a wonderful spirit of celebration.  Great accomplishments and great joy: these things are offspring of good stewardship.<br />
Take Away: When the people of the Lord are faithful stewards of all the Lord has placed in their hands great things are accomplished to the glory of God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
