<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>God&#8217;s provision &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gods-provision/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 01:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>God&#8217;s provision &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Haggai</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-haggai-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 11:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Haggai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generosity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My attitude toward things that matter to the Lord Haggai 1: I’ve matched your tight-fisted stinginess. Jesus taught his disciples to pray, “Forgive us our debts as we also have forgiven our debtors.” Generally, I put about 95% of the emphasis on the first part of that statement. I certainly know I need the Lord’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15611" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15611" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15611" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/image-003.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15611" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Middle Tennessee</figcaption></figure><br />
My attitude toward things that matter to the Lord<br />
Haggai 1: I’ve matched your tight-fisted stinginess.<br />
Jesus taught his disciples to pray, “Forgive us our debts as we also have forgiven our debtors.”   Generally, I put about 95% of the emphasis on the first part of that statement.  I certainly know I need the Lord’s forgiveness for the many “debts” of my life.  It makes me a bit uncomfortable to realize that the Lord uses the level of my forgiving attitude toward those indebted to me as his measure of his forgiveness in my life.  In the passage before me today the Lord uses Haggai to deliver a message concerning current events in the lives of the people of his day.  They’ve been stingy in their support for rebuilding the Temple.  Now, the Lord says he’s treating them with that same level of stinginess.  They’re holding back in supporting the rebuilding of the Temple and the Lord’s holding back in his provision of rain for their crops.  I’m glad today for the abundant generosity of God.   His provision in my life greatly exceeds all that I do for him.  Still, there’s a time to be reminded that some of the Lord’s blessings to me are linked to my attitude toward the things that matter to the Lord.  Jesus teaches me to pray, “Lord, forgive me to the same extent that I forgive others.”  Today, Haggai adds that I should be able to pray, “Lord, care for the needs of my life in the same way I care for the place in which I worship you.”  If that makes me squirm a bit, well, maybe it’s supposed to!<br />
Take Away: Remember that some of the Lord’s blessings to us are linked to our attitude towards the things that matter to him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you think copiers pick up on our stress level? Luke 12: What I’m trying to do here is get you to relax. Most Sundays I arrive at church early, meeting with friends for coffee and prayer. Usually, as we’re praying I can hear the church “waking up” as folks start arriving. Generally, I like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15783" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15783" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" class="size-large wp-image-15783" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2860.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15783" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Day trip to Vancouver, BC</figcaption></figure>
<p>Do you think copiers pick up on our stress level?</p>
<p>Luke 12: What I’m trying to do here is get you to relax.</p>
<p>Most Sundays I arrive at church early, meeting with friends for coffee and prayer.  Usually, as we’re praying I can hear the church “waking up” as folks start arriving.  Generally, I like what I hear.  I’m a real fan of happy chatter, children playing, folks sounding glad to see one another.  Sometimes, though, I can tell that the morning isn’t going well for some.  They’ve met with some issue or another on the way to church.  Maybe there’s some family argument going on.  Others have things to take care of when they get to church.  They arrive and want to get past the friendly greetings as quickly as possible so they can hurry and make copies before their class begins.  I appreciate their dedication but wish I could get them to relax a bit.  In the passage I’m reading today Jesus notes that some people are always worried about one thing or another.  His examples aren’t just frivolous stuff either.  They’re concerned about having food to eat and clothes to wear.  In soothing tones our Lord points to how God supplies the needs of nature and assures them that they’re more valuable to him than all else.  I understand that life brings unexpected, last minute concerns to us so I’m not being critical of those folks who anxiously wait for the copier to warm up.  Still, I have the idea that their day will go much better if they’ll make it their practice to join us in prayer, enjoying some quiet time in the presence of the Lord before launching into a busy Sunday morning.</p>
<p>Take Away: If I view the Lord as a stern unyielding judge I have every reason to be stressed – if I see him as my loving Heavenly Father I can rest in the assurance of his provision for me.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 18:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last word Exodus 2: Take this baby and nurse him for me. I’ll pay you. Moses is not only born into slavery, he’s also condemned at birth. In a callous effort to stem the booming population growth of the Israelites Pharaoh has ordered the execution of all boys born to the slaves. When his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nIIqY0EpLT8/XO2zC1Bg4rI/AAAAAAAA7yo/8HN983cMUpM6r199tc1wUvM3rmSDXLj3wCKgBGAs/s1600/image-017.jpg" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Pride RV Resort &#8211; Maggie Valley, NC</figcaption></figure>
<p>The last word<br />
Exodus 2: Take this baby and nurse him for me. I’ll pay you.<br />
Moses is not only born into slavery, he’s also condemned at birth. In a callous effort to stem the booming population growth of the Israelites Pharaoh has ordered the execution of all boys born to the slaves. When his mother can hide him no longer Moses is placed in a small basket that will float and hidden among the reeds along the river. His older sister Miriam is given the task of watching over him from a distance. Apparently, the idea is to hide the baby by day and then retrieve him at night. In a surprising twist that is characteristic of the Lord’s work, it’s Pharaoh’s own daughter who discovers the baby. Then, making things even more delightful, quick thinking Miriam offers to find a nanny for the baby. She goes directly to her mother who’s given the job. Instead of seeing her baby murdered, Moses’ mom is paid to raise her own son who&#8217;s now under the protection of the house of Pharaoh! I love stuff like this and, apparently, so does God. He loves taking impossible situations and turning them upside down. As I read this story today I’m reminded that God always has the last word even in the darkest of nights. In my life, it won’t be the writer of my obituary who’ll have the last word – it’ll be him.<br />
Take Away: God has the last word even when everything seems to be going wrong.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 22:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stinking blessings Exodus 16: It got wormy and smelled bad. It doesn’t take long for the 600,000 people to go through their food supply. Now, they’re out in the wilderness and wondering where their next meal will come from. One of the methods used by the Lord to meet this need is the introduction of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nBNfQo5eHL0/XQbvO6-6kEI/AAAAAAAA8PA/BMckV-2MPpwhxoog7vUL9iVuuUiG0cMgQCKgBGAs/s1600/P5029298.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
Stinking blessings<br />
Exodus 16: It got wormy and smelled bad.<br />
It doesn’t take long for the 600,000 people to go through their food supply.  Now, they’re out in the wilderness and wondering where their next meal will come from.  One of the methods used by the Lord to meet this need is the introduction of a unique food source.  It appears like the morning dew, tasting like bread and honey.  Each morning the people literally “pick up” their breakfast.  Thus begins what will be an ongoing provision of the Lord that will continue for four decades.  Except for the Sabbath, each morning begins with their going out to receive this blessing of the Lord.  Right off some people try to hoard this heavenly bread, but that turns out to be a bad idea as day old manna gets wormy and stinks.  This blessing from the Lord can’t be stored up.  Instead, it has to be received anew each day.  Centuries later Jesus will teach his followers to ask their Father for their “daily bread.” This reminds us that, even as it was for the Israelites, the Lord provides but that each day requires a renewed trust from us.  I’m not against hearing folks share precious memories from days gone by, but as I watch these Israelites collecting their manna, I’m reminded that if yesterday’s blessing’s all I’ve got, well, I haven’t got much.<br />
Take Away: God’s blessings are made new in our lives every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 23:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God will go before you Exodus 23: I won’t get rid of them all at once lest the land grow up in weeds and the wild animals take over. The Lord promises his people that he’ll not only be with them but will also go before them. Before they ever arrive in Canaan the Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/--C128c7I8ms/XRA9HUtFUSI/AAAAAAAA8Zg/_Dzec-Z5WzAXGLISaPOuINBCPmLJQtFBgCKgBGAs/s1600/P5069414.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Canyonlands National Park, UT</figcaption></figure><br />
God will go before you<br />
Exodus 23: I won’t get rid of them all at once lest the land grow up in weeds and the wild animals take over.<br />
The Lord promises his people that he’ll not only be with them but will also go before them.  Before they ever arrive in Canaan the Lord will already be at work there, preparing the way for them.  The inhabitants of that land will be visited by “Terror” and “Despair.”  Just the thought of the coming Israelites will cause them to withdraw, yielding the land to them without a fight.  However, the Lord also tells them that the withdrawal of these heathen people won’t happen all at once.  If all human beings desert the land then the weeds and wild animals will take over and Canaan land won’t be as wonderful as the Lord wants it to be for his people.  While I know it didn’t work out, I can’t help but imagine a very different picture from both the books of Joshua and Judges.  As I consider this passage I find myself thinking of God’s work in my life.  As one of God’s people I have some precious promises.  He’s with me and he’ll make a way even when there is no way.  However, that doesn’t mean all the battles are already won.  Like the people of Israel, I’m to trust in the Lord and to move forward, believing that, by his grace, I can face whatever obstacles might arise.  It would be nice if all the signal lights in my life were permanently on green even as I sit in the driveway, but it doesn’t work that way.  I have to move out in trust and allow the Lord to help me through the rough areas one step at a time.<br />
Take Away: God’s work in my life is that of unfolding grace, him making the way for me, one day at a time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 23:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Covenants Exodus 24: Then he took the Book of the Covenant and read it as the people listened. They said, “Everything God said, we’ll do. Yes, we’ll obey.” Things are coming together for this nation of ex-slaves. They’ve been delivered from the bondage of Egypt, are receiving constant guidance from the Lord who is also [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DKfFD2uFEUI/XRA94VMJw8I/AAAAAAAA8Zo/29sN0OeGa4UncgNRH6G9lBn1Klb4TAk3QCKgBGAs/s1600/P5069396.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Canyonlands National Park, UT</figcaption></figure><br />
Covenants<br />
Exodus 24: Then he took the Book of the Covenant and read it as the people listened.  They said, “Everything God said, we’ll do.  Yes, we’ll obey.”<br />
Things are coming together for this nation of ex-slaves.  They’ve been delivered from the bondage of Egypt, are receiving constant guidance from the Lord who is also providing their needs.  Now the rules for living have been laid out.  Soon, God, Himself, will write out the basics on tablets of stone.  To their credit, the people are ready.  They pledge themselves to obedience.  Now, you and I know that this isn’t going to work out.  God’s faithfulness to them will be contrasted by their failure to keep the Covenant. Still, God isn’t setting them up to fail.  In this Covenant we see all the potential for success.  Their failure in breaking the Covenant is what stops the plan from being a success.  Hundreds of years later God will initiate another plan.  You know it: “For God so loved the world that he gave his only begotten Son….”  Once again, and in an even more complete way, everything&#8217;s in place for success.  And, once again God’s part is perfect.  In fact, he&#8217;s even gone so far as to provide us the grace to make the same commitment they made.  Now, Heaven awaits our response to the New Covenant.<br />
Take Away: We have every reason in the world to live victorious, godly lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 12:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[He never has failed me yet Deuteronomy 8: So it&#8217;s paramount that you keep the commandments of God…walk down the roads he shows you and reverently respect him. The road God has led them down has not always been easy. At times, they&#8217;ve been pushed to the limit. Still, in all of it God proved [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4_PMLTRzYy0/XWr-FHkb5ZI/AAAAAAABAzo/uLCTM6oWDLIv5CmgCZqyeo5xnWTO-WNFACKgBGAs/s1600/100_3123.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR</figcaption></figure><br />
He never has failed me yet<br />
Deuteronomy 8: So it&#8217;s paramount that you keep the commandments of God…walk down the roads he shows you and reverently respect him.<br />
The road God has led them down has not always been easy.  At times, they&#8217;ve been pushed to the limit.  Still, in all of it God proved faithful.  There has been manna from heaven, perpetual clothes and shoes, and many other direct evidences of God&#8217;s steady faithfulness.  The fact of the matter is that while their wilderness journey is about to end, there are more times of testing to come.  Those same giants that scared their parents off 40 years earlier still live down the road a few miles ahead.  The cities are still fortified and the armies there are still superior.  Moses says they need to learn from the past as they move to the future.  I’m reminded today that sometimes God leads me down roads that scare me to death!  Still, as the old song says, &#8220;He never has failed me yet.&#8221;  With that in mind, I walk down the roads he shows me.  If he says, &#8220;go&#8221; that means he&#8217;ll go with me and make a way even when I can&#8217;t imagine how it can all work out.<br />
Take Away: The Lord never leads us where he doesn’t go with us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Joshua</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-joshua-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 17:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Joshua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manna]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Give us this day our daily bread. Joshua 5: As soon as they started eating food grown in the land, there was no more manna for the People of Israel. All their lives they&#8217;ve eaten manna that appears every morning. It’s God&#8217;s provision for them, meeting their needs in places and under circumstances in which [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KTuFT6w4Wrk/XYkztE3BtLI/AAAAAAABBd8/Wqk61evnQYc2VHCQMeLpFRQ8boEMdbBLgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8019694.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure><br />
Give us this day our daily bread.<br />
Joshua 5: As soon as they started eating food grown in the land, there was no more manna for the People of Israel.<br />
All their lives they&#8217;ve eaten manna that appears every morning.  It’s God&#8217;s provision for them, meeting their needs in places and under circumstances in which that need could be met in no other way. They eat other things too but it’s manna that’s the staple in their diet. Now they have a toe hold on the land God promised to them.  There’s much to be done: wars to be fought, land to be claimed, but finally they are here.  Apparently, they’ve camped at Gilgal long enough to plant and harvest their first crop of grain.  What a great Passover, remembering not only deliverance from Egypt but also now beginning to receive the land God promised them.  With the harvest of this first Canaan crop the manna stops.  The end of the manna isn&#8217;t an indication that God’s no longer going to provide for them.  It’s simply a change in how he’s going to do it.  Now the Lord’s providing for them in a new (only to them) way.  Sometimes God does things in miraculous ways but most of the time he uses common tools for that purpose.   Either way, it’s God who’s supplying the need.  This concept works not only with manna and crops, but also with my health, job, and the many other concerns of life.  I thank God for &#8220;the manna&#8221; but also for the ordinary, everyday provision for life.<br />
Take Away: The Lord does, indeed, “give us this day our daily bread.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 01:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By God’s help we can live steady, Christ-like lives 1 Samuel 7: Samuel gave solid leadership to Israel his entire life. This is a powerful and important statement about Samuel. Only rarely do we encounter such high credentials, even in the Bible. Abraham messed up by trying to &#8220;help&#8221; God in his relationship with Hagar. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EyGCEjJt1JU/Xc9gz17IehI/AAAAAAABC1w/mNmzrzfjJlIJ2ONPNNNq6MZpafmPU2TOwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3512.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; McDonald Observatory &#8211; Fort Davis, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>By God’s help we can live steady, Christ-like lives<br />
1 Samuel 7: Samuel gave solid leadership to Israel his entire life.<br />
This is a powerful and important statement about Samuel. Only rarely do we encounter such high credentials, even in the Bible. Abraham messed up by trying to &#8220;help&#8221; God in his relationship with Hagar. Moses failed at the Waters of Meribah Kadesh. Just about all the heroes of the Bible have blots on their records. But it’s not so with Samuel. From the time that as a lad serving in the house of God at Shiloh he hears God&#8217;s Voice to the end of his life Samuel is faithful. As a result, some of the golden days of the Old Testament are before us in our Scripture reading. Of course, this is actually a God-story more than it is a Samuel-story. It’s God who answers Hannah&#8217;s prayer that brings Samuel into the world in the first place. It’s God who initiates contact with the boy Samuel. And it’s God who continues to lead Samuel even as Samuel leads Israel. We see today that spiritual failure doesn’t have to be part of anyone&#8217;s story. I know it’s true that just about everyone has a story of spiritual breakdown, but here we see that the Lord’s able to keep us as we allow him to work freely in our lives. Isn’t it wonderful to be reminded that because the grace of the Lord is freely available to us that we don’t have to stumble our way through life hoping we can hold it together just enough to squeeze through the Pearly Gates at the finish line of life?<br />
Take Away: The Lord provides us everything we need to live faithful, victorious Christian lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 01:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Transformed 1 Samuel 10: The Spirit of God will come on you&#8230;and you&#8217;ll be transformed. You&#8217;ll be a new person. Beyond Saul’s natural advantages is the stated intention of God Almighty to make him into one of the heroes of the Bible. This big man is humble and practical and will be used by God [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9NmLcZw_FGU/XdMZgd1v8uI/AAAAAAABC3I/avN8SfWIfYkUBpidkF3cUl8HKXR7KRIFgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3545.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Davis Mountains State Park, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Transformed<br />
1 Samuel 10: The Spirit of God will come on you&#8230;and you&#8217;ll be transformed. You&#8217;ll be a new person.<br />
Beyond Saul’s natural advantages is the stated intention of God Almighty to make him into one of the heroes of the Bible. This big man is humble and practical and will be used by God in wonderful ways. What Saul lacks, his shyness and his inexperience as a spiritual leader, is recognized by the Lord so right off the Lord goes to work there. Samuel says that before the day is out Saul will be transformed into a man who openly worships God, one who can be numbered among the prophets. Failure is coming to Saul, but not because God just tossed him into the water to sink or swim. The same God who chooses him also enables him for the task. That’s still true today. What the Lord calls me to be enables me to be. There’s clearly more to be said about that, but this is a truth that’s made real in the lives of all that hear God&#8217;s call.<br />
Take Away: Those the Lord calls he also equips.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
