<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>love &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/love/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>love &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-29/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pleasure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God, enjoying life with me Ecclesiastes 9: God takes pleasure in your pleasure! I know that a common view of God is that he’s against our enjoying life and that his favorite word is &#8220;no!&#8221; That is very mistaken. It’s true that God has a lot of &#8220;no&#8217;s&#8221; for us. Then again, a loving father [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Etu99NDEFyI/X6GrupN2hMI/AAAAAAABHeA/Z3yJLjgcvVsLMGUAabOAGHAMwc_tpSyrQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/07georgetown.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Georgetown, Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
God, enjoying life with me<br />
Ecclesiastes 9: God takes pleasure in your pleasure!<br />
I know that a common view of God is that he’s against our enjoying life and that his favorite word is &#8220;no!&#8221;  That is very mistaken.  It’s true that God has a lot of &#8220;no&#8217;s&#8221; for us.  Then again, a loving father has a lot of &#8220;no&#8217;s&#8221; for his children too.  When his toddler picks something up off the floor and is about to put it in his mouth his mom and dad say, in chorus: &#8220;No!&#8221;  Their desire is not to ruin his life, but to protect him from something that might be downright hazardous to his health.  Even so, the Lord has some prohibitions for us and every one of them is for our benefit.  The other side of the coin is wonderfully positive.  When I enjoy some new discovery, or take pleasure in one of God&#8217;s many gifts to me; when I laugh out loud as one of my precious grandchildren comes up with a terrific one liner &#8212; at that moment God laughs with me.   The writer of Ecclesiastes struggles with the meaning of life and is trying to understand just what it is that will bring real satisfaction.  However, he has this one just right: &#8220;God takes pleasure in your pleasure!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: All the joys of life come from our Heavenly Father who takes pleasure in our pleasure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 01:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Night at the opera Song of Songs 1: The Song &#8212; best of all &#8212; Solomon&#8217;s song! I confess here and now that I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to do with Song of Songs. I can tell you this; my devotional journey through these eight chapters isn&#8217;t going to take long! As my beloved [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N0lknVi1RIo/X6mbUuRbSpI/AAAAAAABHjc/hPATGfho9KMci2CQEqYc5VUV4Nykp7XzgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/20garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Garden of the Gods, Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>Night at the opera<br />
Song of Songs 1: The Song &#8212; best of all &#8212; Solomon&#8217;s song!<br />
I confess here and now that I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to do with Song of Songs. I can tell you this; my devotional journey through these eight chapters isn&#8217;t going to take long! As my beloved wife will tell you I’m not the most romantic fellow in the world so this portion of Scripture doesn&#8217;t really resonate very well with me. I can write about the technical side of things though. Song of Songs is, basically, an opera. There are different characters and they interact in telling of the passion of two lovers. The woman, the man, and a chorus sing to one another all through the opera. The KJV doesn&#8217;t make this very clear, so, for us who were introduced to this book by that translation, this was a very confusing book. The Message, and most current translations tell us who is singing when and that helps a bit. Some have &#8220;Christianized&#8221; Song of Songs by making it an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. I’m not knowledgeable enough to debate the point but it seems to me that it&#8217;s more of a celebration of God&#8217;s gift of human sexuality than anything else. To be honest about it, I&#8217;m a lot more comfortable with the sexuality of Song of Songs when it’s left in that realm and not made into a spiritual allegory so I intend to leave it at that. Finally, Solomon is the writer and apparently the male character in the opera is based on him. Because of that, this book is also called Song of Solomon. When I remember how many wives Solomon had I have to smile and wonder which of his wives inspired this opera. However, I do understand that many of his marriages were political in nature, basically arraigned to seal some treaty between Israel and a neighboring nation. The actual identity of the woman is, so far as I can see, unknown to us.<br />
Take Away: We believe this book of the Bible is the inspired Word of God, so we read it and consider it even when we don’t fully understand it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t just fall in love with being in love Song of Songs 2: Don&#8217;t excite love, don&#8217;t stir it up, until the time is ripe &#8212; and you&#8217;re ready. The woman, who co-stars in the opera, is speaking to her &#8220;sisters in Jerusalem&#8221; and she has some good advice for them. She tells them to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jBZb-7H42RY/X6r3fb4wl-I/AAAAAAABHkM/a3Q89p4hnHoy-Csrb7mEJQWcKOoG1SkIQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/16garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>Don’t just fall in love with being in love<br />
Song of Songs 2: Don&#8217;t excite love, don&#8217;t stir it up, until the time is ripe &#8212; and you&#8217;re ready.<br />
The woman, who co-stars in the opera, is speaking to her &#8220;sisters in Jerusalem&#8221; and she has some good advice for them. She tells them to wait for the right time and for the right person to be sent into their lives before falling in love. Sometimes young women are more in love with the idea of being in love than they are actually in love. They get emotionally involved with someone who has a very different agenda than they do and the result is, at best, disappointment and a feeling of having been used and cheapened. Song of Songs is a celebration of human love and sexuality &#8212; and the two are very much linked. The woman who is loved by the King says, &#8220;The real thing is worth waiting for &#8212; don&#8217;t sell out too soon.&#8221; Young women across the ages have faced the temptation to do otherwise but to do so is to accept a cheap imitation that won&#8217;t last. In Song of Songs, the opera about love, we’re told: &#8220;wait, you&#8217;ll be glad you did!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The real thing is worth waiting for &#8212; don&#8217;t sell out too soon.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 01:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of love Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love! Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kcF20kAoXS4/X62rvAEuytI/AAAAAAABHls/P8eM6_KmFEM7VfaEIMzvY5K5TvOXHV4JgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/11garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>The power of love<br />
Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love!<br />
Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, although passages like this do remind me of scriptures like Ephesians 4 where I’m told that: &#8220;Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her to make her holy&#8230;and to present her to himself as a radiant church&#8230; holy and blameless.&#8221; That passage describes Christ&#8217;s passionate love for the Church, a love that takes him to the cross. In the portion of Song of Songs that&#8217;s before me today, the man describes the power of his love for the woman. In Ephesians I see the power of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. Whether or not Song of Songs is intended to connect me to Christ and his love for us, I’m reminded in this passage of the power of love and the sacrifice one who loves is willing to make for his beloved.<br />
Take Away: “Love” is, ultimately, an action word…real love takes action on behalf of the one who is loved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-45/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dare to discipline Proverbs 13: A refusal to correct is a refusal to love. I love being around my grandkids. There’s nothing better than spending time with these little ones. However, believe it or not, even my own precious grandchildren aren’t always perfect! I’m sure they come closer to perfect than any grandchildren who&#8217;ve ever [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 399px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wjG8VfXHF6M/X3d_huz8URI/AAAAAAABGzQ/GTYr_CxXHWgUuYuEKwGGOExmL7nEVewlwCPcBGAsYHg/s399/normal_underwater28.jpg" width="399" height="261" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure>
<p>Dare to discipline<br />
Proverbs 13: A refusal to correct is a refusal to love.<br />
I love being around my grandkids. There’s nothing better than spending time with these little ones. However, believe it or not, even my own precious grandchildren aren’t always perfect! I’m sure they come closer to perfect than any grandchildren who&#8217;ve ever lived, but still, there are a few little things that have to be kept in check. That’s what their dad and mom, along with maybe a little help from their grandparents, are supposed to do. Parents need to provide loving discipline to their children. I&#8217;m not trying to debate the value of a particular type of discipline here, but as I read the words &#8220;a refusal to correct is a refusal to love&#8221; I’m taken by the common sense truth being stated. Parents who love don&#8217;t just throw up their hands and let the kids do &#8220;whatever.&#8221; Loving parents step up to the plate even when they’re worn out from the day. Even then, they expend the energy to take their children in hand, insisting that they behave themselves within the limits of their capability. The disciplining part of parenting isn’t the fun part, but it’s one of the loving parts. As the wise man says, &#8220;love your children by disciplining them.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Children are a gift of the Lord, but that gift does come with responsibilities attached.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-61/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Running out of wood can be a good thing Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down. As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church. There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-MTTFgHdu11I/X4tVOZuVjqI/AAAAAAABG-E/AXU72ikIuKM_0MSgLcTsQdPeK5gCViOxACPcBGAsYHg/s400/11cripple_creek.JPG" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Cripple Creek, CO</figcaption></figure>Running out of wood can be a good thing<br />
Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down.<br />
As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church.  There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to take control of a church service but that&#8217;s unlikely.  I have the main say concerning the order of worship and, of course, what is said in the sermon.  However, what happens &#8220;out there&#8221; during the week is out of my control.  Because of that, all the efforts on Sunday to create a loving, supportive family of God can be derailed if that same crowd spends the week fanning the flames of division.  Knowing this is humbling to me and it reminds me that I’m not nearly as influential in my own church as I think I am.  However, it also reminds me that my greatest resource is not my leadership ability.  Instead, my greatest Resource is the One I serve.  It’s my desire that the Lord will help me to love people even when they’re behaving in ways that cause pain.  I want to personally set an example of how a sanctified Christian conducts himself, to help people who tend to gossip understand that there’s an underlying spiritual issue, and to pray that the Lord will exhaust their supply of &#8220;wood&#8221; sooner and not later that the church might be united in love for Christ and one another.<br />
Take Away: Some issues will simply die out and go away if we stop fanning the flames.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-john-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-john-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Loving the people of God 1John 5: The proof that we love God comes when we keep his commandments and they are not at all troublesome. Before moving to other things John says a bit more about love in action. He’s already insisted that to be a follower of God requires more than words or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16346" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16346" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16346" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3223.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16346" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sightseeing in San Francisco, CA &#8211; Alcatraz</figcaption></figure>
<p>Loving the people of God</p>
<p>1John 5: The proof that we love God comes when we keep his commandments and they are not at all troublesome.</p>
<p>Before moving to other things John says a bit more about love in action. He’s already insisted that to be a follower of God requires more than words or even sincere desire. Again, “love,” to him is an “action” word rather than a “feelings” word. To love God is to love the Son and to love the Son is to love those he’s brought into the family of God. So what does it mean to love the children of God? Immediately, John takes us back to action. I love God’s people, not by feeling a certain way about them but, rather, by treating them in a certain way. John reminds me that God has given me some commandments concerning how I’m to treat my brothers and sisters. If I love God, I’ll keep those commandments and in doing so I’ll “love” those who are part of this great family of God. If I want proof of my love of God I’ll find it in how I treat his people. John adds that this isn’t that big a deal because this “love in action” that’s required of me isn’t all that troubling. I’m to love people as I love myself. That is, I’m to care about the needs of their lives, their comfort, and their security. Loving self isn’t about feeling a certain way about myself but is, rather, about the action I take on my own behalf. That’s exactly how I’m to love God’s people.</p>
<p>Take Away: To learn about your relationship with God, take a good look at your relationship to his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jonah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jonah-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 22:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s man isn’t much like God Jonah 4: Jonah was furious. The heart of the book of Jonah isn’t the first part with the oft-repeated big fish story. Instead, it’s the last part. It’s here that we find the motor that drives the story. When the reluctant prophet gives in and goes to Nineveh he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Dy4bTnV3nco/YQLS6yYDHyI/AAAAAAABK10/xfKKz8ttLLUbp5d8v2KTOEvHtbXIyiAIQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P8209021.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Shenandoah National Park, VA &#8211; Skyline Drive</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s man isn’t much like God<br />
Jonah 4: Jonah was furious.<br />
The heart of the book of Jonah isn’t the first part with the oft-repeated big fish story.  Instead, it’s the last part.  It’s here that we find the motor that drives the story.  When the reluctant prophet gives in and goes to Nineveh he does so in fear, not that he&#8217;ll fail, but that he&#8217;ll succeed.  Jonah is nationalistic to the core and he’d like nothing better than for the capital city of Israel’s enemy, Assyria, to be destroyed.  Still, with all his failings, Jonah knows a thing or two about God.  The priests and other religious leaders of his country may promote a doctrine of Israel having a corner on the Almighty, but Jonah understands that God has compassion on all people.  Israel may be the chosen people but that means God wants to use them to bless all the nations on earth, not that God loves them and hates all others.  When Jonah runs from God, refusing to go to Nineveh he does so because he understands these things.  He understands them, but he doesn’t agree with them.  Now that his mission to Nineveh is a success Jonah&#8217;s angry with the Lord, not only for sparing his enemies when they repent, but for using him to bring it to pass.  In spite of his unique understanding of God, Jonah isn’t much like God at all.<br />
Take Away: God is love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Micah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-micah-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 23:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Micah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's purposes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What God expects of us Micah 6: He’s already made it plain how to live, what to do. This passage is one of the gems of the Old Testament. Micah asks the rhetorical question: “How can I&#8230;show proper respect to the high God?” He wonders if bigger offerings will do it: lots of rams and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-x__-xUhnMmo/YQ8GviG8ReI/AAAAAAABK_M/lAc_2q5-7DE7bZ4NrL-A6fF4-8vF5dptACPcBGAsYHg/s2048/image-010.jpg" width="2048" height="1530" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Pilot Mountain, North Carolina</figcaption></figure>What God expects of us<br />
Micah 6: He’s already made it plain how to live, what to do.<br />
This passage is one of the gems of the Old Testament.  Micah asks the rhetorical question: “How can I&#8230;show proper respect to the high God?”  He wonders if bigger offerings will do it: lots of rams and barrels of oil.  He wonders if following the practice of the pagans and offering his child as a sacrifice will satisfy the Lord.  Having asked the question he then states the answer.  God has already made his desires for the human race abundantly clear.  Micah says, “It’s quite simple: Do what is fair and just to your neighbor, be compassionate and loyal in your love, and don’t take yourself too seriously – take God seriously.”  Micah’s insight into God’s purposes for people is breathtaking.  Some have called this the “John 3:16” of the Old Testament.  I do well to take this dusty old statement of God’s purpose for humanity and use it as a guide to my life.  How am I doing on the “fair and just, compassionate and love” standard set here?  Do I have a handle on not taking myself too seriously while taking God very seriously?  There’s nothing in the Bible any more “contemporary” than this statement.<br />
Take Away: Am I living up to the standard of the Lord?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You’re getting warmer Mark 12: You’re almost there, right on the boarder of God’s kingdom. I’ve been in a few discussions with people who want to play “stump the pastor.” The exchange usually starts with something like, “Being that you’re a preacher, let me ask you this&#8230;” and off we go to some burning theological [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15735" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15735" style="width: 577px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665-577x1024.jpg" alt="" width="577" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15735" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665-577x1024.jpg 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665-169x300.jpg 169w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665-768x1364.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665-865x1536.jpg 865w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2665.jpg 1153w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15735" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>You’re getting warmer</p>
<p>Mark 12: You’re almost there, right on the boarder of God’s kingdom.</p>
<p>I’ve been in a few discussions with people who want to play “stump the pastor.”  The exchange usually starts with something like, “Being that you’re a preacher, let me ask you this&#8230;” and off we go to some burning theological issue like where Cain’s wife came from.  In this passage, Jesus deals with the same level of discussion.  The Sadducees bring him their old worn out “whose wife is she?” question that they’ve used for years.  Others want Jesus to go out of a limb about paying taxes.  Standing on the sidelines is a religion scholar with a question.  It too is an old one that the rabbis like batting around.  Of all the commandments of the Old Testament, which is the most important?  Jesus looks the man in the eye and gives him a serious answer.   The number one command is that we’re to love God with every fiber of our being.  Jesus even goes so far as to throw in a bonus answer.  The number two command is to love our neighbor as we love ourselves.  This scholar deals with issues like this every day and he responds that he’s concluded the same thing and, in fact, he’s never heard the answer stated so well.  Jesus says to him that he’s almost there, just a short step from the kingdom of God.  This exchange is so refreshing.  On a day when people are lining up to play “stump Jesus” we meet a man who’s on a legitimate spiritual journey.  He’s done a lot of thinking about these things and needs just a gentle nudge to close the deal and commit his life to the Lord.  Jesus instantly recognizes the difference between the cat and mouse game of the Sadducees and a sincere question from a real seeker of the truth.  My prayer for all those who sincerely seek that they’ll find not only the answers to their questions, but, even better, as it was for this good man so long ago, the Answer to the greatest need of life.</p>
<p>Take Away: Those who aren’t playing games but are serious about God will find real answers in Jesus Christ.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
