<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>discipline &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/discipline/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>discipline &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-45/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dare to discipline Proverbs 13: A refusal to correct is a refusal to love. I love being around my grandkids. There’s nothing better than spending time with these little ones. However, believe it or not, even my own precious grandchildren aren’t always perfect! I’m sure they come closer to perfect than any grandchildren who&#8217;ve ever [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 399px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wjG8VfXHF6M/X3d_huz8URI/AAAAAAABGzQ/GTYr_CxXHWgUuYuEKwGGOExmL7nEVewlwCPcBGAsYHg/s399/normal_underwater28.jpg" width="399" height="261" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure>
<p>Dare to discipline<br />
Proverbs 13: A refusal to correct is a refusal to love.<br />
I love being around my grandkids. There’s nothing better than spending time with these little ones. However, believe it or not, even my own precious grandchildren aren’t always perfect! I’m sure they come closer to perfect than any grandchildren who&#8217;ve ever lived, but still, there are a few little things that have to be kept in check. That’s what their dad and mom, along with maybe a little help from their grandparents, are supposed to do. Parents need to provide loving discipline to their children. I&#8217;m not trying to debate the value of a particular type of discipline here, but as I read the words &#8220;a refusal to correct is a refusal to love&#8221; I’m taken by the common sense truth being stated. Parents who love don&#8217;t just throw up their hands and let the kids do &#8220;whatever.&#8221; Loving parents step up to the plate even when they’re worn out from the day. Even then, they expend the energy to take their children in hand, insisting that they behave themselves within the limits of their capability. The disciplining part of parenting isn’t the fun part, but it’s one of the loving parts. As the wise man says, &#8220;love your children by disciplining them.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Children are a gift of the Lord, but that gift does come with responsibilities attached.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tearstained letters 2Corinthians 7: I know I distressed you greatly with my letter. The book of 1 Corinthians is almost painful to read. It’s clear the there are some sick situations there and that this church is far from being a healthy congregation. The Corinthian church isn’t a prototype of what a Christian church is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16095" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16095" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" class="size-large wp-image-16095" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1536x960.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658.jpg 2025w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16095" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Tearstained letters </p>
<p>2Corinthians 7: I know I distressed you greatly with my letter.</p>
<p>The book of 1 Corinthians is almost painful to read.  It’s clear the there are some sick situations there and that this church is far from being a healthy congregation.  The Corinthian church isn’t a prototype of what a Christian church is supposed to look like, although how Paul deals with them is a primer on how a spiritual leader is to deal with a difficult church situation.  An insight in this passage is that as Paul writes to Corinth he knows the impact his words will have on the church.  Beyond that, his words impact him as well.  Administrating this strong medicine is painful for Paul too.  The old “this hurts me more than it hurts you” line is literally true in this situation.  Paul gets no pleasure in writing to his friends at Corinth as he does.  He’s frustrated with them and somewhat fearful for them.  Still, he expects his strong medicine to bring about, in the long run, good results.  Sometimes parents have to be disciplinarians.  It would be nice to always feel warm and fuzzy about things but to do so isn’t what real love is like.  In his first letter Paul steps up to the plate, telling them the facts of spiritual life even though, in his words, “I felt awful at the time.”  Sometimes preachers have to be disciplinarians.  As it is for Paul and as it is for parents, proper discipline should never carry with it a sense of pleasure in causing pain.  I imagine tearstains on the parchment that contains what we think of as 1 Corinthians.  In the same way, there should be tearstains on the sermon notes of a pastor who preaches a sermon that will cause some pain.  Otherwise, that sermon should never be preached.</p>
<p>Take Away: Sometimes discipline must be done but it should never be done with pleasure.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
