<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>passion &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/passion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 07:46:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>passion &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unreservedly in love with God Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings. The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife. She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back. However, he knows that just getting her back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lvqSMImmE1Q/YNpYs5kXkuI/AAAAAAABKlg/wXeaCZAdJMIJLFU4mLTwRzJ3UVjKy9WwgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-05-28%2B20.27.13.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Saylorville Lake &#8211; near Des Moines, IA</figcaption></figure><br />
Unreservedly in love with God<br />
Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings.<br />
The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife.  She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back.  However, he knows that just getting her back won&#8217;t be enough.  For her to return yet remain unchanged will only start this whole destructive sequence over again.  Something in her has to change if there&#8217;s any hope for their future together.  That, Hosea says, is how it is between God and his people.  The Lord loves them and wants them to turn from their idol worshiping ways and return to him.  However, what he wants from them isn&#8217;t just a polished approach to doing worship.  Instead, he wants them to love him with the abandon and passion that he has for them.  He says to them, &#8220;I&#8217;m after love that lasts, not more religion.&#8221;  As old as this concept is, and as reasonable as it is, people to this very day fail to grasp this.  God doesn&#8217;t want me to go to church; to &#8220;practice religion,&#8221; or to attend Bible studies.  He wants me to passionately love him.  He wants me to throw myself into that relationship without reservation.  When that happens, no one has to tell me I ought to worship and pray and study my Bible.  The only reason for me to go to church and study my Bible is that in doing these things I better experience the Object of my strongest attraction: God, Himself.  That&#8217;s the kind of relationship God wants to have with me and with you.<br />
Take Away: The Lord wants us to passionately love him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-13/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s people doing what God’s people do Revelation 13: Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground. As I struggle my way through symbolism that has challenged Bible scholars across the centuries it’s nice to find some firm footing, if for just a moment. I can’t identify the Beast or the Beast’s puppet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16397" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16397" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16397" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16397" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s people doing what God’s people do</p>
<p>Revelation 13: Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground.</p>
<p>As I struggle my way through symbolism that has challenged Bible scholars across the centuries it’s nice to find some firm footing, if for just a moment. I can’t identify the Beast or the Beast’s puppet or solve the 666 riddle. Since John writes to specific congregations in a specific place and time I don’t buy into any interpretation that can only be grasped 2000 years in the future, so the 666 reference, in particular has to make sense historically, but again, I’m not the go to guy for this kind of stuff. What I do like is the momentary firm footing of “Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground.” Their situation doesn’t sound very good. There’s some kind of leopard-bear-lion Beast dominating the whole world. This Beast hates the Church and intends to destroy it. Life is hard under this persecution (is it Rome or some future event or both?) and it appears that the Church will be crushed. God’s people, though, stand firm. In spite of prison and the sword their passion for Christ empowers them. In the face of this crisis of (literally) Biblical proportions they “stand their ground.” That’s exactly what God’s people do. It’s not that we travel easy roads, smelling roses all the way. Sometimes we take some hits that are anything but easy. We don’t like it and we do all we can to avoid it, but in the end, whatever comes we passionately and faithfully stand for God. Even as I have a hard time getting the rest of this passage into focus, my view of this truth is 20/20.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord’s people have staying power even in impossible situations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-david-and-solomon-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 12:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The long arm of the law 1Kings 2: Do what God tells you. Walk in the paths he shows you. The transition of the throne from David to Solomon will not be bloodless, but considering the day and age, it comes close to it. David calls for Solomon to come to him and they have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zfyTXZQCssU/XiuuoB7zjjI/AAAAAAABDpE/RwCOceD7630eaL8N7JFTyfQhe22gxx28gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129994.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
The long arm of the law<br />
1Kings 2: Do what God tells you. Walk in the paths he shows you.<br />
The transition of the throne from David to Solomon will not be bloodless, but considering the day and age, it comes close to it. David calls for Solomon to come to him and they have a father-son (or maybe better, a king-king) talk. Some of what David says is lofty, truly uplifting. He encourages Solomon to walk in God&#8217;s ways. If he does that, the Lord will lead and bless him. Some of what David says sounds cold and calculating. There are some people who have acted in ways intended to promote their own agendas rather than his but for various reasons they’ve never been brought to justice. From his deathbed David lists them for the new king. He doesn&#8217;t tell him what to do in each case but he reminds him that he thinks something should be done. At its worst, this is just plain old revenge. At its best, it’s a cold reminder of reality. This, I think sums up David&#8217;s life. On one hand, he’s a hard pragmatist who’ll unflinchingly kill a man he thinks is a threat to the kingdom. On the other hand, he’s a man who loves God with all his heart, who can write soaring poetry and lift the spirits of all those around him. One thing is certain: there&#8217;s nothing lukewarm about David and that’s abundantly clear in this, his final appearance in the Bible.<br />
Take Away: Let’s let David’s unhesitant devotion to the Lord inspire and challenge us in our own relationship with God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on the Psalms</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-the-psalms-45/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 07:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Psalms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steadiness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Highs and lows and in-betweens Psalm 30: I can&#8217;t keep quiet about you. It’ll come as a surprise to no one, but I confess that I’m no David. He lives larger than life. I have the idea he’s more passionate over his breakfast each morning than I am over the biggest events in my life. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lrOOLoE4Ze8/X0l3mrYumcI/AAAAAAABGAc/_qIswqciy28i6mtHfYT5rWlHKwkwWT9qACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190918_200111.jpg" width="1600" height="904" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Horseshoe Lakes Thousand Trails &#8211; Clinton, IN</figcaption></figure><br />
Highs and lows and in-betweens<br />
Psalm 30: I can&#8217;t keep quiet about you.<br />
It’ll come as a surprise to no one, but I confess that I’m no David.  He lives larger than life.  I have the idea he’s more passionate over his breakfast each morning than I am over the biggest events in my life.  When David&#8217;s up, he’s really up, filled with joy and praises and song.  That&#8217;s not me.  The top of his roller coaster ride is far above mine!  I confess that I sometimes envy those &#8220;Davids&#8221; in my life, so full of life and passion.  On the other hand, when David is down, he’s really down!  He doesn&#8217;t stop at being somewhat discouraged, instead, he feels absolutely abandoned.  He isn&#8217;t just frustrated; instead, he’s filled with despair.  The bottom of the roller coaster ride for people with the &#8220;David personality&#8221; is far below mine and when I see them down there in so much pain I confess that I feel a little superior, or at least a bit glad that I&#8217;m not like that.  The neat thing is that God made both of us and he sees something of himself in each of us.  I have a long way to go, but in my personality, and in others who are wired like me, there’s just a hint of God as the &#8220;solid Rock,&#8221; our &#8220;firm foundation.&#8221;  Then, when I am around a &#8220;David&#8221; I see something of God&#8217;s passion and zest.  Of course in God we see it all without the flaws that are associated with the human versions, then in Jesus we see humanity perfected, just as God intended in the first place.  It occurs to me that one purpose of the Psalms is to let people like me hitch a ride with people like David.  I won&#8217;t make it to the top with him and I won&#8217;t have to ride with him to the bottom, but I might be stretched just a little.  That’s a good thing.<br />
Take Away: There’s something of the Lord in every positive personality type.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
