<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>God&#8217;s mercy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gods-mercy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 19:21:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>God&#8217;s mercy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-106/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 20:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s last word Jeremiah 33: The last word is, I will have mercy on them. This phrase is the conclusion of another of Jeremiah&#8217;s &#8220;prison epistles.&#8221; King Zedekiah feels he can&#8217;t have Jeremiah preaching defeat even as their enemies have their city under siege so he’s thrown Jeremiah into jail. It’s interesting that the prophet&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-alpsrCp_bEk/YGiabW2BrpI/AAAAAAABJt0/sH5LJpyIMZ0M1GIMYbCkyWjFUoIODnvKwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B3-56-02%2BPM.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s last word<br />
Jeremiah 33: The last word is, I will have mercy on them.<br />
This phrase is the conclusion of another of Jeremiah&#8217;s &#8220;prison epistles.&#8221;  King Zedekiah feels he can&#8217;t have Jeremiah preaching defeat even as their enemies have their city under siege so he’s thrown Jeremiah into jail.  It’s interesting that the prophet&#8217;s focus turns away from &#8220;right now&#8221; to looking to a much brighter day.  In the future the people of Israel and Judah will return to this land.  At that time the Lord will do &#8220;marvelous and wondrous things&#8221; for them (that is, their descendants).  God has made some specific promises to this nation and even though, right now, it seems that everything’s falling apart, God has never lost sight of those promises.  It’ll all start with the return of the people of Israel to this land.  Every promise the Lord has given them will be fulfilled.  While it’s true that things are going to get worse before they get better, it is just as true that things will get better; in fact, better than they can imagine.  Right now it seems that God&#8217;s anger and dismissal of them will be their epitaph, but it isn&#8217;t so.  Jeremiah says that in the end, when everything’s being summed up that the conclusion to it all will be that God has had mercy on them.  Getting from where they are to that wonderful conclusion isn&#8217;t going to be easy, but in the end, when all’s said and done, it’ll be clear that everything that happened was an act of divine mercy.  It&#8217;s hard to see the big picture when I’m in the middle of things that aren&#8217;t going to suit me.  At times like that I have to simply trust the character of God: that he’s a good and merciful God who loves me.  The last word concerning God&#8217;s dealings with me will be: &#8220;mercy.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for his unfathomable mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Lamentations</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-lamentations-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 22:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Lamentations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s love dominating even a bleak landscape Lamentations 3: God&#8217;s loyal love couldn&#8217;t have run out. The beautiful state of Colorado boasts over 50 &#8220;fourteeners.&#8221; These are mountain peaks that rise to heights of 14,000 feet or more. Likely the most famous of all the fourteeners is Pikes Peak. That mountain isn&#8217;t the tallest of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ysjQ0npDnaU/YIHjKvHOfiI/AAAAAAABJ7A/GWcq1V7WG-Q2xsWgNjXQSJyvs9LdBNL5wCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/estes%2Bpark%2B-%2Brmnp%2B-%2B%2B7-3-2010%2B11-55-00%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Rocky Mountain National Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s love dominating even a bleak landscape<br />
Lamentations 3: God&#8217;s loyal love couldn&#8217;t have run out.<br />
The beautiful state of Colorado boasts over 50 &#8220;fourteeners.&#8221;  These are mountain peaks that rise to heights of 14,000 feet or more.  Likely the most famous of all the fourteeners is Pikes Peak.  That mountain isn&#8217;t the tallest of the big ones of Colorado but it&#8217;s special because it stands alone on the eastern edge of the Rocky Mountains.  Some say that on a clear day it can be seen from as far away as the Colorado-Kansas state line many miles distant.  Pikes Peak comes to mind as I read the central part of Lamentations 3.  Not only is it a beautiful hymn of God&#8217;s mercy and love, it rises out of the lowlands of pain and loss that dominate all else in the book.  Even as Jeremiah recounts for us the devastation of the fall of Judah; even as he describes God&#8217;s anger as his judgment falls on a backslidden nation; even there, Jeremiah finds the loyal and merciful love of God.  He encourages us with a vision of God&#8217;s love being recreated every morning.  I&#8217;m encouraged today that right in the middle of the saddest book of the Bible, even as I walk through the desert of loss, pain, and destruction, I can look up and see a fourteener of God&#8217;s love and mercy.  Even in Lamentations it isn&#8217;t &#8220;lament&#8221; that dominates the landscape: it&#8217;s God&#8217;s love.<br />
Take Away: The love of the Lord dominates all else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-32/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Faithful to the task Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern. I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book. I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being. Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DHvnggkeU9E/YImOJyC4wEI/AAAAAAABKBg/Kxg3rHoq9HIan-JNougekjY1pOc2lmodgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B5-04-47%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Faithful to the task<br />
Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern.<br />
I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book.  I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being.  Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of Jeremiah.  The Lord warns him that the people he&#8217;s going to speak to aren&#8217;t likely to listen to his message.  Ezekiel is to proclaim just what he&#8217;s told to proclaim and not worry about the results.  As I find this theme I first found in Jeremiah being repeated here I can&#8217;t help but think about free will.  Jeremiah pled with his people to listen and return to God and thus divert the disaster that was promised.  In spite of his faithful proclamation, the bottom line was that people could respond or not.  Now that the catastrophe has come, the Lord raises up a prophet to the exiles, giving him similar instructions.  He&#8217;s to reach out to these rebellious people while knowing that they&#8217;ll probably not respond.  The Lord tells Ezekiel it&#8217;s his job to do the preaching and that he has to leave the results in the hands of those who can accept or reject his message.  A couple of things come to mind.  First, I see the absolute value God places on free will.  He won&#8217;t negate it even for my own good.  Second, I see the amazing love and grace of the Almighty.  Even when he sees that his invitation to mercy is likely to be rejected he insists on reaching out anyway.   Also, the Lord&#8217;s quite willing to enlist us to this task.  Still my responsibility ends with my obedience to the Lord, for those to whom I’m sent that&#8217;s where their responsibility begins.<br />
Take Away: All anyone can do is to obey the Lord – the results are out of our hands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebellion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A sad love story Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head. This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting. It&#8217;s graphic and weighty. The sin of Israel is described as adultery. The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting. Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G6StTmlRGE4/YJWpEYEoWgI/AAAAAAABKHk/UYiJhwXT004zLwB1RgB0IPqUE-4QGCkvACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B004.jpg" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
A sad love story<br />
Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head.<br />
This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting.  It&#8217;s graphic and weighty.  The sin of Israel is described as adultery.  The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting.  Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, destined to die without ever having a chance at life.  Instead, the Lord rescues this pitiful infant and lavishes his love on it.  Then the imagery changes as he describes this rescued one as a grown woman, beautiful and loved by the Lord as a devoted husband loves his wife.  Ezekiel says that Israel, who should have never even existed, has become vain and disinterested in the God to whom she owes everything.  Instead of being faithful to the Lord, though, she’s become an unfaithful harlot.  Anyone hearing Ezekiel&#8217;s words should be disgusted with such betrayal and sin.  None of this is intended to be a pretty picture.  Instead, Ezekiel wants us to recoil at what he describes.  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that my nation is a blessed nation too.  In the early days our chances of survival were small, yet we survived by the grace of God.  Now we&#8217;re a nation many others watch, and many watch with envy.  And even as Israel began to take God for granted and rebel against him, so have we.  This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t fun to read but it needs to be allowed to speak to us in this day.<br />
Take Away: It’s a dangerous thing to forget the blessings of the Lord and take them for granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-52/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 22:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What pleases God? Ezekiel 33: I take no pleasure from the death of the wicked. I love this insight into the heart of the Lord. We Christians are sometimes guilty of making the Lord out to be angry and vengeful. Here I am, reading a book of the Bible that&#8217;s full of words of condemnation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YwE8nKLwDcg/YKVvaneFlrI/AAAAAAABKM8/WyRVgxIKekE6ZKTyFfpVFNURNjwKODQZwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BBlanco%2BState%2BPark%2B-%2B%2B5-23-2011%2B5-09-00%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Blanco State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
What pleases God?<br />
Ezekiel 33: I take no pleasure from the death of the wicked.<br />
I love this insight into the heart of the Lord.  We Christians are sometimes guilty of making the Lord out to be angry and vengeful.  Here I am, reading a book of the Bible that&#8217;s full of words of condemnation and judgment and finding as compassionate a word as I could ever find.  God hates sin but he loves the sinner.  For the Lord to blink at sin &#8212; to call it something less than what it is &#8212; would be for him to deny his own nature.  Rather than do that, he does everything he can to call us from our sin and to remake us into a clean people.  If God&#8217;s remedy for sin was to wipe out the sinners, well, I wouldn&#8217;t be writing this and you wouldn&#8217;t be reading it.  Ezekiel&#8217;s ministry is to call sinners to repentance.  Today, through Jesus Christ, that same call is heard.  The thing that brings pleasure to God is not punishing sinners.  Instead, it&#8217;s rescuing us from death to life.  With God on our side like that, we have every reason to trust him and surrender to him.<br />
Take Away: The Lord hates sin but he loves the sinner.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jonah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jonah-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Attitude adjustment Jonah 4: Why can’t I likewise change what I feel about Nineveh? Let’s see: one shade tree killed by a worm verses 120,000 poor ignorant people repenting and being saved from destruction. Which should receive the greatest response? It’s a no-brainer, right? Not for Jonah. He retreats a safe distance from Nineveh to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tlktL1LDZNQ/YQXcyjlNReI/AAAAAAABK2w/2br_vq3YYYQNHKNfBRH1hjMvomILuiWagCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-08-22%2B19.53.17.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Chesapeake Bay Thousand Trails &#8211; Gloucester, VA</figcaption></figure><br />
Attitude adjustment<br />
Jonah 4: Why can’t I likewise change what I feel about Nineveh?<br />
Let’s see: one shade tree killed by a worm verses 120,000 poor ignorant people repenting and being saved from destruction.  Which should receive the greatest response?  It’s a no-brainer, right?   Not for Jonah.  He retreats a safe distance from Nineveh to watch the fireworks of its destruction.  When the Lord provides a miraculous shade plant for him it calms him down and he feels good about things for the first time in days.  Then, overnight, the plant&#8217;s dead and Jonah’s mood dies with it.  At this point the Lord decides it’s time for this pitiful man to change his attitude.  If the short life cycle of a shade plant can cause Jonah to go through such a mood swing doesn’t it make sense that the Almighty change his thinking about a city full of repentant people?   Of course it does.  Like Jonah, I tend to get all wound up about stuff that isn’t worth a hill of beans: getting my own way in some unimportant thing, or the World Series, or buying some new gadget.  If my team wins, I’m in a good mood and if they don’t&#8230;well, I’m not a happy camper.  Meanwhile, God is focused on people.  He’s already judged sin, and he very much wants people to let him change their lives so he can change their eternity.  I really need to get on the same page as God.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is focused on people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 11:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A courtroom scene Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes. In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene. Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation. Their situation is a dire one. Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15626" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15626" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15626" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; LeFleur&#8217;s Bluff State Park, Jackson, MS</figcaption></figure><br />
A courtroom scene<br />
Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes.<br />
In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene.  Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation.  Their situation is a dire one.  Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the consequences of their sin and returned to their homeland, they remain unclean before God.  And that’s what the Accuser comes to declare.  However, there&#8217;s a remedy.  In the vision, the Lord removes the high priest’s uncleanness and outfits him in clean clothes.  Then, the prophet asks that Joshua be given a clean turban as well.  Now, remember that Joshua&#8217;s the high priest.  The clothes he&#8217;s given aren’t just average clothes and the turban isn’t an average turban.  They&#8217;re the robes and turban of the high priest: rich garments reflecting his high position.  That hat, in particular, has meaning.  The turban worn by the high priest has a gold plate on it that’s inscribed with the words “Holiness unto the Lord.”  This is powerful symbolism.  Although the people are redeemed they remain unclean in the sight of the Lord.  Through the mercy and grace of God there’s a remedy.  The Lord purifies their lives and then outfits them in his holiness.  Believers of today can identify with this.  After I put my faith in Jesus as my Savior I come to realize that there remains a basic uncleanness in my heart.  It’s when I throw himself to the mercy of God that he takes action to graciously purify my heart and fill me with his Holy Spirit that I might be holy in his sight.<br />
Take Away: Through the mercy and grace of the Lord there’s a remedy for the stain of sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 12:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the end of myself and at the beginning of God 2Corinthians 1: And he’ll do it again, rescuing us as many times as we need rescuing. Since his first letter to the church at Corinth Paul has gone though some hard times. His words remind me of some of the Psalms of complaint when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16070" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16070" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16070" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2605.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16070" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Meares, OR &#8211; in the fog</figcaption></figure>
<p>At the end of myself and at the beginning of God</p>
<p>2Corinthians 1: And he’ll do it again, rescuing us as many times as we need rescuing.</p>
<p>Since his first letter to the church at Corinth Paul has gone though some hard times. His words remind me of some of the Psalms of complaint when David thought it was all over for him. In words similar to what David used, Paul describes how he was crushed and sure that he was at the end. In his despair he realized he was out of options and that there was nothing he could do to save himself. At that low point, he remembered his greatest Resource. When he came to the end of himself he found himself at just the beginning of God. Throwing himself on the mercy of God is the smartest thing he ever did. After all, Paul reminds us, this is the God who even raises the dead. The Lord was equal to the challenge and, for Paul, the sun rose once again in his life, giving him a new lease on life. This journey to death’s door and back, Paul says, has turned out to be a positive event in his life. These days he’s quicker to stop struggling and to start trusting in God to bring about a rescue in his life. This is a lesson I need to learn anew. I serve a God who loves me and who has the power to, when necessary, raise the dead. I may not like it when life brings me my share of uncertainty and even pain. At the same time, I can remember that the same God who has brought me through difficult times in the past can “rescue me as many times as I need rescuing.”</p>
<p>Take Away: In an uncertain world the Lord remains my steadfast certainty.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 11:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Road to ruin Genesis 19: God was so merciful to them! I really dislike the story of the destruction of the wicked cities, Sodom and Gomorrah. There’s almost nothing uplifting in it. Years earlier, Lot and his family had taken up residence in the vicinity of Sodom. Now, in spite of its reputation for sexual [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VWXOTpOJ5yI/XMX5JT4QFoI/AAAAAAAA66Q/rojYHlvK2JUMZtaNBe4qCc7QSA-bmGtRwCKgBGAs/s1600/100_3157.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 -Along California 101 &#8211; smoke from forest fire</figcaption></figure>
<p>Road to ruin<br />
Genesis 19: God was so merciful to them!<br />
I really dislike the story of the destruction of the wicked cities, Sodom and Gomorrah. There’s almost nothing uplifting in it. Years earlier, Lot and his family had taken up residence in the vicinity of Sodom. Now, in spite of its reputation for sexual wickedness, we find him at home there. When the messengers of God warn him to take his family and flee he doesn’t want to go. His wife can’t bear leaving and his daughters have a warped view of morality. Even when he’s convinced to run he can’t bring himself to leave the area and, even though he later changes his mind about it, strikes a bargain to move to a smaller town in the area. I squirm a bit as I read all this and then, even though I’ve read the story many times, I want to turn my head as the fire and brimstone falls in judgment. I come away from this passage thinking I’d better be careful about the choices I make&#8230;that they may have more impact on me and those I love than I realize. I’m also reminded that I must never underestimate the seriousness of sin. As does Abraham, once in a while I need to glance out over the plain and see the smoke rising from the destruction and remember that Judgment is real and sure and serious. And, as I see Lot and his family being ushered away prior to that Judgment, I had better be reminded of God’s mercy. That was their only hope and it’s also my only hope.<br />
Take away: I’d better be careful about the choices I make.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 19:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best thing to say to God Exodus 4: God got angry with Moses. Later on we’re told that Moses is the most humble man alive and knowing that I tend to cut him some slack when he keeps backing up on God’s call on his life. However, when I see the Lord getting angry [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-G0_e7CzaZpI/XPQkVE1H9EI/AAAAAAAA768/y02KHxk45kYMcPoEdrk35QZbgRg1kR3GwCKgBGAs/s1600/2014-04-23%2B10.28.45.jpg" width="1600" height="902" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sumner Lake State Park, NM</figcaption></figure><br />
The best thing to say to God<br />
Exodus 4: God got angry with Moses.<br />
Later on we’re told that Moses is the most humble man alive and knowing that I tend to cut him some slack when he keeps backing up on God’s call on his life.  However, when I see the Lord getting angry in the face of all his objections I realize that humble or not, Moses is treading on thin ice with the Almighty.  The Lord is appearing to Moses in a burning bush with the promise that, in spite of the king’s opposition that Moses will lead the people out of Egypt.  Moses wants the Lord to give him a Name to use when he goes to the Hebrews and the King.  The Lord obliges.  Moses wants some kind of sign that will convince Pharaoh that it’s the Almighty he’s dealing with.  The Lord gives him not one sign but three.  Then Moses adds that he doesn’t want to actually do any of the talking and wants the Lord to name a spokesperson other than himself.  At that point, he’s nearly found the end of God’s patience.  The Lord promises Moses that he’ll give him the words to say and everything will be okay.  When Moses persists in wanting someone else to do his talking for him, he nearly blows the whole deal with God.  However, the Lord is merciful and tells Moses he’ll use his brother, Aaron, as spokesman.  This, my friend, is a lesson in how not to deal with God.  It’s not that exchanges with the Lord shouldn’t be open and honest.  However, they should also be reverent and trusting.  The best answer to God is just two words, “Yes, Lord.”<br />
Take Away: The only reasonable response to the Almighty is: “yes.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
