<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>free will &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/free-will/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:38:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>free will &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-111/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 04:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free will and accountability Isaiah 8: No, we’re going to study the Scriptures. While telling of future events wasn&#8217;t the major job of most prophets, it’s the one we immediately think of when we think of the work of the prophets. Actually, these men of God mostly &#8220;forth-told&#8221; rather than &#8220;fore-told.&#8221; Even when they speak [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YfS9Yva1LOE/X8A19FfsmSI/AAAAAAABHsE/abYQ1ijkaVAa12C7mHmqSaMIWZe5M4rOgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Mo%2BRanch%2BHunt%2BTx%2B11-28-2006%2B11-44-11%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Free will and accountability<br />
Isaiah 8: No, we’re going to study the Scriptures.<br />
While telling of future events wasn&#8217;t the major job of most prophets, it’s the one we immediately think of when we think of the work of the prophets.  Actually, these men of God mostly &#8220;forth-told&#8221; rather than &#8220;fore-told.&#8221;  Even when they speak of the future it’s often spoken of in a conditional way: &#8220;If you do this, then that will happen; if you do that, then this will happen.&#8221;  In fact, a major theme of these men of God is to remind the people of their free will.  That doesn&#8217;t mean God is helpless, but it does mean, at least in this context, that the Lord allows people the freedom to decide, and then makes them accountable for their decisions.  As Isaiah goes about proclaiming what’s coming if these people stay on the road they’re on, people say to him, &#8220;When I want to know what&#8217;s coming, I&#8217;ll go to a fortune teller or hold a séance.&#8221;  Isaiah says, &#8220;If you want to know what’s coming, take a look in the Scriptures.&#8221;  He isn’t saying that the Scriptures contain some kind of secret road map to the future.  Instead, he’s saying that there’s plenty of evidence in the Scriptures that God won’t forever put up with their foolishness.  Repeatedly, in the Scriptures, the Lord has warned them and it doesn&#8217;t take some supernatural experience to see what’s coming.  Talk about a timeless truth, this is one!  Today, I don’t need a fortune teller.  There&#8217;s plenty of information already available to me in the Bible about how God responds to sin and rebellion.  If I insist on ignoring God I don&#8217;t need a crystal ball to know what’s coming.<br />
Take Away: The Bible is quite clear as to the intentions of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-117/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Babylon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Only God can speak of the future with certainty Isaiah 14: Exactly as I planned, it will happen. The topic is still the downfall of mighty Babylon. The very subject likely sounds like so much wishful thinking to many. After all, Isaiah is talking about an unstoppable world power that dominates the entire region. Any [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 987px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-e_NTnzmEVN4/X8fciGV2ALI/AAAAAAABHvE/w28tKexosNUX6K2cjGo7cjUjzOQOAIekwCPcBGAsYHg/s987/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B4-00-30%2BPM.JPG" width="987" height="789" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Only God can speak of the future with certainty<br />
Isaiah 14: Exactly as I planned, it will happen.<br />
The topic is still the downfall of mighty Babylon.  The very subject likely sounds like so much wishful thinking to many.  After all, Isaiah is talking about an unstoppable world power that dominates the entire region.  Any suggestion that Babylon will come crashing down must be an excursion into fiction.  Still, that’s Isaiah&#8217;s message.  Even though no power on earth can challenge this mighty army, a Power above earth has it in His sights.  Now, some have used this passage as a proof that God has either fully mapped out the future or somehow travels through time or even exists in all of time at once.  I accept the possibility of the first, but can&#8217;t see the &#8220;time travel&#8221; versions.  For one thing, everything we know about God is what he’s told us or shown us about himself.  We might read something in the Bible and conclude that God did it, or knew it, because he &#8220;looked ahead in time.&#8221;  However, to do that is to come to our own conclusions, and not because we’ve been given a Biblical insight about God.  Well, so much for the &#8220;time travel.&#8221;  The first suggestion is that God mapped it all out.  As I said, I believe that’s possible.  That is, I believe the Almighty has the power and authority to do just that.  The problem for me isn’t in that arena at all.  Instead, it’s that such a view destroys the possibility of free will.  In other words, God could map everything out, but he can&#8217;t plan it all and still grant free will to human beings.  That leaves me with a view of God that concludes he &#8220;could&#8221; have designed a universe in which he could travel through time, but we have no evidence that he did and that he could have written the entirety of Creation out on day one, but he couldn&#8217;t have done that and given human beings anything greater than the illusion of free will.  So what do I do with a passage in which God says things will happen as he planned?  I’ll simply accept it.  Babylon has displeased the Almighty who says, &#8220;Because you have acted as you have, I’ve decided just how I’m going to do away with you.&#8221;  Things will happen to Babylon as God has said because God is going to bring it to pass.  It’s not because he’s already seen it, looking into the future or because he intended, from the beginning, for Babylon to fail as it will.  Rather, it’s God, in Sovereign authority, declaring what he is going to bring to pass.<br />
Take Away: It’s fun to think about the nature of time and the foreknowledge of God, but we’d better not get too theologically invested in our musing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-52/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 10:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s guidance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free will with strings attached Proverbs 19: People ruin their lives by their own stupidity, so why does God always get blamed? The Proverbs have a strong undercurrent of self-determination that runs counter to the mysticism I hear so often. For instance, a person uses tobacco for years. When they’re diagnosed with cancer, they say, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lZLXMf75GuM/X39qr4LQbwI/AAAAAAABG10/mVfNICzW4G0_PkQO-WJfI7DSZXDTp-d3wCPcBGAsYHg/s400/2002newport_RI-1.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2002 &#8211; Newport, RI</figcaption></figure><br />
Free will with strings attached<br />
Proverbs 19: People ruin their lives by their own stupidity, so why does God always get blamed?<br />
The Proverbs have a strong undercurrent of self-determination that runs counter to the mysticism I hear so often.  For instance, a person uses tobacco for years.  When they’re diagnosed with cancer, they say, &#8220;God gave me cancer as punishment for smoking.&#8221;  The wise man of the proverbs would say, &#8220;No, you gave it to yourself, don&#8217;t blame God for it!&#8221;  Now, I do believe God is active in this world and touching our lives in many ways.  Still, I’ve been given free will and with that freedom comes responsibility.  I can&#8217;t have things both ways, declaring that I’ve been granted the freedom to choose and, at the same time, think that everything that happens to me is brought about by divine intervention.  The Lord will walk with me and will guide me in my choices if I’ll allow it.  However, he’ll also let me make dumb choices if I insist.  When I, in my own free will, decide to get on some toll road I shouldn&#8217;t be surprised when I come to a toll booth!<br />
Take Away: The Lord is willing to help us with our choices, but, ultimately, we’ve been granted the freedom to choose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-154/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 11:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not blind trust Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open. Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion. The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic. In his message, Isaiah includes the words of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-v_vbCZKM80o/X_cokt1xWaI/AAAAAAABIJo/KmflYienVpoWJnL9TvIE3zAktpeMgUoJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9052229.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Near Estes Park in RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Not blind trust<br />
Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open.<br />
Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion.  The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic.   In his message, Isaiah includes the words of the Lord who reminds them that he’s never told them to, &#8220;Seek me in emptiness, in dark nothingness.&#8221;  In fact, the Lord has done just the opposite.  He’s told them his plans ahead of time.  He’s even offered them choices: &#8220;do this and I will do that, or do that, and I will do this.&#8221;  This God doesn&#8217;t work in the darkness and serving him doesn&#8217;t involve a bunch of mumbo-jumbo.  Serving God certainly requires faith on our part.  There’s much about that Almighty that’s transcendent, beyond our understanding.  However, his desires for us are an open book.  As Isaiah says it, &#8220;Turn to me and be helped &#8212;saved! &#8212; everyone, whoever and wherever you are!&#8221;  Living in a relationship with God isn’t an exercise in ignorance.  This God partners with us, directing our lives, but, at the same time, allows us to operate freely within his purposes.  This God prefers light to darkness and is, in fact, the Creator of Light (both physical and spiritual).  We serve him in absolute trust, but, since his purposes for us have already been clearly stated, it isn&#8217;t blind trust.<br />
Take Away: Living in a relationship with the Lord isn’t an exercise in ignorance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-156/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 11:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Babylon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temptation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free will and accountability Isaiah 47: You&#8217;re acting like the center of the Universe. God Almighty hands his chosen people over to Babylon, the powerhouse of that day. His purpose is to humble Israel and bring this rebellious people back to himself. However, Babylon goes farther than God intends and now the Lord rebukes Babylon [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IPPHE61hX3U/X_oyb4ixpJI/AAAAAAABIKo/dRM85MonD2kdEAFAi72HIIfxZYexuLoLACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042195.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2008 &#8211; Elk in Rocky Mtn Natl Park, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Free will and accountability<br />
Isaiah 47: You&#8217;re acting like the center of the Universe.<br />
God Almighty hands his chosen people over to Babylon, the powerhouse of that day.  His purpose is to humble Israel and bring this rebellious people back to himself.  However, Babylon goes farther than God intends and now the Lord rebukes Babylon for going too far.  I think there’s a case to be made here for the doctrine of free will.  God gives Babylon the power and position to dominate the region.  Then when Babylon behaves in cruel ways God says they’ve gone too far and that he’ll now knock them off their high horse.  They think they’re the &#8220;center of the universe&#8221; but the real &#8220;Center of the Universe&#8221; is about to put them in their place.  Another thing that comes to mind here is the underlying theme of God&#8217;s love.  God has been stern with Israel, but it’s out of love.  He’s willing to use Babylon to bring them to submission but there’s a limit to how far God wants that to go.  I’m reminded of how in the book of Job that God gives Satan permission to strike Job, but in doing so the Lord also tells him that there’s a limit to how far he can go.  On one hand, therefore, I see here my accountability to God as to what I say and do, even when I’m operating within the providence of God.  On the other hand, I see that God loves me, and when I’m on the receiving end of hardship that he’s set boundaries, not allowing me to be tempted beyond what I can bear.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s discipline of us is governed by his love for us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-66/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have it your way Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running. Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them. They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5hjy4W45ajM/YDQRSicp-ZI/AAAAAAABIs0/KZRzd4xM9PENfeleyEkCY0gkweOPPsSrQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0567.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Big Lagoon State Park, FL</figcaption></figure><br />
Have it your way<br />
Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running.<br />
Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them.  They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t hesitate to run to him for help.  The Lord says, &#8220;You&#8217;ve plenty of gods, let them take care of you; let them save you from the bad times.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve seen it.  I&#8217;ve known people who know God&#8217;s purpose for them but don&#8217;t want any part of it.  When the wheels come off, they “get religion” and want God to rescue them.  I know the Lord is gracious and forgiving and long suffering.  As one of his people I want those qualities to be evident in my life.  At the same time, there’s a fair word of warning in this.  At some point, the Lord yields to our decisions and allows us to have it our way.  We shouldn’t presume on the grace of God.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for his grace – at the same time don’t be so foolish as to see just how far you can push the Almighty.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-119/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johanan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zedekiah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking into the future Jeremiah 43: He&#8217;ll set up his throne on the very stones I&#8217;ve had buried here. I don&#8217;t believe that the future is mapped out in detail because I firmly believe God has given us the gift, and responsibility, of free will. However, I certainly believe that some things about the future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PLe2riXuIPU/YHhuyk9OIEI/AAAAAAABJ2g/9riyD9YTYJoWDuPSC_gHDliyy08hQFtCACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PB285810.JPG" width="1600" height="1280" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Brazos Bend State Park &#8211; TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Looking into the future<br />
Jeremiah 43: He&#8217;ll set up his throne on the very stones I&#8217;ve had buried here.<br />
I don&#8217;t believe that the future is mapped out in detail because I firmly believe God has given us the gift, and responsibility, of free will.  However, I certainly believe that some things about the future are preordained.  It isn&#8217;t that the Lord has looked into the future and seen things happening; it&#8217;s just that he&#8217;s Sovereign and he&#8217;s declared he&#8217;s going to bring certain things to pass.  When the Almighty says he&#8217;s going to do something, that&#8217;s just as sure as if it already happened.  In this passage we find Jeremiah in Egypt.  I&#8217;m not sure why Johanan and the others brought him along.  Apparently, it&#8217;s similar to why King Zedekiah kept Jeremiah locked up but couldn&#8217;t resist going to him for the latest word from the Lord.  Jeremiah&#8217;s message to them is unwavering.  The Lord said, &#8220;Don&#8217;t go to Egypt&#8221; and they&#8217;ve gone to Egypt anyway.  The Lord said, &#8220;If you go to Egypt you&#8217;ll find the death and destruction you&#8217;re fleeing.&#8221;  Now, Jeremiah drives that point home by having some stones laid along the walkway that leads to one of Pharaoh&#8217;s palaces.  He says that the day&#8217;s coming when King Nebuchadnezzar of Babylon will sit his throne right on top of those stones as he claims the gem of Egypt for Babylon.  Again, I don&#8217;t see every detail of the future as predetermined.  Still, there&#8217;s plenty that God has already declared to be certain.  For instance, Jesus is coming back, Judgment day is sure, and everyone will spend forever somewhere.  I have the freedom to prepare for those certainties or not, as my future isn’t predetermined.  By the grace of God that much is up to me and my eternity hangs in the balance based on that decision.<br />
Take Away: Certain things about the future are sure but how I respond to the grace of God in preparing for that future he leaves to me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-32/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Faithful to the task Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern. I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book. I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being. Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DHvnggkeU9E/YImOJyC4wEI/AAAAAAABKBg/Kxg3rHoq9HIan-JNougekjY1pOc2lmodgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B5-04-47%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Faithful to the task<br />
Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern.<br />
I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book.  I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being.  Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of Jeremiah.  The Lord warns him that the people he&#8217;s going to speak to aren&#8217;t likely to listen to his message.  Ezekiel is to proclaim just what he&#8217;s told to proclaim and not worry about the results.  As I find this theme I first found in Jeremiah being repeated here I can&#8217;t help but think about free will.  Jeremiah pled with his people to listen and return to God and thus divert the disaster that was promised.  In spite of his faithful proclamation, the bottom line was that people could respond or not.  Now that the catastrophe has come, the Lord raises up a prophet to the exiles, giving him similar instructions.  He&#8217;s to reach out to these rebellious people while knowing that they&#8217;ll probably not respond.  The Lord tells Ezekiel it&#8217;s his job to do the preaching and that he has to leave the results in the hands of those who can accept or reject his message.  A couple of things come to mind.  First, I see the absolute value God places on free will.  He won&#8217;t negate it even for my own good.  Second, I see the amazing love and grace of the Almighty.  Even when he sees that his invitation to mercy is likely to be rejected he insists on reaching out anyway.   Also, the Lord&#8217;s quite willing to enlist us to this task.  Still my responsibility ends with my obedience to the Lord, for those to whom I’m sent that&#8217;s where their responsibility begins.<br />
Take Away: All anyone can do is to obey the Lord – the results are out of our hands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 22:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t push God too far Ezekiel 24: I wanted to clean you up, but you wouldn&#8217;t let me. I don&#8217;t like this portion of Ezekiel. He graphically describes people&#8217;s betrayal of God as adultery. The picture is ugly and the images are &#8220;R&#8221; rated. Not only that, but Ezekiel offers them no hope. God, he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-97m-JYrVMZU/YJ2Nok_lRpI/AAAAAAABKKA/d323g-NCOAcHVO1dWb-j_C30VLIP-8geACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2BCamping%2BTrip%2B-%2BGoose%2BIsland%2Band%2BVicinity%2B11-30-2010%2B5-07-27%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Don’t push God too far<br />
Ezekiel 24: I wanted to clean you up, but you wouldn&#8217;t let me.<br />
I don&#8217;t like this portion of Ezekiel.  He graphically describes people&#8217;s betrayal of God as adultery.  The picture is ugly and the images are &#8220;R&#8221; rated.  Not only that, but Ezekiel offers them no hope.  God, he says, is done with them.  Even if the sexual content of this passage didn&#8217;t earn an &#8220;R&#8221; the violence Ezekiel says is coming would.  Again, this isn’t a warm, fuzzy passage!  The Lord doesn&#8217;t want it to be this way.  Even after his people committed spiritual adultery with other gods and nations he reached out to them.  The problem was that they wanted none of it.  No matter what God did or said, they refused to respond.  They turned their backs on God and acted in ways intended to send him the message that they didn&#8217;t want anything to do with him.  It could have been different.  His plan was to clean them up, to make them into a holy people, his very own.  In fact, that&#8217;s still his plan.  However, that will come in a different generation.  For now, he&#8217;s finished with them and he&#8217;s going to clean the place up by getting rid of them.  Their children and grandchildren will get another chance, not them.  The Lord won&#8217;t force us to come to him.  We can break his heart and we can make him angry but he&#8217;ll never force us to do the right thing even when it&#8217;s for our own good.  I may not be able to solve the needs of my life but I do have the final say as to whether or not God is allowed to do so.  If I agree, he&#8217;ll go to work, cleaning up the mess I&#8217;ve made.  If I refuse, there&#8217;s a very real danger that he&#8217;ll let me continue down the path I insist on traveling and in so doing, will arrive at the destination I&#8217;ve persisted in reaching.<br />
Take Away: We may not be able to solve the needs of our lives but we have been granted the responsibility and ability to allow the Lord to do so.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Theism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Take your pick Daniel 4: Make a clean break with your sins&#8230;quit your wicked life&#8230;then you will continue to have a good life. Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s been dreaming again. This time he dreams of a larger-than-life tree that commands the landscape and provides for all around it. In the dream God orders the tree to be cut [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3Ayb8tsdWtI/YL0f5UX8m_I/AAAAAAABKZE/GkLlLW0dcM8Zg-P5h4lDu5c2eOWK8_QUACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA037698.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Windsor Castle, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
Take your pick<br />
Daniel 4: Make a clean break with your sins&#8230;quit your wicked life&#8230;then you will continue to have a good life.<br />
Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s been dreaming again.  This time he dreams of a larger-than-life tree that commands the landscape and provides for all around it.  In the dream God orders the tree to be cut down but the stump be saved.  Nebuchadnezzar wants to know the meaning of the dream and Daniel comes through for him.  The king’s &#8220;statue&#8221; dream was about his kingdom.  His &#8220;tree&#8221; dream is about him personally.  The Lord&#8217;s weary of Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s ignoring him.  When there are miraculous events that declare God Almighty to him Nebuchadnezzar gives God lip service, but goes on living his own way.  This time, the Lord will touch his life directly to humble him enough that he&#8217;ll stop merely declaring the Lord to be God but will start acting as though he believes it.  After explaining the dream to Nebuchadnezzar Daniel pleads with him to respond now and avoid the reality of what he&#8217;s dreamed.  In other words, through the dream and Daniel&#8217;s interpretation of it Nebuchadnezzar is being given a choice.  If he continues as he is the dream will become reality.  If he repents right now and changes his ways he can continue &#8220;to have a good life.&#8221;  I see this as an example of the openness of God.  Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s future isn&#8217;t already set, but based on how he responds to this warning, it&#8217;s already known.  If he heeds this warning from God things will go one way.  If he ignores it, things will go the other.  In this I see the Lord as knowing, not just one set future, but all possible futures.  In this application we see God not only warning Nebuchadnezzar, but offering him a much more desirable alternative.  Still, the Lord won&#8217;t negate his free will&#8230;the ball is in Nebuchadnezzar’s court.<br />
Take Away: The Lord has granted us free will, but he holds us accountable for our exercise of that free will.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
