<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>new hearts &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/new-hearts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:17:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>new hearts &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-38/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cry of God’s people Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you. Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies. They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance. They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God. Through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1014px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WvKrAQm6pis/YJGgq_6tWhI/AAAAAAABKEU/rCFvfOQBbcIrk_P-3GjgSJEipNFyMN20ACPcBGAsYHg/s1014/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B008.jpg" width="1014" height="814" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The cry of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you.<br />
Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies.  They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance.  They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God.  Through their history, time and time again, they&#8217;ve followed a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration &#8212; only to have it all start again.  Now many of them have been exiled from the land God gave them.  Back in Jerusalem sin reigns and soon the result of that sin will be the total destruction of their beloved city.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to break the cycle by changing their hearts.  The result will be a people who love God and love his ways.  Many Christians can identify with the cycle of failure we see when we journey with these ancient Israelites.  We too have been trapped in a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration.  As we read the promise of a &#8220;new heart&#8221; our spirits respond with longing for that kind of relationship with God.  These words stir us and challenge us to let God have his way in our lives even if that means we need a spiritual &#8220;heart transplant.&#8221;  The result is a healthy spiritual life: &#8220;You&#8217;ll be my people! I&#8217;ll be your God!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Only the Lord can do what must be done in us and he’ll only do it as we allow him to and cooperate with him in that work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-56/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God&#8217;s in the heart transforming business Ezekiel 36: I&#8217;ll&#8230;replace it with a heart that&#8217;s God-willed, not self-willed. I&#8217;ve always felt that this is the mountain top of the book of Ezekiel. Things are going to change in a glorious day to come. Through the centuries the Lord has sent gifted leaders to Israel. He&#8217;s given [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VoQe5K9c7CM/YKqcB5vjFoI/AAAAAAABKQA/GigRpDV-C9kKXxv7s74lO-GxSzKC4sAEwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2Bbrazos%2Bbend%2Bcamping%2B2-27-2011%2B5-38-12%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Brazos Bend State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God&#8217;s in the heart transforming business<br />
Ezekiel 36: I&#8217;ll&#8230;replace it with a heart that&#8217;s God-willed, not self-willed.<br />
I&#8217;ve always felt that this is the mountain top of the book of Ezekiel.  Things are going to change in a glorious day to come.  Through the centuries the Lord has sent gifted leaders to Israel.  He&#8217;s given them the Law upon which to build their civilization and a beautiful Temple in which to worship.  He’s given them a land of their own and has been with them through their many ups and downs.  Still, failure has dominated them.  They&#8217;ve tossed all their advantages aside and have paid a terrible price for doing so.  Ezekiel says that things are going to change.  The change won&#8217;t come because some new national leader leads them back to God.  It won&#8217;t come by God&#8217;s restating his laws to them, and it won&#8217;t come simply because they try harder to please the Lord.  The change will be at the core of their lives.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to give them a new heart.   Under this new arraignment self-centered living will give way to God-centered living.  Their very affections will be transformed.  The result will be a people fully connected to God.  I love this portion of scripture because I believe the message is not only for these ancient Israelites, but for God&#8217;s people today.  For every Christian who battles inner battles, who struggles with living wholly for God, this is a wonderful word of hope.  The Lord&#8217;s not only in the sin forgiving business &#8212; he&#8217;s in the heart transforming business as well.  We find hope for a deeper, heart changing work of God in this passage.  Throughout the years Christians have read this message and come away with a prayer on their lips: &#8220;Lord, do that for me &#8211; do it in me &#8211; today.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord not only forgives sins: he transforms lives as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
