<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>lost people &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/lost-people/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:35:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>lost people &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-81/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 19:11:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are sinners Jeremiah 14: We know we&#8217;re guilty. The prophet has no false illusions about his people. They’ve sinned against God and their sins have horrible consequences. I note that in this passage Jeremiah uses &#8220;we&#8221; language instead of &#8220;they&#8221; language. He identifies with his sinning countrymen. As I read this passage any picture [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9qj_6T17Xuk/YEe0x4yUiiI/AAAAAAABJNo/HgcyQHntHk8Brj6uqMbkC3wypGxQXir3wCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/aboard%2Brhapsody%2B-%2Bseattle%2B-%2B%2B8-14-2009%2B5-53-13%2BPM.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; View from Rhapsody of the Seas &#8211; Seattle, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
We are sinners<br />
Jeremiah 14: We know we&#8217;re guilty.<br />
The prophet has no false illusions about his people.  They’ve sinned against God and their sins have horrible consequences.  I note that in this passage Jeremiah uses &#8220;we&#8221; language instead of &#8220;they&#8221; language.  He identifies with his sinning countrymen.  As I read this passage any picture I might have of a craggy old prophet shaking his finger at the &#8220;sinners&#8221; and telling them to shape up vanishes.  Jeremiah cries out for God&#8217;s mercy using &#8220;first person&#8221; language: &#8220;we know we&#8217;re guilty,&#8221; &#8220;we&#8217;ve betrayed you.&#8221;  Could it be that one reason the church fails to reach the lost is that we’ve adopted an &#8220;us and them&#8221; mentality?   Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I know it’s important to pray for the lost while thanking the Lord that I’ve been found.  Still, there’s a place for corporate confession.  Our culture is rotten.  Immorality is the norm.  These are &#8220;our&#8221; sins.  Lord, we know we&#8217;re guilty, we&#8217;re bad people.  Please do something to help us, do it for your sake.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: There’s something powerful and life changing in praying prayers of corporate confession.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 12:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-15/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jesus likes people of doubtful reputation Luke 15: A lot of men and women of doubtful reputation were hanging around Jesus. One problem the religious leaders have with Jesus is the type of people he attracts. He gets along with prostitutes and tax collectors, the very ones they use in their sermons as the kind [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15792" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15792" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892-1024x641.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="601" class="size-large wp-image-15792" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892-1024x641.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2892.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15792" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Day trip to Vancouver, BC</figcaption></figure>
<p>Jesus likes people of doubtful reputation</p>
<p>Luke 15: A lot of men and women of doubtful reputation were hanging around Jesus.</p>
<p>One problem the religious leaders have with Jesus is the type of people he attracts.  He gets along with prostitutes and tax collectors, the very ones they use in their sermons as the kind of people who should be avoided at all cost.  Jesus, though, welcomes them.  He doesn’t tell them to go clean up their acts and then come back.  Rather, he welcomes them just as they are.  When the religious leaders complain about this, Jesus tells three “lost and found” stories.  In each story that which is lost is of real value and in each there’s great rejoicing when it’s found.  The religious leaders might think of these folks of doubtful reputation as worthless fodder for the fires of hell.  Jesus, however, places great value on them and when one of them comes and listens and then chooses to be a friend of his he thinks a celebration is in order.  As I read these lost and found stories I fear I’m less like Jesus and more like the religious leaders who are represented as the elder son in the final parable.  In our society a Christian can pretty much saturate his or her life with “Christian stuff.”  If I handle things right, I can avoid these people of “doubtful reputation” and not have to deal with them at all.  If I do that, though, I have more in common with the religious leaders than I do with Jesus. </p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus loves lost people and so should I.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
