<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>symbolism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/symbolism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:16:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>symbolism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-12/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Merry Christmas…maybe Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child. John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16394" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16394" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16394" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259744.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16394" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Merry Christmas…maybe</p>
<p>Revelation 12: She was giving birth to a Child.</p>
<p>John’s vision shifts to new images including that of a dragon and war in heaven. It’s my guess that his original readers better understand the symbolism than we do. Interpretations are all over the map but due to the fact this book is written to be read by first century Christians I lean toward understandings of it that keep their perspective in mind. Also, there’s such a strong parallel to the story of the birth of Christ that I tend to think that John’s using that well known story to illustrate something more. Mary, the most blessed of women, gives birth to the Son of God. Immediately, Satan tries to have him killed but, being warned in a dream, his earthly father, Joseph, takes them and flees to the desert, Egypt. Throughout his ministry there’s a war for the hearts of men, women, boys, and girls. Ultimately, though, Satan&#8217;s defeated as Jesus goes to the cross, winning the ultimate victory for all who will come to him. It all fits, kind of. The question for Bible scholars is “What does it illustrate?” Most say that the woman represents the Church and that the battle represents the war waged by the enemy of our souls in an attempt to defeat the Church. If that’s right the message here is one of divine protection and ultimate victory. Even readers like me, in spite of my struggles in understanding the passage, can conclude that, whatever the exact meaning here, God will protect his people and that ultimately, in Christ, victory is ours. I know I don’t get everything that’s going on here, but that’s a pretty good place to start.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to have a firm grasp on the fact of the Lord’s provision for, and protection of, us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The end is at hand, the end is at hand! Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings. John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16409" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16409" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16409" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16409" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The end is at hand, the end is at hand!</p>
<p>Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings.</p>
<p>John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told that that, too, is a riddle name, and the city, Rome, is described. In John’s day, seeing Rome as the seat of evil in the world makes a lot of sense. Some continue to take the woman, Babylon, and description of the riddle to add up to the literal Rome, carrying with it lots of religious overtones. Frankly, it’s beyond me (seems I’ve been saying that a lot lately). If it isn’t to be taken literally, it may be that the “Babylon” represents a current world power that dominants the world as Rome did in John’s day. All of this is the set up for the big battle. This world power will rally the nations of the world to battle against the Lamb of God. Then, before the battle is even described, we’re told the outcome of it. The Lamb wins. In the end, there will be no doubt as to his high standing: Lord over all lords, King over all kings. The descriptions of judgment, war, and destruction are soon to give way to victory, worship, and the exaltation of the Lamb of God.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to understand this: in the end, the Lamb reigns.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jakin and Boaz 2 Chronicles 3: The right pillar he named Jakin (Security) and the left pillar he named Boaz (Stability). These chapters of 2 Chronicles are devoted to the construction of the Temple. Some of the descriptions may be merely historical. Some things, though, like the perfect cube of the Holy of Holies likely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-sTMp4wT2YMM/XrXfyuGXsXI/AAAAAAABFAE/ZqwKlOFho3cYSSLKZ831sLo5K5fNvAj7ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180706_112533.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Woodland, PA Campground</figcaption></figure><br />
Jakin and Boaz<br />
2 Chronicles 3: The right pillar he named Jakin (Security) and the left pillar he named Boaz (Stability).<br />
These chapters of 2 Chronicles are devoted to the construction of the Temple. Some of the descriptions may be merely historical. Some things, though, like the perfect cube of the Holy of Holies likely carries meaning beyond the description. In the case of the two huge bronze (or copper) pillars at the doorway of the Temple, we don’t have to guess because we’re given the symbolic meaning. The six foot thick, twenty-seven foot tall pillars represent “Jakin” and “Boaz” – that is, Security and Stability. These are wonderful attributes whether we’re talking about the life of an individual or that of a nation. Every time the people of Israel of that era enter the Temple they’re reminded of the Source of their Security and Stability. We may not have a couple of large shining pillars at the entrance to our churches, but we certainly need to be reminded of the truth they symbolize. If I want to live a spiritually secure and stable life I must be firmly grounded in the Lord. The same benefit is available to a nation that allows the Lord to shape its character.<br />
Take Away: We must build our lives on the Rock and not on the sand if we want to live secure, stabile lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
