<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 2John &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-2john/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 2John &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-john/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congregations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-john/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pastor to people 2John: My dear congregation, I, your pastor, love you in very truth. Compared to some books of the Bible, 2John isn’t much of a “book.” It’s more of an “email.” It’s just a few lines, written as a quick placeholder for a congregation by their pastor. He’ll fill in the material in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16349" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16349" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16349" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/100_3239.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16349" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sightseeing in San Francisco, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pastor to people</p>
<p>2John: My dear congregation, I, your pastor, love you in very truth.</p>
<p>Compared to some books of the Bible, 2John isn’t much of a “book.” It’s more of an “email.” It’s just a few lines, written as a quick placeholder for a congregation by their pastor. He’ll fill in the material in person. He greets them by declaring his love for them. I can’t help but think, as I read this opening line, that’s it’s a beautiful thing when a pastor loves his or her congregation “in very truth.” Because of that love-based relationship John starts his note to them by encouraging them, telling them how happy he is with them. Anyone who thinks the pastor’s job is to “tell it like it is” and “set people straight” needs to spend some time here. John tells his church how much he loves them and how pleased he is with their faithfulness to Christ’s command that his followers love one another. It’s only after doing that that he moves on to warning them about some false teachers who are taking advantage of gullible Christians. He has more to say to them, but until he can be with them personally, he thinks this little “email” will do. The brevity of this letter speaks volumes about the friendly, loving relationship between this pastor and his congregation. I can’t help but think that sometimes saying less is saying more.</p>
<p>Take Away: Pastors need to love and appreciate the churches under their charge. Churches, on the other hand, need to love and appreciate pastors who lovingly care for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
