<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>opportunity &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/opportunity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:05:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>opportunity &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best laid plans&#8230; Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest. These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples. They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions. The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed. Upon their return, Jesus calls a time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15716" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15716" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15716" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/P5059371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15716" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>The best laid plans&#8230;</p>
<p>Mark 6: Let’s take a break and get a little rest.</p>
<p>These are busy days for Jesus and his disciples.  They’ve just returned from preaching/healing expeditions.  The possessed have been set free, the sick have been healed, and the Good News has been proclaimed.  Upon their return, Jesus calls a time out for a retreat of sorts.  They head for a wilderness spot where he can debrief them and they can be refreshed.  In this case it doesn’t work out.  People find out where they’re going and there’s a big, needy, crowd waiting for them when they arrive.  Jesus’ heart is stirred by their need and he abandons the retreat idea in favor of ministering to these poor, lost sheep.  I know, first hand, of the need to unplug and get away from the day to day responsibilities of life.  In my case, as a pastor, I guess I get just a very small taste of what it is that has zapped the energy of the disciples in this incident.  However, I think the concern is similar for just about everyone who goes out to face the world each day.  There’s a time for unplugging from the stuff of everyday and letting body, soul, and spirit be refreshed.  Still, in light of the entirety of this passage, I’m also reminded that when I love people and have a chance to minister to their need I’m to respond as best I’m able.  In this situation, the opportunity to minister to people trumps the desire of Jesus that the disciples get some rest.  Life is a balancing act.  Here we see Jesus changing his priorities because he’s presented with a great need and opportunity.</p>
<p>Take Away: If we’re to properly represent Jesus in this world we have to remain flexible and responsive to opportunities that come our way.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shiloh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Making the most of what God has given 1 Samuel 2: I’ll establish for myself a true priest. He’ll do what I want him to do, and be what I want him to be. The priest Eli is an interesting person in the story of Samuel. He presides over the worship activities at Shiloh but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L4ft7LaoFmc/XcDNis0oMYI/AAAAAAABCmo/aLg_gp481Y0V8jxUoDlP43N2mycoheb1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3037.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oak Creek Canyon near Sedona, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>Making the most of what God has given<br />
1 Samuel 2: I’ll establish for myself a true priest. He’ll do what I want him to do, and be what I want him to be.<br />
The priest Eli is an interesting person in the story of Samuel. He presides over the worship activities at Shiloh but is a deeply flawed individual. He has some spiritual insights, but won’t control his own sons who make a mockery of spiritual things. At the same time, he’s entrusted with the young Samuel who&#8217;ll usher in a new day in Israel’s relationship with God. I want to cut him some slack because he lives in these days of transition but it’s plain that the Lord holds him accountable for his failure. I don’t have to judge him because the Lord already has. Eli is, I think, a person who has great potential that’s never realized. He has position, insight, and opportunity to make a real impact for God. Instead, he shows only occasional flashes of that and is ultimately told by the Lord that he and his family will be replaced by someone more worthy. Frankly, I think one reason I want to go easy on Eli is that I fear my life also sometimes fails to measure up. God has been good to me and blessed me in many ways. I don’t want to someday look back and see years of wasted opportunity.<br />
Take Away: Make the most of opportunities the Lord gives you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
