<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 1Peter &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-1peter/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 01:16:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 1Peter &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy in Jesus 1Peter 1: You trust him, with laughter and singing. Peter’s words are addressed to believers who are “scattered to the four winds.” These followers of Jesus don’t have it easy. They’re treated as outsiders and sometimes they suffer because of their faith. However, Peter’s writing to them isn’t heavy and grim. He [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16311" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16311" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16311" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140819_092951.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16311" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Lotus, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Happy in Jesus</p>
<p>1Peter 1: You trust him, with laughter and singing.</p>
<p>Peter’s words are addressed to believers who are “scattered to the four winds.” These followers of Jesus don’t have it easy. They’re treated as outsiders and sometimes they suffer because of their faith. However, Peter’s writing to them isn’t heavy and grim. He doesn’t advise them to grit their teeth and hold on. Rather, he describes the victory that’s already theirs. He envisions their gatherings as joyful, celebrative events in which they sing and laugh, buoyed by the living presence of Jesus in their lives. The idea here isn’t that they pretend everything’s okay when it obviously isn’t. Instead, it’s that they see a bigger picture and weighing their current situation against “total salvation” they find that they’re the big winners. Beyond that, it’s more than just “pie in the sky” for them. Something has happened and is happening in their lives right now. These are people who just can’t get over how blessed they are. While it’s true that my life is quite easy, especially in comparison to that of these scattered Christians, I do share in their blessings. As I get together with my Christian friends, whether it’s in formal worship or relaxed fellowship, I hear lots of good singing and good natured laughter. That, my friend, is exactly as it should be.</p>
<p>Take Away: It’s good to remember that it’s a joy living in Jesus and that it’s fun being with his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testimony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[witnessing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Putting Jesus on display 1Peter 2: Treat everyone with dignity. Love your spiritual family. Revere God. Respect the government. Being a Christian in a non-Christian society has its challenges. Sometimes Christians are viewed with suspicion and other times with contempt. Peter says it’s up to us to correct the mistaken views of our faith. We [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16313" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16313" style="width: 765px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16313" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854-765x1024.jpg" alt="" width="765" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854-765x1024.jpg 765w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854-224x300.jpg 224w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854-768x1028.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854-1148x1536.jpg 1148w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2854.jpg 1530w" sizes="(max-width: 765px) 100vw, 765px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16313" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; near Sutter&#8217;s Mill &#8211; Coloma, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Putting Jesus on display</p>
<p>1Peter 2: Treat everyone with dignity. Love your spiritual family. Revere God. Respect the government.</p>
<p>Being a Christian in a non-Christian society has its challenges. Sometimes Christians are viewed with suspicion and other times with contempt. Peter says it’s up to us to correct the mistaken views of our faith. We do that, not by standing up for our rights or debating to prove our point or by withdrawing from society. Instead, we take our spiritual lives out to the streets and let our faith be seen by anyone who cares to look. We treat people well, granting them dignity no matter what their station in life. We treat one another well, refusing to sink to petty infighting over minor differences of opinion. We live as people who reverence God, unashamedly putting our high regard for the Lord on display. Finally, we conduct ourselves as good citizens, not using our citizenship of heaven as an excuse for neglecting our duties as citizens of the country in which we live. The result is that people who don’t know much about our religion will come to respect us. That, in turn, will open the door for us to have a real influence for Jesus. We don’t try to win people by beating them over their heads with our Bibles. Rather, we win them by putting the Jesus we serve on display in our lives every day and in every situation.</p>
<p>Take Away: People are drawn to lives that reflect the real Jesus.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The disposition of the believer 1Peter 3: Be agreeable, be sympathetic, be loving, be compassionate, be humble. The original readers of this letter are under pressure, suffering for their faith. Not only that but they’re in the first generation of Christianity. In this passage Peter describes the general disposition of a believer. Christians are to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16316" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16316" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16316" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269719.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16316" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Yosemite National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>The disposition of the believer</p>
<p>1Peter 3: Be agreeable, be sympathetic, be loving, be compassionate, be humble.</p>
<p>The original readers of this letter are under pressure, suffering for their faith. Not only that but they’re in the first generation of Christianity. In this passage Peter describes the general disposition of a believer. Christians are to be agreeable, sympathetic people. We’re to be known for our compassion on others and our humility concerning ourselves. We’re not to advance the cause of Christianity by force and people aren’t to have to worry about watching their “P’s &amp; Q’s” when they’re around us. Even non-Christians are to feel comfortable and it should go without saying that we’re to treat one another in kind, agreeable ways. Sad to say, some believers haven’t gotten this memo. They think that they’re doing God a favor by forcing their moral code down people’s throats. They think they’re being good soldiers in his army by creating lots of collateral damage on fellow believers with whom they have a few differences of opinion. The question I need to ask myself is how do I score on this “agreeable, sympathetic, loving, compassionate, humble” test? Peter, it seems, can almost hear people’s self-justification at this point, so he adds: “That goes for all of you, no exceptions.” He continues, “That’s your job, to bless.” Of course, my non-Christian friends are to know that I believe there’s a superior way for them to live. At the same time, they’re to conclude an encounter with me feeling that they’ve been blessed and not cursed.</p>
<p>Take Away: Do people think of time with us as a blessing or a curse?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott Cundiff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suffering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Breaking the “me centered” way of life 1Peter 4: Think of your sufferings as a weaning from that old sinful habit of always expecting to get your own way. Peter’s target audience is Christians who are isolated and suffering for their faith. He doesn’t suggest to them that suffering in itself is good but he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16319" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16319" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16319" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866-1536x960.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2866.jpg 1798w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16319" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Yosemite National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Breaking the “me centered” way of life</p>
<p>1Peter 4: Think of your sufferings as a weaning from that old sinful habit of always expecting to get your own way.</p>
<p>Peter’s target audience is Christians who are isolated and suffering for their faith. He doesn’t suggest to them that suffering in itself is good but he does tell them that their suffering for the right reason gives them reason to rejoice. If the same people who hate Jesus hate us because they see Jesus in our lives their poor treatment of us may be unwelcome but in it we can see a compliment. He also tells his readers that suffering tends to wean us from the idea that we&#8217;re always supposed to get our own way. As infants, we all start off there, caring not at all about the needs of those around us, but instead, totally focused on what we want and having it right now. To some extent we never outgrow that. Peter says that suffering (something no one wants) helps break that “me centered” way of life. This, in turn, sets the table for allowing the One who knows and loves us best to have his way in our lives. Again, the suffering isn’t a good thing, but the result can be a good one. My earnest desire is that I’ll learn these lessons early and well as the Lord uses the ups and downs of my life to benefit me and his kingdom.</p>
<p>Take Away: If we’ll allow it the Lord will use both the ups and downs of our lives to our benefit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shepherds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-peter-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pulpit committee 1Peter 5: I have a special concern for you church leaders. A church is without a pastor and the search is on to fill that vacancy. The pulpit committee has a list of pastoral qualifications and they’re sifting through applicants. They want an experienced pastor who still has children at home. The new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16322" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16322" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16322" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269722.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16322" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Yosemite National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pulpit committee</p>
<p>1Peter 5: I have a special concern for you church leaders.</p>
<p>A church is without a pastor and the search is on to fill that vacancy. The pulpit committee has a list of pastoral qualifications and they’re sifting through applicants. They want an experienced pastor who still has children at home. The new pastor needs to be a good preacher, but who&#8217;s also a people person who&#8217;ll get along well with the diverse congregation. It’s not a bad idea to have such a list but Peter’s qualifications for church leaders ought to be prominently in the mix. He urges pastors to see themselves as shepherds who are dedicated to caring for God’s flock. He expects them to be servants who aren’t always trying to figure out ways to get more money or leverage over the congregation. He wants them to be tender in spirit and be good examples for God’s people. It would be nice to have a pastor with the right mix of youth and maturity, who is studious in sermon preparation but is also a people person. Still, I can’t help but think Peter’s criteria trumps all the above. A church with such a pastor is blessed indeed.</p>
<p>Take Away: Ultimately the Lord’s list of pastoral qualifications is the one that makes the most sense.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
