<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>motivation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/motivation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:37:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>motivation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-49/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 08:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leadership, not dictatorship Proverbs 16: A good leader motivates, doesn&#8217;t mislead, doesn&#8217;t exploit. Solomon knows a lot about leadership. He’s watched his father, David, lead Israel for many years. Then when he becomes King he asks God for wisdom that he might lead His people. In all this he comes to understand leadership dynamics as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HIEuHxbiIXs/X3thIv5jQoI/AAAAAAABG0w/qemQhwX5X2oXmPuwGwLXmJYVrKiSq-HWQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/normal_pe_epe_e%2Bfalls.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Leadership, not dictatorship<br />
Proverbs 16: A good leader motivates, doesn&#8217;t mislead, doesn&#8217;t exploit.<br />
Solomon knows a lot about leadership.  He’s watched his father, David, lead Israel for many years.  Then when he becomes King he asks God for wisdom that he might lead His people.  In all this he comes to understand leadership dynamics as well as anyone who ever lived.  In the passage before me today I get just a taste of his philosophy of leadership.  The guy who says these things isn’t some pastor with an all-volunteer staff of church people who might just walk off if they don’t like the way things are going.  Rather, he’s King of Israel.  He has &#8220;off with their heads&#8221; authority.  In other words, if he wants he can order the direction and everyone has to follow.  However, Solomon has learned that dictatorship isn’t leadership.  He says his job is to motivate people to move together in positive directions.  He says he isn&#8217;t supposed to promise what can&#8217;t be delivered and he isn&#8217;t to get people to do what he wants just to get something for himself.  Honesty, unselfishness, persuasiveness &#8212; these are leadership qualities Solomon brings to my attention today.<br />
Take Away: Dictatorship isn’t leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5050</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is it about what I’m getting out of it? Job 1: So do you think Job does all that out of the sheer goodness of his heart? While the audience Satan has with the Almighty is challenging from a theological viewpoint, I think it, and this question in particular, is the absolute key to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yzua5rvqtbw/Xxc8UdjSwmI/AAAAAAABFl0/FD3qbLxoHY8UFnsOR3RLv5-h47z8WqOQgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_125948.jpg" width="1600" height="1038" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Is it about what I’m getting out of it?<br />
Job 1: So do you think Job does all that out of the sheer goodness of his heart?<br />
While the audience Satan has with the Almighty is challenging from a theological viewpoint, I think it, and this question in particular, is the absolute key to the whole book.  We tend to think that the book of Job focuses in undeserved suffering and how Job responds to it, but even more basic is the issue here.  The Lord points out Job’s righteousness to Satan, says that Job is his friend, and is an outstanding servant.  Satan, that old accuser, replies that the only reason Job lives right and loves God is for what he gets out of it.  Certainly, God has blessed Job, delighting in bringing good things into his life.  Is Job a righteous man simply because it’s good business, the smart thing to do, or is he righteous because he loves the Lord and chooses to serve him?   What if Job wasn&#8217;t getting anything out of his service of God?  What if, instead of blessings, curses are brought to his life?  Will Job then turn his back on God and curse him?  While the issue of undeserved suffering is a basic one I think this issue is even more basic.  Why do I serve the Lord?  Is it to escape hell and go to heaven?  Is it so I won&#8217;t be plagued with guilt over my sin?  What if all the &#8220;perks&#8221; are removed?  Again, this is about as basic a question as there is.<br />
Take Away: Why do you serve the Lord?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
