<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cross &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/cross/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 02:07:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>cross &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipleship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The carried cross Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple. Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel. Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd. On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15789" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15789" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15789" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15789" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Day trip to Vancouver, BC</figcaption></figure>
<p>The carried cross</p>
<p>Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple.</p>
<p>Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel.  Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd.  On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all.  There’s nothing gentle about what he says to them.  If they want to really follow him and not just be tagalongs they have to let go of all else.   Family ties have to be loosed.  Claims to self-sovereignty have to be renounced.  These are hard enough words, but then he adds, “If you won’t shoulder your own cross you can’t be my disciple.”  These Jewish people absolutely hate the cross.  It’s not only the instrument of cruel execution but it’s the symbol of their humiliation under Roman rule.  The cross not only means death for the one who is so unfortunate as to be hung on it, but it’s also the means of grinding to dust the pride of the entire nation.  Those who are following Jesus in hopes of seeing a miracle or at least getting a free meal need to rethink their discipleship.  To this day the decision to follow Jesus should be a thoughtful one.  Long after the memory of seeing a “miracle” fades and the meal has been digested the cross remains.  The occupied cross becomes for Christians the symbol of God’s love for us.  The empty cross becomes the symbol of resurrection and hope.  The carried cross is the mark of our continued sacrifice and commitment to Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: Am I a tagalong or a genuine follower of Jesus?  The answer is found in my willingness or unwillingness to take up the cross.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of the cross John 8: When he put it in these terms, many people decided to believe. The debate concerns the relationship of Jesus to his Father. His enemies listen for any misstatement, any slip of the tongue of our Lord, that they might pounce and score some debate points. Jesus tells them [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15895" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15895" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15895" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199509.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15895" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>The power of the cross</p>
<p>John 8: When he put it in these terms, many people decided to believe.</p>
<p>The debate concerns the relationship of Jesus to his Father.  His enemies listen for any misstatement, any slip of the tongue of our Lord, that they might pounce and score some debate points.  Jesus tells them that they need to open their minds and stop thinking in such a small, earthly scale.  Meanwhile, others are listening, considering and trying to decide for themselves about Jesus.  Finally, Jesus says to his enemies, “When you raise me up, then you’ll know who I am.”  The “raise me up” phrase is crystal clear to his listeners.  Jesus is talking about crucifixion.  In this culture, to be “raised up” is a very bad thing.  Even as his enemies prepare for more debate and the crowd tries to digest what Jesus is saying, he continues.  When he is “raised up,” as bad as that is, his Father won’t abandon him.  Even to crucifixion Jesus will take joy in pleasing his Father.  At this point, many in the crowd are convinced.  If Jesus is willing to obey his Father even to a cross, and if he believes that even at such a terrible moment the Father will be faithful to him, they will believe in him.  Such confidence and such a level of commitment is compelling.  Once in a while I happen upon some profane, blasphemous use of the cross.  The enemies of Christ are still among us and they think that the cross is silly or proof of weakness and defeat.  For many, though, it’s convincing and compelling.  In this passage, even before Jesus actually goes to the cross, it’s the cross that convinces them to follow.  Never question the power of the cross.</p>
<p>Take Away: The cross convinces us of Christ and his ability to transform our lives.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 02:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[B-B’s and Battleships Job 7: Even suppose I&#8217;d sinned &#8212; how would that hurt you? In this passage Job wonders why it is that God is so serious about sin in the first place. He has a hard time understanding how a puny man&#8217;s sins can impact the Almighty. Now that&#8217;s an interesting question! If [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kI1P521kGP0/XyG9MMBGr5I/AAAAAAABFpY/3nojDQ3ggWszIG2ftJm3Ili_JfYVsSeuwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190810_131718.jpg" width="1600" height="949" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 – Watkins Glen, NY State Park</figcaption></figure><br />
B-B’s and Battleships<br />
Job 7: Even suppose I&#8217;d sinned &#8212; how would that hurt you?<br />
In this passage Job wonders why it is that God is so serious about sin in the first place.  He has a hard time understanding how a puny man&#8217;s sins can impact the Almighty.  Now that&#8217;s an interesting question!  If God is merely sitting on his throne making up rules for me to follow this argument has some merit.  Job, though, underestimates the relational intimacy the Lord wants to have with us.  He doesn’t want to be far above me, looking down from heavenly realms, keeping his distance.  Rather, he wants to live in me and through me. When he created me, he made me in his own image.  Now, even though that image is marred, there remains something of God in me.  If this is true, and the Lord has connected me to his life then my sin will touch him in a direct way.  Sin not only destroys my relationship with God but it actually wounds him.  Now, I don’t intend to be too hard on Job at this point.  After all, I have one big advantage Job doesn&#8217;t have.  I can turn to the New Testament Gospels and watch God being touched by sin as Jesus hangs on a cross.  For God our sin is more than our firing B-B’s at a Battleship and it’s more than an academic issue.<br />
Take Away: Because the Lord connects us directly to his life, we actually have the ability to cause him pain or bring him pleasure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
