<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Second Chances &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/second-chances/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:37:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Second Chances &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good theology from Johnny Cash Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom. The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen. At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-E_1VkmdhITE/X6MTYEsK8zI/AAAAAAABHew/MSgFGd12GEQ69iWj9UBv0nsDUHrDw8ehgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/22rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Good theology from Johnny Cash<br />
Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom.<br />
The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen.  At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so I just smiled and moved on.  A person can say and do a lot of wise things in their life, but one blunder can pretty much ruin it all.  I&#8217;ve seen that happen with presidents and pastors; with CEO&#8217;s and secretaries.  When my son got his first driver&#8217;s license I commented to him that many drivers only make one mistake in their lives, and it&#8217;s their last.  Car wrecks can be unforgiving.  It’s true of other life situations too.  A man can be a good husband and father for 30 years and then get involved with someone for a brief fling that ruins all those years of faithfulness.  While I’m a big believer in second chances and grace I also know that a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; can ruin a lot of godly living.  Johnny Cash wasn&#8217;t singing a hymn when he sang, &#8220;I keep a close watch on this heart of mine&#8230;because you&#8217;re mine I walk the line&#8221; but his words do apply in that sense.  I don&#8217;t want a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; to ruin a lifetime of faithfulness.<br />
Take Away: Watch out for “dead flies” in your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-152/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 11:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buried in the deepest sea, yes, that’s good enough for me Isaiah 44: I&#8217;ve wiped the slate of all your wrongdoings. There&#8217;s nothing left of your sins. As I read these words an old Sunday School chorus comes to mind: &#8220;Gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221; As a Sunday School kid to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gJ1uIkMO3fU/X_S2mADvvfI/AAAAAAABII8/5vzhxkRCUP4GF05UrLm1AGC1eEYsmCPaACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9062265.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along the trail to Dream Lake, Rocky Mt Natl Park</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Buried in the deepest sea, yes, that’s good enough for me<br />
Isaiah 44: I&#8217;ve wiped the slate of all your wrongdoings. There&#8217;s nothing left of your sins.<br />
As I read these words an old Sunday School chorus comes to mind: &#8220;Gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221;  As a Sunday School kid to me that was mainly just a catchy tune, although I know that it’s important to &#8220;train up a child in the way he should go&#8230;.&#8221;  The message here is mainly for grownups, especially for those who are troubled by the mess they’ve made of their lives.  They look at their lives and see a disaster that can, in their view, never be cleaned up.  You may have things in your past that are so ugly that you seldom allow yourself to remember them, and when you do, you’re filled with shame.  Or there may be things that everyone knows about: broken promises, failures, and destroyed relationships.  The words of Isaiah are so filled with hope that our hearts cannot hold it all.  The only One who can deal with the mess that is our lives has already acted to do just that.  He cries out, &#8220;Come back to me, come back. I&#8217;ve redeemed you.&#8221;  As I respond to that invitation, the words of the old chorus become mine&#8230;&#8221;gone, gone, gone, gone, yes my sins are gone.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-159/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 12:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global Salvation Isaiah 49: Even if mothers forget, I&#8217;d never forget you &#8212; never. The prophet describes the glorious reign of the Messiah, looking not only to his distant future, but to ours as well. The work of the Messiah isn’t only to provide salvation to the people of Israel, but to bring, in his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Q6krwNSpB7A/X_4j8RHtmcI/AAAAAAABIL8/3GKNCpWyIbgG1R5MItwZTccatBb3Igm0ACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042173.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Global Salvation<br />
Isaiah 49: Even if mothers forget, I&#8217;d never forget you &#8212; never.<br />
The prophet describes the glorious reign of the Messiah, looking not only to his distant future, but to ours as well.  The work of the Messiah isn’t only to provide salvation to the people of Israel, but to bring, in his words, &#8220;global salvation.&#8221;  Of course, that’s good news for me, since I&#8217;m on the &#8220;global&#8221; side of the equation.  Isaiah envisions some of his fellow Israelites looking at their current situation and thinking that God has forgotten them.  Their lives are anything but glorious and, while they want to hear this good news, they can&#8217;t get their hearts around it.  To them, Isaiah says, &#8220;Can a mother forget her own child?  God has been Father and Mother to us and he hasn&#8217;t forgotten us.&#8221;  Israel has messed up in every way and her sin has had real, and painful, consequences.  In the darkness of those consequences she feels forsaken and forgotten.  But it isn&#8217;t so.  God reaches out to them with the compassion of a mother nursing her infant.  Israel isn&#8217;t the only one who’s messed up.  The world is filled with people who’ve had far more failures than successes in their moral lives.  Does this describe you?  If so, the message of this passage isn&#8217;t just for ancient Israelites; it&#8217;s God&#8217;s word to you, today.<br />
Take Away: The Lord reaches out to us with the compassion of a mother reaching out for her infant child.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-160/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 12:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prodigal son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The journey home begins with this first step Isaiah 50: It&#8217;s your sins that put you here, your wrongs that got you shipped out. The Lord tells Israel that he didn&#8217;t &#8220;divorce&#8221; them and he didn&#8217;t just kick them out. They’re where they are because of their intentional rejection of him. Even when he reached [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Z2pko0K9iM8/X_9TgRoYKFI/AAAAAAABIMM/36YkCkiiyfEbY3DWz1Ym8NKR1ZIAb7aSQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042172.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The journey home begins with this first step<br />
Isaiah 50: It&#8217;s your sins that put you here, your wrongs that got you shipped out.<br />
The Lord tells Israel that he didn&#8217;t &#8220;divorce&#8221; them and he didn&#8217;t just kick them out.  They’re where they are because of their intentional rejection of him.  Even when he reached out to them, they ignored him.  The disaster didn&#8217;t come because he changed the rules or backed out of his promises to them.  It’s their doing.  Because of that, the road back, as it does for the prodigal son, starts with their coming to their senses and acknowledging their sin.  There&#8217;s hope here, because there is, indeed, a way back; the possibility of restoration even after sin.  It starts with admitting, &#8220;I&#8217;m a sinner.&#8221;  If I think I’ll return to God on my terms I’m only fooling myself.  In this passage the Lord proclaims, &#8220;I’m as powerful as ever.&#8221;  Things don&#8217;t have to stay the same because God has the power to make things right.  It&#8217;s a long road home for these who’ve been exiled to distant lands and that road starts with their repentance.  That&#8217;s true for them, it’s true for the prodigal, and it&#8217;s true for me when my sins have separated me from God.<br />
Take Away: Things don&#8217;t have to stay the same because he Lord has the power to make things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-177/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hope of restoration Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed. God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it. His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity. This awesome God is a demanding God. He calls me to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 704px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iv0kO_jxD2g/YBWrX4vBb4I/AAAAAAABIX8/BOOAkTIWViItqCIQ8NMxoqCyVIqjKWvzwCPcBGAsYHg/s704/PC253031.JPG" width="704" height="564" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Hope of restoration<br />
Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed.<br />
God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it.  His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity.  This awesome God is a demanding God.  He calls me to live in fellowship with himself and his standard for me is nothing short of holiness.  If I rebel it’s not his purpose that is broken, but me.  However, this God is not untouched by that brokenness.  He not only sits on his throne way up in Heaven, but he also inhabits the world he created.  When my sins have divorced me from the Lord and I begin to realize the awfulness of those sins I find that he&#8217;s been there, reaching out to me all the time.  The same God, this high and towering Being, cares for me even in my ruined state.  He longs to transform my &#8220;spirit-crushed&#8221; life into something wonderful and new.  His language to me is filled with powerful and welcome words: healing, leading, comforting.  As I reach up from the bottom, I realize that God has been there all the time, reaching down from the top.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-68/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 18:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prodigal son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s telling the truth to lost people Jeremiah 3: I&#8217;m committed in love to you. The sins of Judah and Israel are described in graphic terms. Their idol worship has a sexual component and the Lord uses that imagery to speak of their betrayal of him in terms of adultery. He’s loved them and been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-b8M3jI-ileU/YDae00PVbEI/AAAAAAABIxE/wSklfcmdrU4TPeFF3ARSnjWdXs7URZjyQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0587.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Fred Hartman Bridge, Houston</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s telling the truth to lost people<br />
Jeremiah 3: I&#8217;m committed in love to you.<br />
The sins of Judah and Israel are described in graphic terms.  Their idol worship has a sexual component and the Lord uses that imagery to speak of their betrayal of him in terms of adultery.   He’s loved them and been faithful to them but they’ve betrayed that love and degraded themselves in the most lewd ways.  If this were a husband and wife relationship no one would question the husband&#8217;s right to kick her out.  It isn&#8217;t that way though.  In spite of their unfaithfulness God calls out to them saying he&#8217;s committed to love them and that all they have to do is admit their sin and return to him.  The imagery changes to that of a parent speaking to a rebellious child as the Lord says, &#8220;Come back wandering children.&#8221;   Before Jesus ever tells the story of the prodigal son Jeremiah pictures for us a loving God reaching out to those who’ve rejected him, wounding his heart.  On one hand, it&#8217;s foolish to presume upon the mercy of God, thinking, &#8220;When I&#8217;m good and ready I&#8217;ll return to him.&#8221;  On the other hand, it&#8217;s an insult to him to say, &#8220;I&#8217;ve sinned in such a terrible way that he won&#8217;t take me back.&#8221;  God says he&#8217;s &#8220;committed in love to&#8221; us.  He promises that if I repent and return he’ll welcome me back.  To doubt that is to think that God doesn&#8217;t tell the truth.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-86/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 18:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooperation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the hands of the Master Workman Jeremiah 18: In the same way that this potter works his clay, I work on you. People who have no idea that this illustration of how God works in lives comes from the book of Jeremiah are well aware of this parable. The picture of the potter sculpting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1204px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bL7YWRT87BI/YE5Z1hwASBI/AAAAAAABJic/PDFTxLeKcx0UItA0_YBzhJ9P8Ttf81L6gCPcBGAsYHg/s1204/Ketchikan%2B-%2B%2B8-18-2009%2B6-18-11%2BPM.JPG" width="1204" height="966" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Sea Plane at Ketchikan, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
In the hands of the Master Workman<br />
Jeremiah 18: In the same way that this potter works his clay, I work on you.<br />
People who have no idea that this illustration of how God works in lives comes from the book of Jeremiah are well aware of this parable.  The picture of the potter sculpting the clay and then remaking it is as clear a parable as we’ll ever see.  It’s not that the potter doesn&#8217;t know what he’s doing or that he becomes distracted and messes up.  The problem is that something in the clay resists and the result isn’t satisfactory to the craftsman.  However, as long as the clay is pliable in the master&#8217;s hands it can be remade into something just as beautiful and usable as the first version would have been.  It’s somewhat sobering to read on.  The point Jeremiah’s making is that, while the Potter is capable of salvaging the situation, the clay continues to resist.  The prophet says his people say, &#8220;What&#8217;s the point? We&#8217;ll live just the way we&#8217;ve always lived.&#8221;  God can handle their failure and rebellion.  He can remake them, bringing something good out of even this hopeless situation.  Sadly though, they won&#8217;t let him.  Today, I don’t have to be a perfect person to be sculpted by the Master’s hand.  However, I do have to be willing for that to happen.  I don&#8217;t come to God and say, &#8220;I&#8217;ve done a pretty good job on my life so far, how about you doing the finishing touches?&#8221;   Instead, I say, &#8220;Here&#8217;s my life, the good and bad of it.  I place myself in your hands knowing you can remake me in a way that will be good.&#8221;  God save us from thinking our lives can&#8217;t be made new by his hand.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-97/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 19:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A big two-letter word: IF Jeremiah 26: If you refuse to listen to me and live by my teaching&#8230;. On one side of the coin Jeremiah tells what’s coming, and it isn&#8217;t good. Soon his nation will fall to Babylon and with that fall terrible things will happen. Later on, Babylon itself will be judged. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_I22fXsgcV4/YFyx6ndKO3I/AAAAAAABJpU/mQtuPgFAHDAqEgmyKqrMcTUFP68dQrp0ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B5-22-33%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
A big two-letter word: IF<br />
Jeremiah 26: If you refuse to listen to me and live by my teaching&#8230;.<br />
On one side of the coin Jeremiah tells what’s coming, and it isn&#8217;t good.  Soon his nation will fall to Babylon and with that fall terrible things will happen.  Later on, Babylon itself will be judged.  Even as Jeremiah preaches this message the flow of events has begun, bringing it all to pass.  On the other side of the coin is God&#8217;s hope that Jeremiah&#8217;s message will cause people to consider their ways and repent.  The message of the Almighty contains the powerful word &#8220;if.&#8221;  What a huge word it is.  It indicates a fork in the road; an opportunity to decide.  It’s also a word of mercy, hope, and grace.  So here we have it all before us.  God intends to bring disaster but IF they listen and IF they repent he will, even at this late stage, relent.  Frankly, he doesn&#8217;t expect it to happen.  The Lord says, &#8220;You&#8217;ve never listened! Why would you start now?&#8221;  The Lord doesn&#8217;t expect things to change, but he offers them a different path.  Two thousand years ago the Lord personally came to this world to offer all humans a choice.  He didn&#8217;t come to condemn, we’re already condemned even as were those people of Jeremiah&#8217;s day.  Through Jesus we’re offered hope.  Once again &#8220;if&#8221; becomes the operative word.  He says: &#8220;I tell you the truth, if anyone keeps my word, he will never see death.&#8221; (John 8:51)<br />
Take Away: The little word “if” becomes a big offer of hope, mercy, and grace when the Lord speaks it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-102/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 19:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Lord, reaching out Jeremiah 31: Everything in me cries out for him. Softly and tenderly I wait for him. In this passage the tribe of Ephraim represents the people of Israel. Jeremiah imagines Israel humbly coming to the Lord, asking if it&#8217;s too late and wondering if the Lord can ever embrace her again. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mRicpu7MJYo/YGNa2lelAEI/AAAAAAABJrw/d-hmbPwaSO0eCaKzcl7MDIVh5nt4ZVkyQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B4-06-34%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
The Lord, reaching out<br />
Jeremiah 31: Everything in me cries out for him. Softly and tenderly I wait for him.<br />
In this passage the tribe of Ephraim represents the people of Israel.  Jeremiah imagines Israel humbly coming to the Lord, asking if it&#8217;s too late and wondering if the Lord can ever embrace her again.  God&#8217;s answer is immediate and compassionate.  The Lord says that that’s all he’s wanted to hear all along and that the strong medicine was administered not because he had stopped loving Israel but preciously because of his love.  This great God of love has longed for his people to return to him and with great tenderness he waits to receive them back to himself.  I can’t help but respond to this passage in a personal way.  I’m moved by God&#8217;s compassion on, not only ancient Israel, but on the lost people of my day.  When I’m in rebellion against God he longs for my return; reaching out to me, crying out in love.  Today, I stand in awe of the mercy, grace, and compassion of God for a lost human race.<br />
Take Away: God is love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-123/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The end – sort of Jeremiah 52: Judah went into exile, orphaned from her land. The final pages of Jeremiah are a sort of historical wrap up. We hear about Zedekiah&#8217;s failure, the fall of Jerusalem, the destruction of the Temple, and the striping of the city of anything of value. People are marched off [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Z2s6a0j4COo/YH36dxFxSBI/AAAAAAABJ54/3BZGBPX1KkUqY0KkOCX4fQG_OcEUEI-VQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/estes%2Bpark%2B-%2Brmnp%2B-%2B%2B7-5-2010%2B11-34-33%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Emerald Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The end – sort of<br />
Jeremiah 52: Judah went into exile, orphaned from her land.<br />
The final pages of Jeremiah are a sort of historical wrap up.  We hear about Zedekiah&#8217;s failure, the fall of Jerusalem, the destruction of the Temple, and the striping of the city of anything of value.  People are marched off into exile and it seems the story of the people of Israel has ended.  The epitaph is: &#8220;Judah went into exile, orphaned from her land.&#8221;   It all happened as Jeremiah said it would.  The nation has refused to take every off ramp it came to, steadily advancing to this point.  Thus, we come to &#8220;the end.&#8221;  Well, not quite.  God not only promised this destruction, he also promises restoration.  The final words of the book describe the kindness shown to the surviving king, Jehoiachin, by Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s successor, Evil-Merodach.  After many years of imprisonment, Jehoiachin becomes an honored guest at the Babylonian king&#8217;s table.  By concluding with this account we see that even as the curtain has fallen on a horrible period of Israel&#8217;s history, the story continues with a new, hopeful episode about to begin.  I find that story both by moving forward and backward in my Bible.  I can go back to Ezra, Nehemiah, and Esther.  Or, I can turn forward a few pages and spend time in Daniel or Haggai or Zechariah and continue this story.  If I want I can hit the fast forward button and advance to Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John to find the account of God&#8217;s ultimate deliverance of his people.<br />
Take Away: With the Lord “the end” might just also be “the beginning” – that’s true because God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
