<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sanctification &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sanctification/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 18:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>sanctification &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-126/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 06:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sanctification Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives. They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter center center"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tLxpJRYogHU/X9UfaGwBouI/AAAAAAABH2w/0K5sAXq0Ems8aKduLwY10bRqwtcAgNZhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251345.JPG" alt="" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sanctification<br />
Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives.<br />
They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, has no compliments for them. However, the Lord does have words of hope. It will take some doing but God’s going to make them into a holy people. He’s going to have people who worship in holiness, who reverence him as the holy God of Israel. Getting there is going to cost them everything. They’ll lose the land God gave them and, frankly, many in this generation will lose their lives. Out of the destruction, God will begin remaking them into a people worthy of his Name. Today, God’s still in the business of creating holy people. The process is, in some ways, the same. He brings us to the place where we give up everything, dying out to self. Once all else is gone he fills us with himself. This sanctification process is often painful for us as we struggle with the Lord over ownership of our lives. When we do surrender to him, though, the result is holiness; God honoring, wonderfully satisfied lives.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is still in the business of creating holy people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-78/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 18:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[selfishness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Letting God be Lord Jeremiah 10: Mere mortals can&#8217;t run their own lives. Years ago there was a TV commercial in which a stressed homemaker rudely said to her well-meaning mother, &#8220;Mother please, I&#8217;d rather do it myself.&#8221; According to the ad, she needed to take a pill, and not just any pill: their pill. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1544px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-u1Yo7_lXmIk/YEPN-ztBFoI/AAAAAAABI6k/XgnJVFuKaGAmE10bjojxzaLuNl8R5N4mgCPcBGAsYHg/s1544/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-13-2009%2B6-39-40%2BPM.JPG" width="1544" height="1236" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier National Park, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Letting God be Lord<br />
Jeremiah 10: Mere mortals can&#8217;t run their own lives.<br />
Years ago there was a TV commercial in which a stressed homemaker rudely said to her well-meaning mother, &#8220;Mother please, I&#8217;d rather do it myself.&#8221;  According to the ad, she needed to take a pill, and not just any pill: their pill.  However, her desire to &#8220;do it herself&#8221; could never be fixed by her taking a pill.  It&#8217;s a part of the human condition.  Specifically, it’s what we say to our Creator.  We’re made to live in fellowship with the Lord, to be partners with him in his purposes in our world.  Instead, we turn our backs on God, insisting &#8220;I&#8217;d rather do it myself.&#8221;  The result is, well, it&#8217;s what I see on the evening news every day.  Pain and suffering, hating and killing: it&#8217;s all the result of our doing it ourselves.  The fact is that as long as we make the most basic of mistakes: the exclusion of God from our lives, everything else is just putting band aids on life-threatening wounds.  On the largest scale, the only hope of humanity is surrender to God.  On the personal scale, it’s the same.  Jeremiah says, &#8220;Men and women don&#8217;t have what it takes to take charge of life.&#8221;  His solution is to do what God designed us to do in the first place: connect to God and let him be Lord of all that we are.<br />
Take Away: We’re designed to live in fellowship with the Lord and nothing else will do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-94/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 19:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new heart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heart transplant Jeremiah 24: I’ll give them a heart to know me, God. In a vision Jeremiah sees two baskets of figs. One basket has good fruit and the other has bad fruit. The Lord tells Jeremiah that the good figs represent people who’ll obey God&#8217;s call to surrender to the Babylonians and be relocated [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-RfcfDgyXcPM/YFjpWTEbbBI/AAAAAAABJn4/QzIuejacMcwj2Q9DFmfScBNjUgAniW9YACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B5-41-51%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Heart transplant<br />
Jeremiah 24: I’ll give them a heart to know me, God.<br />
In a vision Jeremiah sees two baskets of figs.  One basket has good fruit and the other has bad fruit.  The Lord tells Jeremiah that the good figs represent people who’ll obey God&#8217;s call to surrender to the Babylonians and be relocated to other lands by them.  The bad figs represent the leaders and others who are ignoring God&#8217;s demand that they surrender and accept the Lord&#8217;s judgment on the nation.  Even the &#8220;good fig&#8221; population, though, is in need of a divine heart transplant.  God says he&#8217;s going to do just that.  Those who trust and obey him, placing their lives in his hands, aren&#8217;t considered complete until the Lord makes some basic changes in their hearts.  I think this illustrates the work of the Lord in our individual lives.  On one hand, I surrender my life to the Lord, committing myself to live for him, no matter what might come.  On the other hand, God does in me what I can&#8217;t do for myself.  He changes my very heart, enabling me to love him with all my being.  It is then, Jeremiah tells me, that I&#8217;m one of God&#8217;s people, and he is Lord of my life.<br />
Take Away: The Lord does in me what I can&#8217;t do for myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-103/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new heart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s Law in my heart Jeremiah 31: I will put my law within them &#8212; write it on their hearts! I love this statement. Jeremiah sees the sin and rebellion of his people, not as a cultural or educational or behavioral problem, but as a heart problem. Their failure isn&#8217;t the result of misunderstanding and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YARmN-6FM8U/YGSwAze4B2I/AAAAAAABJsM/fVsdTj7hkcAcu8uSKvYEOU5jSk4mtWSpgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B4-04-33%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s Law in my heart<br />
Jeremiah 31: I will put my law within them &#8212; write it on their hearts!<br />
I love this statement.  Jeremiah sees the sin and rebellion of his people, not as a cultural or educational or behavioral problem, but as a heart problem.  Their failure isn&#8217;t the result of misunderstanding and it isn&#8217;t a mistake.  They sin because they’re sinners at heart.  The great need of their lives isn’t that they straighten up and act right.  They need heart surgery; a change at the very foundation of their being.  In this passage the Lord describes this change.  On the first level, it’s a change that will take place following the Babylonian exile but on a larger scale it’s a change Jesus, the Son of God, will bring.  In fact, the writer of the New Testament book of Hebrews returns to this passage to describe the new spiritual reality Christ has brought into the world.  God&#8217;s Law is no longer written on stone tablets.  Rather, it’s written on the hearts of those who receive Jesus as their Lord and Savior.  Jeremiah sees the need and he has the promise from God that the need will be met, but he can’t imagine how it will all be brought about.<br />
Take Away: We need more than to change our behavior – we need for our hearts to be transformed by the grace of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-38/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cry of God’s people Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you. Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies. They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance. They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God. Through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1014px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WvKrAQm6pis/YJGgq_6tWhI/AAAAAAABKEU/rCFvfOQBbcIrk_P-3GjgSJEipNFyMN20ACPcBGAsYHg/s1014/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B008.jpg" width="1014" height="814" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The cry of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you.<br />
Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies.  They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance.  They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God.  Through their history, time and time again, they&#8217;ve followed a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration &#8212; only to have it all start again.  Now many of them have been exiled from the land God gave them.  Back in Jerusalem sin reigns and soon the result of that sin will be the total destruction of their beloved city.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to break the cycle by changing their hearts.  The result will be a people who love God and love his ways.  Many Christians can identify with the cycle of failure we see when we journey with these ancient Israelites.  We too have been trapped in a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration.  As we read the promise of a &#8220;new heart&#8221; our spirits respond with longing for that kind of relationship with God.  These words stir us and challenge us to let God have his way in our lives even if that means we need a spiritual &#8220;heart transplant.&#8221;  The result is a healthy spiritual life: &#8220;You&#8217;ll be my people! I&#8217;ll be your God!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Only the Lord can do what must be done in us and he’ll only do it as we allow him to and cooperate with him in that work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-56/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God&#8217;s in the heart transforming business Ezekiel 36: I&#8217;ll&#8230;replace it with a heart that&#8217;s God-willed, not self-willed. I&#8217;ve always felt that this is the mountain top of the book of Ezekiel. Things are going to change in a glorious day to come. Through the centuries the Lord has sent gifted leaders to Israel. He&#8217;s given [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VoQe5K9c7CM/YKqcB5vjFoI/AAAAAAABKQA/GigRpDV-C9kKXxv7s74lO-GxSzKC4sAEwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2Bbrazos%2Bbend%2Bcamping%2B2-27-2011%2B5-38-12%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Brazos Bend State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God&#8217;s in the heart transforming business<br />
Ezekiel 36: I&#8217;ll&#8230;replace it with a heart that&#8217;s God-willed, not self-willed.<br />
I&#8217;ve always felt that this is the mountain top of the book of Ezekiel.  Things are going to change in a glorious day to come.  Through the centuries the Lord has sent gifted leaders to Israel.  He&#8217;s given them the Law upon which to build their civilization and a beautiful Temple in which to worship.  He’s given them a land of their own and has been with them through their many ups and downs.  Still, failure has dominated them.  They&#8217;ve tossed all their advantages aside and have paid a terrible price for doing so.  Ezekiel says that things are going to change.  The change won&#8217;t come because some new national leader leads them back to God.  It won&#8217;t come by God&#8217;s restating his laws to them, and it won&#8217;t come simply because they try harder to please the Lord.  The change will be at the core of their lives.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to give them a new heart.   Under this new arraignment self-centered living will give way to God-centered living.  Their very affections will be transformed.  The result will be a people fully connected to God.  I love this portion of scripture because I believe the message is not only for these ancient Israelites, but for God&#8217;s people today.  For every Christian who battles inner battles, who struggles with living wholly for God, this is a wonderful word of hope.  The Lord&#8217;s not only in the sin forgiving business &#8212; he&#8217;s in the heart transforming business as well.  We find hope for a deeper, heart changing work of God in this passage.  Throughout the years Christians have read this message and come away with a prayer on their lips: &#8220;Lord, do that for me &#8211; do it in me &#8211; today.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord not only forgives sins: he transforms lives as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 11:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A courtroom scene Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes. In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene. Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation. Their situation is a dire one. Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15626" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15626" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15626" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; LeFleur&#8217;s Bluff State Park, Jackson, MS</figcaption></figure><br />
A courtroom scene<br />
Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes.<br />
In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene.  Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation.  Their situation is a dire one.  Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the consequences of their sin and returned to their homeland, they remain unclean before God.  And that’s what the Accuser comes to declare.  However, there&#8217;s a remedy.  In the vision, the Lord removes the high priest’s uncleanness and outfits him in clean clothes.  Then, the prophet asks that Joshua be given a clean turban as well.  Now, remember that Joshua&#8217;s the high priest.  The clothes he&#8217;s given aren’t just average clothes and the turban isn’t an average turban.  They&#8217;re the robes and turban of the high priest: rich garments reflecting his high position.  That hat, in particular, has meaning.  The turban worn by the high priest has a gold plate on it that’s inscribed with the words “Holiness unto the Lord.”  This is powerful symbolism.  Although the people are redeemed they remain unclean in the sight of the Lord.  Through the mercy and grace of God there’s a remedy.  The Lord purifies their lives and then outfits them in his holiness.  Believers of today can identify with this.  After I put my faith in Jesus as my Savior I come to realize that there remains a basic uncleanness in my heart.  It’s when I throw himself to the mercy of God that he takes action to graciously purify my heart and fill me with his Holy Spirit that I might be holy in his sight.<br />
Take Away: Through the mercy and grace of the Lord there’s a remedy for the stain of sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-26/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Church camp commitment Matthew 26: I’m ready. Do it your way. When I was growing up a high point of my summers was attending church camp. I loved playing ball and taking hikes and all the other things associated with camp. The ministry at children’s camp focused on the plan of salvation. Many children first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15690" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15690" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15690" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15690" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; On the road to Dead Horse Point State Park &#8211; also Canyonlands NP</figcaption></figure>
<p>Church camp commitment</p>
<p>Matthew 26: I’m ready.  Do it your way.</p>
<p>When I was growing up a high point of my summers was attending church camp.  I loved playing ball and taking hikes and all the other things associated with camp.  The ministry at children’s camp focused on the plan of salvation.  Many children first gave their hearts to Jesus at camp.  At teen camp, though, the focus was more on full surrender, sanctification, accepting a call to the ministry.  Teens, more than any other group, grasp the idea of radical commitment.  Still, there was a sort of insider’s secret shared by “old timers” like me who had been going to camp through our childhood years.  It worked something like this: the Lord will ask you if you’re willing to be a missionary or a pastor but it’s just a test.  Once you say “yes” and mean it with all your heart, he won’t actually call you.  With that tidbit of information buried in one’s mind, even a sincere seeker had a little bit easier time making a full surrender.  When I work with teens I still see in them a willingness to go all out in their commitment to the Lord.  Adults carry baggage (jobs, bills to pay, family responsibilities) that has to be sorted through so it’s a more thoughtful process for them.  However, adults also have a more realistic attitude concerning what it means to sign on the dotted line.  If I commit myself to making monthly mortgage payments I’m really going to have to pay them; there’s nothing theoretical about it!  When I see Jesus praying in the Garden I hear him making a full commitment to do his Father’s will.  No doubt, Jesus is emotional at this point but there’s more.  He knows that this “yes” is the real deal.  With his eyes wide open Jesus commits to go to the cross.  His full commitment to do the Father’s will both challenges and instructs me as I live the Christian life.</p>
<p>Take Away: The call to full surrender is a real call and needs to be taken seriously.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 12:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yielding center stage to Jesus John 3: This is the assigned moment for him to move into the center, while I slip off to the sidelines. John the Baptist blazed to prominence in the land like a shooting star that, seemingly out of nowhere, lights the sky and draws the attention of everyone. Now, like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15839" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15839" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15839" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2470.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15839" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Anacortes, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Yielding center stage to Jesus</p>
<p>John 3: This is the assigned moment for him to move into the center, while I slip off to the sidelines.</p>
<p>John the Baptist blazed to prominence in the land like a shooting star that, seemingly out of nowhere, lights the sky and draws the attention of everyone.  Now, like a shooting star, he&#8217;s just as quickly fading from the scene as all attention is focused on a new “Sun” rising, shedding light, not just for a passing moment but for all time.  John’s disciples are defensive about this.  They believe in and support him and they don’t like it that his role is diminishing as Jesus is drawing more and more attention.  For John, though, this is exactly how it should be.  As he said when he introduced Jesus, Jesus is vastly superior to himself.  As Jesus moves into the limelight John happily stands off on the sidelines cheering him on.  I think there’s a spiritual parallel to this in the lives of those on the Christian journey.  Once I acknowledge Jesus as the Savior of the world and as my personal Savior, it quickly becomes apparent that this Savior is also King of kings and Lord of lords.  I understand that I need to stop being the center of my universe so that he can move to his rightful place as Lord of my life.  I must decrease that he might increase.</p>
<p>Take Away: The only proper place for Jesus is sitting on the throne of my life.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s answer to sin-in-me Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved. What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16014" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16014" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16014" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-768x482.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065-1536x963.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3065.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16014" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; At Long Beach, WA Thousand Trails &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; on the beach a short walk from the campground</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s answer to sin-in-me</p>
<p>Romans 8: With the arrival of Jesus, the Messiah, that fateful dilemma is resolved.</p>
<p>What’s the answer to a failure filled Christianity? Am I destined to a defense oriented spiritual life? Is my constant excuse, “the spirit is willing but the body is weak”? The gloom of Romans 7 is blown away by the opening words of Romans 8. Before Christ, Romans 7 was the norm, but it’s the norm no more. In Christ “a new power is in operation” and everything’s changed. When I cry out to God for relief from sin he responds in Christ to defeat sin-in-me once and for all. The blood of Christ is applied to my life to bring about a “deep healing” and sin-as-a-condition is defeated. Now, a new day dawns in my spiritual life. I’m led “out into the open, into a spacious, free life.” I’ve been “delivered from that dead life” and the Spirit is now living in me. As a child of God who struggles with sin, I cry out to my Heavenly Father for help. He responds by doing a work in me as “God’s Spirit touches” my spirit resulting in a deeper relationship with God and a level of spiritual living I never before dreamed possible.</p>
<p>Take Away: In God, there’s wonderful freedom from self and sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
