<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mission &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/mission/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 21:11:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>mission &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t leave home without it John 14: Whatever you request along the lines of who I am and what I am doing, I’ll do it. Some of the most empowering words ever spoken are those of our Lord as he prepares his disciples for the soon coming events in these closing days of his earthly [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15860" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15860" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15860" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/PHOTO_20140606_152249.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15860" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; La Conner, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Don’t leave home without it</p>
<p>John 14: Whatever you request along the lines of who I am and what I am doing, I’ll do it.</p>
<p>Some of the most empowering words ever spoken are those of our Lord as he prepares his disciples for the soon coming events in these closing days of his earthly ministry.  The clock is ticking and soon their world will be rocked in ways they can’t imagine.  Still, there’s a light at the end of the tunnel.  As a result of all that’s coming they’ll do even greater things than what they’ve seen Jesus do.  I think Jesus is speaking to them as a cooperate group and not as individuals.  They won’t all go out and be messiahs in the world, but together, as the Church, they’ll transform the world in the Name of Jesus.  They won’t be alone in their task.  Jesus is sending the Holy Spirit, his Spirit, who’ll not only be with them but will be in them, empowering them to do his work.  When they run up against impossible situations that threaten to stop them from carrying on his work, all they’ll need to do is call out to him and he’ll make the impossible possible for them.  This “asking in Jesus’ Name” isn’t an open credit card that they can use for doing anything they want.  Rather, this is all about ministry empowerment.  Jesus wants them to carry on his work in this world, bringing the Good News of the Gospel to every nation.  He promises them power for the task and he tells them that he’ll never be more than a prayer away.  This may not be an all-purpose “credit card” but it is, I think, a mighty fine “Master’s Card” that I need to use more often.</p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus has provided us exactly what we need to do his work in this world.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gospel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mission]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-18/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Method upgrade Acts 18: Paul had finally had it with them and gave it up as a bad job. Paul spends a lot of time in Corinth, likely over two years. In the beginning he focuses his ministry on the Jews living there and has some success. However, others become more and more entrenched in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15949" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15949" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15949" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199543.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15949" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Method upgrade </p>
<p>Acts 18: Paul had finally had it with them and gave it up as a bad job.</p>
<p>Paul spends a lot of time in Corinth, likely over two years.  In the beginning he focuses his ministry on the Jews living there and has some success.  However, others become more and more entrenched in their rejection of his message.  At some point he decides there are more productive ways to minister in the Name of Jesus and ends up next door to the Jews’ meeting place at the home of Titius Justus.  There Paul sets up shop for at least 18 months, preaching about Jesus and establishing a church in Corinth.  After working primarily with the Jews Paul realizes that continuing to do so is not a profitable use of his time and energy.  In his case, there’s a better place right next door.  How often do we get so locked into a certain way and place that we continue to try to ride a horse that’s long dead?  As the truism goes: “when the horse is dead it’s time to dismount.”  Some churches are still trying to do things the way they were done in 1950 and they wonder why what worked so well then no longer packs any punch today.  They blame others who aren’t on board for not being spiritual enough or yield to living in a defeated shadow of yesterday.  Paul decides that continuing to do what he has been doing is no longer effective so he changes his approach, opening the way for a long and productive ministry.  His message remains the same, but his method is upgraded.  The mission is permanent but the method is fluid.</p>
<p>Take Away: We must not confuse the message with some transitory method.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
