<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>writing &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/writing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 16:55:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>writing &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ephesians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ephesians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In over my head Ephesians 3: So here I am, preaching and writing about things that are way over my head. It was hidden in plain view. Throughout the ages the Lord God has intended to save all people. Some considered to be insiders are no more “inside” than those assumed to be outside the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16140" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16140" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-16140" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209623.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16140" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along Oregon Hwy 101 &#8211; north of Florence &#8211; Heceta Head Lighthouse</figcaption></figure>
<p>In over my head </p>
<p>Ephesians 3: So here I am, preaching and writing about things that are way over my head.</p>
<p>It was hidden in plain view.  Throughout the ages the Lord God has intended to save all people.  Some considered to be insiders are no more “inside” than those assumed to be outside the saving work of God.  It was always there, easy enough to see, but missed by most.  Now, the secret is out and throughout the Gentile world people are responding to the way made clear by the work of Jesus, the Son of God.  The Apostle Paul is amazed to find himself in the middle of things.  He, more than most anyone, had been blind to God’s intention, at one point actively fighting against it.  In fact, Paul has been twice surprised: first, by the fact that all along God intended to save all who will come and second, by the fact that he, Paul, has a role to play in the revelation of this plan.  The Apostle considers himself to be, of all people, an especially unlikely candidate.  Still he finds himself uniquely equipped for the work, with words and ministry flowing out of his life.  He knows that the Source of all this isn’t in him at all, but, rather, is the result of God’s doing through him what he could never do otherwise.  Paul’s experience is, of course, extraordinary and a person who wants to lay claim on any similarities had better tread carefully.  Still, it’s important for preachers and teachers and professors to get their heads around this.  On one hand, believing God has chosen us and uses us in surprising ways lends us a sense of spiritual authority and self-assurance in our service of the Lord.  On the other hand, knowing that none of it actually comes from us grounds us in real humility.  Otherwise, we end up thinking more highly of ourselves than we ought to think, and the possibility of our ministry being used of God is greatly diluted.</p>
<p>Take Away: When God calls and uses a person that person must never lose sight of the fact that their usefulness is the Lord’s doing and not theirs.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
