<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 1Chronicles &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-1chronicles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 06:02:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 1Chronicles &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 04:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Genealogical research 1 Chronicles 1: Abraham&#8217;s family tree developed along these lines. The books called 1st and 2nd Chronicles cover the same period of history that is covered in 1st and 2nd Samuel and 1st and 2nd Kings. However, these books were written around 100 years after the others. Because of that we see a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uu6cxkSk1VY/XpSeUx6xXBI/AAAAAAABEps/k9wWKB7Ou7wrTK-2j_6KmZzvefhWa4upQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_155221.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
Genealogical research<br />
1 Chronicles 1: Abraham&#8217;s family tree developed along these lines.<br />
The books called 1st and 2nd Chronicles cover the same period of history that is covered in 1st and 2nd Samuel and 1st and 2nd Kings. However, these books were written around 100 years after the others. Because of that we see a different perspective here. Not only are there different details, as happens any time two or more people tell about the same events, but the emphasis is different too. The books of the Chronicles are written for people whose ancestors were exiled from Israel and Judah two or more generations earlier. These people are in danger of being swallowed up by other cultures to the point that they&#8217;re forgetting that they&#8217;re &#8220;children of Abraham.&#8221; The writer (maybe Ezra) wants to reconnect them to their roots and to their God. He sets out to tell them their own story; where they came from and why they’re where they now are. With that in mind, he starts off with genealogy: page after page of names. He wants his readers to find their place in the story. Today, most of us skip through these pages of names. The writer, though, wants his original readers to see their own family record, and in connecting with their ancestry to reconnect their lives to the story of God. To some extent we all need to do some spiritual genealogical work once in a while. It’s to our benefit to remember how we’ve arrived at our current place among the people of God. I&#8217;m not just talking about that precious Sunday School teacher who showed an interest in us, but even looking farther back to those who served God and passed the faith along to our &#8220;spiritual ancestors.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: While we can’t spend all our time looking back it’s not a bad idea to consider our spiritual genealogy once in a while.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 04:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health and wealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The prayer of Jabez 1 Chronicles 3: Jabez prayed to the God of Israel. Few people had ever taken note of the “prayer of Jabez” before a little book was written about it and this prayer became well known. Here&#8217;s the prayer from The Message: &#8220;Bless me, o bless me! Give me land, large tracts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8t9P6il1nAk/XpYVFh6b6OI/AAAAAAABEqs/roWfcw6UiC4T5jrQFpjExF7apfOvVuoLACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_155714.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
The prayer of Jabez<br />
1 Chronicles 3: Jabez prayed to the God of Israel.<br />
Few people had ever taken note of the “prayer of Jabez” before a little book was written about it and this prayer became well known.  Here&#8217;s the prayer from The Message: &#8220;Bless me, o bless me!  Give me land, large tracts of land.  And provide your personal protection &#8212; don&#8217;t let evil hurt me.&#8221;  Then we’re told: &#8220;God gave him what he asked.&#8221;  When everyone was talking about this prayer, I added it to my prayer journal and spent time meditating on it, finding ways to make it &#8220;my&#8221; prayer.  The “Jabez prayer fad&#8221; faded and we don’t hear people talking about it anymore.  I doubt that this prayer is intended take the place of the Lord&#8217;s Prayer or some of the Psalm prayers.  We aren&#8217;t told to pray this prayer of Jabez but we are told to pray the Lord&#8217;s Prayer and we’re wise to keep that in mind.  Also, I’m glad that The Message reminds us that Jabez is praying for more land.  He wants to increase his wealth.  In other words, the &#8220;more territory&#8221; he prayed for wasn’t a larger Sunday School class or greater spiritual influence.  We’ve spiritualized the prayer but he’s asking for wealth.  Before I make this into a model prayer I might want to spend some time with the words of our Lord who told us to seek his Kingdom and trust him with the material things of life.  Finally, I think his prayer for protection from evil is right on.  The reason I know that is that Jesus taught us to pray the very same thing.  So, what do I do with this prayer?  For one thing, I think I’m free to use it by filtering it through the teachings of our Lord.  Jabez asked for wealth and when I ask for &#8220;spiritual wealth&#8221; I’m stepping away from Jabez but moving in direction of Lord.  Also, I can remember that Jabez prayed out of absolute sincerity and faith and that pleased God.  In fact, I’m told that God answered this man&#8217;s prayer.  I learn here that God loves it when I pray in faith.  Finally, before I start asking for &#8220;more&#8221; I might want to spend some time thinking about what it means for me to take up my cross and follow Jesus.<br />
Take Away: Lord, teach us to pray.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 04:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appreciation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God bless the singers 1 Chronicles 6: These are the persons David appointed to lead the singing in the house of God. As I read page after page of “Chronicles” I meet lots of people. There are fighters who cried out to God and received his help, farmers, potters, and linen workers. Now, I’m introduced [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-V9Hp9SjPNvs/Xpd5DBD565I/AAAAAAABErk/dahqSbHSZ68ZwWQelnQAWC9IbkamqdyiwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_6263.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
God bless the singers<br />
1 Chronicles 6: These are the persons David appointed to lead the singing in the house of God.<br />
As I read page after page of “Chronicles” I meet lots of people.  There are fighters who cried out to God and received his help, farmers, potters, and linen workers.  Now, I’m introduced to some professional singers.  These are the song leaders who served during David’s reign.  Here’s choirmaster Herman and his associate Asaph, the writer of some of the Psalms in our Bibles.  These singers were faithful to their assignment and, now we see them included in the list of people in the opening pages of 1 Chronicles.  Music has always been important to the people of God.  David, a song writer and musician himself, didn’t want to take any chances with the worship music of his day so he appointed people to give their full attention to it.  I don’t want to carry things too far here, but it’s good to remember that the music of worship is worth our best effort.  That doesn’t mean that any one style is the right one, but it does mean that our music is an offering to the Lord and we want to give him our best.  Personally, I’m thankful for the talented musicians and singers and song writers who have blessed me and helped me focus on the Lord.  This Sunday it might be a good idea to let these folks know they’re appreciated.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for those who lift our hearts to God through their music.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 04:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Family skeletons 1 Chronicles 7: Ezer and Elead [were] cattle-rustlers, killed on one of their raids. The accounting of Ephraim’s family tree unearths the gem that some of the family were cattle-rustlers. Things got so bad that the natives of Gath caught them and killed them. Their dad was deeply grieved by their deaths and, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-paksM9KB6Ew/Xpit0isdLII/AAAAAAABEsY/FTctLffmrNgaXEl_xaRJGjK8Lf9_EozNwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_160639.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
Family skeletons<br />
1 Chronicles 7: Ezer and Elead [were] cattle-rustlers, killed on one of their raids.<br />
The accounting of Ephraim’s family tree unearths the gem that some of the family were cattle-rustlers.  Things got so bad that the natives of Gath caught them and killed them.  Their dad was deeply grieved by their deaths and, when a baby was born to the family he named him “Unlucky” to reflect how he felt about things.   The story is just thrown in with the continued listing of who was the father of whom, but it does spark the imagination a bit and it feels like we’re hearing about the old American west rather than about life centuries before Christ.  I wonder how the original readers reacted to this bit of information.  Did they hang their heads in shame or did they sheepishly grin at one another?  I think there’s room for both reactions.  It’s that way for us too.  We can’t escape our connection to family.  Sometimes we’re quite pleased with it and other times, well, not so much.  At one level, I’m reminded that I’m not above the ups and downs, successes and failures of life.  At another level, I don’t need to take myself too seriously.  At least, so far as I know, I don’t have any ancestors named “Unlucky.”  I’m not as sure about the cattle-rustling though.<br />
Take Away: Don’t take life too seriously – sometimes it’s best to smile and move on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 04:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Full Circle 1 Chronicles 9: The first Israelites to return from exile to their homes and cities were the priests, the Levites, and the temple support staff. After page after page of genealogy we arrive at the wrap up statement that “this is the complete family tree for all Israel.” After wading through the names [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jHgORSkd59U/XppUXHU5ZeI/AAAAAAABEvA/PdofBXXKg4Qz3T1FWKw31lQYKKZDJ_z2ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_161628.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
Full Circle<br />
1 Chronicles 9: The first Israelites to return from exile to their homes and cities were the priests, the Levites, and the temple support staff.<br />
After page after page of genealogy we arrive at the wrap up statement that “this is the complete family tree for all Israel.”  After wading through the names (or maybe skipping them) we breathe a sigh of relief, ready to get back to the story telling of the book.  Instead, there are more names!   The writer skips over the years of exile to the beginning of the return to Jerusalem.  He speaks of these people differently, though, and it feels as though the writer may be a contemporary of some of these folks.  In just a few paragraphs we’ll be back to the story of King Saul and begin marching through the king stories of Israel and Judah.  However, having just finished the genealogy followed by the list of early returnees to Israel after the exile, I can’t help but reflect on how connected it all is.  Other nations that are exiled are absorbed into the culture of the Babylonian and, later on, Persian empires.  These descendants of Abraham, though, hold together.  There are changes to their culture and traditions, but they remain a separate people through it all.  It’s only because of that that I can read “this is how it ended” followed immediately by “this is how it continued.”  There’s only one way to explain it: it’s the Hand of God.  This God made promises to Abraham and centuries later to David.  Through the prophets, even in the darkest of days before the exile, there’s the promise of restoration.  Now, in an almost offhand way I see part of the fulfillment of that.  “Here’s the end of the story&#8230;now, let’s get back to the story.”  Caution: God at work here!<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s faithfulness spans lifetimes and generations.  His faithfulness never fails.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 05:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disobedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Starting at the end 1 Chronicles 10: Saul died in disobedience. When we first read the story of King Saul in 1 Samuel we get the full treatment, so we know all about how he was anointed and how his rejection of God unraveled his kingship and his life in general. Here, we start at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--J57P6wzzZU/Xpt2ysVnYwI/AAAAAAABEv8/EccegxuBsNwEBdMqTjEETzhQvJetVRERwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_162144.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills Needles Highway</figcaption></figure><br />
Starting at the end<br />
1 Chronicles 10: Saul died in disobedience.<br />
When we first read the story of King Saul in 1 Samuel we get the full treatment, so we know all about how he was anointed and how his rejection of God unraveled his kingship and his life in general.  Here, we start at the end of his life.  The writer seems to be in a hurry to get to King David and I think I know why.  This book is being written to remind the people of Israel where they came from and who they are.  The desire is to reignite their connection to one another and to God.  Saul could have been the first and greatest king of Israel, but he failed, dying not in glory, but in disobedience.  Later on, we’ll work through the failures that led to the exile, but here in the early going the idea is to inspire and ignite enthusiasm.  Sad to say, Saul’s story might be good for warning people of pending failure but it won’t do much to unite and give a sense of pride.  There’s a time to focus on such things.  After all, spiritual failure is a real possibility.  For now, though, the writer just wants to set up the story of David and give his readers something to cheer about.  Know what?  That’s okay with me too!<br />
Take Away: While we know all about spiritual failure it’s good to be reminded of the very real possibility of spiritual success too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Water from the well 1 Chronicles 11: He refused to drink it. Included in the genealogy of the Chronicles are the names and sample exploits of great warriors who serve under David. &#8220;The Thirty,&#8221; is a band of brave and capable fighters. This group has an awesome leader and some especially outstanding men called the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-fyyTloP8keM/Xpxsk3snOZI/AAAAAAABExA/SOCr0DEjsy8jmv83fDNabbNfLxxgrdU6gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_175843.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Custer State Park, SD</figcaption></figure><br />
Water from the well<br />
1 Chronicles 11: He refused to drink it.<br />
Included in the genealogy of the Chronicles are the names and sample exploits of great warriors who serve under David.  &#8220;The Thirty,&#8221; is a band of brave and capable fighters.  This group has an awesome leader and some especially outstanding men called the &#8220;Big Three.&#8221;  At one point David, who’s on the run from Saul, comments that he’d love a drink of water from the well at Bethlehem.  However, Bethlehem’s under Philistine rule at the time.  That detail doesn&#8217;t stop the &#8220;Big Three&#8221; from fighting their way into Bethlehem, drawing water from the well there, and then withdrawing to bring it to David.  David’s overwhelmed by this gift and refuses to drink it.  To him, this is a gift too precious to be received as a common thing so instead of drinking the water he pours it out as an offering to God.   I&#8217;ve never had anyone go to battle to bring me a drink of water but I’ve had some people do some wonderful things for me.  When that happens I don&#8217;t want to treat their sacrifice as a common thing.  Some gifts that are intended for me are so valuable that I know they’re too good for me.  When that happens, I can take the example of David, and make it an offering to the Lord.<br />
Take Away: Kindnesses done to us ought to be appreciated.  They should also humble us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 05:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Department of human resources 1 Chronicles 12: Hardly a day went by without men showing up to help – it wasn’t long before his band seemed as large as God’s own army! David’s cause is a just one. He’s been open and honest and faithful. Still, King Saul knows that his throne is, in reality, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qAM3KgoeXbI/Xp3egmZE-eI/AAAAAAABEyE/22lYh5St7ikrJa08rJIg2aOIEL3PEPANwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_6329.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Scotts Bluff National Monument, NE</figcaption></figure><br />
Department of human resources<br />
1 Chronicles 12: Hardly a day went by without men showing up to help – it wasn’t long before his band seemed as large as God’s own army!<br />
David’s cause is a just one.  He’s been open and honest and faithful.  Still, King Saul knows that his throne is, in reality, David’s.   He’s done nothing but be loyal to Saul yet he finds himself named public enemy number one.  David withdraws simply to save his own life.  However, like a magnet, he begins drawing fellow outcasts.  Saul can’t find David, but everyday people just show up and ask to join him.  Before long, he commands a force to be reckoned with and some of the great warriors of history are numbered among David’s band.  How’d this happen?  I think God’s finger prints are all over this.  The Lord picked David and now the Almighty’s building his team for the work to be done.  Many years later David’s most famous descendant has surrounded himself with twelve good men.  Still, there’s much to do.  A great harvest beckons, but more workers are needed.  Jesus tells his core group to pray that the Father will send more harvest workers.  In David’s day people who probably weren’t even sure how they found him just showed up to join his cause.  In the Gospels, Jesus puts out a call for harvest workers.  Maybe we church leaders should take note of what happens here.  If we’re doing what God wants done, he’ll supply the people to do it.  The Lord doesn’t use up human resources so we can do what we want to do.  However, as we see in David’s case, he has an abundant supply of people to help us do what he wants done.<br />
Take Away: If we’re faithful to the Lord he’ll supply the resources necessary for us to do what he wants done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ll just trust God anyway. 1 Chronicles 13: God erupted in anger against Uzziah and killed him because he grabbed the Chest. The death of Uzziah is shocking to me even as it is to David in this passage. They’re doing a good thing, bringing the Chest of God back from obscurity to its rightful [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4KNpOKn1MKE/Xp9k6AqKFyI/AAAAAAABEzA/JAegfg2iwXYiqpL-_pi2ZD_XF5Pn5HuWQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170909_115039.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Scotts Bluff National Monument, NE</figcaption></figure><br />
I’ll just trust God anyway.<br />
1 Chronicles 13: God erupted in anger against Uzziah and killed him because he grabbed the Chest.<br />
The death of Uzziah is shocking to me even as it is to David in this passage.  They’re doing a good thing, bringing the Chest of God back from obscurity to its rightful place of honor in Jerusalem.  Everyone agrees that it’s “the right thing to do.”  For transport they go so far as to build a brand new cart and David and others lead the way in a joyful procession.  It’s at the threshing floor in Kidon that disaster strikes.  The oxen pulling the cart stumble and Uzziah, who is, it seems, somehow involved in the mechanical part of the move reaches out and touches the Ark to steady it.  That’s when the shocking thing happens.  God strikes Uzziah dead for showing a lack of reverence for this holy object.  If you expect me to explain all this away I’m afraid I must disappoint you.  Even David who&#8217;s right there is frightened by what he’s just seen.  He decides to put the Ark in the building there, unwilling to bring it to Jerusalem.  It may be that Uzziah didn’t really need to steady the Ark and only used the incident as an excuse to reach out and touch it.  After all, everyone knew that the Ark was to be carried with poles so that the Levites who were entrusted with the task wouldn’t ever actually touch it.   However, that’s just speculation.  Ultimately I’m left with my belief that God’s character is pure love and that he never acts in a way contrary to his character.  This situation, like a million others, is beyond me.  It’s another of those “I’ll just trust God anyway” situations we find in both the Bible and in our own lives.<br />
Take Away: Happily, our salvation isn’t based on knowledge, but is, rather, based on faith.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 06:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Precious memories 1 Chronicles 15: God exploded in anger at us because we didn&#8217;t make proper preparation and follow instructions. This is the second effort David has made to bring the Ark of the Covenant to Jerusalem. The first ended with death. David says that was because the proper preparations and procedures weren’t followed. This [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-p9Uw-iEh-aQ/XqCqOz0DGmI/AAAAAAABE0M/y-AtCwENNTcCJ0kfSGUIF8fbd0Bl2rUzQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170909_115722.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Scotts Bluff National Monument, NE</figcaption></figure><br />
Precious memories<br />
1 Chronicles 15: God exploded in anger at us because we didn&#8217;t make proper preparation and follow instructions.<br />
This is the second effort David has made to bring the Ark of the Covenant to Jerusalem.  The first ended with death.  David says that was because the proper preparations and procedures weren’t followed.  This time things will be different because he&#8217;s paying better attention to the details.  There’s nothing like the Ark in Christianity.  Many traditions have holy objects but none of them are revered as was the Ark.  There’s a reminder here of the importance of sacred places and things.  For instance, there are places that are special to me because I’ve had especially powerful encounters with God in them.  Maybe you have your mother’s old Bible and just holding it causes you to feel not only closer to her, but to the Lord.  These things aren&#8217;t the same as the Ark or, later on, the Temple’s Holy of Holies.  Still, though, as I see David making plans to move the Ark, I’m reminded of the power of some things that have been used by the Lord to connect me to him.  I don’t worship them, but they are precious to me.<br />
Take Away: It’s a good thing to be reminded of times and places where the Lord has seemed especially near.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
