<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>pastoring &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/pastoring/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 16:46:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>pastoring &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-20/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking care of God’s people Acts 20: God’s people they are&#8230;God himself thought they were worth dying for. As did Jesus several years earlier, now Paul “sets his face toward Jerusalem” knowing that his arrival there will result in hardship. To speed his journey the Apostle doesn’t go back into Ephesus but, instead, sends word [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15955" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15955" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15955" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199546.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15955" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Taking care of God’s people </p>
<p>Acts 20: God’s people they are&#8230;God himself thought they were worth dying for.</p>
<p>As did Jesus several years earlier, now Paul “sets his face toward Jerusalem” knowing that his arrival there will result in hardship.  To speed his journey the Apostle doesn’t go back into Ephesus but, instead, sends word to the church leaders to meet him in Miletus, located about fifty miles south of Ephesus.  Here he has an emotional meeting with his dear friends and co-workers.  He charges them to guard and protect God’s people in Ephesus, reminding them that “God himself thought they were worth dying for.”  Even as this great Apostle is going to go through trials so will this great church.  As I study this passage I can’t help but think of the role of the ministry.  Paul, I see, isn’t worried about the organization and program of the church.  He doesn’t urge the leaders to focus on current worship trends or new technology.  Rather, he reminds them that they’re to guard and protect the “sheep” placed under their watch care.  They’re to value God’s people as God, himself, values them.  Happily, Paul has good news for these leaders of Ephesus and for church leaders across the ages.  He tells them that God “can make you into what he wants you to be and give you everything you could possibly need in this community of holy friends.”  The work of the ministry includes guarding and protecting God’s people from false teaching.  The power for accomplishing that task comes from a gracious God who works in our lives, giving us everything we need to successfully do the work to which we’re called.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord not only calls people to spiritual leadership, he also empowers them for that task.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pastoring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tearstained letters 2Corinthians 7: I know I distressed you greatly with my letter. The book of 1 Corinthians is almost painful to read. It’s clear the there are some sick situations there and that this church is far from being a healthy congregation. The Corinthian church isn’t a prototype of what a Christian church is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16095" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16095" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" class="size-large wp-image-16095" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658-1536x960.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2658.jpg 2025w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16095" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Tearstained letters </p>
<p>2Corinthians 7: I know I distressed you greatly with my letter.</p>
<p>The book of 1 Corinthians is almost painful to read.  It’s clear the there are some sick situations there and that this church is far from being a healthy congregation.  The Corinthian church isn’t a prototype of what a Christian church is supposed to look like, although how Paul deals with them is a primer on how a spiritual leader is to deal with a difficult church situation.  An insight in this passage is that as Paul writes to Corinth he knows the impact his words will have on the church.  Beyond that, his words impact him as well.  Administrating this strong medicine is painful for Paul too.  The old “this hurts me more than it hurts you” line is literally true in this situation.  Paul gets no pleasure in writing to his friends at Corinth as he does.  He’s frustrated with them and somewhat fearful for them.  Still, he expects his strong medicine to bring about, in the long run, good results.  Sometimes parents have to be disciplinarians.  It would be nice to always feel warm and fuzzy about things but to do so isn’t what real love is like.  In his first letter Paul steps up to the plate, telling them the facts of spiritual life even though, in his words, “I felt awful at the time.”  Sometimes preachers have to be disciplinarians.  As it is for Paul and as it is for parents, proper discipline should never carry with it a sense of pleasure in causing pain.  I imagine tearstains on the parchment that contains what we think of as 1 Corinthians.  In the same way, there should be tearstains on the sermon notes of a pastor who preaches a sermon that will cause some pain.  Otherwise, that sermon should never be preached.</p>
<p>Take Away: Sometimes discipline must be done but it should never be done with pleasure.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
