<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Revelation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-revelation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:19:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Revelation &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 08:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The book of the Bible that promises to make things plain to us Revelation 1: A revealing of Jesus, the Messiah. God gave it to make plain to his servants what is about to happen. It’s interesting that a book of the Bible that states its purpose to be “revealing” and making “plain” God’s intentions [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16442" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16442" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16442" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/PHOTO_20140910_165514.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16442" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sightseeing in San Francisco, CA &#8211; Golden Gate bridge</figcaption></figure>
<p>The book of the Bible that promises to make things plain to us</p>
<p>Revelation 1: A revealing of Jesus, the Messiah. God gave it to make plain to his servants what is about to happen.</p>
<p>It’s interesting that a book of the Bible that states its purpose to be “revealing” and making “plain” God’s intentions is considered by most people to be secretive, filled with hidden meanings and puzzles that can only be unraveled thousands of years after it was written. To some extent I think its John’s own fault. He likes to write using symbols and poetry. Also in play, I think, are the advances of technology John never imagined. He writes this letter thinking it’ll be passed around among seven churches. He never imagines that 1500 years later an invention will allow his letter to be mass produced and put in the hands of anyone who wants to read it. Had he thought about people greatly removed from the seven churches reading and trying to understand his words he might have at least added a few footnotes for those of us reading his writing hundreds of years later and under vastly different circumstances. However, that doesn’t mean that there’s nothing here for us today. In fact, it’s just the opposite. John’s Revelation connects us to Jesus in a way very different than do the Gospels or the Epistles. Here, we get a glimpse of how things look when viewed from heaven’s side. As long as I remember the purpose of this book – that it’s a revelation of Jesus &#8212; it has great value to me. Also, let me remind you that I’m writing devotionally here so don’t expect me to find any secret messages or unique interpretations here.</p>
<p>Take Away: When reading any book of the Bible it’s important to understand its purpose and read it with that purpose in mind.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appreciation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[He sees Revelation 2: I see what you’ve done…I see where you live…I see everything you’re doing for me. In his Revelation John has a message for seven churches. Each message follows a similar format: a description of Jesus as conqueror followed by a declaration that he sees what’s happening in the churches. Then there’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16364" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16364" style="width: 768px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16364" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P9179737.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16364" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pinnacles National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>He sees</p>
<p>Revelation 2: I see what you’ve done…I see where you live…I see everything you’re doing for me.</p>
<p>In his Revelation John has a message for seven churches. Each message follows a similar format: a description of Jesus as conqueror followed by a declaration that he sees what’s happening in the churches. Then there’s a word of encouragement followed by a word of correction followed by a call to response. Finally, there’s a command to hear these words and respond by taking action. These churches are operating in some extreme circumstances with lots of opposition both inside and outside their number. There are enemies of Christ dressed up as apostles and there are those who are trying to blend Christianity with the local religion. As the church stands firm in the faith and stands up to these deceivers the Lord is pleased. If the church fails here it places itself in danger of being something other than Christian. The thing that stands out to me today is that the Lord sees all this. He wants the believers to know that they aren’t operating out in the darkness apart from him. He also wants those who are dabbling in some of these beliefs and practices to know that he knows what they&#8217;re doing. It’s good to remember that our labor for the Lord doesn’t go unnoticed. As I faithfully serve him he takes note and wants to encourage me. It’s nice when people tell me I’m doing a good job. It makes me feel good, even appreciated. However, whether that happens or not there’s One who sees what I’ve done, where I live, and appreciates what I do in his name. Ultimately, that’s the only thing that really matters.</p>
<p>Take Away: Even if no one else sees the Lord sees. In the long run, that what matters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not one size fits all Revelation 3: The people I love, I call to account – prod and correct and guide so that they’ll live at their best. The message of the Lord to each of the last three churches is far from uniform. Two of these churches are in trouble. The third is doing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16367" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16367" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16367" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2927.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16367" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pinnacles National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Not one size fits all</p>
<p>Revelation 3: The people I love, I call to account – prod and correct and guide so that they’ll live at their best.</p>
<p>The message of the Lord to each of the last three churches is far from uniform. Two of these churches are in trouble. The third is doing quite well. One of the two that is failing on the surface looks quite healthy. It’s a church that’s operating an aggressive program with lots of meetings and activities – a full calendar. The other church that’s failing believes in moderation. They feel they’re successful and have earned a respite. Sorry to say, that attitude has caused them to take a bit of a break from God too. The result is a stern warning from Jesus. The third church, though, has been through some tough times. Many have fallen away leaving a small, but dedicated group that&#8217;s been tested in painful ways. Through it all they kept the Word of the Lord with “passionate patience.” In other words, their love for the Lord has done nothing but increase even as they’ve patiently worked through some of the hardest days of their lives. The Lord&#8217;s pleased with them and promises to open doors for them and to vindicate them and to keep them safe. As I read about these three churches my takeaway today isn’t that it’s a bad thing for a church to have an aggressive program or for church and people to take a breather once in a while. I don’t come away thinking that to be small and poor is to be more spiritual. Frankly, I’ve been around a few groups that were small and poor and proud of it. What does come to mind is that there are challenges to be found in just about every situation. A busy, successful church needs to be careful not to mistake what it does for Jesus for a vital, living relationship with him. A church that has had some success needs to be careful to keep its priorities straight. To personalize this farther, I need to remember that it’s the same for individuals. The satisfied, fulfilled Christian life isn’t defined by past success or current business for the Lord. It’s all about living in a daily, connected relationship with him.</p>
<p>Take Away: My spiritual life isn’t defined by what I’ve done or am doing for the Lord. Rather, it’s all about my living in a current, abiding relationship with him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 10:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anticipation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What an invitation! Revelation 4: Ascend and enter. Having received messages for seven churches John looks upward to see an opening door providing an entrance into Heaven. He hears a voice, issuing to him a command and a word of permission. He’s been invited into Heaven and is immediately filled with a sense of deep [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16370" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16370" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16370" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/IMG_2939.jpg 1407w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16370" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pinnacles National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>What an invitation!</p>
<p>Revelation 4: Ascend and enter.</p>
<p>Having received messages for seven churches John looks upward to see an opening door providing an entrance into Heaven. He hears a voice, issuing to him a command and a word of permission. He’s been invited into Heaven and is immediately filled with a sense of deep worship as he finds himself gazing on the very Throne of God. Everything’s overwhelming and, as he tells us about it, human language fails him. There’s worship going on and we’re left with the feeling that this is business as usual at the Throne. Heavenly beings sing “Holy, holy, holy” and those with crowns of righteousness cast those crowns at the feet of the One seated on the Throne. What&#8217;s business as usual in Heaven is all too rare on this side of that door. I’ve had some wonderful moments of blessing, some too precious for me to write about. They haven’t come nearly often enough but when they have come I’ve tasted just enough to long for more. Still, I&#8217;ve received an invitation to that place. I don’t know when it is that I’ll hear “Ascend and enter” but I do know that that command and word of permission will come someday. I’m sure I won’t like the process of getting there, but once I do, it&#8217;ll be worth it all.</p>
<p>Take Away: We’ve received that wonderful invitation to “ascend and enter” so let’s live as invited people, preparing for that day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lamb, Lion, King Revelation 5: Look – the Lion from Tribe Judah, the Root of David’s Tree, has conquered. The One who sits on the Throne has a small, sealed scroll full of mysteries to be revealed. However, not just anyone is qualified to open it. In fact, no one can be found and it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16373" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16373" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16373" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3319.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16373" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Lamb, Lion, King</p>
<p>Revelation 5: Look – the Lion from Tribe Judah, the Root of David’s Tree, has conquered.</p>
<p>The One who sits on the Throne has a small, sealed scroll full of mysteries to be revealed. However, not just anyone is qualified to open it. In fact, no one can be found and it appears to John as though his “revelation” isn’t going to happen. Then, he sees a Lamb that appears both weak and strong at the same time; bearing marks of death but with traits of unequaled wisdom and strength. John hears one of the Elders call this Lamb “the Lion from Tribe Judah.” We know about Judah. That’s the royal family tree of Israel. King David was of that family; so is Jesus. The One John sees looks like a slain Lamb that&#8217;s very much alive and powerful. This Lamb is also a Lion – a conqueror. He takes the scroll but at that moment no one&#8217;s thinking of the scroll. All heaven bursts forth in praise for the Lamb-Lion. It’s a thrilling moment as “thousand after thousand after thousand” of heavenly beings break forth in a song of praise. That group gets the first verse, then for the next one, all creation joins in. What a scene! There’s more to read, more to be revealed, and more to consider. For the moment though, as happens in this scene of worship I think I’ll just stop and join them in worshiping this Lamb-Lion-King.</p>
<p>Take Away: Worship of Jesus is at the heart of all Creation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The blood of the martyrs Revelation 6: I saw the souls of those killed because they had held firm in their witness to the Word of God. The seals unveil future events, although readers though the centuries have been all over the place in their understanding of just what it is John is seeing. Perhaps [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16376" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16376" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16376" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3321.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16376" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>The blood of the martyrs</p>
<p>Revelation 6: I saw the souls of those killed because they had held firm in their witness to the Word of God.</p>
<p>The seals unveil future events, although readers though the centuries have been all over the place in their understanding of just what it is John is seeing. Perhaps the broad view is the best one. History is marching to a climax and as that climax draws near the world&#8217;s going to experience powerful and disturbing events. As the fifth seal is removed we see those martyred for their faithfulness to the Lord. In John’s day people are already suffering for their faith. John, himself, in fact, is exiled from the church. However, things are going to get worse. Many will die on the floor of the Coliseum in Rome. History, in fact, will see many faithful Christians die as martyrs. Sad to say, it continues to this day. John hears their voices as they cry out for justice. They’re told that the day of justice is coming. As I think about these who&#8217;ve followed Jesus even into death I feel small and insignificant. I confess that I’m hardly worthy to share the name “Christian” with them. I don’t want to forget that my heritage of faith has been a costly one. I don’t want to forget those who, even as I write these words, are paying a dear price for standing firm in their faith. At the same time, the promise of this passage speaks to my heart today. These have already been given “white robes” – honored in heaven. The day will come when the books will be balanced and justice will prevail. It doesn’t take my feeling any sense of vengeance at all for me to say, if God is just, then he&#8217;ll “avenge their murders.”</p>
<p>Take Away: The justice of the Lord demands that things be set right, and that day is, indeed, coming.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Victory in Jesus Revelation 7: Who are these dressed in white robes, and where did they come from? As the worship scene in heaven unfolds John sees more and more worshipers. First, there are 144,000 people from the family trees of Israel. Then, he sees thousands and thousands from “all nations and tribes.” The number [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16379" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16379" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16379" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/100_3328.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16379" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Victory in Jesus</p>
<p>Revelation 7: Who are these dressed in white robes, and where did they come from?</p>
<p>As the worship scene in heaven unfolds John sees more and more worshipers. First, there are 144,000 people from the family trees of Israel. Then, he sees thousands and thousands from “all nations and tribes.” The number is too vast to count and they all begin singing praise to God and to the Lamb. John is transfixed by the scene but his focus is interrupted when one of the Elders asks him a question. He asks John who they are, this white robed, too-vast-to-be-counted throng of worshipers. John doesn’t know, but the Elder answers his own question. These are those who have come through the great tribulation. This huge multitude isn’t made up of everyone in heaven, just of those who faithfully serve Christ right at the end, as earth’s history is being wrapped up. A couple of things come to mind at this point. First, heaven won’t be a lonely place. In spite of “many called, few chosen” the “few” comprise a huge number. Second, as bad as the time of tribulation might be, by God’s power his people can overcome, not just surviving, barely limping in, but thriving in numbers too great to count, coming through clean and rejoicing. This is a testimony, not to human perseverance, but to God’s power at work in the lives of his people.</p>
<p>Take Away: By the grace of the Lord, by his power in our lives…by the Lord, we can hold fast in our faith and receive a glorious entrance into the place he’s prepared for us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When’s the best time to pray? Revelation 8: Smoke billowed up from the incense-laced prayers of the holy ones. The seventh seal marks, not the end, but the beginning of a series of judgments about the fall on the earth. Things are about to get bad, with huge events coming to earth, each announced by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16446" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16446" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16446" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/05/PHOTO_20140919_134621.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16446" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>When’s the best time to pray?</p>
<p>Revelation 8: Smoke billowed up from the incense-laced prayers of the holy ones.</p>
<p>The seventh seal marks, not the end, but the beginning of a series of judgments about the fall on the earth. Things are about to get bad, with huge events coming to earth, each announced by the blast of a trumpet. The sober nature of these events is underscored as a foreboding silence falls in heaven. Before that first trumpet blast John sees an angel carrying a gold censer. The scene in heaven is one of worship at the Temple and the angel with the censor is in the role of priest. The offering, made with incense, is the prayers of God’s people. Even as the judgment of God is about to be poured out on the earth, the prayers of his people are heard. Obviously, there’s a lot going on in this passage and Bible scholars are pressed to the limit to explain all the symbolism. I don’t claim to have any deep insight into the meaning here. However, I do note that before bad things ever start happening that God’s people are praying and that he’s listening to their prayers. While I doubt that the purpose of this passage is to encourage prayer I do see here an example of the importance of it. Of course we should pray when “something like a huge mountain…is flung into the sea” of our lives. However, it’s a good idea to already do some praying before such earth shaking events (literally in this case) start happening. God’s people need to pray before, during, and after unwelcome life events.</p>
<p>Take Away: Prayer matters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 10:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A good time to turn to God Revelation 9: There wasn’t a sign of a change of heart. The final three trumpets are called by some “woe-trumpets” because each one ushers in a period of suffering on earth. John is seeing future events, the end of time. He sees spiritual beings through his limited point [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16385" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16385" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16385" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PHOTO_20140919_142110.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16385" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>A good time to turn to God</p>
<p>Revelation 9: There wasn’t a sign of a change of heart.</p>
<p>The final three trumpets are called by some “woe-trumpets” because each one ushers in a period of suffering on earth. John is seeing future events, the end of time. He sees spiritual beings through his limited point of view so his descriptions are of strange, terrifying beings. The “locusts” are beings freed from the Abyss. They sweep across the earth like a huge plague of locusts, inflicting pain on a third of humanity. Angels that have been chained are set free to lead a destroying army that kills another third of humanity. Rather than fearfully turning to God those who survive continue as before: focused on material possessions, promiscuous lifestyles, and worshiping evil rather than God. Even as time draws to a violent end and the judgment of God is obvious they persist in their self-indulgent, God-ignoring ways. It hardly seems possible that it could be this way. Still, I’ve seen just a hint of it. I’ve seen people who’ve rejected the goodness of God and then, in the face of the hardship of life responded by hardening their hearts. In their case, their personal “woe-trumpet” didn’t result in their facing the spiritual facts of life. Of course, it doesn’t have to be that way. First of all, God’s love; his mercy and grace: these things should cause us to turn to him in sweet surrender. Second, when hardship does come, it doesn’t have to drive us away from God. Instead, it can cause us to run to him even as a hurt child runs to his or her Father for protection and comfort. It’s not smart to wait for such a time before turning to God, but if one hasn’t done it yet, days of trials and hardship, pain and suffering, are good days to turn to the one who offers us hope even as our world crumbles around us.</p>
<p>Take Away: When life is especially hard it is, as is always true, a good time to turn to the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 10:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A mystery within a mystery Revelation 10: Don’t write a word. The final three of the seven trumpets are called the “woe-trumpets.” Following the sounding of the sixth trumpet and the woe ushered in by it, there’s an interlude before the final trumpet sounds. Mysterious things happen. A mighty angel calls out and is answered [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16449" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16449" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16449" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/06/PHOTO_20140925_144250.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16449" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>A mystery within a mystery</p>
<p>Revelation 10: Don’t write a word.</p>
<p>The final three of the seven trumpets are called the “woe-trumpets.” Following the sounding of the sixth trumpet and the woe ushered in by it, there’s an interlude before the final trumpet sounds. Mysterious things happen. A mighty angel calls out and is answered by Seven Thunders. John dutifully starts to write it all down but is told, as the prophet Daniel was told centuries earlier, to seal up what he’s just heard. To this day any effort to understand this scene is more a guess than anything else. Simply put, no one has a clue as to what’s happening here. For an event in a book called “Revelation” it feels quite strange to have John commanded to silence. However, not knowing or understanding something leaves us in familiar territory. Frankly, what I do know of spiritual matters might fill a thimble. What I don’t know would fill an ocean. That doesn’t mean that I rejoice in my ignorance. I want to know all that’s knowable and understand all that’s understandable. This mysterious passage reminds me that not only am I not expected to fully understand everything that there are some things I’m not allowed to understand even in part. In some cases, I explore the best I can, grasp as I’m able and then move on, trusting God with all the mysteries that are beyond my grasp. In the specific case of this passage, I read it, scratch my head a bit, and move on; filing this mystery with a million others that I must leave in the capable hands of the Almighty.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t understand many of the things of God, but we can know him. That’s enough.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
