<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>God&#8217;s faithfulness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gods-faithfulness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>God&#8217;s faithfulness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-58/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust in God, not in chance Proverbs 22: Don&#8217;t gamble on the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow, hocking your house against a lucky chance. From the middle of Proverbs 22 through most of chapter 24 we’re given a list of thirty wise sayings collected by Solomon. In fact, this is the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-niY3Djbg5p0/X4dh3Bn01lI/AAAAAAABG74/dhCD4coPg00HSQOQl28BrjTGGNl91xNpACPcBGAsYHg/s400/2002new_hampshire-03.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2002 &#8211; New Hampshire</figcaption></figure><br />
Trust in God, not in chance<br />
Proverbs 22: Don&#8217;t gamble on the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow, hocking your house against a lucky chance.<br />
From the middle of Proverbs 22 through most of chapter 24 we’re given a list of thirty wise sayings collected by Solomon.  In fact, this is the first of three such collections, the last being some of Solomon&#8217;s own gems.  Clearly this wise man is not only a source of wisdom but is a collector of it too.  The proverb concerning gambling catches my eye today as gambling is everywhere in our culture.  Several states have turned to casinos as an answer to financial shortfalls.  Also, there are many state sponsored lotteries.   It isn&#8217;t unusual to be approached by someone selling raffle tickets in support of some worthy cause. (If I think it is truly worthy, I make a donation but decline taking a ticket.)  When I turn on the TV I find shows about poker games.  It’s clear that our society is awash with gambling.  This isn&#8217;t how people of faith are supposed to operate.  My hope isn’t that by taking a chance I can get hold of the money of other people who have taken the same chance.  The life of faith isn’t about getting all I can from anywhere I can.  Rather than gambling on my future by guessing the right lotto numbers I can stake my future on the solid rock of God&#8217;s faithfulness to me.  Jesus said it’s impossible to serve both God and money.  In this proverb, I see the wisdom of avoiding the gambling trap.<br />
Take Away: Our hope is in the Lord, not in picking the right lotto numbers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-139/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 09:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disappointment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the solid Rock I stand Isaiah 40: God doesn&#8217;t come and go. God lasts. Sooner or later everything fails us. Some failures come on purpose and can be considered betrayal. Others come by accident but are painful none-the-less. Still others come with great reluctance; such as the death of a loved one who promised [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-V1zK4EkuG-s/X-OKMY5MgZI/AAAAAAABIAE/KDSHMffQdk0ZTAbDSlkPUrPEa6YdvCNPACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281794.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
On the solid Rock I stand<br />
Isaiah 40: God doesn&#8217;t come and go.  God lasts.<br />
Sooner or later everything fails us.  Some failures come on purpose and can be considered betrayal.  Others come by accident but are painful none-the-less.  Still others come with great reluctance; such as the death of a loved one who promised to be with us always.  Sometimes I make something that was never intended to be permanent into a centerpiece in my life.  When the time comes for it to be taken away it becomes, spiritually speaking, a surgery rather than a simple letting go.  Because of the temporary nature of this life, I must remember the truth of Isaiah&#8217;s words here.  There’s only one place of absolute firm footing and that’s on the solid rock of God.  He’s the only One who never fails.  As I take my stand on the rock of his faithfulness everything else falls into its proper place.  I can weather betrayal because One vastly greater has not betrayed me.  I can survive some thoughtless, accidental failure and I can find hope even in genuine personal disasters because my hope isn’t focused there in the first place.  Everything else comes and goes.  If I’ve pinned my hopes and dreams on anything or anyone else, I’ll become a sad, broken man.  The only stability I really have (and need) is in the Lord.<br />
Take Away: There’s only one place of absolute firm footing and that’s on the solid rock of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-146/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s guidance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s voice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A personal Guide through life Isaiah 42: I&#8217;ll be a personal guide to them, directing them through unknown country. Have you ever been in a situation in which you needed a guide? Some years ago Jackie and I rafted some serious white water and part of the deal was that we, along with some other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 533px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vlHZ6c5cquk/X-zvEzbo7_I/AAAAAAABIFo/lSIqEUY2a6kj9thT8pRKX0oOcS1xmP5XQCPcBGAsYHg/s533/P9072354.JPG" width="533" height="425" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Stanley Hotel, Estes Park, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
A personal Guide through life<br />
Isaiah 42: I&#8217;ll be a personal guide to them, directing them through unknown country.<br />
Have you ever been in a situation in which you needed a guide?  Some years ago Jackie and I rafted some serious white water and part of the deal was that we, along with some other folks, hired a guide.  As I recall, he earned his money, directing us along the way so that we got wet without getting dumped into the raging water.  Isaiah pictures for us God&#8217;s offer to be our personal guide in life.  I don&#8217;t think I’m to draw from this that I&#8217;m to be a private in the army, marching to the bark of a stern drill sergeant, but I do see the promise of God&#8217;s faithfulness to me in the decisions of life.  Rather than barking out orders the Lord more often speaks in that oft mentioned &#8220;still small voice.&#8221;  Therefore, his offer of guidance can be refused.  Due to the fact that everything in my future can be classified as &#8220;unknown country&#8221; I thank the Lord for his offer to be my &#8220;personal guide.&#8221;  I have to admit that I still need some work in the listening part of this arrangement.<br />
Take Away: As I cooperate with him, the Lord is faithful to me in the decisions of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Lamentations</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-lamentations-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Lamentations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surveying the devastation, with hope Lamentations 3: The &#8220;worst&#8221; is never the worst. On the surface the words &#8220;the &#8216;worst&#8217; is never the worst&#8221; sounds pretty naive. It apparently goes along with &#8220;Cheer up, things could be worse&#8221; &#8212; just a shallow throwaway line that has no traction in a broken life. I have to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wFu-gBZrrD8/YIW9j-RSyCI/AAAAAAABJ8I/zhyV23h0vKI2NpeAMa-JKKJfGSTso7q3QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/estes%2Bpark%2B-%2Brmnp%2B-%2B%2B7-2-2010%2B6-31-44%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Rocky Mountain National Park , CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Surveying the devastation, with hope<br />
Lamentations 3: The &#8220;worst&#8221; is never the worst.<br />
On the surface the words &#8220;the &#8216;worst&#8217; is never the worst&#8221; sounds pretty naive.  It apparently goes along with &#8220;Cheer up, things could be worse&#8221; &#8212; just a shallow throwaway line that has no traction in a broken life.  I have to remind myself of where I am and who it is giving this, seeming trite, advice.  I&#8217;m standing in the midst of the rubble that was Jerusalem.  Decaying bodies are in sight.  The man speaking is Jeremiah, the weeping prophet.  He&#8217;s the one saying, &#8220;Hang in there. You think this is the worst situation possible, but something good will rise even out of these ashes.&#8221;  The prophet knows that his words won&#8217;t make sense unless he adds the reason for his surprising optimism.  He continues: &#8220;Why? Because the Master won&#8217;t ever walk out and fail to return. He works severely, he also works tenderly.&#8221;  The worst isn&#8217;t the worst because God doesn&#8217;t walk out, never to return; and when he returns, it&#8217;s with tender compassion.  I may be traveling down an unwelcome road right now.  The darkness may seem complete because it appears God has forsaken me for good.  Jeremiah reminds me that it&#8217;s never that way.  Even Jeremiah, who has first-hand seen the &#8220;severity&#8221; of God, is absolutely convinced of the &#8220;tenderness&#8221; of God.  I need to sit at the feet of this man who can stand in the midst of devastation and declare his trust in the Master&#8217;s tender faithfulness.  These are deep, and necessary truths; especially in the painful days of life.<br />
Take Away: Trust in the Lord even in the hardest days of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s messenger]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The story continues Ezekiel 1: God&#8217;s hand came upon him that day. Jeremiah&#8217;s story leads up to the fall of Israel to Babylon. We leave Jeremiah in Egypt with the handful of survivors who fled there after the destruction of Jerusalem. Now, as I turn the page, I find myself in the company of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 703px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-p1F4SBXnpWw/YJRAgK6xKhI/AAAAAAABKF4/EDImMt5swEo3k_4kI-cmmzGGwmodSDbpACPcBGAsYHg/s703/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B005.jpg" width="703" height="565" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The story continues<br />
Ezekiel 1: God&#8217;s hand came upon him that day.<br />
Jeremiah&#8217;s story leads up to the fall of Israel to Babylon.  We leave Jeremiah in Egypt with the handful of survivors who fled there after the destruction of Jerusalem.  Now, as I turn the page, I find myself in the company of the majority who are exiled in Babylon.  The clock has been turned back a bit as I join those taken in the first stage of the exile.  The destruction of Jerusalem is still ten years away.  This particular group of refugees has been settled along the Kebar River, southwest of city of Babylon.  Their beloved Jerusalem is now a distant memory; they&#8217;ll never return.  It seems to them that their connection to the God of Abraham is severed.  Simply put, they&#8217;ve failed the Almighty and the Almighty has kicked them out.  Their religion has focused on the Temple and now they&#8217;ll never see it again.  It&#8217;s time to move on.  Interestingly, they aren&#8217;t very far from the place where God first spoke to their ancestor, Abraham in the town of Ur, just to the east of them.  They&#8217;re about to find out that God isn’t limited by location and he doesn&#8217;t need a Temple as a headquarters. This God who spoke to Abraham promising their very existence, is about to speak to them.  A young priest named Ezekiel will take up where Jeremiah left off as God&#8217;s spokesman to his people.<br />
Take Away: The Lord isn’t limited by location and he doesn&#8217;t need a Temple as a headquarters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebellion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A sad love story Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head. This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting. It&#8217;s graphic and weighty. The sin of Israel is described as adultery. The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting. Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G6StTmlRGE4/YJWpEYEoWgI/AAAAAAABKHk/UYiJhwXT004zLwB1RgB0IPqUE-4QGCkvACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B004.jpg" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
A sad love story<br />
Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head.<br />
This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting.  It&#8217;s graphic and weighty.  The sin of Israel is described as adultery.  The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting.  Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, destined to die without ever having a chance at life.  Instead, the Lord rescues this pitiful infant and lavishes his love on it.  Then the imagery changes as he describes this rescued one as a grown woman, beautiful and loved by the Lord as a devoted husband loves his wife.  Ezekiel says that Israel, who should have never even existed, has become vain and disinterested in the God to whom she owes everything.  Instead of being faithful to the Lord, though, she’s become an unfaithful harlot.  Anyone hearing Ezekiel&#8217;s words should be disgusted with such betrayal and sin.  None of this is intended to be a pretty picture.  Instead, Ezekiel wants us to recoil at what he describes.  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that my nation is a blessed nation too.  In the early days our chances of survival were small, yet we survived by the grace of God.  Now we&#8217;re a nation many others watch, and many watch with envy.  And even as Israel began to take God for granted and rebel against him, so have we.  This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t fun to read but it needs to be allowed to speak to us in this day.<br />
Take Away: It’s a dangerous thing to forget the blessings of the Lord and take them for granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-59/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 23:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gog and Magog Ezekiel 39: I&#8217;ll use them to demonstrate my holiness with all the nations watching. The prophet has encouraging words for the broken people of God. The Lord will breathe life back into their dry bones and the nation will be brought back from the destruction that has come. It&#8217;s at this point [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rHooHeMQXNI/YLFDJklJD1I/AAAAAAABKTg/-xVTPmWqlPUo8JvK3jE1qBGu5qkTAD68gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-27-2011%2B5-33-31%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Thames Cruise &#8211; the actual London Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
Gog and Magog<br />
Ezekiel 39: I&#8217;ll use them to demonstrate my holiness with all the nations watching.<br />
The prophet has encouraging words for the broken people of God.  The Lord will breathe life back into their dry bones and the nation will be brought back from the destruction that has come.  It&#8217;s at this point that Ezekiel turns his attention to the &#8220;distant future&#8221; and the mysterious &#8220;Gog and Magog.&#8221;  From what I can tell, the more down to earth commentators think that Ezekiel&#8217;s original audience knew just who he was talking about and that this prophecy is much like those given against Egypt, Tyre, Sidon, and other nations in the region.  Taken at face value, then, Ezekiel is prophesying that in a more distant future, after the restoration of Israel, another regional power will come against God&#8217;s people.  When that happens, the Lord will move to defend them and will destroy the invaders.  However, there are two things that get the attention of many.  First, this nation from &#8220;the north&#8221; isn&#8217;t clearly identified in history.  Second, &#8220;Magog&#8221; is mentioned in a similarly vague way in Genesis and then Gog and Magog make a major appearance in the book of Revelation as part of the wind up of history.  If we conclude that the &#8220;distant future&#8221; Ezekiel&#8217;s talking about is still in our future we find ourselves swimming in the deeper waters of prophecy.  I hate to disappoint you, but I&#8217;m not ready to go there.  I think it&#8217;s more likely that Ezekiel is talking about a nation well known to him and his listeners and that the distant future isn&#8217;t &#8220;book of Revelation distant.&#8221;  I think that when John writes Revelation he&#8217;s reminded of Ezekiel&#8217;s words: an attack on God&#8217;s people by a coalition of enemy forces.  He uses that reference to describe the scene of the final battle.  To me, the key to the whole passage is God&#8217;s promise to defend his people and to &#8220;demonstrate his holiness&#8221; to the world.  That concept plugs into both the Ezekiel and the Revelation prophecies.  It also plugs into my life: when everything seems to be against me the Lord knows how to rescue me as one of his people.  Rather than getting all mystic about this passage, I&#8217;d rather find here yet another promise of God&#8217;s faithfulness even in the most difficult of circumstances.<br />
Take Away: Even when it seems everything is falling apart God is still God and God is always faithful to those who trust in him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Babylon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nebuchadnezzar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God is still God even when everything’s falling apart Daniel 1: The Master handed King Jehoiakim of Judah over to him. My devotional journey moves now to the book of Daniel. I&#8217;m glad to arrive here. For several months I&#8217;ve spent time in some of the hard scrabble writings of Isaiah, Jeremiah, and Ezekiel. I&#8217;m [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KU1y0H8c8wA/YLLx1GxpvTI/AAAAAAABKVM/yxVTFT-OzCkFscPHkpfpmBawhQy_LunHQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-27-2011%2B6-14-23%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Parliament and Big Ben, London, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
God is still God even when everything’s falling apart<br />
Daniel 1: The Master handed King Jehoiakim of Judah over to him.<br />
My devotional journey moves now to the book of Daniel.  I&#8217;m glad to arrive here.  For several months I&#8217;ve spent time in some of the hard scrabble writings of Isaiah, Jeremiah, and Ezekiel.  I&#8217;m ready to enjoy some devotional reading of some of the greatest stories of the Bible.  Daniel isn&#8217;t above giving us visions and prophecies.   In fact, his book is divided almost equally between stories of God&#8217;s deliverance and prophecies of God&#8217;s sovereignty.  For now, though, I&#8217;m looking forward to Daniel&#8217;s rise to prominence in Babylon, the story of the fiery furnace, and, of course, the lion&#8217;s den!  The events of Daniel take place around 600 years before Christ.  When King Jehoiakim of Judah rebels against his master Nebuchadnezzar of Babylon Jerusalem is attacked and brought to her knees.  The Temple is ransacked and many of its citizens are taken captive.  Among the captives are members of the royal line.  Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s policy is to pick of the best of the people of this defeated nation and indoctrinate them into the ways of his nation.  Daniel is one of those chosen for this.  Off he goes to Babylon, apparently, under the control of a king and government that has no interest in his Hebrew heritage.  In this dark hour of uncertainty it may seem to Daniel and friends that God had lost interest in them, but it isn&#8217;t so.  Things are just getting interesting!<br />
Take Away: When it seems all is lost the Lord is just getting started!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God has ways of getting our attention Daniel 2: If it please your majesty, tell us the dream. Nebuchadnezzar is having some repeating, vivid dreams and he&#8217;s sure they&#8217;re a message from some god. He has an entire division of wise men who are supposed to be experts in such things but he suspects that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uxOlUQz7338/YLUtDZDseFI/AAAAAAABKV0/1VzO4gZeVF8EvFyU9em5a-yHkuBS2feBgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P9307489.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; London &#8211; Changing of the Guard at Buckingham Palace</figcaption></figure><br />
God has ways of getting our attention<br />
Daniel 2: If it please your majesty, tell us the dream.<br />
Nebuchadnezzar is having some repeating, vivid dreams and he&#8217;s sure they&#8217;re a message from some god.  He has an entire division of wise men who are supposed to be experts in such things but he suspects that they&#8217;re all just carnival fortune tellers.  He knows that if he tells them his dream that they&#8217;ll make up an interpretation so he decides to really put them to the test.  Not only are they to interpret his dream, they&#8217;re to first tell him the dream, itself.  If they can do that he&#8217;ll know something supernatural is going on.  Nebuchadnezzar also has decided on an incentive plan for his wise men.  If they can&#8217;t tell him his dream he&#8217;ll kill them and their families.  If they do tell him, he&#8217;ll make them rich beyond their wildest dreams.  I can&#8217;t help but feel sorry for the fortunetellers who are in over their heads.  If the king told them his dream some would, no doubt, take it quite seriously and try to figure it out for him.  I&#8217;m also a bit frustrated with Nebuchadnezzar.  Here&#8217;s a man arrogant in his power.  The lives of all these men and their loved ones (including Daniel and his friends) are, in his eyes, disposable.  However, the Lord knows all of this and is using it for his own purposes.  Nebuchadnezzar has already been impressed with Daniel, Hananiah, Mishael, and Azariah as individuals.  Now, he&#8217;s going to find out about the God they serve.<br />
Take Away: The Lord has ways of getting our attention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 19:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It isn’t over till it’s over Hosea 12: What are you waiting for? Return to your God! Hosea is unique in the Old Testament in his understanding of God. The opening “living parable” of his enduring love of his unfaithful wife flavors the entire book. Now, it isn’t all romantic love. There’s some strong medicine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1347px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-acVK0QNdFxk/YOCYfsYiwQI/AAAAAAABKqo/X4bRfnBalqwFTnMWyDTWyAUaipeDhlDpACPcBGAsYHg/s1347/2013-06-07%2B16.33.10.jpg" width="1347" height="841" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Amish country &#8211; Arthur, IL</figcaption></figure><br />
It isn’t over till it’s over<br />
Hosea 12: What are you waiting for? Return to your God!<br />
Hosea is unique in the Old Testament in his understanding of God.  The opening “living parable” of his enduring love of his unfaithful wife flavors the entire book.  Now, it isn’t all romantic love.  There’s some strong medicine here, what could be called “tough love.”  Still, it&#8217;s love.  The Almighty is so in love with these people that he can’t let them go.  The God who could wipe them out in a second instead calls to them and reasons with them and, yes, uses some tough love in dealing with them.  In this passage the Lord illustrates his intentions by appealing to history.  He reminds them that Jacob started out as a “heel” who even tried to manipulate his Creator.  The Lord says that, in the end, he won and Jacob was changed into a new person.  Now, this same God turns his attention to the current sorry state of things.  He tells this rebellious nation that he loves them too much to cast them away.  He says that in his love, he won’t give up and he won’t give in.  They might as well surrender to it now because, ultimately, he&#8217;ll win.  Today, I’m reminded that God doesn’t give up on people and I shouldn’t give up on them either.  The person who seems the most lost; who has burned his bridges and declared his abandonment of the Lord is still on God’s radar screen.  Really, it isn’t over till God says it’s over!<br />
Take Away: The Lord doesn’t give up on people and I shouldn’t give up on them either.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
