<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>obedience &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/obedience/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:44:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>obedience &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-109/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 03:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No guarantee of success Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;. Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness. The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-i_a3YDShAZA/X71OF_Au9hI/AAAAAAABHrc/gzn2cFk2OU8x8X8KgmE4E1tceuPKuEqhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B12-58-18%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
No guarantee of success<br />
Isaiah 6: &#8230;they won&#8217;t have a clue about what is going on&#8230;so they won&#8217;t turn around and be made whole&#8230;.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s commission is powerful and associated with a vision of God&#8217;s holiness.  The prophet is personally transformed by the grace of God and he’s ready to &#8220;go&#8221; for the Lord.  However, the next thing the Lord tells Isaiah must be very difficult to swallow.  In spite of his being a man with &#8220;lips touched with a coal from off the altar&#8221; his ministry won’t bear fruit.  I know it takes commitment to step forward and say &#8220;send me&#8221; but how much more to go on this mission with the promise of failure.  The Lord says that the people Isaiah goes to minister to will not respond.  Why the Lord tells Isaiah this is a mystery to me.  Why not just send him on without telling him of the failure to come?  I have no answer.  However, I do see one important thing here: I belong to the Lord and I have to leave the results of my ministry in his hands.  For Isaiah the important thing is &#8220;going&#8221; &#8212; being faithful.  That’s how it is for all of us who serve him.<br />
Take Away: We’re called to obedient faithfulness.  The results we leave in the hands of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-123/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 06:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reason to expect an answer to prayer Isaiah 26: God, order a peaceful and whole life for us because everything we&#8217;ve done, you&#8217;ve done for us. What an interesting prayer this is. I love the request for a &#8220;peaceful and whole life.&#8221; When all is said and done, this is about as insightful a request [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 762px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SPeiZwkoO5k/X9AOnwO4-SI/AAAAAAABHyg/sqzy4fKVCuUVi5sxrOJCHg37n2cvKY4EwCPcBGAsYHg/s762/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-26-55%2BPM.JPG" width="762" height="609" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Reason to expect an answer to prayer<br />
Isaiah 26: God, order a peaceful and whole life for us because everything we&#8217;ve done, you&#8217;ve done for us.<br />
What an interesting prayer this is.  I love the request for a &#8220;peaceful and whole life.&#8221;  When all is said and done, this is about as insightful a request as a person can make for their own life.  Isaiah lives in turbulent times and, in the face of so much uncertainty, this prayer makes a lot of sense.  However, he isn&#8217;t the only one who has lived in such days.  We do too.  Again, I like this simple prayer.  The second half of this sentence though, is the reason the person praying thinks the first half will be granted.  Isaiah says, &#8220;We’re following your directions Lord, only doing what you’d have us do, operating under your power and authority.&#8221;  You see, it makes no sense to plead with the Lord for peace and life if I’m ignoring his intentions for my life.  The only way this prayer makes sense is when I pray it in the context of absolute obedience and trust.  It’s only when I can say, &#8220;Everything I have done and am doing is what God is doing in me&#8221; that I can pray with an expectation of God&#8217;s blessing on my life.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s blessings often depend on my obedience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-131/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To do list Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right. The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one. Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda. Who can survive such a purging? How does a person prepare for it? Isaiah has a list for all who will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6lieSoE49o/X9pXgBBGPBI/AAAAAAABH48/E9zKMFyWXN8_ama67n-b-yXf2dZap3JqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5291839.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Buffalo River, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
To do list<br />
Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right.<br />
The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one.  Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda.  Who can survive such a purging?  How does a person prepare for it?  Isaiah has a list for all who will listen: &#8220;live right, speak the truth, despise exploitation, refuse bribes, reject violence, and avoid evil amusements.&#8221;  This, he says, is the way through the storm, the way to stability and satisfaction.  I know that some things about God are complicated and it takes a lifetime of serious study and application to master them.  However, some things are pretty straight forward and this list is an example of that.  The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;  That is, we can drop the excuses and commit ourselves to, as best we can, doing the things we know we should do.  That isn&#8217;t all there is to it, but it’s a pretty good start.  Soon enough we&#8217;ll realize that our best isn&#8217;t good enough, but it does turn us in the right direction and with that done, we&#8217;ll find ourselves aligned with God&#8217;s grace which is freely extended to us.<br />
Take Away: The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/book-of-proverbs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No one way praying allowed Proverbs 28: God has no use for the prayers of people who won&#8217;t listen to him. I believe in prayer and consider myself to be a prayer learner. I&#8217;ve read books about it, talked about it, and practiced it. I’ve learned that there are different ways to pray. For instance, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ilpCSSaciNk/X43NnNUTHMI/AAAAAAABHBQ/xyA9nOA9oTw7xlSh_d0pqPEZdjvT6fatgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/lajolla08G.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; LaJolla, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
No one way praying allowed<br />
Proverbs 28: God has no use for the prayers of people who won&#8217;t listen to him.<br />
I believe in prayer and consider myself to be a prayer learner.  I&#8217;ve read books about it, talked about it, and practiced it.  I’ve learned that there are different ways to pray.  For instance, a person can kneel by their bedside or sit in an easy chair with a cup of coffee or write out a prayer or take a &#8220;prayer walk.&#8221;  These and several other approaches are good ways to pray.  One deal breaker to prayer is what is stated in this proverb: one way praying.  Prayer is intended to be a conversation with God.  It isn&#8217;t about my airing my list of wants and concerns while God patiently stands by like the waitress in a restaurant taking an order.  I’ve found that, generally speaking, it’s my perspective that’s changed in prayer.  The wise man of the proverbs reminds me of the conversational nature of prayer.  Of course, there’s another aspect of &#8220;listening&#8221; here.  When I spend time in the Presence of God and he does speak I’m to listen to what he says.  That is, I’m to take it to heart and move forward in obedience.  Often, I’ve found, God intends to use me in answer to my own prayers.  He has work for me to do and, no matter how fervently I continue to pray, nothing will come of it until I start listening to what the Lord’s saying to me.<br />
Take Away: Often, the Lord intends to use us in answer to our own prayers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-173/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hearing God Isaiah 55: I don&#8217;t think the way you think. The things I think are vitally important don&#8217;t impress God all that much. Like a child who spends all her money on candy and then doesn&#8217;t have lunch money, I tend to focus on things that might feel good at the time, but won&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-g6Dp3V_mH4o/YBCPd24IJ2I/AAAAAAABIT4/ylkrUR8A9EAQdPZkoMoycw35ybs4zJOXwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9032102.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along Old Fall River Road &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Hearing God<br />
Isaiah 55: I don&#8217;t think the way you think.<br />
The things I think are vitally important don&#8217;t impress God all that much.  Like a child who spends all her money on candy and then doesn&#8217;t have lunch money, I tend to focus on things that might feel good at the time, but won&#8217;t satisfy in the long run.  My deafness is so great that even when someone shouts out the truth I can&#8217;t hear them.  Instead, I hear the cry of materialism and am driven more by mass marketing schemes than by God&#8217;s word.  All along, I think I &#8216;m being smart and that, in the long run, if I do it my way I&#8217;ll be a contented, happy person.  Through Isaiah, the Lord responds that I&#8217;d better pay attention and do things his way.  God sees things differently than I do.  For instance, he sees surrender as the way to victory and death as the way to life.  The &#8220;higher way&#8221; Isaiah mentions isn&#8217;t about God being smarter than I am.  That&#8217;s a given.  The higher thoughts of the Lord spoken of here are about how he wants me to live my life.  I must retune my ears to hear his voice above the silliness of the crowd and then, in obedience, I am to align my life with his ways rather than those of the world.<br />
Take Away: It takes practice and self-discipline to learn to hear the voice of the Lord over the noise of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-174/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 15:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s more than a chicken in every pot Isaiah 55: So will the words that come out of my mouth not come back empty-handed. As we near national elections we hear a lot from politicians. The common wisdom is that a person will say whatever they need to say to get elected. Hopefully, that isn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1B-t91enAyA/YBGI-8ZwzRI/AAAAAAABIUY/8F24wl0Pta4sRyFVMeIcSZBzMALfHi6YQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PC253096.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston, TX</center></figcaption></figure><br />
It’s more than a chicken in every pot<br />
Isaiah 55: So will the words that come out of my mouth not come back empty-handed.<br />
As we near national elections we hear a lot from politicians.  The common wisdom is that a person will say whatever they need to say to get elected.  Hopefully, that isn&#8217;t always the case.  A nation needs leaders who lead with integrity.  Still, it isn&#8217;t hard for anyone who’s been paying attention to remember broken promises from vote seekers.  Isaiah says that God has things to say and that the Lord doesn’t hesitate to make some promises.  God&#8217;s message isn’t the common message of the world.  After all, his ways are higher than our ways.  Not only is his message unique, but his faithfulness to make good on that message is unique too.  When God says I’m to live my life his way and that, if I do, I’ll have a better life, well, that&#8217;s a word I can take to the bank.  The Lord’s at work, building a people worthy of being called his people.  Even as rain falling from the sky is instrumental in producing bountiful crops, so does the Word of God produce good lives in those who hear and obey.  The message of this scripture is that God isn&#8217;t just making so much noise when he says &#8220;this is the way I want you to live.&#8221;  Rather, he’s giving me an approach to life that will produce the rich harvest of God&#8217;s blessings.<br />
Take Away: The way of the Lord is the best way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-193/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A given life Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say. I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus. The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones. Beyond those [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7ly2NAezS9s/YCrg7H5D4oI/AAAAAAABImc/oAPwqqgH9ngaXn1QXNFEwMtEI9o-rhQhACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034534.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
A given life<br />
Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say.<br />
I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus.  The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones.  Beyond those material things, though, the important thing is that they bring themselves.  In this passage Isaiah reminds me that God made it all and he owns it all.  He&#8217;s not depending on me to bring him gold, frankincense, and myrrh or anything else for that matter.  He is, though, counting on me to bring him my reverent obedience.  I believe a person ought to practice their faith in Christ in practical ways, including being a good steward of all that has been placed in his or her hands.  However, the offering I give is simply an outflow of a given life.  That&#8217;s a gift that’s guaranteed to please the Lord.<br />
Take Away: Our offerings are an outflow of our given lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 17:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s call Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you. It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage. In fact, I am tempted to do just that. However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives. How does God pick people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ABjXB2vdN0Y/YC_5yGxgLtI/AAAAAAABIqA/6PLptGZ2EWMqzPnBdjXSL2c0i_YdS5SCACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034509.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s call<br />
Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you.<br />
It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage.  In fact, I am tempted to do just that.  However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives.  How does God pick people to speak on his behalf?  What criteria does he use?  Apparently, at least sometimes, he picks people to represent him who have no credentials at all!   In this case Jeremiah looks back on his call to be a prophet and remembers that it was God who picked him, not he who picked God.  Before he had any &#8220;credentials,&#8221; in fact, before he could make any decisions at all, God laid his hand on him, calling him to be his servant.  Clearly, the Almighty has his own agenda and makes decisions based on things totally beyond us.  Now, I have to add that that doesn&#8217;t mean that Jeremiah had no say in the matter.  God&#8217;s call came: that was God&#8217;s role alone.  Jeremiah had to cooperate: that was his role.  In theory at least, Jeremiah could have refused God and walked away and another person&#8217;s ministry would appear in place of this book of the Bible.  Since God called and Jeremiah (howbeit reluctantly) said &#8220;yes&#8221; we have his story here.  I&#8217;m reminded today that when God calls we can&#8217;t always understand why.  We just have to &#8220;trust and obey.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord doesn’t call us to understand everything but he does call us to obey all we understand him to call us to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-73/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 18:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Telling it the way it is Jeremiah 7: Do what I command so that your lives will go well. The original sin of the Garden of Eden is committed by human beings who decide that what God says isn&#8217;t right. Adam and Eve either doubt the wisdom or the honesty of God who commands them [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6ttfb4XePPo/YD1rRVR3poI/AAAAAAABI2M/ycGsMAvwr6gEsVzTgS091gL9BNvr3j-qgCPcBGAsYHg/s1443/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B8-13-2009%2B7-06-41%2BPM.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Telling it the way it is<br />
Jeremiah 7: Do what I command so that your lives will go well.<br />
The original sin of the Garden of Eden is committed by human beings who decide that what God says isn&#8217;t right. Adam and Eve either doubt the wisdom or the honesty of God who commands them to avoid the fruit of a certain tree because to eat it, he says, will result in death. As I read from Jeremiah I hear the Lord insisting that his orders are for our own good. &#8220;If you do what I say your lives will go well&#8221; he says. If I’m not careful, I translate this to mean, &#8220;Do it the way I say and I&#8217;ll go easy on you, do it your own way and I&#8217;ll go hard on you.&#8221; However, that isn&#8217;t his message. The idea is that God not only has my best interests in mind, but he knows what will help me and what will harm me. If I say to my 5 year old, &#8220;honey, don&#8217;t play with electric outlets&#8221; I&#8217;m not just making a random rule. Rather, I&#8217;m speaking out of both good will and superior knowledge. The Lord tells me that if I obey him, he&#8217;ll be my God and I&#8217;ll be his son. He says that as I abide in that relationship I&#8217;ll have a better life than I would have otherwise. Really, this isn&#8217;t mystical or theoretical stuff; it&#8217;s just the way it is.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s way is the best way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-74/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bible Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One more Bible study will do it Jeremiah 8: They know everything but God&#8217;s Word. My immediate reaction upon reading this line is that it&#8217;s a call to spend more time studying the Scriptures. After all, Bible study is a good thing; at least I hope so since I spend a lot of my time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8Oc95HMQEvk/YD5cJvvsCZI/AAAAAAABI3E/ECFzSvFiSCo3qCCoyRKsLYGBJngEzDZSwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/mt%2Branier%2Bnational%2Bpark%2B-%2B%2B8-13-2009%2B8-35-10%2BPM.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Mt Ranier National Park, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
One more Bible study will do it<br />
Jeremiah 8: They know everything but God&#8217;s Word.<br />
My immediate reaction upon reading this line is that it&#8217;s a call to spend more time studying the Scriptures.  After all, Bible study is a good thing; at least I hope so since I spend a lot of my time doing it.  To be honest though, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s what Jeremiah is talking about.  His listeners know what their Scriptures say and consider themselves to be &#8220;owners of God&#8217;s revelation.&#8221;  In other words, they know the Scriptures and claim they’re written just for them.  The problem isn&#8217;t that they don&#8217;t read God&#8217;s Word.  Rather, it&#8217;s that they don&#8217;t listen to the word of the Lord!  Through Jeremiah the Almighty is shouting out at them, trying to get their attention.  They&#8217;re going in the wrong direction and need to turn around before it&#8217;s too late.  While they’re faithfully going to Bible studies they’re ignoring what the Lord’s saying to them at that very moment!  What an important reminder for us today.  We have our KJV&#8217;s and our NIV&#8217;s and our NASB&#8217;s, and yes, our copies of The Message.  We tune in to TBN or Sky Angel, listen to our Christian radio station, and then attend our Bible Studies.  That&#8217;s just fine, in fact, that&#8217;s great.  However, when the Lord bypasses all that stuff and speaks to our hearts what are we doing with it?  Jeremiah says that even though they&#8217;re good at learning what the Scripture says they’re terrible at listening to the Lord when he speaks.  Are we, and am I, doing the same?<br />
Take Away: All the Bible study in the world won’t compensate for our ignoring what the Lord is saying to us this very moment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
