<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>seeking God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/seeking-god/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 07:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>seeking God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Habakkuk</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-habakkuk-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 11:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Habakkuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disappointment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeking God]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Telling it like it is Habakkuk 1: Why are you silent now? The complaint of the prophet to God is startling. He comes to the Lord and lays it all on the table, confessing his confusion and disappointment. He knows God to be righteous and loving but what he sees happening has none of that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15475" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15475" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15475" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9199115.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15475" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Telling it like it is<br />
Habakkuk 1: Why are you silent now?<br />
The complaint of the prophet to God is startling.  He comes to the Lord and lays it all on the table, confessing his confusion and disappointment.  He knows God to be righteous and loving but what he sees happening has none of that in it.  The godless army of Babylon is destroying God’s chosen people and that doesn’t make sense to Habakkuk.  Not only that, but his prayers go unanswered.  Why, of all times, does the Almighty choose this dark hour to go silent?  Where is God when evil is winning the day?  Does God’s use of unrighteous people to achieve his purposes make God, himself, unrighteous?  Habakkuk writes more on this topic, including a report on how God finally responds to his questions.  However, today I’m taken with how he goes into the presence of the Lord to state his fear and disappointment.  There’s something refreshing about Habakkuk’s approach to the Lord here.  Habakkuk isn’t irreverent toward the Almighty, but he openly expresses his disappointment in how the Lord is doing (maybe better, isn’t doing) things at this point.  I know I’m called to trust the Lord no matter what, but if I’m having doubts the Lord wants me to bring them to him.  To pretend I believe when I don’t does me no good and is dissatisfying to the Lord as well.<br />
Take Away: Better to victoriously march on in overcoming faith but when there is doubt we can be frankly honest with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 07:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prevenient grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeking God]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Seeking and being found 1 Chronicles 28: If you seek him, he&#8217;ll make sure you find him. In his old age David’s ready to hand the kingdom over to his son, Solomon. David has accomplished much during his years as king of Israel. Most notably he’s unified Israel and made them &#8220;one nation under God.&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-c9LOyMAfC9c/Xq3z3YtovYI/AAAAAAABE-c/hCwIZzYU0LElRXgDmhgPjeUsh1Y3LIaGgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180605_204251.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Bear Cave Thousand Trails &#8211; Buchanan, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Seeking and being found<br />
1 Chronicles 28: If you seek him, he&#8217;ll make sure you find him.<br />
In his old age David’s ready to hand the kingdom over to his son, Solomon.  David has accomplished much during his years as king of Israel.  Most notably he’s unified Israel and made them &#8220;one nation under God.&#8221; David well remembers his predecessor, Saul.  He knows that Saul failed, not because he lacked the ability to lead, but because he turned away from God.  David&#8217;s charge to Solomon is to seek God and serve God with all his heart.  The good news is that when a person does that God is drawn to him.  I’m glad today that God isn’t hidden from me.  I don&#8217;t have to perform some elaborate dance to get to him.  In fact, he’s already made the first move, providing me a way to himself, planting his grace in my heart before I’ve ever thought of him.  When I start to come to God, I may think that I’m starting some long and mysterious journey.  That’s mistaken.  When I start to come to God, I think I’m a “long way off.”   I take my first step only to discover, to my joy, that he’s running to me even as the father ran to the prodigal.  I start out to seek God only to discover that he’s already found me.<br />
Take Away: If you’re looking for God today, guess what?  He’s already found you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
