<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Hosea &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-hosea/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:07:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Hosea &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 18:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The living parable Hosea 1: This is God&#8217;s Message to Hosea. Having just spent time in the Old Testament book of Daniel it takes some reorientation to turn the page and find myself in the book of Hosea. Here I see that it will be 200 years before Daniel has his adventures in distant Babylonia. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SEF9stPHWPY/YM4gz0qgxXI/AAAAAAABKig/sSy-EJD_frMun4CMplyCyPo8BE2_iQuqACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-44.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; Versailles &#8211; Gardens</figcaption></figure><br />
The living parable<br />
Hosea 1: This is God&#8217;s Message to Hosea.<br />
Having just spent time in the Old Testament book of Daniel it takes some reorientation to turn the page and find myself in the book of Hosea.  Here I see that it will be 200 years before Daniel has his adventures in distant Babylonia.  I find myself back in the day of Isaiah and his warnings of future destruction and here I find God at work, reaching out to a rebellious people in an effort to restore them to him and spare them from what&#8217;s coming otherwise.  Also, as I reach the book of Hosea I find I&#8217;m now in the final segment of the Old Testament in the writings of those called the &#8220;minor prophets.&#8221;   Of course, it isn&#8217;t their message that&#8217;s &#8220;minor.&#8221;  It&#8217;s just that their books are shorter and more focused.   All the books of the Minor Prophets together contain less material than, say, the book of Ezekiel.  Hosea&#8217;s prophecy is called a &#8220;living parable.&#8221;  As will Ezekiel in years to come, Hosea is called to live out his message.  His prophecy is also a love story.  The love he demonstrates for us is not some silly, &#8220;love ya&#8217; man&#8221; or a shallow, &#8220;baby, I need your lovin'&#8221; kind of love.  Hosea demonstrates for us the depth and power of God&#8217;s love for us.<br />
Take Away: The Lord loves us with a powerful, persisting love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 18:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Who is this really? Hosea 1: The first time God spoke to Hosea&#8230; The book of Hosea contains no preface aside from the opening sentence or two. There&#8217;s no wading into this pool. Instead, we immediately jump off into the deep end! The thing is it appears it&#8217;s that way for Hosea too. Here&#8217;s a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-d8-W2aKl32Y/YM-sMqARhyI/AAAAAAABKjI/NAsGx7JAj_opxtI6qc_hvr6iZe6ys5DEwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA077910.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; taken from the Eiffel Tower &#8211; Level 2 &#8211; note the shadow</figcaption></figure><br />
Who is this really?<br />
Hosea 1: The first time God spoke to Hosea&#8230;<br />
The book of Hosea contains no preface aside from the opening sentence or two.  There&#8217;s no wading into this pool.  Instead, we immediately jump off into the deep end!  The thing is it appears it&#8217;s that way for Hosea too.  Here&#8217;s a godly man, minding his own business suddenly hearing from God.  Having grown up in the &#8217;60&#8217;s I loved Bill Cosby&#8217;s &#8220;Noah.&#8221;  Cosby imagines Noah hearing from the Lord and then asking &#8220;who is this really?&#8221;  If, out of nowhere, being told to build an ark was a strange command imagine what it’s like for Hosea when his first message from God is to go, find a prostitute, and marry her!  &#8220;Who is this really?&#8221; wouldn&#8217;t have been an unreasonable question.  However, Hosea recognizes the Voice of God and he responds, not as Bill Cosby might imagine, but in immediate, humble obedience.  God speaks, Hosea obeys.  We&#8217;ve hardly begun reading this book and before us is the line &#8220;Hosea did it.&#8221;  If I push everything back for a moment, before plunging on into the story, I can&#8217;t help but marvel at Hosea&#8217;s ability to hear, recognize, and then obey the Voice of God even though what he&#8217;s heard seems highly unreasonable.  Today, I can&#8217;t help but be impressed by that.<br />
Take Away: We all need lessons from people like Hosea and Noah in learning to hear and recognize the voice of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 18:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Picking a wife Hosea 1: He picked Gomer daughter of Diblaim. Somewhere in my sermon files I have a sermon on the &#8220;beautiful, vivacious, Gomer.&#8221; Aside from this being the name of Hosea&#8217;s bride the only other Gomer I know of is the TV character and he&#8217;s about as plain a guy and you&#8217;ll ever [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y7JgMQ61zi4/YNDAxqtkHMI/AAAAAAABKjg/mXX_kTGJcjMF9grDjIkkykr4CaSuD6jPQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-75.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; taken from the Eiffel Tower &#8211; on the elevator down</figcaption></figure><br />
Picking a wife<br />
Hosea 1: He picked Gomer daughter of Diblaim.<br />
Somewhere in my sermon files I have a sermon on the &#8220;beautiful, vivacious, Gomer.&#8221;  Aside from this being the name of Hosea&#8217;s bride the only other Gomer I know of is the TV character and he&#8217;s about as plain a guy and you&#8217;ll ever find.  I can&#8217;t help but wonder how Hosea went about obeying God&#8217;s command.  Did he head down to the red light district and pick a wife?  Did he already know Gomer from their childhoods and, maybe remembered a childhood crush he had on her?  This situation almost begs for more information.  Frankly, I doubt that Gomer is a lovely lady at all.  Instead, I think she’s hard and brittle and jaded and rebellious.  The reason I think that is not because I think all women who sell their bodies are like that.  I think many are victims for whom one bad choice has led to another.  Rather, I see Gomer thus because in this &#8220;living parable&#8221; she represents the rebellious people of Israel.  I don&#8217;t think that Hosea goes out and picks the prettiest of the lot.  Instead, I think he picks the person whose most like Israel: hard, brittle, jaded, and in rebellion against their loving God.  Obviously, such a marriage is doomed from the start.  However, in spite of this oil and water marriage, Hosea finds himself bound to his wife by an irresistible, undeniable love.  The reason for this is that, in this living parable Gomer represents Israel; Hosea represents God.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is bound to us in love, but not because we’re irresistibly loveable.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 18:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These preacher’s kids had it hard Hosea 2: Rename your brothers &#8220;God&#8217;s Somebody.&#8221; I&#8217;m not a preacher&#8217;s kid, but I raised one! Hopefully, my son doesn&#8217;t feel that growing up in a parsonage was all that bad. However, I&#8217;ve heard some horror stories from &#8220;PK&#8217;s.&#8221; I&#8217;ve concluded that while some of those stories are true, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-q6NRp60kM3Q/YNIT_ZXpDYI/AAAAAAABKj4/QDm2syaykOcClfUw1p_I1ywBN-auyQJTQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-80.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; Eiffel Tower</figcaption></figure><br />
These preacher’s kids had it hard<br />
Hosea 2: Rename your brothers &#8220;God&#8217;s Somebody.&#8221;<br />
I&#8217;m not a preacher&#8217;s kid, but I raised one!  Hopefully, my son doesn&#8217;t feel that growing up in a parsonage was all that bad.  However, I&#8217;ve heard some horror stories from &#8220;PK&#8217;s.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve concluded that while some of those stories are true, some are simply basic &#8220;growing up&#8221; stories that could be applied to just about any family.  However, Hosea&#8217;s kids have some no-questions-asked horror stories.  For one thing, their dad gives them strange names intended to preach a sermon.  Two of the three, in particular, get terrible names: a daughter named &#8220;No-Mercy&#8221; and a son who gets the awful name of &#8220;Nobody.&#8221;  I bet those kids needed therapy!  Every time the girl is called it’s to be a sermon warning that unless the nation repents God will show them &#8220;no mercy.&#8221;  When the boy is named it’s intended to declare that this &#8220;chosen people&#8221; is on the verge of being kicked out and becoming &#8220;nobody&#8221; in the sight of God.  There&#8217;s a ray of sunshine near the end of the first chapter and continuing into the second.  As a person might look across the hot and deadly desert to the distant cool mountains, Hosea looks down the road to a day of restoration.  One thing he sees is a day for new names.  When the discipline of God has done its work, children, and the whole nation, will be worthy of new names like &#8220;God&#8217;s Somebody&#8221; and &#8220;All Mercy.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: I’m glad I live on the “all mercy” side of this story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 18:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[betrayal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A love that never gives up Hosea 2: Then I&#8217;ll marry you for good &#8211; forever! The book of Hosea is a book of extremes. There&#8217;s nothing mundane or middle of the road here as everything is at one end or the other end of the spectrum. Here we see powerful love and painful betrayal. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-m7BCXoIFWM8/YNOLdVDkodI/AAAAAAABKkE/0fiOlmaiTbIV3f8V8UJkUsSYrWNpasIYwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BParis%2B-%2B-88.JPG" width="1200" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Paris &#8211; Eiffel Tower</figcaption></figure><br />
A love that never gives up<br />
Hosea 2: Then I&#8217;ll marry you for good &#8211; forever!<br />
The book of Hosea is a book of extremes.  There&#8217;s nothing mundane or middle of the road here as everything is at one end or the other end of the spectrum.  Here we see powerful love and painful betrayal.  We see the beauty of tender, marital sex and we also see the brutal, cheapening side of sex in the market place.  In one place we see the anger of God as he declares the coming destruction as a result of their sin but we also see God&#8217;s mercy as he promises restoration.  There&#8217;s nothing in Hosea that lends itself to a relaxing late night read before sleep.  This book is an emotional rollercoaster.  God&#8217;s people have betrayed him and, because of that betrayal he&#8217;s rejected them, kicking them out.  Israel has committed spiritual adultery against God and God has issued a decree of divorce against them.  Then as we&#8217;re emotionally ready to close the book on this relationship the tone of the Lord changes.  He&#8217;s kicked them out and declared his anger with them and judgment on them.   Just as I get my mind around that the landscape suddenly changes.  The Lord declares his intentions to clean them up, to romance them again and ultimately to reinstate his marriage to them.  The sweep of all this is stunning and I realize I&#8217;m reading about a love that never gives up.  God is truly the God of Second Chances.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The second time around Hosea 3: God ordered me, &#8220;Start all over: Love your wife again.&#8221; It isn&#8217;t hard to read between the lines here. Hosea married a prostitute, they had children, but she left him to return to her previous life. That sounds pretty cut and dried but I don&#8217;t think it was that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zIEk5SWevq0/YNSzJjlLAYI/AAAAAAABKkU/FZRqZDJFM38ajSDHObgfxZwU2dqrmIVBgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2012%2B-%2BMay%2BCamping%2BTrip-005.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2012 &#8211; Lost Maples State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
The second time around<br />
Hosea 3: God ordered me, &#8220;Start all over: Love your wife again.&#8221;<br />
It isn&#8217;t hard to read between the lines here.  Hosea married a prostitute, they had children, but she left him to return to her previous life.  That sounds pretty cut and dried but I don&#8217;t think it was that way at all.  What started off as Hosea&#8217;s obedience to a surprising command of God became a series of intense emotional experiences for the prophet.  Without choosing to, Hosea fell in love and for a time it seemed things were going to work out.  His wife, however, had a hard time settling down into a family routine.  The day came when she turned her back on her husband and children to return to her previous life.  Hosea&#8217;s heart was broken.  Sadly, I know too many people who can identify with the story of broken promises and marriages.  No one walks away unscarred by such a tragedy.  Hosea, trying to cope, throws himself into his work.  That helps him cover the pain.  One day at a time, he begins to get over it.  If the Lord&#8217;s first communication was surprising, his second must have left Hosea in shock.  God tells him to love her again.  That must have seemed like an impossible command.  In the time since their divorce Hosea has carefully crafted a shell about himself, insulating him from the pain she&#8217;s caused even as he hears what she&#8217;s returned to.  Now, God says Hosea is to emerge from that shell and open himself up to her again; not because she&#8217;s reformed, she hasn&#8217;t, but to reflect what God has done in his relationship with humanity.  Hosea&#8217;s wife will get another chance, not because she deserves it, but because Hosea loves her too much to give up on her.<br />
Take Away: The Lord loves us and reaches out to us even though we don’t deserve it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 18:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sacrificing, stubborn love Hosea 3: Love her the way I, God, love the Israelite people. Gomer has messed up big time. She&#8217;s left the man and children who love her. Her story will end with her in bondage physically, emotionally, and legally if not for Hosea. Under the Lord&#8217;s direction, he moves to rescue her [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8GqrKvFCQGA/YNYwhInEn1I/AAAAAAABKks/VB6rhaku9wkeQNWWn8iGqNFJ3GKZ0zImgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P5218231.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Near Columbus, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Sacrificing, stubborn love<br />
Hosea 3: Love her the way I, God, love the Israelite people.<br />
Gomer has messed up big time.  She&#8217;s left the man and children who love her.  Her story will end with her in bondage physically, emotionally, and legally if not for Hosea.  Under the Lord&#8217;s direction, he moves to rescue her from the stupid mess that binds her.  Hosea acts under God&#8217;s command but he also acts out of love.  In spite of Gomer&#8217;s rejection of him he can&#8217;t move past his love for her.  She&#8217;s brought disgrace to Hosea, possibly making him a laughingstock in the community.  She&#8217;s broken his heart and turned away from his love without even a word of apology.  Still, Hosea can&#8217;t let go.  This is no simple picture of romantic love.  Here I see love that demands sacrifice.  I see a stubborn love that persists even when the object of that love is unworthy.  God says he loves his people like this.  On one hand, he can&#8217;t ignore their sin and rebellion.  On the other, he can&#8217;t just walk away.  Because God is who he is, he loves.  This is the hope of every human being.  I&#8217;m fallen, unlovely, and condemned.  My only hope is God&#8217;s love: his sacrificing, stubborn love.  &#8220;While we were yet sinners Christ died for us.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Because the Lord is who he is, he loves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 18:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Identifying with the right person Hosea 3: From now on you&#8217;re living with me. I guess it&#8217;s just human nature but when I read the parables of Jesus my first inclination is to identify with &#8220;good guy&#8221; in the story. I see myself as the &#8220;tax collector&#8221; who prays for mercy, the servant who invests [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HOhuVEXHIXI/YNdonhHMOyI/AAAAAAABKk8/xnBvuFMpReYFXcq1C70tfQzSB-pceVjXQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2012%2B-%2BLost%2BMaples%2BState%2BPark%2BTX-009.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2012 Lost Maples State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Identifying with the right person<br />
Hosea 3: From now on you&#8217;re living with me.<br />
I guess it&#8217;s just human nature but when I read the parables of Jesus my first inclination is to identify with &#8220;good guy&#8221; in the story.  I see myself as the &#8220;tax collector&#8221; who prays for mercy, the servant who invests his talent, and the woman who finds the lost coin. It&#8217;s only when I&#8217;m willing to see myself from the less than stellar point of view that the parable can truly instruct me and help me become the person God would have me be.  Since Hosea&#8217;s story is a living parable, who am I in this story?  I know that the primary focus is on God and the ancient Israelites, but if I read this story devotionally who am I?  It has to be Gomer.  She&#8217;s a pitiful figure in the story.  Her origins are unknown to us, but she&#8217;s both a victim and a trespasser.  Even when she&#8217;s given a second chance at life she blows it, making a bigger mess than she had in the first place.  She&#8217;s stubborn and deeply flawed and, seemingly not worth redemption.  Hosea, though, loves her so much that he can&#8217;t do what common sense dictates.  He waded into the filth and got her the first time, and, when she betrays him and returns to it, he wades in again.  As I read this I&#8217;m not to say, &#8220;Yes, I&#8217;m like Hosea, and I&#8217;ll be gracious and kind and forgiving&#8221; (although, I&#8217;m supposed to be all of these things).  Instead, I&#8217;m to say, &#8220;I&#8217;ve been like Gomer.  In spite of God&#8217;s goodness to me I&#8217;ve been hard-headed and hard-hearted.  God has not only rescued me, but he&#8217;s waded out into sin to bring me back when I&#8217;ve failed.&#8221;  If I refuse to identify with Gomer in this story it will never have the impact on my life it&#8217;s intended to have.<br />
Take Away: The parables work best when I rightly identify myself in them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 19:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebellion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Farther than you want to go Hosea 4: That whirlwind has them in its clutches. Hosea&#8217;s personal parable soon gives way to his prophecies concerning sinful Israel. The background of his own experience is especially evident in his constant references to the debauchery of Israel and descriptions of God&#8217;s disgust with their practices even as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tKjmoNWwhZU/YNjOODuCNrI/AAAAAAABKlU/EQpDfae0mYsv62W7GHf1fEYMxa_gPmQOQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2012%2B-%2BLost%2BMaples%2BState%2BPark%2BTX-002.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2012 Lost Maples State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Farther than you want to go<br />
Hosea 4: That whirlwind has them in its clutches.<br />
Hosea&#8217;s personal parable soon gives way to his prophecies concerning sinful Israel.  The background of his own experience is especially evident in his constant references to the debauchery of Israel and descriptions of God&#8217;s disgust with their practices even as he loves them and calls them back.  The experience of Hosea with his unfaithful wife is a reflection of all that.  In this passage Hosea complains about their idol worshipping, sexually explicit religion.  They think promiscuity and drunkenness is their ticket to happiness and satisfaction.  Instead, as some wise people have said, &#8220;Sin will take you farther than you want to go.&#8221;  They&#8217;re willingly giving themselves to something that won&#8217;t satisfy and will ultimately destroy them.  What starts out as willful sin (&#8220;I can quit anytime I want&#8221;) becomes obsession and possession.  What they thought they could control now controls them.  People start down some foolish path thinking they&#8217;re in control.  Before long, they&#8217;re where they never expected to be and bound by what they never thought could control them.<br />
Take Away: Sin will take you farther than you want to go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unreservedly in love with God Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings. The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife. She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back. However, he knows that just getting her back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lvqSMImmE1Q/YNpYs5kXkuI/AAAAAAABKlg/wXeaCZAdJMIJLFU4mLTwRzJ3UVjKy9WwgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-05-28%2B20.27.13.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Saylorville Lake &#8211; near Des Moines, IA</figcaption></figure><br />
Unreservedly in love with God<br />
Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings.<br />
The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife.  She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back.  However, he knows that just getting her back won&#8217;t be enough.  For her to return yet remain unchanged will only start this whole destructive sequence over again.  Something in her has to change if there&#8217;s any hope for their future together.  That, Hosea says, is how it is between God and his people.  The Lord loves them and wants them to turn from their idol worshiping ways and return to him.  However, what he wants from them isn&#8217;t just a polished approach to doing worship.  Instead, he wants them to love him with the abandon and passion that he has for them.  He says to them, &#8220;I&#8217;m after love that lasts, not more religion.&#8221;  As old as this concept is, and as reasonable as it is, people to this very day fail to grasp this.  God doesn&#8217;t want me to go to church; to &#8220;practice religion,&#8221; or to attend Bible studies.  He wants me to passionately love him.  He wants me to throw myself into that relationship without reservation.  When that happens, no one has to tell me I ought to worship and pray and study my Bible.  The only reason for me to go to church and study my Bible is that in doing these things I better experience the Object of my strongest attraction: God, Himself.  That&#8217;s the kind of relationship God wants to have with me and with you.<br />
Take Away: The Lord wants us to passionately love him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
