<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Hebrews &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-hebrews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:12:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Hebrews &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communication]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[None other has these credentials Hebrews 1: But he says to the Son, You’re God. God has always been a communicating God. That’s abundantly obvious as I read through the Old Testament. Hardly a page can be read without reference to God’s communicating something. Outside the pages of the Bible there are other communications of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16241" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16241" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16241" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019698.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16241" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>None other has these credentials</p>
<p>Hebrews 1: But he says to the Son, You’re God.</p>
<p>God has always been a communicating God. That’s abundantly obvious as I read through the Old Testament. Hardly a page can be read without reference to God’s communicating something. Outside the pages of the Bible there are other communications of God; sometimes in direct, undeniable ways, other times for anyone willing to pay attention. The unnamed writer of the Book of Hebrews focuses on the ultimate communication of God. In Jesus, I’m told, God has spoken to us as he has never spoken before or will ever speak again. Up to this time, people might debate on who has been the greatest messenger of God. Perhaps it was one of the great patriarchs or prophets. Some might argue that it has to be the angels, whose very name means “messenger.” In the Book of Hebrews the case is made, and won, that only one messenger has spoken with the very authority of God. Other genuine messengers should be honored and their message heeded. Only one messenger is to be worshiped as God. His name is Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: In Jesus we see God, himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 10:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My brother is King Hebrews 2: It’s logical that the savior took on flesh and blood in order to rescue them by his death. Once the awful persecution of the ancient Church ended, it turned its attention to formalizing the doctrines of Christianity. What beliefs are required to be “Christian” and what beliefs are outside [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16242" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16242" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16242" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019700.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16242" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>My brother is King</p>
<p>Hebrews 2: It’s logical that the savior took on flesh and blood in order to rescue them by his death.</p>
<p>Once the awful persecution of the ancient Church ended, it turned its attention to formalizing the doctrines of Christianity. What beliefs are required to be “Christian” and what beliefs are outside of the boundaries of Christianity? Creeds were debated, created, and adjusted as Christians tried to better understand what was and what was not “Christian.” It’s no surprise that the main focus in all this was Jesus, himself. Who was he? What does it mean for him to be the “Son of God”? What does it mean for him to be the “Son of man”? Some people focused on his humanity and decided Jesus was a very good man who was picked by God to be the Savior of the world. Others focused on his divinity. They decided that Jesus appeared to be human, but was actually God dressed up in human flesh. Ultimately, the Church abandoned mathematics in favor of faith. It was concluded that Jesus was, at the same time 100% man and 100% God. Never mind that this adds up to 200% &#8212; we’d just believe that that’s how it is. Here we are, way down the road and so comfortable with this approach that we don’t think much about it. Today’s passage played a role in this understanding of Jesus. The writer of Hebrews describes one who was so human that he died a very human and real death for all. At the same time, he’s positioned in the loftiest of realms. For human beings, this is good news indeed, it’s great having one we call “brother” also be our Lord and Savior.</p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus is 100% man. He’s also 100% God. This God-man is the Savior of the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 10:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s all about Jesus Hebrews 3: Take a good hard look at Jesus. He’s the centerpiece of everything we believe. I have but a vague idea of what church was like for the original readers of this letter. Even if I can’t hear what’s being said I can walk into nearly any Christian worship event [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16243" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16243" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16243" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019708.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16243" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s all about Jesus</p>
<p>Hebrews 3: Take a good hard look at Jesus. He’s the centerpiece of everything we believe.</p>
<p>I have but a vague idea of what church was like for the original readers of this letter. Even if I can’t hear what’s being said I can walk into nearly any Christian worship event today and recognize elements I identify as “Christian.” Could I do the same if I found myself back in 50 A.D.? It’s a good question but I don’t have a good answer. How much of what we do is at the core of Christianity? Is preaching or singing or receiving the offering at the core? The writer of Hebrews reminds me today that Christianity is all about Christ. That must be the same whether I’m doing “high” or “low” church. In fact, if I make Christianity about church I’ve already missed the boat. Don’t get me wrong, I’m not anti-church, in fact, I’m all for it. However, for Christianity to be Christian it has to be absolutely focused on Jesus Christ. Even beyond that, it’s a living, right-now, kind of focus. I’m not looking at some old, dusty story or some tried and true belief system. I’m looking to a person who’s alive and well and with whom I have an up-to-date relationship. Only in such a relationship can I be a real Christian.</p>
<p>Take Away: If we’re not careful, we make Christianity about behavior or beliefs or church…that’s all mistaken. Christianity is about Christ.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The “rest” for the people of God Hebrews 4: The promise of “arrival” and “rest” are still there for God’s people. In the Old Testament story of the people of God we read of their deliverance from Egyptian slavery. By God’s hand they triumph at the Red Sea and not long after that come to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16244" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16244" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16244" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019710.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16244" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>The “rest” for the people of God</p>
<p>Hebrews 4: The promise of “arrival” and “rest” are still there for God’s people.</p>
<p>In the Old Testament story of the people of God we read of their deliverance from Egyptian slavery. By God’s hand they triumph at the Red Sea and not long after that come to the Jordan River with the promise that this is to be their land of rest. Once they possess Canaan they’ll be home at last. However it doesn’t work out. The people refuse to trust God and, because of that, are sentenced to a lifetime of wilderness wandering. The writer of Hebrews uses that sad story to tell his readers that the Lord calls his people to a “rest experience” in their relationship with him. After deliverance from sin, there’s a “Jordan River” crisis in which believers are to trust God to give them rest from the inner struggle and freedom to love him with all their heart and soul and mind. The failure of the people of Israel is a real possibility for the believer: to doubt the extent to which the Lord can deliver his people from the bondage of sin. To fail here is to turn back to the wilderness and to experience the spiritual journey as a constant struggle with failure and sin. To believe God and trust him with all of one’s life is to cross the Jordan and enter into a deeper spiritual life of freedom and liberty. “The promise of ‘arrival’ and ‘rest’ are still there for God’s people.”</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord not only forgives our sins – he also delivers us from that sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maturity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The importance of the journey Hebrews 5: Milk is for beginners…solid food is for the mature. The book of Hebrews, like the book of Romans, contains some challenging material. Both are intended to be not only read, but studied. The writer of Hebrews tells his readers that he’s about to take them out into some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16245" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16245" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16245" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019712.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16245" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>The importance of the journey</p>
<p>Hebrews 5: Milk is for beginners…solid food is for the mature.</p>
<p>The book of Hebrews, like the book of Romans, contains some challenging material. Both are intended to be not only read, but studied. The writer of Hebrews tells his readers that he’s about to take them out into some deep waters, at least that’s his desire. The problem, he says, is that some aren’t ready for that journey. It would be understandable if they were fresh, new believers. However, he’s focusing on those who’ve been around awhile; who, by now, should be ready to move on in their understanding of spiritual things. There are, I see, various stages in our lives in Christ. Spiritual babes need to focus on the basics. Once those are mastered, it’s time to move on, not leaving those things behind, but, instead, building on them as we move forward. On one hand, it’s dangerous for people to “camp out” just inside the gate. On the other hand, it’s dangerous for people to jump into the deeper water without first learning to swim. The church should be a place for people at the various stages of spiritual life. People should find their way in, become established, move into the deeper things of God and then begin helping others who are just finding their way in. Personally, I’m somewhere on that journey, farther along than others are but not as advanced as the rest. I think that in our eyes the destination is most important while in God’s eyes the journey is more important than the destination.</p>
<p>Take Away: Spiritual growth is necessary in the Christian life – but it’s not automatic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baptism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Christianity 101 Hebrews 6: The basic foundational truths are in place. There are lots of important things for Christians to know but what are the most important ones? Before moving on to the deeper things of God what are the basics that must be first mastered. Using the lingo of the university, what courses are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16246" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16246" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16246" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2757.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16246" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>Christianity 101</p>
<p>Hebrews 6: The basic foundational truths are in place.</p>
<p>There are lots of important things for Christians to know but what are the most important ones? Before moving on to the deeper things of God what are the basics that must be first mastered. Using the lingo of the university, what courses are included in Christianity 101? The writer of Hebrews lists 5 “courses” that must be passed before the believer is ready to deal with more advanced topics. First is trust in God. For me to even be a Christian in the first place I must stop trusting in myself as a source of salvation and start trusting in the Lord. Second is baptism. This entry sacrament is an important part of my becoming a participant in the grace of God and shouldn’t be overlooked. Third is “laying on of hands.” This may be the most challenging of the five, but I think it’s an understanding that God calls people to the ministry and that the church is to recognize that they are called and then to ordain them as set apart for service and leadership by the Lord. Perhaps this needs to be understood early in the Christian life because the Lord often calls people to a life of ministry early on, or even as a part of, their salvation experience. Fourth is “resurrection of the dead.” Believers are, well, believers. We believe Jesus was resurrected from the grave on that first Easter morning. We believe that because of his resurrection all who trust in him share in that same resurrection hope. Fifth is “eternal judgment.” New Christians are to understand that eternity is at stake in their lives and in the lives of all people who will stand before the Lord in final judgment. These five things aren’t all there is to faith. In fact, they aren’t even all there is at the core, but the writer of Hebrews highlights them as a good starting point. Once these things are settled, it’s time to move on. He says, “Let’s get on with it!”</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t want to camp out just inside the gate. At the same time we need to master the basics before we can move on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priesthood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mystery priest of the Bible Hebrews 7: God intervened and called this new, permanent priesthood into being. The writer of Hebrews spends a great deal of time talking about a little known person named Melchizedek from the Old Testament book of Genesis. Abraham goes out to fight a great battle which he wins by [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16247" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16247" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16247" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019713.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16247" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mystery priest of the Bible</p>
<p>Hebrews 7: God intervened and called this new, permanent priesthood into being.</p>
<p>The writer of Hebrews spends a great deal of time talking about a little known person named Melchizedek from the Old Testament book of Genesis. Abraham goes out to fight a great battle which he wins by the help of God. As he returns with the people he’s rescued and the spoils of the battle this “king of Salem” greets him. Abraham, the man with the promise of God, treats him as a priest, giving him a tithe of the spoils and receives a blessing from him. It will be centuries before Abraham’s descendants will have a formal priesthood and the case could be made that if anyone&#8217;s positioned as a priest it would be Abraham, not this otherwise unknown man. The Hebrews writer concludes that Melchizedek was ordained to the priesthood by none other than the Lord and that in him we have a priesthood that operates completely outside the Levitical priesthood of Israel. Then, many centuries later, another priest who&#8217;s outside the Levitical tradition appears. In a much greater way, he serves in the priestly role. This great priest makes the ultimate sacrifice for sins and thus blesses all people. The writer of Hebrews connects the dots for us that here’s another priest ordained, not because of lineage and not by man, but by God’s own decree. In Jesus we have a never ending, absolutely effective, God-ordained priest.</p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus is our high priest. We need no other.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the law]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What God wanted all along Hebrews 8: God put the old plan on the shelf. Prior to Christ, the old plan was the only plan. It included laws written on stone, rules and regulations. It was characterized by failure, repentance, and trying harder. It actually never had a chance of setting people right with God [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16248" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16248" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16248" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019714.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16248" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>What God wanted all along</p>
<p>Hebrews 8: God put the old plan on the shelf.</p>
<p>Prior to Christ, the old plan was the only plan. It included laws written on stone, rules and regulations. It was characterized by failure, repentance, and trying harder. It actually never had a chance of setting people right with God and had more to do with letting people who wanted to “do it themselves” find out just how dissatisfying that kind of religion is. All along, the Lord had a superior way in mind. That better way started, not with rules and regulations, but with the Lord taking charge of salvation. His plan all along was to change people’s hearts so that their religion would be less religion and more relationship. There were plenty of hints that this was coming. The revered prophets of old were much more relationship oriented than they were rules oriented. Jeremiah, who&#8217;s quoted in this passage, longed for a day when God’s Law would be written inside a person rather than written on stone tablets. Their greatest king, David, was remembered, not as a man of rules but, instead, as a man after God’s heart. The rules had their place, but now they’ve been replaced by grace through Jesus Christ. Now, the old way is a museum exhibit. The new way is life, itself.</p>
<p>Take Away: Through Christ’s death we have abundant life – something rule keeping could never accomplish.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No more blood needed Hebrews 9: He brought together God and his people in this new way. It was a bloody religion. Even the giving of the Law was accompanied by the sheading of the blood of innocent animals. Through the centuries the blood continues to flow and on one day each year, in particular, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16249" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16249" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16249" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019717.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16249" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>No more blood needed</p>
<p>Hebrews 9: He brought together God and his people in this new way.</p>
<p>It was a bloody religion. Even the giving of the Law was accompanied by the sheading of the blood of innocent animals. Through the centuries the blood continues to flow and on one day each year, in particular, the blood is taken behind the curtain into the Holy of Holies to atone for the sins of the High Priest and all the people. Then, Jesus, the Son of God, comes to make the ultimate blood sacrifice: his own. This High Priest gives himself, and in so doing, finishes the old bloody system once and for good. No more blood and no more curtain. These things that stood as a barrier between God and man are abolished for good, belonging in history books and museums rather than in real life. Jesus creates a new connection between God and man, the curtain removed and no more blood necessary. Today, we follow the Lord’s command to “remember” by receiving the Lord’s Supper. In the cup though, we don’t need blood. The absence of blood is, in itself, a lesson. Because Christ’s blood was shed long ago, just a bit of wine (in my church tradition, its “new wine”) is all that’s needed.</p>
<p>Take Away: Christ’s sacrifice was what was needed all along and it never needs to be made again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hebrews</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-hebrews-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Church attendance Hebrews 10: Not avoiding worshiping together as some do but spurring each other on. All the heavy lifting to provide my salvation has already been done by Jesus. It’s his obedience to the cross that&#8217;s opened a new, living way to God. It’s his blood that’s been shed, providing the final, ultimate sacrifice. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16250" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16250" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16250" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2759.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16250" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oregon 101 &#8211; along the southern coast</figcaption></figure>
<p>Church attendance</p>
<p>Hebrews 10: Not avoiding worshiping together as some do but spurring each other on.</p>
<p>All the heavy lifting to provide my salvation has already been done by Jesus. It’s his obedience to the cross that&#8217;s opened a new, living way to God. It’s his blood that’s been shed, providing the final, ultimate sacrifice. Now, the way to God is opened and I have sure, absolute promises upon which to take my stand. So, that’s what I do. I respond in belief and then do all I can to nurture that hope I’ve been so graciously given. One of the ways I do that, according to the writer of Hebrews, is to worship with fellow believers. In spite of the fact that some folks don’t think it is necessary or worth the time, I’m to see it as a valuable component of the life of faith. As part of a worshiping community my connection to Jesus is strengthened, my understanding of the things of God is deepened, and opportunities for serving the Lord are provided. Some may think they know better or that they have bigger fish to fry. I see it as one of several ways in which I more firmly grasp my hold on the things of God. After all, Jesus has already done the heavy lifting here. My being faithful to his Church and all the other disciplines of the Christian life is nothing in comparison to his bleeding and dying on the cross.</p>
<p>Take Away: Thank the Lord for the gift of the Church, the Body of Christ.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
