<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cruising &#8211; Here and There</title>
	<atom:link href="/travel/tag/cruising/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/travel</link>
	<description>Scott and Jackie&#039;s Travels – Thousand Trails Reviews, Campground Reviews, Fulltime RVing, European Travel</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 16:27:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2022 &#8211; Lucerne, Switzerland</title>
		<link>/travel/2022/12/30/2022-lucerne-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[grscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 20:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Jackie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cruising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italy-switzerland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sightseeing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switzerland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pastorscott.com/travel/?p=5018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, we left Milan, Italy on a high-speed train bound for Lucerne, Switzerland.  The train was very fast, very quiet, and quite comfortable.  Our route took us *under* the Swiss Alps.  The Gotthard Base tunnel is the longest and deepest tunnel of its type in the world – over 35 miles long!  When not [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe title="2022  - Lucerne, Switzerland" width="960" height="720" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F_FecuaFnPU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>On Thursday, we left Milan, Italy on a high-speed train bound for Lucerne, Switzerland.  The train was very fast, very quiet, and quite comfortable.  Our route took us *under* the Swiss Alps.  The Gotthard Base tunnel is the longest and deepest tunnel of its type in the world – over 35 miles long!  When not in the tunnel the scenery was very nice.  We enjoyed the journey and it set the table for the world class rail journeys yet to come on this trip.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve heard a lot about Lucerne, and it measures up to the reviews.  We walked through the old town area which is filled with shops and restaurants and beautiful old buildings.  The city is divided by the Reuss River which has two historic covered wooden bridges.  The oldest is the Chapel Bridge which was built in the 1300&#8217;s.  There are photo opportunities galore in the old city.</p>
<p>The most famous sculpture in Lucerne is the Lion Monument.  It&#8217;s a sad but beautiful work of art dedicated to 1792 Tuileries war heroes.  After seeing it we took a short bus ride back to the train station, bus station, and ferry dock for our cruise on Lake Lucerne.</p>
<p>Here are some things for people considering a trip to Switzerland.  First, everything here is expensive.  Even a hamburger will cost $15-20.  Food is always good, but never cheap.  We did a load of laundry at a self-serve place, and it costs over $15 for that single load washed and dried.  Second, for $20 you can get a sim card from Sunrise Mobile that will give you unlimited data most anywhere in Switzerland for a week.  Unless your phone accepts multiple sims or e-sims your regular number won&#8217;t work while the Swiss sim is inserted, so keep that in mind.  Still, it&#8217;s a really good deal that lets you get email, use your maps program, etc. while in the country.  Third, we stayed at a neat old hotel named &#8220;Drei Könige.&#8221;  The name means &#8220;Three Kings&#8221; and the logo of the wise men is everywhere.  I thought that was pretty neat, especially on the week after Christmas.  It isn&#8217;t unusual for hotels here to include breakfast.  And they really mean it – we had a hearty breakfast each morning.  That&#8217;s a real plus when you consider how expensive the eating places are.  Fourth, when you book a hotel in Lucerne you are given free bus access.  That&#8217;s a big savings and sets you free to explore the city.  Finally, most everyone speaks a little English (German is the most common language).  It never hurts to know a few common phrases.  Even saying &#8220;Thank you&#8221; in German will bring a smile as a response.</p>
<p>The highlight of our stay in Lucerne was the Lake Lucerne cruise.  The passenger ferry boats run regular routes around the lake.  We paid the winter day rate to give us unlimited time on the ferries.  Honestly, that discount rate is about the same price as most round-trip tickets.  By having a day ticket, we were able to decide just how much time we wanted to give to the cruise even while we were already underway.  To our delight the scenery was amazing, and we opted to go for the longer route, not returning to Lucerne until after dark.  Words can&#8217;t describe the beauty!  We were reminded of our Alaskan cruise but also of time we spent in Colorado at Rocky Mountain National Park.  We took tons of photos and hope you will enjoy them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
