<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Ezekiel &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-ezekiel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:45:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Ezekiel &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-33/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Basics Ezekiel 3: Get all these words that I&#8217;m giving you inside you. Ezekiel&#8217;s vision is intended to prepare him for the ministry God has for him. At one point in his vision he&#8217;s given a scroll and told to eat it. He reports that it tastes like honey. When the Lord applies the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-o1rBvFslmWU/YImL5i1EsxI/AAAAAAABKBM/S1MANeQRayYnf6YtikDzKxi7wIt7hAM1gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B5-04-55%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The Basics<br />
Ezekiel 3: Get all these words that I&#8217;m giving you inside you.<br />
Ezekiel&#8217;s vision is intended to prepare him for the ministry God has for him.  At one point in his vision he&#8217;s given a scroll and told to eat it.  He reports that it tastes like honey.  When the Lord applies the vision he tells Ezekiel that he needs to fully digest the message he has for the exiles.  God&#8217;s message needs to become part of him to the point that even if people disagree or simply refuse to listen to him that he&#8217;ll have absolute confidence in what he says.  While I don&#8217;t enjoy arguing religion, I certainly enjoy talking about it.  I love dealing with the finer points of the faith, especially the more difficult to understand passages.  However, there are some things that ought not to be subject to debate.  I&#8217;ve learned that there are a few, very few, absolute basics that need to be swallowed hook, line, and sinker.  They&#8217;re to become as much a part of me as are my heart and lungs.  It&#8217;s not that I refuse to discuss them, but that they are at the core of my existence.  Without diving off into the deep end of the pool here, I think I can name them off the top of my head.  First, God is.  Second, Jesus is the Son of God who died for my sins and was resurrected to life.  Third, as I trust in Jesus as my Savior I have the hope of eternal life in him.  These truths not only &#8220;taste like honey,&#8221; they also make me who I am today and for eternity.<br />
Take Away: Some things are debatable and a few, just a few, aren&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-32/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s message]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Faithful to the task Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern. I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book. I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being. Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DHvnggkeU9E/YImOJyC4wEI/AAAAAAABKBg/Kxg3rHoq9HIan-JNougekjY1pOc2lmodgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B5-04-47%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Faithful to the task<br />
Ezekiel 2: Whether they listen is not your concern.<br />
I don&#8217;t know what to do with the strange vision of wheels, faces, and wings Ezekiel has as I start reading his book.  I think I&#8217;ll retreat to my devotional approach for the time being.  Ezekiel&#8217;s commission is similar to that of Jeremiah.  The Lord warns him that the people he&#8217;s going to speak to aren&#8217;t likely to listen to his message.  Ezekiel is to proclaim just what he&#8217;s told to proclaim and not worry about the results.  As I find this theme I first found in Jeremiah being repeated here I can&#8217;t help but think about free will.  Jeremiah pled with his people to listen and return to God and thus divert the disaster that was promised.  In spite of his faithful proclamation, the bottom line was that people could respond or not.  Now that the catastrophe has come, the Lord raises up a prophet to the exiles, giving him similar instructions.  He&#8217;s to reach out to these rebellious people while knowing that they&#8217;ll probably not respond.  The Lord tells Ezekiel it&#8217;s his job to do the preaching and that he has to leave the results in the hands of those who can accept or reject his message.  A couple of things come to mind.  First, I see the absolute value God places on free will.  He won&#8217;t negate it even for my own good.  Second, I see the amazing love and grace of the Almighty.  Even when he sees that his invitation to mercy is likely to be rejected he insists on reaching out anyway.   Also, the Lord&#8217;s quite willing to enlist us to this task.  Still my responsibility ends with my obedience to the Lord, for those to whom I’m sent that&#8217;s where their responsibility begins.<br />
Take Away: All anyone can do is to obey the Lord – the results are out of our hands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 21:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust and obey for there’s no other way Ezekiel 3: &#8230;but you won&#8217;t die. You&#8217;ll have saved your life. As the prophet is commissioned he&#8217;s told that his job is to warn people. If they refuse his warning, then they&#8217;re responsible to God for that refusal. Ezekiel&#8217;s job is to issue God&#8217;s message. His salvation [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1vEENiscTRs/YIxkjAD5NNI/AAAAAAABKB4/8UENIpghjfo_IlbLQQG_AHFSlKxRpWFpACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-47-18%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Trust and obey for there’s no other way<br />
Ezekiel 3: &#8230;but you won&#8217;t die.  You&#8217;ll have saved your life.<br />
As the prophet is commissioned he&#8217;s told that his job is to warn people.  If they refuse his warning, then they&#8217;re responsible to God for that refusal.  Ezekiel&#8217;s job is to issue God&#8217;s message.  His salvation is contingent on his faithfulness in doing so.  My first reaction to this passage is one of caution.  I read this from a New Testament point of view and immediately respond that my hope of salvation isn’t in my performance but in my faith in the Savior, Jesus.  Does that, in some way nullify this passage for me today?  Upon reflection, I think not.  Old or New Testament, preacher or listener, the requirement of God is the same: obedience.  The Lord calls Ezekiel to preach his message and that&#8217;s what&#8217;s required of him.  He&#8217;s called to obedience even as he calls his listeners to obedience.  It&#8217;s the same for me.  As I understand that Jesus is the Savior of the world I must obey his call to yield my life to him and follow him.  Anything else is disobedience.  So, Ezekiel obeyed by preaching God&#8217;s message.  His listeners were to obey by forsaking their sin and worshiping the Lord.  I obey by trusting in Jesus as my Lord and Savior and living in a relationship with him.  People may refuse Ezekiel&#8217;s message, but he&#8217;ll be saved in his obedience in preaching it anyway.<br />
Take Away: No matter where a person is on their spiritual journey, the Lord’s requirement is this: obey.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-35/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materialism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No more business as usual Ezekiel 7: They throw their money into the gutters. The prophet tells us some of the things he does under God&#8217;s command to get the attention of people. Ezekiel isn&#8217;t an easy going guy; he&#8217;s a rugged, no-holds-barred kind of preacher who makes us think of Elijah or maybe John [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xJpSfWOAFF0/YI3NSiQkmQI/AAAAAAABKCc/GAj7XI4Ph-gzlfkY4yEQfq2T_fHyEvrsgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-40-52%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1281" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs. CO</figcaption></figure><br />
No more business as usual<br />
Ezekiel 7: They throw their money into the gutters.<br />
The prophet tells us some of the things he does under God&#8217;s command to get the attention of people.  Ezekiel isn&#8217;t an easy going guy; he&#8217;s a rugged, no-holds-barred kind of preacher who makes us think of Elijah or maybe John the Baptist.  This prophet does weird stuff and then preaches hard, crushing sermons.  In one sermon he describes the end of business as usual for those who&#8217;ve turned their backs on God.  He says that the day&#8217;s coming when people will toss their money aside because it will be meaningless and useless.  I&#8217;m reminded of the last power outage we had in our neighborhood.  Somewhere a breaker had thrown and every household in our area was without electricity.  I couldn&#8217;t help but laugh at myself when, for a fleeting moment, I thought, &#8220;Well, I can&#8217;t do my work; I guess I&#8217;ll watch some TV till the power comes back on!&#8221;  It took me a nanosecond to realize how silly that thought was.  Without electricity that nice TV was nothing but a big paperweight!  Today, as I consider Ezekiel&#8217;s warning that the money they think is so important is going to be simply thrown away as so much rubbish I&#8217;m reminded that a day&#8217;s coming when all the &#8220;stuff&#8221; I tend to think matters will be just another piece of trash.  I&#8217;ve got to keep that in mind and discipline myself to major on the majors while minoring on the minors of life!<br />
Take Away: All the “stuff” we have will, ultimately, be worthless – so, invest in that which matters in the long run.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-36/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mark of God’s people Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark. In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem. The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there. The sin is outrageous and disgusting. Anyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TruL9SmdBfo/YI8fidWJRVI/AAAAAAABKC8/Il7o9gOsHrc3t3gLmi5P1b0FrYDED1XqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-28-28%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The mark of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark.<br />
In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem.  The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there.  The sin is outrageous and disgusting.  Anyone who loves the Lord and worships him would be broken hearted to see their precious Temple desecrated in this way.  Then, Ezekiel sees a man on a mission.  He&#8217;s to walk the streets of Jerusalem, putting a mark on the foreheads of those who are distressed at the sin of their nation.  All others will be wiped out.  I find it interesting that in Revelation we find the &#8220;mark of the beast.&#8221;  In that case, it&#8217;s those who refuse the mark who are saved.  Here in Ezekiel, we see the reverse.  It is those with the mark who are spared from the judgment that comes.  Comparing the two &#8220;marks&#8221; ought to cause some who subscribe to a &#8220;Left Behind&#8221; brand theology to pause and consider!  I think of the mark of Ezekiel as the &#8220;mark of caring.&#8221;  You see, God cares about people and righteousness and holiness.  He&#8217;s always on the lookout for people who&#8217;ll join him in that concern.  If that fellow with the writing kit passed by my life today I wonder if I would receive that mark.<br />
Take Away: The sin of our society should break our hearts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-37/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reverence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A visit to God’s throne Ezekiel 10: Court and Temple were both filled with the blazing presence of the Glory of God. Ezekiel encounters those &#8220;wheels within wheels&#8221; once again, this time as part of a glorious vision of God. Most of what I&#8217;d call the &#8220;personal&#8221; side of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t attractive to me. Under [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 988px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0FUoCJNAcKA/YJAzfNMvq4I/AAAAAAABKEA/YuVH32Vtt9cokRN97D6eKWQOPkuSX-onACPcBGAsYHg/s988/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B013.jpg" width="988" height="792" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico Lava Rocks from Capulin Volcano (maybe)</figcaption></figure><br />
A visit to God’s throne<br />
Ezekiel 10: Court and Temple were both filled with the blazing presence of the Glory of God.<br />
Ezekiel encounters those &#8220;wheels within wheels&#8221; once again, this time as part of a glorious vision of God.  Most of what I&#8217;d call the &#8220;personal&#8221; side of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t attractive to me.  Under God&#8217;s direction he does some pretty strange stuff and some of it must have been downright painful.  On the other side of the coin, though, are encounters like this one with the Glory of God.  I&#8217;m not saying I can read his words and come away with an accurate understanding of it all.  These are complex events and I&#8217;m sure I wouldn&#8217;t have done as good a job as he does in his attempt to describe his famous &#8220;wheels within wheels&#8221; or the sound of cherubim wings or the Voice like thunder or a sky-blue, sapphire colored throne.  I can&#8217;t grasp it all and I can&#8217;t help but feel a little jealous (is it okay to be jealous of another man&#8217;s vision?) of Ezekiel&#8217;s moment in the presence of God.  Still, I appreciate his allowing me to tag along as he encounters the Lord Almighty.  Even though I know I&#8217;m like a blind man in the presence of a rainbow, I still get just a faint sense of it all.  In this place I&#8217;m fearfully reverent and I know that there are depths to the Glory of God that I can&#8217;t hope to comprehend.  I still can&#8217;t grasp it all but thanks to Ezekiel I know more than I would otherwise.<br />
Take Away: There are depths to the Glory of the Lord that I can&#8217;t hope to comprehend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-38/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cry of God’s people Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you. Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies. They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance. They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God. Through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1014px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WvKrAQm6pis/YJGgq_6tWhI/AAAAAAABKEU/rCFvfOQBbcIrk_P-3GjgSJEipNFyMN20ACPcBGAsYHg/s1014/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B008.jpg" width="1014" height="814" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The cry of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you.<br />
Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies.  They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance.  They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God.  Through their history, time and time again, they&#8217;ve followed a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration &#8212; only to have it all start again.  Now many of them have been exiled from the land God gave them.  Back in Jerusalem sin reigns and soon the result of that sin will be the total destruction of their beloved city.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to break the cycle by changing their hearts.  The result will be a people who love God and love his ways.  Many Christians can identify with the cycle of failure we see when we journey with these ancient Israelites.  We too have been trapped in a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration.  As we read the promise of a &#8220;new heart&#8221; our spirits respond with longing for that kind of relationship with God.  These words stir us and challenge us to let God have his way in our lives even if that means we need a spiritual &#8220;heart transplant.&#8221;  The result is a healthy spiritual life: &#8220;You&#8217;ll be my people! I&#8217;ll be your God!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Only the Lord can do what must be done in us and he’ll only do it as we allow him to and cooperate with him in that work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-39/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 21:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sickness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A pastoral visit to the hospital Ezekiel 13: They&#8217;ve said, &#8220;No problem, everything&#8217;s just fine,&#8221; when things are not at all fine. Several years ago I was at the hospital visiting a friend who was having surgery the next morning. When someone came into the room to go through a pre-surgery checklist, I excused myself [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1aOTvQnqess/YJLjpYQdeAI/AAAAAAABKFM/lvwhhQ8prn8QmicIaKR0-6ZDsZYPGrtwQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B007.jpg" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
A pastoral visit to the hospital<br />
Ezekiel 13: They&#8217;ve said, &#8220;No problem, everything&#8217;s just fine,&#8221; when things are not at all fine.<br />
Several years ago I was at the hospital visiting a friend who was having surgery the next morning.  When someone came into the room to go through a pre-surgery checklist, I excused myself and was about to leave.  However, my friend asked me to stay.  I reluctantly did so (by the way, I still don&#8217;t recommend that the pastor be present for such an interview).  As they went through the checklist I was amazed at how blunt it was.  Every possible problem was explained.  There was a 3% chance of this and a 5% chance of that.  Really, it was enough to scare a person!  As I reflected on that experience I made a decision to deal with spiritual realities with people in the hospital with the same frankness.  Rather than only focusing on praying for them that everything will be okay, I decided that, when the situation was right, I&#8217;d find a way to ask them how it is between them and God and offer to help them pray.  I&#8217;m not pretending that I always get that done.  For one thing, so many surgeries are now outpatient surgeries and the opportunity for such a conversation isn&#8217;t there.  Still, I&#8217;m reminded that we Christians aren&#8217;t to always tell people &#8220;everything&#8217;s going to be just fine&#8221; when there&#8217;s a real chance that it isn&#8217;t going to be fine.  I don&#8217;t have to scare people to death to offer to pray with them about spiritual needs in their life.  In fact, it may be the most comforting encounter of all.<br />
Take Away: When the time is right Christians should be ready to have spiritual conversations with people they care about.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s messenger]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The story continues Ezekiel 1: God&#8217;s hand came upon him that day. Jeremiah&#8217;s story leads up to the fall of Israel to Babylon. We leave Jeremiah in Egypt with the handful of survivors who fled there after the destruction of Jerusalem. Now, as I turn the page, I find myself in the company of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 703px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-p1F4SBXnpWw/YJRAgK6xKhI/AAAAAAABKF4/EDImMt5swEo3k_4kI-cmmzGGwmodSDbpACPcBGAsYHg/s703/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B005.jpg" width="703" height="565" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The story continues<br />
Ezekiel 1: God&#8217;s hand came upon him that day.<br />
Jeremiah&#8217;s story leads up to the fall of Israel to Babylon.  We leave Jeremiah in Egypt with the handful of survivors who fled there after the destruction of Jerusalem.  Now, as I turn the page, I find myself in the company of the majority who are exiled in Babylon.  The clock has been turned back a bit as I join those taken in the first stage of the exile.  The destruction of Jerusalem is still ten years away.  This particular group of refugees has been settled along the Kebar River, southwest of city of Babylon.  Their beloved Jerusalem is now a distant memory; they&#8217;ll never return.  It seems to them that their connection to the God of Abraham is severed.  Simply put, they&#8217;ve failed the Almighty and the Almighty has kicked them out.  Their religion has focused on the Temple and now they&#8217;ll never see it again.  It&#8217;s time to move on.  Interestingly, they aren&#8217;t very far from the place where God first spoke to their ancestor, Abraham in the town of Ur, just to the east of them.  They&#8217;re about to find out that God isn’t limited by location and he doesn&#8217;t need a Temple as a headquarters. This God who spoke to Abraham promising their very existence, is about to speak to them.  A young priest named Ezekiel will take up where Jeremiah left off as God&#8217;s spokesman to his people.<br />
Take Away: The Lord isn’t limited by location and he doesn&#8217;t need a Temple as a headquarters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebellion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A sad love story Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head. This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting. It&#8217;s graphic and weighty. The sin of Israel is described as adultery. The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting. Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G6StTmlRGE4/YJWpEYEoWgI/AAAAAAABKHk/UYiJhwXT004zLwB1RgB0IPqUE-4QGCkvACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B004.jpg" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
A sad love story<br />
Ezekiel 16: Your beauty went to your head.<br />
This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t uplifting.  It&#8217;s graphic and weighty.  The sin of Israel is described as adultery.  The prophet is a rough and tough guy and his language is hard and attention getting.  Ezekiel describes Israel as a baby abandoned at birth, destined to die without ever having a chance at life.  Instead, the Lord rescues this pitiful infant and lavishes his love on it.  Then the imagery changes as he describes this rescued one as a grown woman, beautiful and loved by the Lord as a devoted husband loves his wife.  Ezekiel says that Israel, who should have never even existed, has become vain and disinterested in the God to whom she owes everything.  Instead of being faithful to the Lord, though, she’s become an unfaithful harlot.  Anyone hearing Ezekiel&#8217;s words should be disgusted with such betrayal and sin.  None of this is intended to be a pretty picture.  Instead, Ezekiel wants us to recoil at what he describes.  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that my nation is a blessed nation too.  In the early days our chances of survival were small, yet we survived by the grace of God.  Now we&#8217;re a nation many others watch, and many watch with envy.  And even as Israel began to take God for granted and rebel against him, so have we.  This section of Ezekiel isn&#8217;t fun to read but it needs to be allowed to speak to us in this day.<br />
Take Away: It’s a dangerous thing to forget the blessings of the Lord and take them for granted.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
