<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>end times &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/end-times/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 19:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>end times &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 11:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-24/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it feels like the end of the world Matthew 24: This is no sign of the end. The “end times” information given in Matthew 24 is hard to understand. Some of it has to do with the generation Jesus is addressing in this moment. Jesus says, “I’m not just saying this for some future [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15686" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15686" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15686" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/100_2642.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15686" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure>
<p>When it feels like the end of the world</p>
<p>Matthew 24: This is no sign of the end.</p>
<p>The “end times” information given in Matthew 24 is hard to understand.  Some of it has to do with the generation Jesus is addressing in this moment.  Jesus says, “I’m not just saying this for some future generation, but for all of you.”  Some of the stuff in this chapter has already happened.  Still, we know that there’s been no trumpet blast and we haven’t seen the “one taken-one left” event take place.  Part of the mix is that some events that feel as though they must be part of the end of the world are just common history.  Jesus says reports of war, famine, and earthquakes aren’t signs of the “big event.”  Of course, for those in the middle of a bombing, or facing starvation, or experiencing a major earthquake it may very likely be “the end.”  However, when we hear of such things (and hopefully respond with Christ-like compassion to them) we’re not to panic, thinking “this is it.”  Instead, God’s people are to trust him to be with us when we experience the painful side of life.  We’re to stay true to the Lord even when we face opposition, and take advantage of the opportunity offered by unwelcome events to share the Good News with those who are desperate for some good news.  I know it’s easy for me to sit in a comfortable chair and write this stuff and not so easy when the world feels like it’s coming apart.  Still, if our faith is what we say it is and if it does for us what we say it does, it has to hold up even in the middle of the chaos the world sometimes throws our way.</p>
<p>Take Away: Not every horrible event is a sign that it’s the end of the world, but even in horrible events we can respond with compassion and hope as a people of God.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Thessalonians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-thessalonians-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Thessalonians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second coming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-thessalonians-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Antichrist and the last days 2Thessalonians 2: Don’t let anyone shake you up or get you excited over some breathless report or rumored letter. The congregation at Thessalonica is, in the words of Elvis, “All shook up,” over some gossip that Paul says Jesus has already returned and they’ve missed it. Paul reminds them [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16201" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16201" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16201" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P7289652.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16201" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sweet Creek Hike &#8211; Mapleton, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Antichrist and the last days</p>
<p>2Thessalonians 2: Don’t let anyone shake you up or get you excited over some breathless report or rumored letter.</p>
<p>The congregation at Thessalonica is, in the words of Elvis, “All shook up,” over some gossip that Paul says Jesus has already returned and they’ve missed it. Paul reminds them of what he told them about this topic while he was with them. The events surrounding the Second Coming will be too big to miss. Two huge, worldwide events will dominate all else: a great Apostasy and the rise of a very bad person who&#8217;ll pretend to be God Almighty. The spirit of this personification of evil is already evident in the world, so they already have an idea of what it will be like but when the real deal comes no one will be left wondering whether or not “this is it.” The Apostle hurries to reassure them that everything’s going to be okay. Just when it seems all is lost Jesus will appear and without any difficulty at all, will handle this bad guy. Paul tells his readers he’s not all that concerned about this stuff. After all, he has bigger fish to fry. Just what is that? Why, it’s putting his time and energy into thanking God for what he’s doing and is going to do in their lives. So, what am I to do with “end days” concerns? I’m to be aware that some bad things are coming to the world. I’m to remember that Jesus is coming back and he’ll handle it all with ease. Especially, I’m to keep my eyes on the Lord and use my energies in living for him and in him and not let myself get worked up over stuff I barely understand in the first place.</p>
<p>Take Away: I trust the Lord, not my knowledge about how everything will happen at the end of time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
