<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>goals &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/goals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>goals &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Follow the leader Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following. There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers. The Bible has several stories of leadership. Moses led for 40 years. David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GKWZD23715U/X3iy3gUoO3I/AAAAAAABGzw/7uTOofCwLGcYE-Eo4mTLHOuMCXf6CN9CACPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Follow the leader<br />
Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.<br />
There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers.  The Bible has several stories of leadership.  Moses led for 40 years.  David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as well.  His son Solomon led to prosperity.  Here are three things that come to mind when I read about these leaders.  First, each of these men is not only a leader, but is also a follower who accepts the authority of the Lord and spends time with him getting his marching orders.  Second, these men know how to share leadership and to train leaders.  They don&#8217;t try to do everything themselves and surround themselves with capable people to help carry the leadership load.  Third, they lead people to meaningful goals.  These men have God given visions that gives their leadership real purpose.  People believe in them and they believe the goal set out for them is worth their sacrifice.  Leaders such as these have no problem attracting followers.<br />
Take Away: God-called leaders lead with purpose in a God-chosen direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 08:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those we empower 2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you. It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MjY1xk74qN4/XgUuWqxpnsI/AAAAAAABDFI/rs_ShgebvPs4s2UqyLSuF9BNRQdXh5ZMACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129899.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Those we empower<br />
2 Samuel 3: Make a deal with me, and I&#8217;ll bring the whole country of Israel over to you.<br />
It’s apparent that David’s going to win the war. Ish-Bosheth, Saul&#8217;s son, is an incompetent leader and even his own men doubt him. In fact, David can finish it off any time he wants but for one thing: he continues to refuse to lay a hand on Saul&#8217;s descendants. Because of that, things drag on as Ish-Bosheth&#8217;s leadership of Israel slowly unravels on its own. One indication is that his general, Abner, secretly comes to David with an offer of peace. Apparently, David thinks that with Abner&#8217;s help the foregone conclusion of all this can end sooner and not later, and without his raising a hand against Saul&#8217;s son. It doesn’t work out. David&#8217;s own general seizes the opportunity to get revenge for the death of his brother at Abner&#8217;s hand. Before Abner can act Joab kills him. As often happens in life, the greatest damage done is from &#8220;inside&#8221; rather than &#8220;outside.&#8221; In this case, David has one agenda and his general, Joab, has another. One of the challenges of leadership is not only knowing where one is going, but being sure that those we lead &#8212; or even better &#8212; those we empower to lead with us, share in that goal. Otherwise, they’ll take the authority we’ve given them and use it to pursue their own purposes.<br />
Take Away: Real leaders don’t try to do everything themselves. At the same time, though, it’s important that those who work with us are on the same page as we are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nehemiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nehemiah-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 19:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nehemiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Easy money Nehemiah 5: What you&#8217;re doing is wrong. The work Nehemiah and his team is doing is physically challenging and time consuming. Not only are they working very hard, but they’re working with defense against an attack in mind so there’s also mental fatigue. Meanwhile, life goes on. These men have families to feed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DoFaQaOABbk/XvOjq4pUXsI/AAAAAAABFUU/aR_ABtgUwrE4p20iLNnwvQxvqNmP7rsQgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180925_144712.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; View at Big Walker Lookout near Wytheville, VA</figcaption></figure><br />
Easy money<br />
Nehemiah 5: What you&#8217;re doing is wrong.<br />
The work Nehemiah and his team is doing is physically challenging and time consuming. Not only are they working very hard, but they’re working with defense against an attack in mind so there’s also mental fatigue. Meanwhile, life goes on. These men have families to feed and bills to pay. The work on wall is vitally important but there’s no income from it. To make ends meet, they go to the local business men for loans. In spite of the fact that the restoration of the wall is to everyone&#8217;s benefit the loan sharks take advantage of the problem faced by the workers. When Nehemiah learns what’s happening he’s furious. He calls for a meeting and reads the riot act to these financial predators. Both the fear of the Lord and fear of Nehemiah takes hold and the gouging of the workmen stops immediately. What a situation! The workers face the challenging task of rebuilding, the threats of their enemies, and the greedy business practices of their fellow Jews. In some ways, this is the unkindest cut of all. Yet it often happens, even within the church. As many pull together to accomplish some worthy goal there are those who can&#8217;t see the big picture because they’re blinded by their own agenda. When that happens those doing the real work are distracted or discouraged from their task. Nehemiah dealt with this problem head on. Our tendency is to just try to work through stuff like this. Sometimes that’s probably best, but not always. I pray that the Lord will give us wisdom to know when Nehemiah’s course of action is necessary and then help us to follow it.<br />
Take Away: If we ignore some problems they will go away, but not always. Sometimes leaders have to deal with issues head on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
