<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Prayer &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/prayer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:44:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Prayer &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 23:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Listening in prayer Ecclesiastes 5: Don&#8217;t be too quick to tell God what you think he wants to hear. Some folks think God wants to hear us pray in the language of the King James Bible: &#8220;Almighty God, Thou Who art from everlasting to everlasting&#8230;.&#8221; To them, prayer is a rather formal event that ought [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CIMBCH0lRLM/X5nW9qXWy9I/AAAAAAABHNQ/pqKamVE0LPI3YoK3Im_d9s4SL5Rm06faACPcBGAsYHg/s400/34rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Listening in prayer<br />
Ecclesiastes 5: Don&#8217;t be too quick to tell God what you think he wants to hear.<br />
Some folks think God wants to hear us pray in the language of the King James Bible: &#8220;Almighty God, Thou Who art from everlasting to everlasting&#8230;.&#8221; To them, prayer is a rather formal event that ought to be filled with plenty of pomp and circumstance. Sometimes, as I’m reminded here, I’m better off to pray without words at all and let God be in charge of what happens next. It does make sense. God is always the &#8220;first mover.&#8221; After all, the Bible doesn&#8217;t start off with &#8220;In the beginning man&#8230;&#8221;! So, rather than coming to prayer in what might be called &#8220;automatic mode,&#8221; in which every prayer is pretty much a copy of the one before, or with a sense of formality, I want to come to him humbly and honestly; not saying what I think he wants to hear, but in a genuine desire to hear from him. If I let him lead the way my prayer time will be more satisfying to both the Lord and to me. Prayer is just as much a matter of listening as it is a matter of talking.<br />
Take Away: Being still before the Lord is a legitimate approach to prayer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-36/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 07:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Learning to listen Proverbs 3: Listen for God&#8217;s voice in everything you do, everywhere you go. We tend to think that hearing from God is a once-in-a-lifetime experience, or maybe that it’s something only saints on earth experience. It isn&#8217;t true. The Lord created us for fellowship with himself. From the beginning he walked with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y6IAPOXE4w8/X2tztxpKGVI/AAAAAAABGoI/kMTGxFXIBU8KLop9pA_M-HqmvFRdwhHowCPcBGAsYHg/s640/DSCN2807.JPG" width="640" height="480" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Learning to listen<br />
Proverbs 3: Listen for God&#8217;s voice in everything you do, everywhere you go.<br />
We tend to think that hearing from God is a once-in-a-lifetime experience, or maybe that it’s something only saints on earth experience.  It isn&#8217;t true.  The Lord created us for fellowship with himself.  From the beginning he walked with Adam in the cool of the day.  I don&#8217;t have to do some extreme thing to hear from God.  All I have to do is listen.  But that&#8217;s a problem isn&#8217;t it?  Hearing the Voice of God in the ordinary flow of life takes practice.  If I want to hear him speak when I’m sitting in the emergency room of a hospital or when a precious friend is pouring his heart out to me seeking spiritual council I have to practice listening for him when I’m not in the pressure cooker of life.  I&#8217;m certain that God speaks, and that he does so constantly.  Sadly, I am also sure that I’m not a very good listener.  For this proverb to work for me; for me to listen for God&#8217;s voice everywhere I go, I need to practice the presence of God every day.  The way to accomplish that is for me to discipline myself to meet God by creating quiet places in life where I can learn to hear his Voice.  Then, when I&#8217;m out there in the &#8220;everywhere you go&#8221; part of life, I will have trained my spiritual ear to recognize the Master&#8217;s Voice.<br />
Take Away: It takes practice to learn to hear the Voice of God in the noisy situations of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-123/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 06:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reason to expect an answer to prayer Isaiah 26: God, order a peaceful and whole life for us because everything we&#8217;ve done, you&#8217;ve done for us. What an interesting prayer this is. I love the request for a &#8220;peaceful and whole life.&#8221; When all is said and done, this is about as insightful a request [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 762px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SPeiZwkoO5k/X9AOnwO4-SI/AAAAAAABHyg/sqzy4fKVCuUVi5sxrOJCHg37n2cvKY4EwCPcBGAsYHg/s762/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-26-55%2BPM.JPG" width="762" height="609" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Reason to expect an answer to prayer<br />
Isaiah 26: God, order a peaceful and whole life for us because everything we&#8217;ve done, you&#8217;ve done for us.<br />
What an interesting prayer this is.  I love the request for a &#8220;peaceful and whole life.&#8221;  When all is said and done, this is about as insightful a request as a person can make for their own life.  Isaiah lives in turbulent times and, in the face of so much uncertainty, this prayer makes a lot of sense.  However, he isn&#8217;t the only one who has lived in such days.  We do too.  Again, I like this simple prayer.  The second half of this sentence though, is the reason the person praying thinks the first half will be granted.  Isaiah says, &#8220;We’re following your directions Lord, only doing what you’d have us do, operating under your power and authority.&#8221;  You see, it makes no sense to plead with the Lord for peace and life if I’m ignoring his intentions for my life.  The only way this prayer makes sense is when I pray it in the context of absolute obedience and trust.  It’s only when I can say, &#8220;Everything I have done and am doing is what God is doing in me&#8221; that I can pray with an expectation of God&#8217;s blessing on my life.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s blessings often depend on my obedience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-136/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hezekiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extraordinary favors from God Isaiah 38: I&#8217;ll add fifteen years to your life. Hezekiah is one of the good guys who trusts in the Lord; a king who has his priorities right. When he gets sick Isaiah visits him and tells Hezekiah that this is it, he needs to prepare to die. Hezekiah prays a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PSQ9sk2Y90A/X-Dnbm8wv3I/AAAAAAABH8I/3dX3ldncO2EH_vCGsknsQzXJ8T8IbHyaQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281811.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure>
<p>Extraordinary favors from God<br />
Isaiah 38: I&#8217;ll add fifteen years to your life.<br />
Hezekiah is one of the good guys who trusts in the Lord; a king who has his priorities right. When he gets sick Isaiah visits him and tells Hezekiah that this is it, he needs to prepare to die. Hezekiah prays a simple, trusting prayer that touches the heart of God who grants the king fifteen more years of life. As I read this story I remember that my life is in the hands of God. He has the final say. In Hezekiah&#8217;s case, the illness that comes to him is a natural one but God trumps it by granting him a supernatural healing. I know that the Lord doesn&#8217;t always do that, even in the lives of people just as good and trusting as Hezekiah. Still, this incident reminds me that I can ask for extraordinary favors from the Lord while trusting him in his wisdom to answer according to his grace.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes, the Lord’s answer is “yes.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-143/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 09:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[praise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The positive, encouraged people of God Isaiah 41: I, God of Israel, will not leave them thirsty. Some folks apparently think that spiritual talk is the language of need and complaint. To them, an evidence of their belief in God is constant requests for prayer: &#8220;Pray for me, life is so hard that I sometimes [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WFZQISilNHM/X-kDBa4d5cI/AAAAAAABIEM/hUAYCmAyrv8mEOBjXoSbBEh111NWjZ7TACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9082407.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Alluvial Fan area &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
The positive, encouraged people of God<br />
Isaiah 41: I, God of Israel, will not leave them thirsty.<br />
Some folks apparently think that spiritual talk is the language of need and complaint.  To them, an evidence of their belief in God is constant requests for prayer: &#8220;Pray for me, life is so hard that I sometimes don&#8217;t think I’ll make it another day.&#8221;  Now, I say this carefully, because challenging difficulties and temptations do come into life and sometimes, that kind of desperate prayer request is, indeed, an evidence of belief in God.  However, that isn&#8217;t the everyday language of the follower of God.  This awesome God satisfies his people.  Even when life isn’t perfect, they’ve found a Source that provides a foundation for their life.  The native language for the one who trusts the Lord is the language of satisfaction: &#8220;In my distress I sought the Lord and he was there for me.&#8221;  Personally, that means I must major on the goodness of God and not on the difficulties of life.  It also may mean that I have a responsibility to help other believers remember that God is there for them and help them learn this language of praise and thanksgiving.<br />
Take Away: The native language of the people of the Lord is the language of satisfaction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/book-of-proverbs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 06:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No one way praying allowed Proverbs 28: God has no use for the prayers of people who won&#8217;t listen to him. I believe in prayer and consider myself to be a prayer learner. I&#8217;ve read books about it, talked about it, and practiced it. I’ve learned that there are different ways to pray. For instance, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ilpCSSaciNk/X43NnNUTHMI/AAAAAAABHBQ/xyA9nOA9oTw7xlSh_d0pqPEZdjvT6fatgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/lajolla08G.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; LaJolla, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
No one way praying allowed<br />
Proverbs 28: God has no use for the prayers of people who won&#8217;t listen to him.<br />
I believe in prayer and consider myself to be a prayer learner.  I&#8217;ve read books about it, talked about it, and practiced it.  I’ve learned that there are different ways to pray.  For instance, a person can kneel by their bedside or sit in an easy chair with a cup of coffee or write out a prayer or take a &#8220;prayer walk.&#8221;  These and several other approaches are good ways to pray.  One deal breaker to prayer is what is stated in this proverb: one way praying.  Prayer is intended to be a conversation with God.  It isn&#8217;t about my airing my list of wants and concerns while God patiently stands by like the waitress in a restaurant taking an order.  I’ve found that, generally speaking, it’s my perspective that’s changed in prayer.  The wise man of the proverbs reminds me of the conversational nature of prayer.  Of course, there’s another aspect of &#8220;listening&#8221; here.  When I spend time in the Presence of God and he does speak I’m to listen to what he says.  That is, I’m to take it to heart and move forward in obedience.  Often, I’ve found, God intends to use me in answer to my own prayers.  He has work for me to do and, no matter how fervently I continue to pray, nothing will come of it until I start listening to what the Lord’s saying to me.<br />
Take Away: Often, the Lord intends to use us in answer to our own prayers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-172/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 14:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surf’s up! Isaiah 55: Seek God while he&#8217;s here to be found. I&#8217;m coming up on four decades of ministry and along the way I&#8217;d like to think I&#8217;ve learned a few things. One of them is that there are &#8220;tides of the Spirit.&#8221; Even as the ocean has times of high and low tide, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rbMvmB40Mv8/YA8lxUHsPEI/AAAAAAABITA/53Db1Aj-FoA44nqu1v264Z4-LYOtNDE2wCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9032103.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Along Old Fall River Road &#8211; Rocky Mountains National Park </center></figcaption></figure><br />
Surf’s up!<br />
Isaiah 55: Seek God while he&#8217;s here to be found.<br />
I&#8217;m coming up on four decades of ministry and along the way I&#8217;d like to think I&#8217;ve learned a few things.  One of them is that there are &#8220;tides of the Spirit.&#8221;  Even as the ocean has times of high and low tide, so do we (individuals as well as churches) experience such cycles in the spiritual realm.  In my career as a pastor I have seen churches that seemed to be doing everything right but weren&#8217;t seeing the results one might expect.  Then, to our delight, one positive thing kicks off a whole series of positive things.  Suddenly, the efforts that had been fruitless before take on a new life and wonderful things start happening.  I laughingly told someone once that I was thinking of writing a book telling how our church had seen significant gains over a two year period.  The problem was that I had no idea of what to write; we were basically doing all the same things we had done in the years previous when there was nothing special happening.  I&#8217;m sure that there were things associated with those memorable days that I simply didn&#8217;t see.  For instance, secret prayer by some saints of God comes to mind.  Still, the difference was that God moved, not because we got all our ducks in a row, but because of his own schedule and purpose.  We were the happy recipients of it.  Today, Isaiah reminds me, not only that there are tides of the Spirit, but that I must seize the moment when the tide is in.  I move because God is moving.  Because God is moving, some doors that have been closed to me might just be open for a while.  You might say that when the tide is in it’s a good time to take a swim!<br />
Take Away: As people who live in the Spirit we move when the Lord moves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-175/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 15:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gentiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All are welcome here Isaiah 56: My house of worship will be known as a house of prayer for all people. Previously, when I’ve read this passage, I focused on the &#8220;prayer side&#8221; of this message: that God&#8217;s house is to be a house of prayer and God&#8217;s people are to be a people of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J36JRUUW8Zo/YBLxhB6wCCI/AAAAAAABIXQ/dvxzSagOEzICVMlRq3jJiY7Yv2I2ZfVswCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PC253091.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston</center></figcaption></figure><br />
All are welcome here<br />
Isaiah 56: My house of worship will be known as a house of prayer for all people.<br />
Previously, when I’ve read this passage, I focused on the &#8220;prayer side&#8221; of this message: that God&#8217;s house is to be a house of prayer and God&#8217;s people are to be a people of prayer.  That theme is very much present in this passage, but it really isn&#8217;t the heart of its message.  The core of this portion of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy is the &#8220;all people&#8221; statement.  God&#8217;s salvation, we’re told, isn’t just for the Jewish &#8220;insiders&#8221; but for the Gentile &#8220;outsiders&#8221; as well.  Those with physical limitations whose worship experience is limited by the laws of Deuteronomy are not to be treated as second class worshipers.  In fact, God promises that those who fall in the &#8220;outside&#8221; category yet are faithful to the Lord will be given an honored place, even more honored than that of the insiders.  Everyone is invited to come to the &#8220;house of prayer for all people.&#8221;  My response to this passage today is on two levels.  First, I thank God for it because I&#8217;m one of the outsiders who have been granted access to the Lord.  I wasn&#8217;t born to the right family but I’ve been adopted in.  Second, I want to conduct my life with a strong realization that God welcomes people who aren’t like me.  As one who’s been graciously granted access, I gladly join the &#8220;welcoming committee&#8221; that invites other outsiders in.  Also, while I won&#8217;t take time to develop it here, the literal meaning of this passage reminds me that there are those who need special accommodation to fully participate in the activities at the house of worship.  I want the church I attend to be as assessable as possible for those who have special needs and as welcoming as possible to people from all walks of life.<br />
Take Away: The Lord welcomes me but he also welcomes people who aren’t like me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-185/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[praise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Praise list Isaiah 63: I&#8217;ll make a list of God&#8217;s gracious dealings. The old gospel song says, &#8220;Count your blessings &#8211; name them one by one; and it will surprise you what the Lord has done.&#8221; I don&#8217;t know that hymn writer Johnson Oatman was inspired by this passage but it certainly fits. Isaiah says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k08KqPWuglE/YCBHI1eYnFI/AAAAAAABIcU/XR7fWrAE9PAJf5kYB43PChZRRt4P6sSvwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Smoky-mountains-national-park-Newfound-gap%2B5-16-2008%2B12-38-43%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Smoky Mountain National Park &#8211; Newfound Gap</figcaption></figure><br />
Praise list<br />
Isaiah 63: I&#8217;ll make a list of God&#8217;s gracious dealings.<br />
The old gospel song says, &#8220;Count your blessings &#8211; name them one by one; and it will surprise you what the Lord has done.&#8221;  I don&#8217;t know that hymn writer Johnson Oatman was inspired by this passage but it certainly fits.  Isaiah says he&#8217;s going to make a list of the things &#8220;God has done that need praising&#8221; and then work his way through that list.  Like many Christians I have a prayer list that’s filled with concerns and needs.  I think it&#8217;s a good idea; after all, there are many genuine needs and the Lord welcomes us to share our heart&#8217;s concerns.  However, I need to balance that out by having, in addition to a prayer list, a &#8220;praise list&#8221; as well.  Otherwise, I’m in danger of behaving like the nine lepers who are healed by Jesus.  They rush on into their new lives without a backward glance while only one returns to say &#8220;thanks&#8221; to our Lord.  I need to purposely make the effort to spend time each day rejoicing in all the Lord has done for me.<br />
Take Away: Our “need filled” prayers should be balanced by strong component of “praise filled” prayers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-192/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 17:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[praise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometimes God answers before I even ask Isaiah 65: Before they call out, I&#8217;ll answer. This passage is written in future tense. The day being described is certainly coming but it hasn&#8217;t arrived yet. Isaiah probably sees it as a time in their near future when Israel’s restored and lives under the direct blessing of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-S0VdDFetik8/YCmN-1FFfTI/AAAAAAABIj4/sxQce40DF8gNXNB3UbQQPHPi7z-tIolBQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5123583.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Cataloochee Valley &#8211; Great Smoky Mtns Ntl Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Sometimes God answers before I even ask<br />
Isaiah 65: Before they call out, I&#8217;ll answer.<br />
This passage is written in future tense.  The day being described is certainly coming but it hasn&#8217;t arrived yet.  Isaiah probably sees it as a time in their near future when Israel’s restored and lives under the direct blessing of God.  Today, I read it as the promise of a blessed future when under the rule of the Messiah the peace promised at his First Coming is made real in the world.  One of the promised blessings is that God will answer our prayers before we can even voice them.  I&#8217;m reminded that I already have at least a taste of that.  There are times when I realize God has been at work in some concern of my life before I ever realized it was there.  What would have been a cry for God&#8217;s help becomes, instead, a word of praise for what the Lord did for me when I was ignorant of the need.  Since I&#8217;ve experienced things like this, I have just a faint vision of what it will be like in that blessed future.  Obviously, in that day I&#8217;ll spend a lot more time thanking and praising God and a lot less time earnestly asking for his help.  Since that kind of praying will be the norm, maybe I had better start practicing the praising part a bit more right now.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for answering our prayers – even before we’ve known enough to pray them!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
