<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>prophecy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/prophecy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 19:24:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>prophecy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-110/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 03:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virgin Birth Isaiah 8: Because when all is said and done, the last word is Immanuel&#8211;God-With-Us. When the tiny nation Judah is under attack on two fronts Isaiah goes to King Ahaz with the promise that Judah will prevail and the attack will fail. Ahaz can hardly believe it. His nation is out manned and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NRp--Oxb21k/X77PL9Z7nPI/AAAAAAABHr0/rZyOzGaLvYUDRIi0oSfDh8MUqvE7X_3xgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B12-55-58%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Virgin Birth<br />
Isaiah 8: Because when all is said and done, the last word is Immanuel&#8211;God-With-Us.<br />
When the tiny nation Judah is under attack on two fronts Isaiah goes to King Ahaz with the promise that Judah will prevail and the attack will fail. Ahaz can hardly believe it. His nation is out manned and out gunned by the invaders. Isaiah tells him to ask for a sign, any sign, and it will be given him. However, Ahaz’s lack of faith is apparent when he off handedly says, “Oh, I won’t do that.” Isaiah tells him that the Lord&#8217;s displeased with his refusal to even bother asking for a sign, but that one will be given anyway. It&#8217;s here that we get into “virgin birth” talk. However, the promise isn’t for the Messiah to come, it has to do with current circumstances. Isaiah says that before a girl, now a virgin, can marry, conceive, and give birth (in other words, a poetic way of saying “nine months”) that those armies attacking Judah will be gone. To underscore the reason for this withdrawal the child could properly be named “Immanuel” or “God-With-Us.” Isaiah goes on to express God’s displeasure with Ahaz but, still, the bottom line remains. When all else is “said and done” “Immanuel” remains true, God is with us. When Christ is born this incident comes to mind and is played out in a very literal way. This time it is literally a virgin who gives birth, and this time it really is God who is with us. In these related incidents we see the dual nature of prophecy as there&#8217;s a very current application that&#8217;s echoed in an unimaginable way in a more distant future. We also see that, today, we can grasp this wonderful truth at a level Isaiah could hardly imagine: God is with us indeed.<br />
Take Away: How wonderful to be reminded of Immanuel God-is-with-us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-111/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 04:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free will and accountability Isaiah 8: No, we’re going to study the Scriptures. While telling of future events wasn&#8217;t the major job of most prophets, it’s the one we immediately think of when we think of the work of the prophets. Actually, these men of God mostly &#8220;forth-told&#8221; rather than &#8220;fore-told.&#8221; Even when they speak [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YfS9Yva1LOE/X8A19FfsmSI/AAAAAAABHsE/abYQ1ijkaVAa12C7mHmqSaMIWZe5M4rOgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Mo%2BRanch%2BHunt%2BTx%2B11-28-2006%2B11-44-11%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Free will and accountability<br />
Isaiah 8: No, we’re going to study the Scriptures.<br />
While telling of future events wasn&#8217;t the major job of most prophets, it’s the one we immediately think of when we think of the work of the prophets.  Actually, these men of God mostly &#8220;forth-told&#8221; rather than &#8220;fore-told.&#8221;  Even when they speak of the future it’s often spoken of in a conditional way: &#8220;If you do this, then that will happen; if you do that, then this will happen.&#8221;  In fact, a major theme of these men of God is to remind the people of their free will.  That doesn&#8217;t mean God is helpless, but it does mean, at least in this context, that the Lord allows people the freedom to decide, and then makes them accountable for their decisions.  As Isaiah goes about proclaiming what’s coming if these people stay on the road they’re on, people say to him, &#8220;When I want to know what&#8217;s coming, I&#8217;ll go to a fortune teller or hold a séance.&#8221;  Isaiah says, &#8220;If you want to know what’s coming, take a look in the Scriptures.&#8221;  He isn’t saying that the Scriptures contain some kind of secret road map to the future.  Instead, he’s saying that there’s plenty of evidence in the Scriptures that God won’t forever put up with their foolishness.  Repeatedly, in the Scriptures, the Lord has warned them and it doesn&#8217;t take some supernatural experience to see what’s coming.  Talk about a timeless truth, this is one!  Today, I don’t need a fortune teller.  There&#8217;s plenty of information already available to me in the Bible about how God responds to sin and rebellion.  If I insist on ignoring God I don&#8217;t need a crystal ball to know what’s coming.<br />
Take Away: The Bible is quite clear as to the intentions of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-112/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 04:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dual level preaching Isaiah 9: For a child has been born &#8212; for us! The gift of a son &#8212; for us! Sometimes the prophet does exactly what we generally think of a prophet doing: he speaks of the future. Isaiah says that even when oppressors come and seem to destroy everything that God will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-EATR1_OegKk/X8GLVXiDA4I/AAAAAAABHtA/ki4VxmfEDMgj3KzLALwbdEcmB48RvzuRwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Mo%2BRanch%2BHunt%2BTx%2B11-28-2006%2B11-42-54%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; Near Hunt, Texas</figcaption></figure><br />
Dual level preaching<br />
Isaiah 9: For a child has been born &#8212; for us! The gift of a son &#8212; for us!<br />
Sometimes the prophet does exactly what we generally think of a prophet doing: he speaks of the future.  Isaiah says that even when oppressors come and seem to destroy everything that God will have the last word.  That Word, Isaiah says, will be in the person of a Child who can rightly be called names like &#8220;Strong God&#8221; and &#8220;Eternal Father.&#8221;  Have you ever wondered about the state of mind of men like Isaiah when they speak words like this?  Does Isaiah see it all: manger, shepherds, and wise men?  Or does he scratch his head and wonder why he just said that?  I think the answer is somewhere in the middle.  I can give a very minor personal example of what I mean.  A few weeks ago I was delivering my Sunday morning sermon and found myself emphasizing something that had originally been only a minor part of my sermon.  Such an event is hard to describe to people who haven&#8217;t preached, but I think most everyone who has carried on spiritual conversations have, at times, experienced something similar.  Honestly, as I thought about that sermon and remembered who was in the congregation I had the idea that maybe the Lord wanted to encourage a good person who was going through some challenges in their life.  Still it never crossed my mind to &#8220;aim&#8221; that portion of the sermon at anyone.  I was surprised that I had pursued that point as far as I did.  A few days later, with no thought of that sermon, I was praying and dealing with what I thought was a totally unrelated issue.  Suddenly, the words that I had said on Sunday morning came back to me and I realized that on an entirely different level they were meant for me!  At that moment, the &#8220;deeper meaning&#8221; of what I had said became real to me.  I think that prophets like Isaiah operate at that level when they speak of things like those in Isaiah 9.  Had you had a frank conversation with Isaiah about his promise of the &#8220;gift of a son&#8221; I think he would have plugged it into some current situation in his nation.  That isn&#8217;t to say he was ignorant of there being more than he could grasp, but that, for him, these words applied right then and there.  Only as God&#8217;s plan is played out does the greater meaning of the old prophet&#8217;s words come to light.<br />
Take Away: Even when we think we know what’s going on we’re often surprised to later realize that the Lord was working at levels beyond our grasp.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-113/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Twigs and forests Isaiah 11: The life-giving Spirit of God will hover over him. The flow from current events to spiritual events of the future makes some passages hard to read. Isaiah has declared that the army of their enemy, Assyria, was used of God to purge his people, but went too far. He pictures [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tAt6X6h_Fuw/X8K1PySxkVI/AAAAAAABHtY/8fUA5QZaY4QeNOliAqvmAsqobfaZ1n-OgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Mo%2BRanch%2BHunt%2BTx%2B11-28-2006%2B11-42-50%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Twigs and forests<br />
Isaiah 11: The life-giving Spirit of God will hover over him.<br />
The flow from current events to spiritual events of the future makes some passages hard to read.  Isaiah has declared that the army of their enemy, Assyria, was used of God to purge his people, but went too far.  He pictures Assyria as a great forest filled with huge trees.  However, for all its majesty, that forest will be leveled because of the anger of God.  Then, with no real segue Isaiah continues with his &#8220;forest&#8221; illustration, proclaiming that out of the remains of Judah just one small twig will spring up. Compared to the great “forest” that is Assyria, this green twig might seem insignificant. That “twig,” though, will be overshadowed by the Spirit of God. It will grow to such a size that all the forests of the world will seem small in comparison and that “twig” will reach out in wisdom, understanding, direction, strength, and knowledge. I don’t know what Isaiah or his contemporaries thought of the unexpected direction of this prophecy, but to a Christian reader it makes perfect sense. The army of Assyria is long gone, only of interest to historians and archeologists. However, that “twig” — the one who sprang up as a helpless baby in Bethlehem so long ago — well, his Kingdom continues to flourish to this very day.<br />
Take Away: “And he shall reign for ever and ever more.  Hallelujah!”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-116/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 04:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Bible]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Letting the Bible say what it says Isaiah 14: You said to yourself, &#8220;I&#8217;ll climb to heaven&#8230;instead of climbing up, you came down.&#8221; If you were raised in church as I was you’ll identify with my observation that church folks develop a lot of folk theology. When I was a kid someone told me that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-EXas_5JxxOc/X8Z6JxMk0pI/AAAAAAABHuo/o_IZQKXZih8GFR2-utahPmcFzoOd6k79QCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/Lost%2BMaples%2BSt.%2BPark%2Bvicinity%2B%2B11-28-2006%2B10-17-34%2BAM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Letting the Bible say what it says<br />
Isaiah 14: You said to yourself, &#8220;I&#8217;ll climb to heaven&#8230;instead of climbing up, you came down.&#8221;<br />
If you were raised in church as I was you’ll identify with my observation that church folks develop a lot of folk theology.  When I was a kid someone told me that Isaiah 14 describes the fall of Satan from the splendor of heaven.   I believed it and grew to adulthood assuming that all Christians thought that about this passage.  One day it dawned on me (and I probably had some help with that awakening) that this passage is about Babylon and its king.  The ruler of Babylon thinks he’s bigger than God.  In fact, because of his nation’s unequaled economic and military power and his unlimited authority over it all that he concludes that he, himself, is a god.  Isaiah prophesies that mighty Babylon is going to fall, and will fall in a very big way.  Now, this passage can be used to illustrate other things, but it really isn&#8217;t about anything aside from Babylon.  For instance the true-ism, &#8220;the bigger they come, the harder they fall&#8221; comes to mind.  Sometimes, even well-meaning people can mistakenly use Scripture in improper ways.  As God&#8217;s people we’re to be people of truth, &#8220;rightly dividing the Word&#8221; even if that means we lose a handy proof text.<br />
Take Away: Even well-meaning people can mistakenly use Scripture in improper ways.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-122/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face. Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself. I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bVc5ehr8RoQ/X869s_8TVCI/AAAAAAABHyE/YYt3gG1zx3w_7ioz8H5QaHDZA_YqWHBZACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-27-46%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted<br />
Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself.  I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet is talking to specific people at a specific moment in history or if he’s slipped into &#8220;prophetic perfect tense&#8221; in which he speaks of the future as though it has already happened.  It may be that he’s speaking on multiple levels of a near future and a distant future with the same words.  At times like this, I take the easy way out and focus on my devotional reading, asking, &#8220;What’s this saying to me right now?&#8221;  As I read this part of Isaiah I can&#8217;t help but think of the book of Revelation which contains almost the exact same words.  In fact, I&#8217;m pretty sure the Revelator is reminded of these words even as he promises the glorious &#8220;no tears&#8221; day.  My conclusion is that whether we’re thinking about the broken people of Isaiah&#8217;s day or persecuted Christians of John&#8217;s day or hurting people today that God&#8217;s message is one of comfort and hope.  Some of that hope is contemporary hope: what God is about to do.  At the same time some of that hope is out there in the uncertain future when the Lord wraps up history and brings a new reality into existence.  I’m not sure about just who it is Isaiah is thinking about in this passage, but I do see here a wonderful theme of God&#8217;s mercy and grace.<br />
Take Away: Yesterday, today, and forever the Lord remains merciful and gracious to his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-137/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second coming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking to the distant mountains Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God. An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range. As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QHj_F29QPmk/X-IZXHRO1-I/AAAAAAABH9U/mCJxOwSoeacenLKkqcw9h_OsO6BQgJuRACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281810.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Looking to the distant mountains<br />
Isaiah 40: Make the road straight and smooth, a highway fit for our God.<br />
An illustration of how the prophets view the future is of looking from the plains up to a towering mountain range.  As I look to the mountains I see one mountain in the &#8220;front range,&#8221; but at the greater distance is yet another taller and even more majestic peak.  Coloradoans call the really big ones, &#8220;fourteeners,&#8221; that is, they’re over 14,000 feet in height.  From my vantage point I can’t tell how far it is between the two mountains.  It’s only as I actually travel through the mountains that I realize there’s a deep valley between the first and the second mountain range.  As the prophets are given a vision of God&#8217;s intentions they sometimes see an act of God that’s close at hand and at the same time see a similar but even greater event more distant than they can imagine.  Here in Isaiah 40 the focus of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecies is on comfort and hope.  These words will become a life line for his people in a few years.  All the terrible things he&#8217;s warned them of will come to pass, and in distant lands the next generation will turn to these words to find comfort in their sorrow.  When I read this passage at the level of the &#8220;front range&#8221; I see that God&#8217;s broken people have hope of restoration.  The Lord’s going to return to their lives as a powerful king might return to his kingdom.  Isaiah&#8217;s command to them is to start preparing for this sure event by making a smooth and straight road into their lives.  However, beyond that &#8220;front range&#8221; is a gigantic &#8220;fourteener,&#8221; the coming of the King of Kings to this world.  Hundreds of years later this prophecy will become John the Baptist&#8217;s text and it’ll be fulfilled in a much greater way by King Jesus.  As a Christian I can identify with the dual nature of this passage.  That &#8220;front range&#8221; view is when I receive Jesus as King in my own heart.  The &#8220;fourteener&#8221; view is when Jesus comes to this world the second time as King and Judge of all.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes the words of the prophets of the Lord cause us to look both to the past and to the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-162/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 13:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crucifixion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two prophecies for the price of one Isaiah 52: He didn&#8217;t even look human. I think this is another of those &#8220;dual prophecies&#8221; in which the prophet speaks of something close at hand, but, maybe without realizing it, speaks words that resonate into the future. On one hand, he’s talking about the restoration of his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-APRjyQ1aiAM/YAJUj_GBhUI/AAAAAAABIM0/ir7n-6fd_4UuAAccd8PFMKZGG7zPAs82QCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9042158.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Hike to Mills Lake &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Two prophecies for the price of one<br />
Isaiah 52: He didn&#8217;t even look human.<br />
I think this is another of those &#8220;dual prophecies&#8221; in which the prophet speaks of something close at hand, but, maybe without realizing it, speaks words that resonate into the future.  On one hand, he’s talking about the restoration of his people.  They’re broken, almost to the point of extinction.  If their condition is described as though they are one person, we would say that individual has been beaten to the point that he or she is unrecognizable.  God&#8217;s salvation is coming but at this point things don&#8217;t look very good.  It makes perfect sense to us that the writers of the New Testament are reminded of this passage as they see what happens to Jesus.  The Jews are God&#8217;s people and Jesus is God&#8217;s Man.  Its sin that nearly destroys the Jews and it’s the burden of our sins that takes Jesus to Calvary.  Physically, God’s people are practically destroyed and the same can be said of Jesus.  Yes, it’s easy enough for us to see the connection.   However, we don&#8217;t have to walk away from this passage with a vision of &#8220;a ruined face, disfigured past recognition&#8221; on our minds.  We do need to spend time gazing at that face, absorbing the full impact of what happens at the cross.  Then, we can move on.  Isaiah describes an amazing transformation saying, &#8220;Just watch my servant blossom!” That’s exactly what we see at the garden tomb that first Easter morning. Israel is to be restored by the grace of God. Jesus rises from the grave, victor over sin and death. Praise His Name!<br />
Take Away: The story of salvation doesn’t end at the cross.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-41/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 21:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking upward, seeing hope Ezekiel 17: I, God, made the great tree small and the small tree great. The prophet pictures the monarchy of Judah as a majestic cedar; a strong, enduring fixture on the landscape. Then the imagery changes and Judah is seen as a fruitful vine, not as majestic as before, but now [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tf_wDkvpOEI/YJbQ4YCiAnI/AAAAAAABKIE/o71DjVjgbFMUR9dsGqIuz5vF7s1ai4R9ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2BCamping%2BTrip%2B-%2BGoose%2BIsland%2Band%2BVicinity%2B12-2-2010%2B12-01-04%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Looking upward, seeing hope<br />
Ezekiel 17: I, God, made the great tree small and the small tree great.<br />
The prophet pictures the monarchy of Judah as a majestic cedar; a strong, enduring fixture on the landscape.  Then the imagery changes and Judah is seen as a fruitful vine, not as majestic as before, but now under the dominion of Babylon and transplanted there.  Ezekiel says that in rebelling against Babylon this &#8220;fruitful vine&#8221; will also be uprooted and then allowed to die out.  It seems that this is just another gloom and doom message.  That&#8217;s just what it is until we reach the final paragraph of the chapter.  The illustration appears to leave us with a destroyed Judah, with no leadership, rejected by God.  Then Ezekiel adds a new dimension to his illustration.  Once again we find ourselves looking at a mighty cedar.  This time, God, personally, takes a cutting from the very crown of the tree.  The great tree will be destroyed, but out of that cutting a new monarchy, a new King, will rise to lead Judah.  This new cedar will be the greatest of all.  Ezekiel has given us a parable of the Messiah.  This Chosen One will rise out of the line of David, but will rule as none of the old line ever ruled.  He&#8217;ll be King of kings, and Lord of lords.<br />
Take Away: The Lord always keeps his promises.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-59/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 23:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gog and Magog Ezekiel 39: I&#8217;ll use them to demonstrate my holiness with all the nations watching. The prophet has encouraging words for the broken people of God. The Lord will breathe life back into their dry bones and the nation will be brought back from the destruction that has come. It&#8217;s at this point [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rHooHeMQXNI/YLFDJklJD1I/AAAAAAABKTg/-xVTPmWqlPUo8JvK3jE1qBGu5qkTAD68gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-27-2011%2B5-33-31%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Thames Cruise &#8211; the actual London Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
Gog and Magog<br />
Ezekiel 39: I&#8217;ll use them to demonstrate my holiness with all the nations watching.<br />
The prophet has encouraging words for the broken people of God.  The Lord will breathe life back into their dry bones and the nation will be brought back from the destruction that has come.  It&#8217;s at this point that Ezekiel turns his attention to the &#8220;distant future&#8221; and the mysterious &#8220;Gog and Magog.&#8221;  From what I can tell, the more down to earth commentators think that Ezekiel&#8217;s original audience knew just who he was talking about and that this prophecy is much like those given against Egypt, Tyre, Sidon, and other nations in the region.  Taken at face value, then, Ezekiel is prophesying that in a more distant future, after the restoration of Israel, another regional power will come against God&#8217;s people.  When that happens, the Lord will move to defend them and will destroy the invaders.  However, there are two things that get the attention of many.  First, this nation from &#8220;the north&#8221; isn&#8217;t clearly identified in history.  Second, &#8220;Magog&#8221; is mentioned in a similarly vague way in Genesis and then Gog and Magog make a major appearance in the book of Revelation as part of the wind up of history.  If we conclude that the &#8220;distant future&#8221; Ezekiel&#8217;s talking about is still in our future we find ourselves swimming in the deeper waters of prophecy.  I hate to disappoint you, but I&#8217;m not ready to go there.  I think it&#8217;s more likely that Ezekiel is talking about a nation well known to him and his listeners and that the distant future isn&#8217;t &#8220;book of Revelation distant.&#8221;  I think that when John writes Revelation he&#8217;s reminded of Ezekiel&#8217;s words: an attack on God&#8217;s people by a coalition of enemy forces.  He uses that reference to describe the scene of the final battle.  To me, the key to the whole passage is God&#8217;s promise to defend his people and to &#8220;demonstrate his holiness&#8221; to the world.  That concept plugs into both the Ezekiel and the Revelation prophecies.  It also plugs into my life: when everything seems to be against me the Lord knows how to rescue me as one of his people.  Rather than getting all mystic about this passage, I&#8217;d rather find here yet another promise of God&#8217;s faithfulness even in the most difficult of circumstances.<br />
Take Away: Even when it seems everything is falling apart God is still God and God is always faithful to those who trust in him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
