<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buildings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/buildings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 17:13:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>buildings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-60/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 23:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sacred Space Ezekiel 43: Draw a picture&#8230; As a casual reader, one of the bewildering portions of Ezekiel has been, to me, all the measuring that takes place in the final chapters of the book. In his vision Ezekiel crawls all over the Temple measuring every nook and cranny, carefully taking note of every inch. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15295" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15295" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15295" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2011-London-9-27-2011-5-33-31-AM.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15295" class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Thames Cruise &#8211; the real London Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
Sacred Space<br />
Ezekiel 43: Draw a picture&#8230;<br />
As a casual reader, one of the bewildering portions of Ezekiel has been, to me, all the measuring that takes place in the final chapters of the book.  In his vision Ezekiel crawls all over the Temple measuring every nook and cranny, carefully taking note of every inch.  If I thought about it at all I thought maybe these were the plans for the promised rebuilding of the Temple.  However, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s the actual intent.  The Lord tells Ezekiel, &#8220;Draw a picture so they can see the design and meaning and live by its design and intent.&#8221;  Concerning the Temple the prophet is told, &#8220;Everything around it becomes holy ground.&#8221;  God had called the people of Israel to be his own, holy nation.  All the laws, rituals, and even the construction of the Temple had the purpose of helping to bring that to pass.  In this case Ezekiel is to rediscover the power of the architecture of that place of worship.  Ezekiel&#8217;s vision of the Temple is to remind his people of how far they&#8217;ve fallen from the holiness to which they were called.  It&#8217;s also intended to give them hope and call them back to God.  Ezekiel&#8217;s going to go right on with his vision, talking about the rituals and the work of the priests and the feasts, all with that same intent.  However, I&#8217;m still thinking about the purpose of sacred space.  The Temple wasn’t just built to be a functional place of worship.  It was to call people to holiness &#8212; a place set apart for the worship of a God set apart by a people set apart.  The layout and the furnishings weren’t just for practical use.  Just looking at the building was to create longing for holiness.  I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;m deep enough to fully grasp this, but I&#8217;m reminded today that as I read of Ezekiel with his tape measure that there&#8217;s more going on than just the drawing of blueprints.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for those gifted in the design of buildings set apart for the purpose of worship.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-kings-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 13:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Glory! 1Kings 8: The glory of God filled The Temple of God! The painstaking work of constructing the Temple is complete. It’s a truly impressive structure with every detail perfect. This house of worship is one of the wonders of the world. But that’s the least of the story. What really matters is what happens [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5bCceD-Ixjc/XjdFeFH7WTI/AAAAAAABDsw/-dIe_xQ1ekg51PuZc4tI8Lyq-kebus88gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3912.JPG" width="1600" height="1600" class="size-medium" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Mackinaw Bridge, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Glory!<br />
1Kings 8: The glory of God filled The Temple of God!<br />
The painstaking work of constructing the Temple is complete. It’s a truly impressive structure with every detail perfect. This house of worship is one of the wonders of the world. But that’s the least of the story. What really matters is what happens next. As the dedication service is about to begin God&#8217;s glory falls on the place. His glory is so powerful that it’s tangible. The Presence of God flows into and through the structure to the extent that the priests, who have assumed their assigned positions of service are driven out! Like a cloud, God&#8217;s glory has descended and the people are in reverent awe of the Lord. I’ve been in church services in my life in which God came in glory and majesty. The scale was much smaller, but I’ve tasted just enough to imagine what it’s like on this day. In less public moments God has touched my life and these are my most precious spiritual memories. I thank him for such wonderful encounters with the divine. Beyond that, I hunger for God to pour his glory out on me and on his church. Passages like this both warm my heart and rekindle a hunger for God in the depths of my spirit.<br />
Take Away: There’s nothing like the presence of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Building fund 2Kings 12: Why haven&#8217;t you renovated this sorry-looking Temple? The sample we’re given of Joash&#8217;s leadership of Judah is his faithfulness to repair the Temple of God. Any building will deteriorate if it is not cared for and Joash realizes that the Temple is overdue for some serious work. He orders the priests [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1073px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mwnlsMUXzdI/XnfZaR__PLI/AAAAAAABEG0/W1Ejh5z22xg2m9mfs6X3ZbRFR_CDZ9A4gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170731_125400.jpg" width="1073" height="601" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; at Minnehaha Falls, Minneapolis, MN</figcaption></figure><br />
Building fund<br />
2Kings 12: Why haven&#8217;t you renovated this sorry-looking Temple?<br />
The sample we’re given of Joash&#8217;s leadership of Judah is his faithfulness to repair the Temple of God. Any building will deteriorate if it is not cared for and Joash realizes that the Temple is overdue for some serious work. He orders the priests who serve there to use offerings for that purpose, but it never happens. Instead of being used on the building, the money is absorbed in the everyday operations at the Temple. When Joash sees this, he changes tactics and creates a system by which money can be given for this specific purpose. The people respond and during his reign Joash sees the Temple restored to much of its former glory. So what do I see in this incident? First, I’m reminded that the building where worship takes place needs regular attention and that the Lord gifts some people for this task. The church needs to recognize that and both finance and empower these people for their work. Second, I see that without leadership things gradually fall apart. In this case, not only is the building deteriorating, but the plans for financing the renovations also come apart without Joash&#8217;s leadership. It isn&#8217;t enough for him to have the vision and then put a plan together. He has to be sure that the plan continues to completion. Third, I see that the best way to finance such an operation is with money specifically given for that purpose. The expenses of the Temple continue even through the building project so the money has to be given above the regular offerings. Finally, I see that people are willing to give to such a project. People don&#8217;t have to be brow beat to give if they see the need and that something is really happening. Clearly, these are good principles for today even as they were good so long ago.<br />
Take Away: Leadership not only provides vision and plans. It also stays engaged as the vision is made reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezra</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezra-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 17:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God and “good old boy” politics Ezra 5: Who issued you a permit to rebuild this Temple and restore it to use? Years ago our small south Texas congregation was preparing for a building project. For a larger church, this would have been a drop in the bucket, but for us, it was a big [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vssc43p2OIA/XuT4yp3RHCI/AAAAAAABFQE/pvtjbBtz4F8k57xs5yhZZjxlIgStnawugCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180807_102919.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing the Schoodic Peninsula, Maine &#8211; Acadia National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
God and “good old boy” politics<br />
Ezra 5: Who issued you a permit to rebuild this Temple and restore it to use?<br />
Years ago our small south Texas congregation was preparing for a building project. For a larger church, this would have been a drop in the bucket, but for us, it was a big deal. One key element was that we needed a city code variance to build a few feet closer to the street than was normally allowed. The whole project depended on that variance. We went to the city planning commission and presented our case. They took it under advisement and then turned us down. This put our project back to stage zero. Disappointed, we went back to the drawing board. A couple of weeks later I noted that the small grocery store across the street from our church was getting ready to do some remodeling. It just so happened that they needed (you guessed it) a zoning variance that was almost exactly the same as the one we had had rejected. No doubt, small town politics had a hand in it and their variance was approved. We went back to the city and asked to be put on the agenda for the next meeting. When our turn came, one of the members asked, in a perplexed voice, “Isn’t this the exact same plans that we turned down a few weeks ago? What makes you think we’ll accept them now?” I patiently replied, “We think you should reconsider in light of your giving the grocery store next door to us a variance to do the exact same thing.” There was a moment as the facts of the matter became apparent to the commission, then one of them said, “I think we should give the church its building permit.” Isn’t it interesting how the Lord can navigate through small town politics? In light of the passage before us, we see that he’s just as good in working through big government. Never count God out of the equation.<br />
Take Away: The Lord can handle building permits, city ordinances, and such.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezra</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezra-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 17:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God and construction projects Ezra 6: …you are to help the leaders of the Jews in the rebuilding of that Temple of God. Orders to stop rebuilding the Temple brought the project to a halt for about 3 years. In time, two prophets, Haggai and Zechariah, began to urge the people to get back to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-jGYFx52nKRk/XuZ45F1SnzI/AAAAAAABFQ4/g2SauCHy5z83zvuOosSxXnys6u8wteRpACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180807_102935.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing the Schoodic Peninsula, Maine &#8211; Acadia National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
God and construction projects<br />
Ezra 6: …you are to help the leaders of the Jews in the rebuilding of that Temple of God.<br />
Orders to stop rebuilding the Temple brought the project to a halt for about 3 years. In time, two prophets, Haggai and Zechariah, began to urge the people to get back to work. Now, the precise chronology of the letters and which king wrote what is a bit muddy, but that doesn&#8217;t diminish the actual story here. First, the king receives a letter that causes him to issue a stop order to the Jews who are rebuilding the Temple. Then, upon the urging of the prophets, the work is started again. The regional governor writes to the king to report what’s happening, and, upon review, the king finds that years earlier they had not only been given permission to rebuild, but were ordered to do so. He responds by directing the governor to allow the work to continue, and beyond that, to assist in any way he’s asked to. The temporary halt to the program actually results in the full support of the current king and speeds up the process. Even though there’s a bit of a mystery in these passages about who is king when there’s a clear message that God works even through what we see to be road blocks to our obedience to his will. This is a difficult lesson for us to learn, as we want green lights all the way before we even start. It’s hard to understand how God&#8217;s &#8220;go&#8221; and how the on-the-ground circumstances that force a &#8220;stop&#8221; can be working together, but, sometimes, that’s just how it is.<br />
Take Away: The Lord works through circumstances beyond our control to accomplish his purposes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
