<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Holiness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/holiness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 22:08:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Holiness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-105/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 03:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcendence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Holiness Isaiah 6: Holy, Holy, Holy is the God-of-the-Angel-Armies. His bright glory fills the whole earth. Isaiah is already a prophet of God when he has his vision of the holiness of God. However, it’s that vision that fuels his ministry and transforms his relationship with God. He sees worship taking place in heaven, with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qTpfojnZlTc/X7hIRVpA1RI/AAAAAAABHqM/FHUGKk7JFeENaEVxNThWFzxRAr9YNRyLACPcBGAsYHg/s600/35washington-virginia-2005.JPG" width="600" height="450" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2005 &#8211; Washington DC Metro</figcaption></figure><br />
Holiness<br />
Isaiah 6: Holy, Holy, Holy is the God-of-the-Angel-Armies.  His bright glory fills the whole earth.<br />
Isaiah is already a prophet of God when he has his vision of the holiness of God.  However, it’s that vision that fuels his ministry and transforms his relationship with God.  He sees worship taking place in heaven, with heavenly beings shouting out the holiness of God.  Everything’s impacted by that holiness: foundations trembling, billowing smoke&#8230;and a humbled prophet of God.  So what does it mean for God to be &#8220;Holy, Holy, Holy&#8221;?  While I think the triple statement of God&#8217;s being holy is intended to cause us to think of his holiness as being complete and not meant to give pastors the makings of three point sermons I do see three aspects of the holiness of God.  First, his holiness is that of purity.  God is untouched by sin and sin is absolutely foreign to his character.  Second, his holiness is that of separateness.   God isn’t humanity multiplied.  There’s an &#8220;otherness&#8221; about him and while we’re created in his image, there is that about God which is forever beyond our understanding.  Third, his holiness is that of transcendence.  Even as the brightness of the sun both warms the earth, giving life, and at the same time is so powerful as to be frightening to us, so is God&#8217;s holiness both beautiful and at the same time awesome and untouchable by us.  Had God not revealed his holiness to us we’d have zero chance of even dimly contemplating it.  Isaiah doesn&#8217;t write an essay about his thoughts on God&#8217;s holiness.  Rather, he has a God-given vision of it, and once he has that vision he’s never the same.<br />
Take Away: A God who is holy, holy, holy should be worshiped and feared.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-106/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 03:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Moment of truth Isaiah 6: Every word I&#8217;ve ever spoken is tainted&#8230;words that corrupt and desecrate. Isaiah&#8217;s first reaction to seeing the holiness of God isn’t reverence or ecstasy. Rather, it’s horror. In view of a holy God he realizes his own lack of holiness. When compared to his fellow citizens, Isaiah’s a good man, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-h9AP6odBVn4/X7mpRBeq8KI/AAAAAAABHqo/jMy8wjgli0scPcEHoKBId0NliV_IGrjDACPcBGAsYHg/s600/P7110389.JPG" width="600" height="450" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 Caddo Lake, Louisiana</figcaption></figure><br />
Moment of truth<br />
Isaiah 6: Every word I&#8217;ve ever spoken is tainted&#8230;words that corrupt and desecrate.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s first reaction to seeing the holiness of God isn’t reverence or ecstasy.  Rather, it’s horror.  In view of a holy God he realizes his own lack of holiness.  When compared to his fellow citizens, Isaiah’s a good man, even a righteous man.  However, when he finds himself in the presence of God he sees himself as he really is, and that vision brings him to his knees.  Isaiah&#8217;s words are deeply personal and my reaction to this passage, if it’s honest, starts with me and not with what I perceive to be failure in others.  Jesus touches on this in the Sermon on the Mount when he says, &#8220;Be perfect as your Father in heaven is perfect.&#8221;  Also, I note that Isaiah doesn&#8217;t announce that he’s now going to commence a self-improvement campaign.  Instead, it’s honest recognition of his sinful ways and deep sadness as he realizes just how broken his life is.  Isaiah, in just a few words, says it all: &#8220;I’m doomed because everything about me, even my words, is unclean and unholy.  Now that I’ve seen God I realize the depth of my lostness.  In myself I see no hope whatsoever.&#8221;  The hope of Isaiah isn’t found within himself.  He knows it, and the Lord knows it.<br />
Take Away: It’s only as we’re honest with ourselves and with the Lord that the Lord can begin transforming our lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-107/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 03:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s response to my need Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out. Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart. In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away. His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for. Immediately, the Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Pq33Oxxh4nc/X7sbikt2k1I/AAAAAAABHq4/BwxFxow0j_o3OkzzULmD5QIHj1d0iY0fgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B5-46-04%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s response to my need<br />
Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.<br />
Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart.  In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away.  His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for.  Immediately, the Lord takes action to cleanse him of his sin.  Since this is a vision, there’s a lot of symbolism here.  We have an altar of sacrifice with fire, which speaks to us of surrender and purification.  There’s Isaiah’s direct reference to his “unclean lips” which refer to, not just a tendency to say the wrong thing, but his whole life, which he sees as speaking in ways that reflect a deep level of spiritual need.  The thrilling thing is how the Lord responds to Isaiah’s cry of repentance.  A heavenly being touches his lips with the burning coal from the altar declaring the wonderful truth that his sin is “wiped out” and his guilt is gone.  Listen, I don’t have to pull some surprising insight out of this passage.  In fact, it’s surprising enough just as it is.  When I realize the purity of God and see my own deep failure…when I confess it, throwing myself on the mercy God…when I do that, I place myself in the only place where the Lord can help me.  I can’t forgive my own sin and I can’t purify my own life, but when I “repent and turn” he immediately does for me what I can never do for myself.  There’s no better word from the Lord than “gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.”<br />
Take Away: As I confess my need the Lord does for me what I can never do for myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-108/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 03:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cleansed and called and sent Isaiah 6: Whom shall I send? Who will go for us? Isaiah&#8217;s vision of God brings him face to face with God&#8217;s holiness and his own uncleanness. However, his cry for mercy is heard, and through the symbolism of fire from the altar, we see true cleansing for this man [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UH7AyXDg420/X7x0YuLBpNI/AAAAAAABHrM/AHCTz_q0m7ULLHpoMJFYqEGLCp4Z4PINwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B5-09-39%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Texas Hill Country &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Cleansed and called and sent<br />
Isaiah 6: Whom shall I send? Who will go for us?<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s vision of God brings him face to face with God&#8217;s holiness and his own uncleanness.  However, his cry for mercy is heard, and through the symbolism of fire from the altar, we see true cleansing for this man of God.  Now here’s his commission.  Immediately, I’m reminded of the need for &#8220;sent people&#8221; in the Kingdom of God.  The need is great, and, as Jesus said, &#8220;The workers are few.&#8221;  The Lord wants to touch every life on the planet in wonderful ways, but workers must be willing to go and work in the harvest.  Also, we see that just any worker won’t do.  The call comes after the cleansing, or, maybe as a part of it.  A cleansed heart seeks only that which pleases the master while the carnal heart is divided between what self wants and what God wants.  A soldier who filters every order he or she receives, deciding whether or not he or she really wants to obey isn&#8217;t going to be very effective in the heat of the battle.  The call of God to go is for those who’ve died out to self and been purified by the work of the Lord.  Finally, there must be absolute willingness on the part of the one called.  The Lord doesn&#8217;t force Isaiah out into the difficult ministry to which he’s to give his life.  Isaiah&#8217;s free will isn’t compromised.  The call goes out for workers and Isaiah willingly steps forward with, &#8220;I&#8217;ll go. Send me!&#8221;  Workers in God&#8217;s Kingdom are servants of the Lord, but we aren&#8217;t in bondage.  We serve gladly and willingly.<br />
Take Away: Workers in God&#8217;s Kingdom are servants of the Lord, but we aren&#8217;t in bondage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-126/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 06:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sanctification Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives. They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter center center"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tLxpJRYogHU/X9UfaGwBouI/AAAAAAABH2w/0K5sAXq0Ems8aKduLwY10bRqwtcAgNZhgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251345.JPG" alt="" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Sanctification<br />
Isaiah 29: These children will honor me by living holy lives.<br />
They&#8217;re such failures at being a people of God! Nothing works for them. Their worship is skin-deep, their vision of God is lost to spiritual blindness, and their relationship with their Creator is upside down and wrong side out! The Lord, through Isaiah, has no compliments for them. However, the Lord does have words of hope. It will take some doing but God’s going to make them into a holy people. He’s going to have people who worship in holiness, who reverence him as the holy God of Israel. Getting there is going to cost them everything. They’ll lose the land God gave them and, frankly, many in this generation will lose their lives. Out of the destruction, God will begin remaking them into a people worthy of his Name. Today, God’s still in the business of creating holy people. The process is, in some ways, the same. He brings us to the place where we give up everything, dying out to self. Once all else is gone he fills us with himself. This sanctification process is often painful for us as we struggle with the Lord over ownership of our lives. When we do surrender to him, though, the result is holiness; God honoring, wonderfully satisfied lives.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is still in the business of creating holy people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-133/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wouldn’t take nothing for my journey now Isaiah 35: There will be a highway called the Holy Road. God is a holy God and his purpose for us is that we be a holy people. Isaiah looks to such a day, a day when the people of God will reflect God in their lives. Of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HA98FVOepaA/X9zp2ID-r6I/AAAAAAABH5s/Ziaa_wo1QK8YXch1wIMOWcAvamV_Eg0hQCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5281819.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Wouldn’t take nothing for my journey now<br />
Isaiah 35: There will be a highway called the Holy Road.<br />
God is a holy God and his purpose for us is that we be a holy people.  Isaiah looks to such a day, a day when the people of God will reflect God in their lives.  Of course, that reflection is incomplete.  Even as the bright moon reflects the sun, but not the entirety of the sun, so do God’s people reflect the holiness of God.  Isaiah promises a day and a people who’ll walk the Holy Road and in that journey will &#8220;be becoming&#8221; the people God intends them to be.  To walk that road is, at the same time, a journey and a destination.  That is, the journey is what the Lord calls us to.  To him, &#8220;arriving&#8221; is not nearly as important as &#8220;journeying.&#8221;  With that in mind we respond to his call on our lives, the call to holiness, and thus get on the Holy Road.  Starting is not the same thing as finishing, but without the start and without the steadfastness of the journey there’s no hope of arrival.  Holiness people are people committed to that journey, not people who have finished it.<br />
Take Away: We are a people on a journey, not people who have reached a destination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-177/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hope of restoration Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed. God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it. His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity. This awesome God is a demanding God. He calls me to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 704px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iv0kO_jxD2g/YBWrX4vBb4I/AAAAAAABIX8/BOOAkTIWViItqCIQ8NMxoqCyVIqjKWvzwCPcBGAsYHg/s704/PC253031.JPG" width="704" height="564" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Hope of restoration<br />
Isaiah 57: I live in the high and holy places, but also with the low-spirited, the spirit crushed.<br />
God is the Almighty and I&#8217;d better never forget it.  His ways are higher than mine and he’s right at home in Eternity.  This awesome God is a demanding God.  He calls me to live in fellowship with himself and his standard for me is nothing short of holiness.  If I rebel it’s not his purpose that is broken, but me.  However, this God is not untouched by that brokenness.  He not only sits on his throne way up in Heaven, but he also inhabits the world he created.  When my sins have divorced me from the Lord and I begin to realize the awfulness of those sins I find that he&#8217;s been there, reaching out to me all the time.  The same God, this high and towering Being, cares for me even in my ruined state.  He longs to transform my &#8220;spirit-crushed&#8221; life into something wonderful and new.  His language to me is filled with powerful and welcome words: healing, leading, comforting.  As I reach up from the bottom, I realize that God has been there all the time, reaching down from the top.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-36/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[concern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mark of God’s people Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark. In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem. The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there. The sin is outrageous and disgusting. Anyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TruL9SmdBfo/YI8fidWJRVI/AAAAAAABKC8/Il7o9gOsHrc3t3gLmi5P1b0FrYDED1XqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B4-28-28%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The mark of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 8: Don&#8217;t lay a hand on anyone with the mark.<br />
In one of his visions Ezekiel finds himself back in Jerusalem.  The Lord takes him on a tour of the Temple, giving him a spiritual view of what&#8217;s actually going on there.  The sin is outrageous and disgusting.  Anyone who loves the Lord and worships him would be broken hearted to see their precious Temple desecrated in this way.  Then, Ezekiel sees a man on a mission.  He&#8217;s to walk the streets of Jerusalem, putting a mark on the foreheads of those who are distressed at the sin of their nation.  All others will be wiped out.  I find it interesting that in Revelation we find the &#8220;mark of the beast.&#8221;  In that case, it&#8217;s those who refuse the mark who are saved.  Here in Ezekiel, we see the reverse.  It is those with the mark who are spared from the judgment that comes.  Comparing the two &#8220;marks&#8221; ought to cause some who subscribe to a &#8220;Left Behind&#8221; brand theology to pause and consider!  I think of the mark of Ezekiel as the &#8220;mark of caring.&#8221;  You see, God cares about people and righteousness and holiness.  He&#8217;s always on the lookout for people who&#8217;ll join him in that concern.  If that fellow with the writing kit passed by my life today I wonder if I would receive that mark.<br />
Take Away: The sin of our society should break our hearts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-38/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 21:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new hearts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cry of God’s people Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you. Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies. They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance. They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God. Through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1014px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WvKrAQm6pis/YJGgq_6tWhI/AAAAAAABKEU/rCFvfOQBbcIrk_P-3GjgSJEipNFyMN20ACPcBGAsYHg/s1014/Eastern%2BNew%2BMexico%2Band%2BTexas%2B2010%2B008.jpg" width="1014" height="814" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Northeastern New Mexico</figcaption></figure><br />
The cry of God’s people<br />
Ezekiel 11: I&#8217;ll give you a new heart. I&#8217;ll put a new spirit in you.<br />
Judah&#8217;s problem isn&#8217;t poor leadership or powerful enemies.  They aren&#8217;t ignorant of God&#8217;s desires for them and they aren&#8217;t the unwitting victims of circumstance.  They are where they are because they&#8217;ve rebelled against God.  Through their history, time and time again, they&#8217;ve followed a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration &#8212; only to have it all start again.  Now many of them have been exiled from the land God gave them.  Back in Jerusalem sin reigns and soon the result of that sin will be the total destruction of their beloved city.  The Lord says he&#8217;s going to break the cycle by changing their hearts.  The result will be a people who love God and love his ways.  Many Christians can identify with the cycle of failure we see when we journey with these ancient Israelites.  We too have been trapped in a cycle of failure, judgment, repentance, and restoration.  As we read the promise of a &#8220;new heart&#8221; our spirits respond with longing for that kind of relationship with God.  These words stir us and challenge us to let God have his way in our lives even if that means we need a spiritual &#8220;heart transplant.&#8221;  The result is a healthy spiritual life: &#8220;You&#8217;ll be my people! I&#8217;ll be your God!&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Only the Lord can do what must be done in us and he’ll only do it as we allow him to and cooperate with him in that work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-43/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 22:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s agenda isn’t a secret Ezekiel 20: I, God, am in the business of making them holy. Through Ezekiel, the Lord recounts the history of his dealings with the people of Israel. We’re reminded of the Exodus from Egypt and Moses going up on the mountain for an encounter with the Almighty. A result of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cbC07bHJrZU/YJmARnMLupI/AAAAAAABKJY/fNUJFEglVhAxt-k-bS_gBuJHAsBuSr7DgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2010%2B-%2BThanksgiving%2BCamping%2BTrip%2B-%2BGoose%2BIsland%2Band%2BVicinity%2B12-2-2010%2B11-54-41%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Pier at Goose Island State Park, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s agenda isn’t a secret<br />
Ezekiel 20: I, God, am in the business of making them holy.<br />
Through Ezekiel, the Lord recounts the history of his dealings with the people of Israel.  We’re reminded of the Exodus from Egypt and Moses going up on the mountain for an encounter with the Almighty.  A result of that meeting is the Law.  They now have Ten Commandments to live by and soon there&#8217;s an entire body of Law to go with them.  In the passage before me today the Lord tells their descendants his purpose in all of that.  He did it as a part of his project to make them holy.  From the beginning and down through the centuries the Lord has continued to work to that end.  As he speaks through Ezekiel we find that God&#8217;s purpose has not been watered down or diverted.  In this passage, the Lord tells them that the whole &#8220;Sabbath day&#8221; approach was for this purpose, part of his grand plan.  This message is addressed to another generation that insists on resisting the Lord and the result is his rejecting them, erasing many lines that have been drawn, and nearly erasing them from the face of the earth.  What&#8217;s next?  The answer is obvious: it&#8217;s God&#8217;s purpose.  Their failure doesn&#8217;t change his purpose for them.  In new ways and with a new generation the Lord will return to the &#8220;business of making them holy.&#8221;  As he said to their ancestors, &#8220;Be holy because I am holy.&#8221;  I&#8217;m reminded today of just how committed God is to this business of holiness.  As one of his people, I want to cooperate with his purposes for me and for the entire human race.<br />
Take Away: The Lord is in the business of making people holy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
