<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Amaziah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/amaziah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Amaziah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Amos</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-amos-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 21:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Amos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amaziah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeroboam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s call Amos 7: I never set up to be a preacher, never had plans to be a preacher. Amos starts out as an unknown, coming out of the fields near a small town to proclaim God’s message. His sermons are rough and tumble, filled with condemnation. They&#8217;re also specific: Amos names names. Now, he’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zGP5tN-z6hs/YPMT6s5yYKI/AAAAAAABKvo/VhLfjJFPADg0wCdEWGxJRKCwcMeFWxarwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/IMG_20130722_152821_487.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Niagara Falls &#8211; Cave of the Winds</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s call<br />
Amos 7: I never set up to be a preacher, never had plans to be a preacher.<br />
Amos starts out as an unknown, coming out of the fields near a small town to proclaim God’s message.  His sermons are rough and tumble, filled with condemnation.  They&#8217;re also specific: Amos names names.  Now, he’s gotten the attention of some people who they don’t like what they’re hearing.  In fact, they see his warning that a pagan army will “make hash of you” to be a threat to national security.  One of the important priests, Amaziah, sends word to king Jeroboam that there’s a traitor in their midst who&#8217;s sowing seeds of fear.  Amaziah then confronts Amos.  He wants this farmer to go back to where he came from and do his preaching in that backwater place.  The context of this confrontation is that Amaziah thinks Amos is just in it for the money and notoriety he’s getting and that he’s come to Bethel with his preaching show for more of the same.  Amos stands up to the powerful priest and declares that he had no desire to preach in the first place.  Unlike Amaziah, Amos has no family tree of ancestors who are clergy.  He’s a mere farmer who&#8217;s heard from God and has been told to proclaim God’s message.  To this day the Lord is still sending people into the ministry.  Some of us heard that call while we were still young children.  Others battled with it as teens, and still others, like Amos, were established in their lives and, in response to the call embarked on a whole new career.  Amos is a poster child for all who are called by God, but he’s especially an example of how God sometimes calls adults who must walk away from one life and obey God in another.<br />
Take Away: To this day the Lord is still sending people into the ministry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amaziah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A chip off the old block, almost 2Kings 14: He lived the way God wanted and did the right thing. But he didn&#8217;t come up to the standards of his ancestor David. When Joash is assassinated his son, Amaziah, becomes king of Judah. This young man picks up where his father left off: doing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PU4VNYRt-Tg/XnzgVvnVRjI/AAAAAAABEWc/6a6sjLHu_-cxWphBtDnIarHtFq6BVMsWACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170815_153845.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Ingalls Homestead, DeSmet, SD</figcaption></figure><br />
A chip off the old block, almost<br />
2Kings 14: He lived the way God wanted and did the right thing. But he didn&#8217;t come up to the standards of his ancestor David.<br />
When Joash is assassinated his son, Amaziah, becomes king of Judah. This young man picks up where his father left off: doing the right thing and honoring God. Because of that, he goes down in history as one of the good kings of Judah. This man rules for 29 years and, over all, does what is pleasing in God&#8217;s sight. Still, I can&#8217;t get past the statement that &#8220;he didn&#8217;t come up to the standards of David.&#8221; In other words, Amaziah does &#8220;okay&#8221; and receives a passing grade from the Lord, yet he could have been much more. You might say that David earns an &#8220;A&#8221; while Amaziah earns a &#8220;C+.&#8221; It’s too bad when a person has great potential yet, while things aren&#8217;t a complete disaster, never quite measures up. Do you know what really bothers me here? I’m not as concerned about Amaziah&#8217;s lukewarm reviews as I am of my own! Can it be said of me, &#8220;Well, he did the right thing, but he never measured up to his full potential.&#8221; I don&#8217;t want to live a lukewarm life.<br />
Take Away: Oh Lord, set me on fire for you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amaziah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perseverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pride]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was w-w-w-wrong 2 Chronicles 25: But what about all this money – these tons of silver I have already paid out to hire these men? The “chronicler” starts off telling us that Amaziah “lives well” and “does the right thing” and then begins an accounting of all the foolish blunders he makes. It’s likely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pw_rgY5XWoc/Xs_wcMSECgI/AAAAAAABFIo/gIjC_VO-NWovNA248Gj1javU4oNxU6z0gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180731_145951.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing Acadia National Park and area</figcaption></figure><br />
I was w-w-w-wrong<br />
2 Chronicles 25: But what about all this money – these tons of silver I have already paid out to hire these men?<br />
The “chronicler” starts off telling us that Amaziah “lives well” and “does the right thing” and then begins an accounting of all the foolish blunders he makes. It’s likely that Amaziah handled things just fine until things begin to unravel near the end of his reign. At one point he’s preparing for war. After numbering his army he concludes that he needs more soldiers so he turns to Israel for help, paying a great deal of money to mercenary soldiers to fight on his side. However, the Lord sends word to him that this is a huge mistake. These soldiers won’t be helped by the Lord because they don’t trust in him. Amaziah’s response is reasonable. He wants to know about all the money he’s already spent on these fighters. The man of God reminds him that it’s better to have God’s help than it is to have a bigger army. The king yields, writing off the wages already spent as a bad investment. This account doesn’t earn Amaziah stellar marks, but it does earn him a passing grade. Failure, in this case, would have been throwing good money after bad. The lesson here is one well learned. Those of us who are of a strong will tend to lock our jaws and press on even when it’s more and more apparent that we shouldn’t have started down a certain path in the first place. Our argument is the same one the king used: “I’ve come too far and invested too much to turn back now.” No one believes in perseverance more than I do, but sometimes perseverance is just a flimsy cover up for pride. At some point a heaping helping of humble pie is in order. “I thought I was right and that this would work, but I was wrong.” Write it off and get on with life.<br />
Take Away: Better to write off a loss than to compound the situation by doubling down on a bad decision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
