<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>trust &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/trust/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>trust &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 23:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investing in painful circumstances Ecclesiastes 7: Sages invest themselves in hurt and grieving. I know it is human nature to want to hurry past the difficulties of life. No one wants to spend the rest of their days dealing with some painful situation. However, I also know that just about everyone has their share of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9YNw7xfoGUg/X5x6BBX13BI/AAAAAAABHOs/Lmj8zdW2u30MGdWKYw5_jewsYXcbuexMQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/25rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Investing in painful circumstances<br />
Ecclesiastes 7: Sages invest themselves in hurt and grieving.<br />
I know it is human nature to want to hurry past the difficulties of life.  No one wants to spend the rest of their days dealing with some painful situation.  However, I also know that just about everyone has their share of &#8220;hurt and grieving.&#8221;  In fact, some folks have more than their share of such things.  Some of the finest people I know carry a burden of broken health, broken dreams, and painful loss with them every day.  I’ve noticed that, for some, those difficulties somehow deepen them.  They know how to enjoy life, but there’s an attractive stability and perspective on life in them.  The writer of Ecclesiastes says that we’re wise to invest something of ourselves in those challenging parts of life.  When I make an investment, I give something of value because I expect to get a return on my investment.  When I go through the darkness I tend to rush through it as quickly as possible.  This portion of Ecclesiastes reminds me that there’s something for me even there if I’ll trust the Lord enough to give myself to such difficulties.<br />
Take Away: Obviously, no one wants to go through hard times, but even in such times the Lord can work in our lives, deepening us, making us more like his Son, Jesus.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-124/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 06:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Baby talk Isaiah 28: This is the meaning of the stone: A TRUSTING LIFE WON&#8217;T TOPPLE. The people who hear Isaiah’s sermons think they have everything figured out. As far as they’re concerned they’ve heard it all before. If Isaiah wants their attention he has to come up with a new approach, something unique and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jQycz2c9Kw4/X9E416VKQLI/AAAAAAABH1w/WZJJsB_Bj6kNffEO8fPdn5yglwQtXlLCACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB261393.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Baby talk<br />
Isaiah 28: This is the meaning of the stone: A TRUSTING LIFE WON&#8217;T TOPPLE.<br />
The people who hear Isaiah’s sermons think they have everything figured out.  As far as they’re concerned they’ve heard it all before.  If Isaiah wants their attention he has to come up with a new approach, something unique and interesting.  Otherwise, in their opinion, they’re too sophisticated for his old message.  The prophet says, &#8220;You aren&#8217;t as advanced as you think you are.  In fact, God’s going to strip everything back to the bare basics and his message to you is going to be &#8216;baby talk.'&#8221;  Isaiah describes the Lord&#8217;s new approach in dealing with these know-it-all people as laying a new cornerstone.  That stone, he says, will be inscribed with God&#8217;s communication to his people: &#8220;A trusting life won&#8217;t topple.&#8221;  That message is, at the same time, both simple and profound.  It’s simple because anyone can understand it.  It’s profound because it’s the secret to maintaining life in the Lord.  God isn&#8217;t looking for clever people who come up with all kinds of gimmicks and cute slogans.  Instead, he’s looking for people who’ll simply trust him.  As I read of the Lord’s future plans for the people of Isaiah&#8217;s day, I see that he wants me, as one of his people, to hold steady, always trusting in him.<br />
Take Away: The Lord’s looking for people who’ll simply trust him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-127/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 06:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Running off to Egypt Isaiah 30: Quit hounding us with The Holy of Israel. As the small nation of Israel realizes just how precarious their place is on the world stage they seek an alliance with a world power, turning to Egypt to be their protector. Meanwhile, God&#8217;s prophets keep pounding away at them, calling [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-KMUhI8mfyjY/X9Ui4xwUMRI/AAAAAAABH28/aBDNzuB2WvoI_dQTXisi0Tk8JK6xFoURACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/PB251338.JPG" alt="" width="1280" height="960" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Garner State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure>
<p>Running off to Egypt<br />
Isaiah 30: Quit hounding us with The Holy of Israel.<br />
As the small nation of Israel realizes just how precarious their place is on the world stage they seek an alliance with a world power, turning to Egypt to be their protector. Meanwhile, God&#8217;s prophets keep pounding away at them, calling on them to trust God and live the way he wants them to live. Their desire to find a protector among the nations seems reasonable, but they have a higher calling. However, Israel won’t listen. Those who speak for God are called irrelevant and impractical. To them, religion has its place but not when there are &#8220;real&#8221; enemies with which to deal. Their response to Isaiah is, &#8220;leave us alone while we deal with these practical issues and quit hounding us with God-talk.&#8221; Since I believe God is very much involved in every aspect of my life; that he directs me and walks with me every day and in every situation, passages like this are of only historical value to me &#8212; right? You know the answer. When something goes wrong, when someone says or does the wrong thing to me, when I have a problem, my first response is to head for Egypt for reinforcements. My actions say, &#8220;Don&#8217;t bother me with God-talk right now &#8212; I&#8217;ve got a &#8216;real&#8217; problem to solve. Once that&#8217;s taken care of I&#8217;ll see you in church next Sunday.&#8221; I know it’s possible to over-state things here because I believe God gave me a brain and he expects me to use it. His plan for my life isn’t for me to sit idly by and wait for him to come to my rescue all the time. Still, the reminder here is that the Lord wants to be connected to my life and he wants me to see all I do as a part of my walk with him; not just the so-called &#8220;religious&#8221; stuff.<br />
Take Away: The Lord calls us to live in a real relationship with him – every day, in every situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-58/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trust in God, not in chance Proverbs 22: Don&#8217;t gamble on the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow, hocking your house against a lucky chance. From the middle of Proverbs 22 through most of chapter 24 we’re given a list of thirty wise sayings collected by Solomon. In fact, this is the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-niY3Djbg5p0/X4dh3Bn01lI/AAAAAAABG74/dhCD4coPg00HSQOQl28BrjTGGNl91xNpACPcBGAsYHg/s400/2002new_hampshire-03.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2002 &#8211; New Hampshire</figcaption></figure><br />
Trust in God, not in chance<br />
Proverbs 22: Don&#8217;t gamble on the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow, hocking your house against a lucky chance.<br />
From the middle of Proverbs 22 through most of chapter 24 we’re given a list of thirty wise sayings collected by Solomon.  In fact, this is the first of three such collections, the last being some of Solomon&#8217;s own gems.  Clearly this wise man is not only a source of wisdom but is a collector of it too.  The proverb concerning gambling catches my eye today as gambling is everywhere in our culture.  Several states have turned to casinos as an answer to financial shortfalls.  Also, there are many state sponsored lotteries.   It isn&#8217;t unusual to be approached by someone selling raffle tickets in support of some worthy cause. (If I think it is truly worthy, I make a donation but decline taking a ticket.)  When I turn on the TV I find shows about poker games.  It’s clear that our society is awash with gambling.  This isn&#8217;t how people of faith are supposed to operate.  My hope isn’t that by taking a chance I can get hold of the money of other people who have taken the same chance.  The life of faith isn’t about getting all I can from anywhere I can.  Rather than gambling on my future by guessing the right lotto numbers I can stake my future on the solid rock of God&#8217;s faithfulness to me.  Jesus said it’s impossible to serve both God and money.  In this proverb, I see the wisdom of avoiding the gambling trap.<br />
Take Away: Our hope is in the Lord, not in picking the right lotto numbers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-140/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 09:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strength]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Soaring like eagles Isaiah 40: Those who wait upon God get fresh strength. They spread their wings and soar like eagles. Isaiah says that when everything else gives way that &#8220;God lasts.&#8221; He doesn&#8217;t lose interest and he doesn&#8217;t grow weary. Everything else can, and will, fail, either intentionally or unintentionally but God never fails. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-y_uTDYhyIDQ/X-USwwJOgTI/AAAAAAABIBA/lkgpJRVJiTQswr5JZ-jJaKSlOtWa7q1wgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5281778.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Soaring like eagles<br />
Isaiah 40: Those who wait upon God get fresh strength.  They spread their wings and soar like eagles.<br />
Isaiah says that when everything else gives way that &#8220;God lasts.&#8221;  He doesn&#8217;t lose interest and he doesn&#8217;t grow weary.  Everything else can, and will, fail, either intentionally or unintentionally but God never fails.  Beyond that, God&#8217;s people draw strength from him.  We’re still human and because of that we face the frailties of humanity.  Still, as we trust in the Lord and lean on him we find strength where it matters the most.  The strength to soar like an eagle isn’t strength to win races or ball games.  It isn&#8217;t strength to never fail in the events of life.  It’s spiritual strength to live in a victorious relationship with our Creator even in the face of our humanity.  When Isaiah talks about people who run and don&#8217;t get tired he’s talking about the race of life.  The body wears out and begins to fall apart.  Physically, we spend 25 years or so gaining strength and then 50 years giving back, little by little, what we’ve gained.  Spiritually though, as we &#8220;wait upon God&#8221; we finish the race with all the vigor we had at the beginning of it because he renews us day by day.  It’s a bit of a paradox, but very often the people we know who on the outside seem to have the least strength are the very ones who &#8220;soar like eagles&#8221; in spirit.<br />
Take Away: The people of the Lord draw strength from him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-154/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 11:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not blind trust Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open. Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion. The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic. In his message, Isaiah includes the words of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-v_vbCZKM80o/X_cokt1xWaI/AAAAAAABIJo/KmflYienVpoWJnL9TvIE3zAktpeMgUoJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9052229.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Near Estes Park in RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Not blind trust<br />
Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open.<br />
Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion.  The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic.   In his message, Isaiah includes the words of the Lord who reminds them that he’s never told them to, &#8220;Seek me in emptiness, in dark nothingness.&#8221;  In fact, the Lord has done just the opposite.  He’s told them his plans ahead of time.  He’s even offered them choices: &#8220;do this and I will do that, or do that, and I will do this.&#8221;  This God doesn&#8217;t work in the darkness and serving him doesn&#8217;t involve a bunch of mumbo-jumbo.  Serving God certainly requires faith on our part.  There’s much about that Almighty that’s transcendent, beyond our understanding.  However, his desires for us are an open book.  As Isaiah says it, &#8220;Turn to me and be helped &#8212;saved! &#8212; everyone, whoever and wherever you are!&#8221;  Living in a relationship with God isn’t an exercise in ignorance.  This God partners with us, directing our lives, but, at the same time, allows us to operate freely within his purposes.  This God prefers light to darkness and is, in fact, the Creator of Light (both physical and spiritual).  We serve him in absolute trust, but, since his purposes for us have already been clearly stated, it isn&#8217;t blind trust.<br />
Take Away: Living in a relationship with the Lord isn’t an exercise in ignorance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-176/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trusting when God is silent Isaiah 57: Because I don&#8217;t yell and make a scene do you think I don&#8217;t exist? The Lord states his charge against a people who follow every god who comes along while ignoring the only One who’s real. Through the generations he’s done some awesome things, so it isn&#8217;t as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 817px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uVHEycp6HBU/YBRkQLFZ_CI/AAAAAAABIXs/NOuDl6xyWCkDNZifmwfFbEfupnkzzDOdACPcBGAsYHg/s817/PC253068.JPG" width="817" height="653" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; taken off of the Port Bolivar Ferry &#8211; Galveston</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Trusting when God is silent<br />
Isaiah 57: Because I don&#8217;t yell and make a scene do you think I don&#8217;t exist?<br />
The Lord states his charge against a people who follow every god who comes along while ignoring the only One who’s real.  Through the generations he’s done some awesome things, so it isn&#8217;t as though he’s been unseen or absent.  Still, if a person wants a god who’ll perform on demand and can be manipulated by some magic incantation, well, to them, the Lord God might seem to be out of the picture.  However, just because the Almighty won&#8217;t let them call the shots doesn&#8217;t mean he doesn&#8217;t know what’s going on.  Even as they practice their secret sex-oriented religion he’s been watching, and he isn&#8217;t amused by it all.  Every detail of their absurd, twisted efforts at religion is going to be brought to light as God assumes the role of both Judge and Prosecutor. On that day they can call on their wooden and stone gods all they want. There’ll be no answer because there’s nothing there that can answer. Thankfully, part of this message has nothing to do with me. I’ve no secret religion and no idols are hidden away in the closet. However, it’s to my benefit to take hold of the other point here. Just because God isn’t doing what I think he ought to be doing about some situation and just because he’s silent about some issue in my life doesn’t mean he’s distant or unconcerned. At times like that I simply have to conclude that God is God and that he’s operating at a level beyond my grasp. I may not always like it, but I don’t have to. I do, though, have to keep on trusting him. That’s part of being one of his people.<br />
Take Away: I don’t have to always understand but I do have to always trust.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 17:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s call Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you. It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage. In fact, I am tempted to do just that. However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives. How does God pick people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ABjXB2vdN0Y/YC_5yGxgLtI/AAAAAAABIqA/6PLptGZ2EWMqzPnBdjXSL2c0i_YdS5SCACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034509.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s call<br />
Jeremiah 1: Before you saw the light of day, I had holy plans for you.<br />
It would be easy for me to make this into a pro-life passage.  In fact, I am tempted to do just that.  However, I find myself thinking more about God&#8217;s call on lives.  How does God pick people to speak on his behalf?  What criteria does he use?  Apparently, at least sometimes, he picks people to represent him who have no credentials at all!   In this case Jeremiah looks back on his call to be a prophet and remembers that it was God who picked him, not he who picked God.  Before he had any &#8220;credentials,&#8221; in fact, before he could make any decisions at all, God laid his hand on him, calling him to be his servant.  Clearly, the Almighty has his own agenda and makes decisions based on things totally beyond us.  Now, I have to add that that doesn&#8217;t mean that Jeremiah had no say in the matter.  God&#8217;s call came: that was God&#8217;s role alone.  Jeremiah had to cooperate: that was his role.  In theory at least, Jeremiah could have refused God and walked away and another person&#8217;s ministry would appear in place of this book of the Bible.  Since God called and Jeremiah (howbeit reluctantly) said &#8220;yes&#8221; we have his story here.  I&#8217;m reminded today that when God calls we can&#8217;t always understand why.  We just have to &#8220;trust and obey.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: The Lord doesn’t call us to understand everything but he does call us to obey all we understand him to call us to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-80/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t sweat the little stuff Jeremiah 12: What&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose? The whole question is: &#8220;If you can&#8217;t keep your wits during times of calm, what&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose like the Jordan in flood?&#8221; God&#8217;s question to Jeremiah is attention getting. My first response is that &#8220;calm&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ngJ8MYq2dB4/YEZtX3DR7HI/AAAAAAABI-A/wPdr6_Xo_3YxzyefZtOkh8QSPEMJnLrHwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/aboard%2Brhapsody%2B-%2Bseattle%2B-%2B%2B8-14-2009%2B5-53-33%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; View from Rhapsody of the Seas &#8211; Seattle, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Don’t sweat the little stuff<br />
Jeremiah 12: What&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose?<br />
The whole question is: &#8220;If you can&#8217;t keep your wits during times of calm, what&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose like the Jordan in flood?&#8221;  God&#8217;s question to Jeremiah is attention getting.  My first response is that &#8220;calm&#8221; is a relative term.  At almost any time I can find something unsettling to think about.  Just watching the evening news provides me plenty of “troublesome” thought ammunition.  Frankly, of course, I don&#8217;t have to reach that far.  Like everyone else I always have something going on: family concerns, finances, and health spring to mind.  Again, calm is a relative term because much of this is just part of living.  No one has confused my neighborhood with the Garden of Eden and the same can be said of yours.  So, I must learn to take life in stride.  I&#8217;m not saying that life is always easy.  For everyone there are times of &#8220;flooding Jordan&#8221; that knock the props out of everything in our lives.  Even in that, though, the Lord isn&#8217;t giving me the permission to fall apart.  Through Jeremiah he tells me to stop making big deals out of little deals in my life; to learn to trust him in those common problems and then, when the &#8220;biggie&#8221; comes, to apply what I&#8217;ve learned about trust even as the flood waters really are sweeping through my life.  I know, I know, it&#8217;s easier said than done.  Then again, that&#8217;s why I have to practice keeping my wits about me in the little stuff first.<br />
Take Away: As we learn to trust the Lord with the little things of life we lay the foundation for trusting him with the big ones when they come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-114/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking the “rest of the story” by faith Jeremiah 39: I&#8217;ll most certainly save you. The hero who rescued Jeremiah from the muddy prison is Ebed-melek. Now, as Jerusalem totters on the brink of destruction Jeremiah seeks him out. The Lord has a message specifically for this hero, and it’s a good one. The Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1636px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gW4LDVEO4AI/YHHhlIWsSlI/AAAAAAABJzA/3TJ-jyh_wqglAbrvr-pUNUfFybC3h4dNQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/100_1279.JPG" width="1636" height="2048" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Iowa fall colors</figcaption></figure><br />
Taking the “rest of the story” by faith<br />
Jeremiah 39: I&#8217;ll most certainly save you.<br />
The hero who rescued Jeremiah from the muddy prison is Ebed-melek.  Now, as Jerusalem totters on the brink of destruction Jeremiah seeks him out.  The Lord has a message specifically for this hero, and it’s a good one.  The Lord has taken note of this good man&#8217;s courage and faithfulness.  Things are going to get really bad very soon but Ebed-melek is going to be spared because God&#8217;s going to see to it.  In a sense, we see here God&#8217;s message to all those who are faithful to him.  There&#8217;s no promise for any of us of an easy life in which bad things never come, but there is the promise of God&#8217;s watch care over us.  It must have been, at the same time, welcome and unbelievable news for Ebed-melek.  Of course, he&#8217;s happy to hear such a message from Jeremiah, God&#8217;s prophet.  At the same time, he, and all Jerusalem, is very aware of the mighty army that&#8217;s poised on their doorstep.  The reality of it all nearly overwhelms the message of assurance from Jeremiah.  It&#8217;s the same for you and me.  The hard facts of pain and disappointment and disaster can nearly obliterate the promise of God&#8217;s presence.  Still, none of that negates it.  Interestingly, the writer of the sacred text doesn&#8217;t follow up on the story.  Jeremiah promises Ebed-melek that God will save him and that&#8217;s it.  Maybe there&#8217;s a lesson for us in what isn&#8217;t included here.  We&#8217;re to read this promise and conclude that, even though we don&#8217;t know the details, God keeps his word.  In the same way, I, right in the middle of life without any specific knowledge of what&#8217;s coming, must conclude that God will &#8220;most certainly save&#8221; me too.<br />
Take Away: Even we don’t know how he’s going to do it we can rest assured that the Lord will, indeed, keep his promises.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
