<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>commitment &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/commitment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>commitment &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-142/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 09:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calvary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promises]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s commitments Isaiah 41: I, your God, have a firm grip on you and I&#8217;m not letting go. In my life I’ve heard a lot about commitment and, well, I&#8217;ve preached plenty of sermons on that topic too. I believe in being committed to things. Jesus told us that to be his followers we must [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nUVCFY4FVAc/X-e3YQaWGvI/AAAAAAABIDk/ZV8-PGRUJB0d5pYdFAAxNrJmmp--ceCigCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5281770.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God’s commitments<br />
Isaiah 41: I, your God, have a firm grip on you and I&#8217;m not letting go.<br />
In my life I’ve heard a lot about commitment and, well, I&#8217;ve preached plenty of sermons on that topic too.  I believe in being committed to things.  Jesus told us that to be his followers we must take up our crosses daily.  One doesn&#8217;t have to be a theologian to label that as a call to radical commitment.  Today, I see that this &#8220;commitment business&#8221; is a two way street.  Before I ever consider committing to God he’s already committed to me.  He tells his people, &#8220;I&#8217;ve picked you. I haven&#8217;t dropped you&#8221; and, &#8220;don&#8217;t panic.  I&#8217;m with you.&#8221;  Human beings commit to things easily and then back out without a great deal of regret.  That is, we join bowling leagues, or agree to take on some project without a lot of thought.  Then, when circumstances change, we say, &#8220;Sorry, but I just don&#8217;t have the time to do it.&#8221;  Sad to say, that attitude extends beyond bowling leagues to marriage and other &#8220;biggies.&#8221;  God&#8217;s commitments are the opposite of that.  He carefully counts the cost, and, once he commits to something he’s willing to go all the way in that commitment, even to Calvary.   And, this &#8220;committing God&#8221; has made a commitment to me.  He claims me as his own and promises to never forsake me.  That&#8217;s a commitment I can take to the bank.<br />
Take Away: When the Lord commits to something he never turns back from that commitment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pride]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you want fries with that? Proverbs 29: If you let people treat you like a doormat, you&#8217;ll be quite forgotten in the end. Not long ago we stopped off at a fast food restaurant for a quick burger. I was taken with the quiet confidence and good nature of the young lady who took [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JVZnXcJhtaE/X4-Ij812wtI/AAAAAAABHB8/NMQsnSk-19oVu5AMweNnSYGZcb86OqpIACPcBGAsYHg/s400/lajolla14G.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; LaJolla, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Do you want fries with that?<br />
Proverbs 29: If you let people treat you like a doormat, you&#8217;ll be quite forgotten in the end.<br />
Not long ago we stopped off at a fast food restaurant for a quick burger.  I was taken with the quiet confidence and good nature of the young lady who took our order.  The job she’s doing isn’t the highest paying, but she’s doing it with real class.  Like many people who are &#8220;flipping burgers&#8221; that job is just a temporary stopping point for her along the way.  The point of this proverb isn’t that we’re to demand respect, refusing to be anyone&#8217;s doormat.  Instead, it’s that we’re to do whatever it is we do with excellence and pride and that will, in itself, demand respect.  Those who think they’re &#8220;saving&#8221; their best for some dream job and just &#8220;getting by,&#8221; giving the least effort possible in some temporary place in life, are the ones who are accepting the &#8220;doormat&#8221; position in life.  That young lady who was asking &#8220;would you like to super-size that order?&#8221; gets it and I seriously doubt she’s in danger of being forgotten in the end.<br />
Take Away: A person can do whatever they do with class – and when they do, people take note.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winning in little ways first Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food. The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation. There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lJE1XjaSU48/YLQVqR4_jqI/AAAAAAABKVk/CYDNktkWgasEd-apehJEqrnPTJjj-OCJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-29-2011%2B12-19-09%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Hyde Park &#8211; the Serpentine &#8211; London, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
Winning in little ways first<br />
Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food.<br />
The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation.  There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what happens on vacation stays on vacation.&#8221;  One &#8220;off diet&#8221; meal leads to another and I end up bringing home, not just pleasant memories and photos of all the places we saw, but a few extra pounds too.  Of course, Daniel and his companions aren&#8217;t on vacation.  They&#8217;ve been taken against their will to a distant land with little hope of returning home.  Even if they could go back, things are very different than when they left.  Still, they&#8217;re in very pleasant surroundings.  They&#8217;re part of the household of the most powerful king on earth and they&#8217;re being groomed to serve in the royal court.  Their rations aren’t bread and water but, instead, are the richest of foods and the finest of wines.  The thing is that their religion has strict dietary rules.  That pork chop might look quite tasty, but it&#8217;s forbidden to them by their God.  If we struggle with our diets just because we’re a few hundred miles from home, think of their struggle.  The Temple, Jerusalem, and their family ties are all in their past.  Do the rules even apply anymore?  If they do just go along with what is being asked of them where will it take them next?  Does saying &#8220;yes&#8221; here mean they&#8217;ll be expected to say &#8220;yes&#8221; somewhere else, like, for instance, the worship of an idol?  Daniel decides to draw the line right where he is.  He&#8217;s a follower of God and God has given him some dietary rules.  He&#8217;ll be respectful, but he&#8217;ll hold steady at this minor point.  If he never starts down the path away from God he&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.  I don&#8217;t know if this passage will help me stay on my diet or not, but it certainly can help me remember that spiritual failure doesn&#8217;t start with my rejecting God in some big way.  Rather, it starts with little things.  If I win there, I&#8217;m much more likely to conquer the &#8220;biggie&#8221; when it shows up.<br />
Take Away: If we never start down the path away from God we&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unreservedly in love with God Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings. The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife. She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back. However, he knows that just getting her back [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lvqSMImmE1Q/YNpYs5kXkuI/AAAAAAABKlg/wXeaCZAdJMIJLFU4mLTwRzJ3UVjKy9WwgCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-05-28%2B20.27.13.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Saylorville Lake &#8211; near Des Moines, IA</figcaption></figure><br />
Unreservedly in love with God<br />
Hosea 6: I want you to know God, not go to more prayer meetings.<br />
The prophet has fallen head over heals in love with his deeply flawed wife.  She&#8217;s left him but he isn&#8217;t over her and wants her to come back.  However, he knows that just getting her back won&#8217;t be enough.  For her to return yet remain unchanged will only start this whole destructive sequence over again.  Something in her has to change if there&#8217;s any hope for their future together.  That, Hosea says, is how it is between God and his people.  The Lord loves them and wants them to turn from their idol worshiping ways and return to him.  However, what he wants from them isn&#8217;t just a polished approach to doing worship.  Instead, he wants them to love him with the abandon and passion that he has for them.  He says to them, &#8220;I&#8217;m after love that lasts, not more religion.&#8221;  As old as this concept is, and as reasonable as it is, people to this very day fail to grasp this.  God doesn&#8217;t want me to go to church; to &#8220;practice religion,&#8221; or to attend Bible studies.  He wants me to passionately love him.  He wants me to throw myself into that relationship without reservation.  When that happens, no one has to tell me I ought to worship and pray and study my Bible.  The only reason for me to go to church and study my Bible is that in doing these things I better experience the Object of my strongest attraction: God, Himself.  That&#8217;s the kind of relationship God wants to have with me and with you.<br />
Take Away: The Lord wants us to passionately love him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One hundred percent Matthew 7: The way to life – to God! – is vigorous and requires total attention. A hitter in baseball might love the cheers of the fans and all the perks of being a star but when he’s in the batter’s box he’d better pay attention to business. Hitting a 95 mph [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15652" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15652" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15652" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5029295.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15652" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure>
<p>One hundred percent</p>
<p>Matthew 7: The way to life – to God! – is vigorous and requires total attention.</p>
<p>A hitter in baseball might love the cheers of the fans and all the perks of being a star but when he’s in the batter’s box he’d better pay attention to business.  Hitting a 95 mph fastball requires one’s full attention.  Jesus calls people to radical commitment.  Fishermen abandon the tools of their trade to follow him.  Tax collectors pay back, with interest, padded tax collections.  Rich people are told to give it all away and follow.  How can we read this kind of stuff in the Bible and come away thinking that all God wants from us is a lukewarm, half-hearted relationship?  If I’m going to be a disciple of Jesus I have to focus and commit.  Living the Sermon on the Mount takes a lot more than an hour of church attendance each week.  How in the world could anyone ever think otherwise?  The payoff is wonderful, but the payout is huge: all of me for all of God.  I’m the winner in that deal, but it’s still a deal I have to be willing to make.  </p>
<p>Take Away: When it comes to living the Christian life it’s all or nothing.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Matthew</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Matthew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-matthew-26/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Church camp commitment Matthew 26: I’m ready. Do it your way. When I was growing up a high point of my summers was attending church camp. I loved playing ball and taking hikes and all the other things associated with camp. The ministry at children’s camp focused on the plan of salvation. Many children first [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15690" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15690" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15690" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/10/P5049344.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15690" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; On the road to Dead Horse Point State Park &#8211; also Canyonlands NP</figcaption></figure>
<p>Church camp commitment</p>
<p>Matthew 26: I’m ready.  Do it your way.</p>
<p>When I was growing up a high point of my summers was attending church camp.  I loved playing ball and taking hikes and all the other things associated with camp.  The ministry at children’s camp focused on the plan of salvation.  Many children first gave their hearts to Jesus at camp.  At teen camp, though, the focus was more on full surrender, sanctification, accepting a call to the ministry.  Teens, more than any other group, grasp the idea of radical commitment.  Still, there was a sort of insider’s secret shared by “old timers” like me who had been going to camp through our childhood years.  It worked something like this: the Lord will ask you if you’re willing to be a missionary or a pastor but it’s just a test.  Once you say “yes” and mean it with all your heart, he won’t actually call you.  With that tidbit of information buried in one’s mind, even a sincere seeker had a little bit easier time making a full surrender.  When I work with teens I still see in them a willingness to go all out in their commitment to the Lord.  Adults carry baggage (jobs, bills to pay, family responsibilities) that has to be sorted through so it’s a more thoughtful process for them.  However, adults also have a more realistic attitude concerning what it means to sign on the dotted line.  If I commit myself to making monthly mortgage payments I’m really going to have to pay them; there’s nothing theoretical about it!  When I see Jesus praying in the Garden I hear him making a full commitment to do his Father’s will.  No doubt, Jesus is emotional at this point but there’s more.  He knows that this “yes” is the real deal.  With his eyes wide open Jesus commits to go to the cross.  His full commitment to do the Father’s will both challenges and instructs me as I live the Christian life.</p>
<p>Take Away: The call to full surrender is a real call and needs to be taken seriously.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living unreservedly for God 2Corinthians 6: The smallness you feel comes from within you. These are emotional words from the Apostle. He loves this church. They’re his dear friends. In fact, he considers them to be his children in Christ. At the same time he’s frustrated with the smallness of their lives. The infighting, bickering, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16092" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16092" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-16092" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2651.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16092" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Living unreservedly for God </p>
<p>2Corinthians 6: The smallness you feel comes from within you.</p>
<p>These are emotional words from the Apostle.  He loves this church.  They’re his dear friends.  In fact, he considers them to be his children in Christ.  At the same time he’s frustrated with the smallness of their lives.  The infighting, bickering, competing attitude of theirs not only breaks his heart but it also limits their view of God and what he does in people’s lives.  Without reservation Paul has given himself to them and to the Church in general.  He’s suffered physically for it but at the same time he’s been blessed beyond description.  If the Corinthians feel their religion puts them in a straightjacket it’s their own fault.  There’s so much more to being a Christian than trying to be first in line at church potlucks or getting to be the one who sings the special song. Paul calls them to a better way: a passionate life lived joyfully for the Lord.  These words speak to church people throughout the ages.  Am I going to make church about meetings and rules and authority or am I going to make it about living passionately for the Lord?  The first binds and limits me.  The second sets me free to live “openly and expansively.”  </p>
<p>Take Away: The Christian life isn’t binding – rather, it’s wonderfully freeing.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ephesians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 10:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ephesians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[focus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Paying attention to the big deal of life Ephesians 5: Observe how Christ loved us. So what does a thoughtful, genuine Christian life look like? What examples are good ones for me to study and then apply to my life? Paul says the place to start is by looking upward. As a child of God [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16146" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16146" style="width: 768px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-16146" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7259634.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16146" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; south of Florence, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Paying attention to the big deal of life </p>
<p>Ephesians 5: Observe how Christ loved us.</p>
<p>So what does a thoughtful, genuine Christian life look like?  What examples are good ones for me to study and then apply to my life?  Paul says the place to start is by looking upward.  As a child of God I study his behavior, doing all I can to make true the proverb, “like Father like son.”  If I want to see those attributes “with skin on them” I look to Jesus.  Whatever I see in Jesus, I attempt to copy into my life.  And what do I see?  I see extravagant love.  Out of love my Lord gives of himself without reservation.  He doesn’t use God for his own purposes.  Rather, he reflects the loving compassion of the Father in all he does.  The Apostle says that I get chances to live like that.  Opportunities to love selflessly come my way and I need to make the most of those opportunities.  Some folks miss that boat and rather than filling their lives with Christ-like love they let other things dominate their lives.  I understand the problem.  Everyday a thousand voices cry out to me.  Like carnival front men they invite me to try their game.  If I’m not careful, I wander off into their diversion.  Today, I’m reminded that love is the thing.  When all is said and done in my life, the big deal will be love.  Have I loved God with all my heart and soul and mind?  Have I loved my neighbor as myself?  This passage reminds me to “make the most out of every chance I get.”</p>
<p>Take Away: Love is the thing.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Philippians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-philippians-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Philippians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-philippians-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What does it mean to have a genuine relationship with Christ? Philippians 3: I gave up all that inferior stuff so I could know Christ personally. A friend of mine commented that he was preparing to do a certain thing. His intention wasn’t to do something bad but it seemed to me that there was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16160" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16160" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-16160" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/PHOTO_20140707_114051.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16160" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along OR 101</figcaption></figure>
<p>What does it mean to have a genuine relationship with Christ? </p>
<p>Philippians 3: I gave up all that inferior stuff so I could know Christ personally.</p>
<p>A friend of mine commented that he was preparing to do a certain thing.  His intention wasn’t to do something bad but it seemed to me that there was a superior course of action.  In an off handed remark I asked, “Have you asked the Lord about it?”  His response was, “Oh, the Lord understands.”  Later, I found myself thinking about the exchange in view of my own life.  How often do I do whatever I want to do with the attitude: “It’s okay, the Lord understands.”  Tell you what; I don’t treat my wife that way.  When I’m thinking about taking some out of the ordinary action I talk it over with her.  Most of the time I could probably go ahead and she would “understand” but the thing is that we have a relationship with one another that includes our respecting each other and valuing one another’s opinions on things.  Surely, I should have a similar respectful, intimate relationship with the Lord.  There’s a place for prayers along the lines of, “Lord, I’m thinking about doing this, what do you think?”  The Apostle says he gave up a lot of stuff that he might have a personal relationship with Jesus.  If I want to have a vital, real, living relationship with Jesus one of the things I must give up is having a self-willed, presumptive attitude toward him.</p>
<p>Take Away: Do we treat the Lord as a real person or as some abstract idea?</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understanding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-13/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s people doing what God’s people do Revelation 13: Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground. As I struggle my way through symbolism that has challenged Bible scholars across the centuries it’s nice to find some firm footing, if for just a moment. I can’t identify the Beast or the Beast’s puppet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16397" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16397" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16397" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259745.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16397" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s people doing what God’s people do</p>
<p>Revelation 13: Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground.</p>
<p>As I struggle my way through symbolism that has challenged Bible scholars across the centuries it’s nice to find some firm footing, if for just a moment. I can’t identify the Beast or the Beast’s puppet or solve the 666 riddle. Since John writes to specific congregations in a specific place and time I don’t buy into any interpretation that can only be grasped 2000 years in the future, so the 666 reference, in particular has to make sense historically, but again, I’m not the go to guy for this kind of stuff. What I do like is the momentary firm footing of “Meanwhile, God’s holy people passionately and faithfully stand their ground.” Their situation doesn’t sound very good. There’s some kind of leopard-bear-lion Beast dominating the whole world. This Beast hates the Church and intends to destroy it. Life is hard under this persecution (is it Rome or some future event or both?) and it appears that the Church will be crushed. God’s people, though, stand firm. In spite of prison and the sword their passion for Christ empowers them. In the face of this crisis of (literally) Biblical proportions they “stand their ground.” That’s exactly what God’s people do. It’s not that we travel easy roads, smelling roses all the way. Sometimes we take some hits that are anything but easy. We don’t like it and we do all we can to avoid it, but in the end, whatever comes we passionately and faithfully stand for God. Even as I have a hard time getting the rest of this passage into focus, my view of this truth is 20/20.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord’s people have staying power even in impossible situations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
