<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cleansing &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/cleansing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 16:36:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>cleansing &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-107/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 03:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s response to my need Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out. Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart. In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away. His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for. Immediately, the Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Pq33Oxxh4nc/X7sbikt2k1I/AAAAAAABHq4/BwxFxow0j_o3OkzzULmD5QIHj1d0iY0fgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B5-46-04%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s response to my need<br />
Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.<br />
Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart.  In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away.  His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for.  Immediately, the Lord takes action to cleanse him of his sin.  Since this is a vision, there’s a lot of symbolism here.  We have an altar of sacrifice with fire, which speaks to us of surrender and purification.  There’s Isaiah’s direct reference to his “unclean lips” which refer to, not just a tendency to say the wrong thing, but his whole life, which he sees as speaking in ways that reflect a deep level of spiritual need.  The thrilling thing is how the Lord responds to Isaiah’s cry of repentance.  A heavenly being touches his lips with the burning coal from the altar declaring the wonderful truth that his sin is “wiped out” and his guilt is gone.  Listen, I don’t have to pull some surprising insight out of this passage.  In fact, it’s surprising enough just as it is.  When I realize the purity of God and see my own deep failure…when I confess it, throwing myself on the mercy God…when I do that, I place myself in the only place where the Lord can help me.  I can’t forgive my own sin and I can’t purify my own life, but when I “repent and turn” he immediately does for me what I can never do for myself.  There’s no better word from the Lord than “gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.”<br />
Take Away: As I confess my need the Lord does for me what I can never do for myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 11:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanctification]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A courtroom scene Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes. In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene. Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation. Their situation is a dire one. Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15626" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15626" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/09/2013-10-16-10.12.58.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15626" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; LeFleur&#8217;s Bluff State Park, Jackson, MS</figcaption></figure><br />
A courtroom scene<br />
Zechariah 3: Get him out of those filthy clothes.<br />
In his vision Zechariah sees the high priest, whose name is Joshua, in a courtroom scene.  Joshua represents not only himself, or the priesthood of Israel, but the entire nation.  Their situation is a dire one.  Even though they&#8217;ve been snatched from the consequences of their sin and returned to their homeland, they remain unclean before God.  And that’s what the Accuser comes to declare.  However, there&#8217;s a remedy.  In the vision, the Lord removes the high priest’s uncleanness and outfits him in clean clothes.  Then, the prophet asks that Joshua be given a clean turban as well.  Now, remember that Joshua&#8217;s the high priest.  The clothes he&#8217;s given aren’t just average clothes and the turban isn’t an average turban.  They&#8217;re the robes and turban of the high priest: rich garments reflecting his high position.  That hat, in particular, has meaning.  The turban worn by the high priest has a gold plate on it that’s inscribed with the words “Holiness unto the Lord.”  This is powerful symbolism.  Although the people are redeemed they remain unclean in the sight of the Lord.  Through the mercy and grace of God there’s a remedy.  The Lord purifies their lives and then outfits them in his holiness.  Believers of today can identify with this.  After I put my faith in Jesus as my Savior I come to realize that there remains a basic uncleanness in my heart.  It’s when I throw himself to the mercy of God that he takes action to graciously purify my heart and fill me with his Holy Spirit that I might be holy in his sight.<br />
Take Away: Through the mercy and grace of the Lord there’s a remedy for the stain of sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calvary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is a fountain… Zechariah 13: A fountain will be opened&#8230;for washing away their sins. God’s prophet describes a wonderful day of hope when the last battle has been fought and the last foothold of sin has been purged from the people the Lord claims as his own. Zechariah envisions a cleansing fountain where people [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15583" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15583" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15583" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309228.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15583" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mesa Verde National Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
There is a fountain…<br />
Zechariah 13: A fountain will be opened&#8230;for washing away their sins.<br />
God’s prophet describes a wonderful day of hope when the last battle has been fought and the last foothold of sin has been purged from the people the Lord claims as his own.  Zechariah envisions a cleansing fountain where people can come to have their sins washed away, their lives made clean.  It was in 1772 that William Cowper penned a poem based on Zechariah’s words.  Cowper had not enjoyed an easy life.  He suffered severe depression and had at one time attempted suicide.  Even after coming to Christ he struggled with depression.  At the same time, he wrote the words to many songs of faith.  His hymn based on the passage before us today is his best known.  Cowper realizes that the fountain Zechariah describes flows, not with cleansing water, but with the blood of Christ.  The fountain that makes “soiled lives clean” was opened at Calvary and the blood spilled there continues to wash away sins to this day.  “There is a fountain filled with blood drawn from Immanuel&#8217;s veins. And sinners plunged beneath that flood lose all their guilty stains.”<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for that cleansing fountain.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
