<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>integrity &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/integrity/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 04:03:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>integrity &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Romans</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-romans-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-romans-16/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No Scripture abuse allowed here Romans 16: Keep a sharp eye out for those who take bits and pieces of the teaching you have learned. The first theology book of Christianity is being concluded. The final pages are more about words of greeting than theology. Now, almost an afterthought, the Apostle warns his readers about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16034" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16034" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16034" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_152307.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16034" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment &#8211; North Head Lighthouse</figcaption></figure>
<p>No Scripture abuse allowed here</p>
<p>Romans 16: Keep a sharp eye out for those who take bits and pieces of the teaching you have learned.</p>
<p>The first theology book of Christianity is being concluded. The final pages are more about words of greeting than theology. Now, almost an afterthought, the Apostle warns his readers about the danger of taking “bits and pieces” of the truth and using them in such a way as to create an untruth. Some people, Paul warns them, are pretty good at doing this bad thing. They take true statements and then twist them to their own purposes. He tells his readers to stay away from people like that. As I read this warning I can’t help but think that one of the best ways for me to avoid this trap is to study God’s Word, making the effort to know what it really says. Another thing that comes to mind is that I don’t ever want to be one of these troublemakers who abuse the Bible, making it say what I want it to say. I can’t help but think that had Paul seen the future and how it would be his own words that would most often be abused in this way that this particular admonition would have been given a more prominent place in this letter. It might have been placed on page one, written in capital letters, rather than being shoehorned between words of greetings here on the final page.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord doesn’t take it lightly when people abuse Scripture.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 04:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bildad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[integrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The difference between imperfection and unrighteousness Job 25: Even the stars aren&#8217;t perfect in God&#8217;s eyes. The final statement from one of Job&#8217;s three friends (although the fourth speaker, Elihu, is still to come), is a short one and it causes us to wonder if maybe Job has argued them to a standstill. However, Bildad [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-B62TqpU8jtA/XzL3Jc98DoI/AAAAAAABFu8/IAoLwaFwxv8dM07SwZ68CtZ3yIId82CLgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190815_130912.jpg" width="1600" height="909" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Niagara Falls, NY</figcaption></figure><br />
The difference between imperfection and unrighteousness<br />
Job 25: Even the stars aren&#8217;t perfect in God&#8217;s eyes.<br />
The final statement from one of Job&#8217;s three friends (although the fourth speaker, Elihu, is still to come), is a short one and it causes us to wonder if maybe Job has argued them to a standstill.  However, Bildad does take us down a bit different track. He argues that only God is truly perfect, and next to him, everything else comes up short.  Even the stars of the sky are lacking in God&#8217;s eyes.  Since that’s true (according to Bildad) God is justified in bringing calamity on anybody, including Job.  After all, we’re all less than insects when compared to God.  That&#8217;s his argument, but it isn&#8217;t a very good one.  Job replies that he maintains his integrity even in the midst of what he sees as an unjust trial.  His argument isn’t that he’s perfect.  Rather, it’s that he’s just.  Job understands something that many modern Christians fail to grasp.  There’s a difference between imperfection and unrighteousness.  God looks, not on our performance, but on our intent.  My humanity guarantees that I’ll have a sub-par performance.  However, by God&#8217;s grace, I can live for God and maintain my integrity before him even in the worst of times.  Samuel learned this truth before anointing David King of Israel: &#8220;Man looks at the outward appearance, but the LORD looks at the heart.&#8221; (1 Samuel 16:7)  Job may be struggling with several theological concepts, but he has this one down pat.<br />
Take Away: By the grace of the Lord it is, indeed, possible to have a pure heart in his sight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
