<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nathan &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/nathan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:23:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Nathan &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 07:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goodness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blown away by God’s grace 2 Samuel 7: You&#8217;ve done all this not because of who I am but because of who you are. The promise God makes to David through the prophet Nathan is an enormous one. His offspring will rule Israel forever. When I see how Saul&#8217;s sad story plays out then compare [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Vt4bVShGJy8/Xg0IpkpT2kI/AAAAAAABDHQ/RP_7bGLJ1aEI_ECAPq20ihB0J8_krBhBwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129913.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Blown away by God’s grace<br />
2 Samuel 7: You&#8217;ve done all this not because of who I am but because of who you are.<br />
The promise God makes to David through the prophet Nathan is an enormous one. His offspring will rule Israel forever. When I see how Saul&#8217;s sad story plays out then compare it to this promise of “forever” made to David I find it to be breathtaking. All this blows David away too. He goes into the presence of the Lord to express his thanks. Along with that is a real sense of unworthiness on his part. While David’s done a lot of the right things, this isn&#8217;t God responding to David’s deeds. Instead, this is God acting out of his goodness and David responding as he ought to respond. It&#8217;s true of me too. Oh how blessed I am! God is good to me in wonderful ways. He’s blessed me, not because I’m more spiritual, or more obedient than others. He’s blessed me because of his goodness. Like David, I’m blown away by all the Lord has done and is doing for me. And, like him, I want to express my thanksgiving to the Lord.<br />
Take Away: How can I say thanks for all the good things the Lord has done for me?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adultery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bathsheba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confrontation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I wonder if Nathan checked his life insurance policy first 2 Samuel 12: You&#8217;re the man! It’s through the prophet Nathan that God responds to David&#8217;s adultery with Bathsheba and his murder of her righteous husband, Uriah. We don&#8217;t know much about Nathan, but he carries on in the spirit of his predecessor, Samuel. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0dc6njAKvtQ/XhPC5s8kxMI/AAAAAAABDIw/Dezeg-5WshMcm5X2DHObODOTUTOS_1D9wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4431.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
I wonder if Nathan checked his life insurance policy first<br />
2 Samuel 12: You&#8217;re the man!<br />
It’s through the prophet Nathan that God responds to David&#8217;s adultery with Bathsheba and his murder of her righteous husband, Uriah. We don&#8217;t know much about Nathan, but he carries on in the spirit of his predecessor, Samuel. In Nathan we see the same boldness we saw in Samuel when he stood up to Saul. A few pages back, when David wants to build a Temple, its Nathan who first agrees but then returns with the disappointing news that God doesn&#8217;t want David to build a Temple. Now, when David has fallen in sin, it’s Nathan who takes his life in his hands and confronts the king with what he’s done. The prophet is pretty smart in his approach. He comes to David with a made-up scenario about a farmer and a lamb. When David reacts with righteous indignation over what he thinks has happened Nathan responds with the famous words, &#8220;You&#8217;re the man!&#8221; David, who could have any available woman in Israel (it’s acceptable in this society for him to have multiple wives), instead wanted another man&#8217;s wife. David, who’s bravely fought God&#8217;s enemies all his life, has used God&#8217;s enemies to do his dirty work for him. It’s Nathan who stands up to David. It&#8217;s nice to be God&#8217;s spokesman and tell people about the story of God&#8217;s love for us, preaching sermons from John 3:16. However, there’s a place for confrontation too. We’d just better be sure it’s God who’s sending us with that strong message.<br />
Take Away: No one is big enough, so valuable to God’s Kingdom, that they can get away with sin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ark of the Covenant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s guidance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Go ahead&#8230;wait! Stop! 1 Chronicles 17: Nathan told David, “Whatever is on your heart, go and do it; God is with you.” It sounds so right. David’s throne is established and now the Ark resides in Jerusalem. When David tells the man of God that he wants to build a Temple of worship Nathan never [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/--NnEeqkF6ww/XqTMv7ElduI/AAAAAAABE5M/vgPXZhgr_cQCyHNkWcC3DEtaSK5XP7nPgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20171116_095441.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Lake Conroe Thousand Trails, Willis, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Go ahead&#8230;wait!  Stop!<br />
1 Chronicles 17: Nathan told David, “Whatever is on your heart, go and do it; God is with you.”<br />
It sounds so right.  David’s throne is established and now the Ark resides in Jerusalem.  When David tells the man of God that he wants to build a Temple of worship Nathan never hesitates to place his stamp of approval on the project.  After all, David is God’s man and who could ever deny God’s man the privilege of building a great house of worship.  That night though, God speaks to Nathan.  The message is quite a positive one for David.  The Lord’s pleased with David and the greatest leader in the history of the world will be one of his descendants.  But David isn’t to build a Temple.  The prophet is a good man who returns to David the next day to relay this message from God.  The “no Temple” thing is brushed aside as David focuses in thanksgiving on the promises he’s just received.  Still, I can’t help but think about Nathan at this point.  When he tells David to go for it I think his heart’s in the right place.  To him, this is a slam dunk that doesn’t even require prayer.  He’s probably the most surprised person in the world when he hears this word from the Lord.  Really, I don’t think Nathan does anything wrong in this story.  His reaction to David’s suggestion has the earmarks of a good man who delights in God being honored and served.  Still, his reaction to the message of the Lord is even better.  Think of it: he’s already set sail on this Temple project.  In fact, he’s granted permission in the Name of the Lord for it to proceed.  Then, with just one word from the Lord he pivots one hundred eighty degrees and goes straight to David with the correction.  This incident doesn’t cause me to fear having opinions and reaching conclusions based on the facts as I know them.  It does, though, teach me not to hold too tightly to those conclusions.  Even as a dedicated Christian, I often reach the wrong conclusions.  Nathan’s story is a good lesson in how I’m to respond when I realize that has, once again, happened.<br />
Take Away: For godly people to have godly opinions is a good thing, but even such people and such opinions are subject to God, himself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
