<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>reminders &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/reminders/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 15:17:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>reminders &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Peter</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-peter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[remembering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reminders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-peter/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Retelling the old story 2Peter 1: This is the post to which I’ve been assigned—keeping you alert with frequent reminders. In the early days of my ministry the so-called “special days” were especially challenging to me. Every year Easter and Christmas came around and I felt challenged to come up with some innovative way to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16326" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16326" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16326" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723-1024x642.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="602" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723-1024x642.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723-768x481.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723-1536x962.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/P8269723.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16326" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Yosemite National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Retelling the old story</p>
<p>2Peter 1: This is the post to which I’ve been assigned—keeping you alert with frequent reminders.</p>
<p>In the early days of my ministry the so-called “special days” were especially challenging to me. Every year Easter and Christmas came around and I felt challenged to come up with some innovative way to preach sermons on them. I was especially challenged by “civil” calendar events like Mother’s Day and Independence Day. Ultimately, I arrived at a two sided solution. For Father’s Day and the like, I don’t preach on the day, but acknowledge and observe it early in the service. Then, having done that, we move on to a regular worship event. “Spiritual” calendar events, though, need to be highlighted. I was still left with the challenge of preaching a sermon that would help people better process the meaning of the day. Finally, the Lord seemed to have mercy on this struggling preacher. It dawned on me that spiritual events come around as reminders. I don’t need to “dress them up” with some impressive new approach. Instead, I need to go back to the basics and retell the story. From that point on, I prepared sermons for those days with a sense of freedom. As I read this passage from 2Peter today I see that he set the example for me and countless spiritual leaders through the centuries. He tells his readers that some things need to be said again and again and that, to some extent, if the leader is successful in keeping people reminded of basic spiritual truths that leader has been successful, fulfilling his or her God-given assignment.</p>
<p>Take Away: We never progress to the point that we don’t need to be reminded of foundational spiritual truths.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 15:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reminders]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Renewal of vows Deuteronomy 26: You&#8217;ve renewed your vows today that God is your God…today God has reaffirmed that you are dearly held treasure. As a pastor I’ve officiated at several renewals of marriage vows ceremonies. In some cases it’s a landmark wedding anniversary, like the 50th. In others, couples just feel that they want [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Ulymzhonr5c/XXrD1qjEdVI/AAAAAAABBD0/AKqvDS4zb-AhTIgP4kwj_eO9lcaCVbp6ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P7259636.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; south of Florence, OR</figcaption></figure><br />
Renewal of vows<br />
Deuteronomy 26: You&#8217;ve renewed your vows today that God is your God…today God has reaffirmed that you are dearly held treasure.<br />
As a pastor I’ve officiated at several renewals of marriage vows ceremonies.  In some cases it’s a landmark wedding anniversary, like the 50th.  In others, couples just feel that they want to publicly reaffirm their commitment to one another.  A renewal of wedding vows doesn&#8217;t make a couple any more married; it’s just a way to celebrate what already exists.  That&#8217;s the feeling I get from this passage.  God&#8217;s people renew their vows to God and he responds by reaffirming that he loves and treasures them.  This also works on a personal level.  It makes sense that I find occasions to restate my vows to the Lord &#8212; and what a blessing it is when he responds, telling me that he, too, treasures our relationship.<br />
Take Away: It’s a good idea for believers to sometimes restate their vows to the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
