<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mercy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/mercy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 19:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>mercy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-100/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 02:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reason]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No reboot necessary Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white. If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage. Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals. The Lord says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fOD5LyiXRhA/X7Gv87Av5OI/AAAAAAABHoE/Jjk_2wAXWgwN2cF_RQcN9a5l64zKyU6UACPcBGAsYHg/s400/06garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
No reboot necessary<br />
Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white.<br />
If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage.  Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals.  The Lord says he’s going to put a stop to it.  However, it doesn&#8217;t have to be with defeat, misery, and destruction.  &#8220;Let&#8217;s be reasonable about this,&#8221; the Almighty says, &#8220;we can fix this, and when I’m finished things will be better than before.&#8221;  All it takes is their being sensible and cooperating with God.  This isn&#8217;t about having a sword hanging over their necks.  It&#8217;s about grace and mercy, not justice.  It&#8217;s still true today.  If God wants to do away with us it’s his right and it’s just what we deserve.  However, rather than hitting the &#8220;delete button&#8221; on humanity he offers restoration.  This passage is filled with sunlight and hope.  Plus that, it&#8217;s a genuine offer from Heaven&#8217;s Throne to each of us.  Come on; let&#8217;s be reasonable about this&#8230;God can fix things, making them right between us and Him.  It&#8217;s too good an offer to refuse.<br />
Take Away: Rather than a re-start of humanity the Lord wants to restore us.  That’s grace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-107/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 03:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleansing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s response to my need Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out. Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart. In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away. His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for. Immediately, the Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Pq33Oxxh4nc/X7sbikt2k1I/AAAAAAABHq4/BwxFxow0j_o3OkzzULmD5QIHj1d0iY0fgCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost%2Bmaples%2Bst%2Bpark%2Btx%2Band%2Barea%2B11-28-2006%2B5-46-04%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
God’s response to my need<br />
Isaiah 6: Gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.<br />
Isaiah’s vision of God’s holiness breaks his heart.  In light of that vision any claims to righteousness are blown away.  His brokenness brings him to the place of honest confession which is just what the Lord’s waiting for.  Immediately, the Lord takes action to cleanse him of his sin.  Since this is a vision, there’s a lot of symbolism here.  We have an altar of sacrifice with fire, which speaks to us of surrender and purification.  There’s Isaiah’s direct reference to his “unclean lips” which refer to, not just a tendency to say the wrong thing, but his whole life, which he sees as speaking in ways that reflect a deep level of spiritual need.  The thrilling thing is how the Lord responds to Isaiah’s cry of repentance.  A heavenly being touches his lips with the burning coal from the altar declaring the wonderful truth that his sin is “wiped out” and his guilt is gone.  Listen, I don’t have to pull some surprising insight out of this passage.  In fact, it’s surprising enough just as it is.  When I realize the purity of God and see my own deep failure…when I confess it, throwing myself on the mercy God…when I do that, I place myself in the only place where the Lord can help me.  I can’t forgive my own sin and I can’t purify my own life, but when I “repent and turn” he immediately does for me what I can never do for myself.  There’s no better word from the Lord than “gone your guilt, your sins wiped out.”<br />
Take Away: As I confess my need the Lord does for me what I can never do for myself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-122/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face. Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself. I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bVc5ehr8RoQ/X869s_8TVCI/AAAAAAABHyE/YYt3gG1zx3w_7ioz8H5QaHDZA_YqWHBZACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-27-46%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted<br />
Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself.  I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet is talking to specific people at a specific moment in history or if he’s slipped into &#8220;prophetic perfect tense&#8221; in which he speaks of the future as though it has already happened.  It may be that he’s speaking on multiple levels of a near future and a distant future with the same words.  At times like this, I take the easy way out and focus on my devotional reading, asking, &#8220;What’s this saying to me right now?&#8221;  As I read this part of Isaiah I can&#8217;t help but think of the book of Revelation which contains almost the exact same words.  In fact, I&#8217;m pretty sure the Revelator is reminded of these words even as he promises the glorious &#8220;no tears&#8221; day.  My conclusion is that whether we’re thinking about the broken people of Isaiah&#8217;s day or persecuted Christians of John&#8217;s day or hurting people today that God&#8217;s message is one of comfort and hope.  Some of that hope is contemporary hope: what God is about to do.  At the same time some of that hope is out there in the uncertain future when the Lord wraps up history and brings a new reality into existence.  I’m not sure about just who it is Isaiah is thinking about in this passage, but I do see here a wonderful theme of God&#8217;s mercy and grace.<br />
Take Away: Yesterday, today, and forever the Lord remains merciful and gracious to his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-130/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 07:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like an eagle circling high above Isaiah 32: Weep and grieve until the Spirit is poured out on us from above. Isaiah is addressing the women of his society, warning them that Judgment is coming and telling them that when it comes their comfortable lives will be disrupted. The coming danger isn’t just that of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-typrpReT6yQ/X9k_qdGni_I/AAAAAAABH4k/wmw0TTvyitkDR8Sn2oIemxJFqHY-99RzACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5291841.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Buffalo River, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Like an eagle circling high above<br />
Isaiah 32: Weep and grieve until the Spirit is poured out on us from above.<br />
Isaiah is addressing the women of his society, warning them that Judgment is coming and telling them that when it comes their comfortable lives will be disrupted. The coming danger isn’t just that of invading armies but of crop failures resulting in famine in the land. Everything will be turned upside down on that day which Isaiah specifically says is just a little over a year away. With such a storm bearing down on them Isaiah says there’s just one thing to do: repent and seek God. The coming disaster isn’t some random event. It’s the Judgment of God. It’s not too late for them to change their ways and seek the Lord. Earlier, the prophet pictured God as a mighty eagle, circling high in the sky, not waiting to pounce upon some unwitting prey, but waiting to deliver. Now, he says that if sinning, God-rejecting people will repent of their sin the Lord will pour his Spirit out upon them from above. We often think of the prophets as having messages of only gloom and doom but that’s only a portion of their work. In this passage we see an abundant measure of hope for even the most God-rejecting life. To this day, the Lord waits for us to look up in repentance and trust that he might pour his Spirit out on our lives.<br />
Take Away: Like a circling eagle, the Lord hovers over us, waiting for an opportunity to dish out abundant mercy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-182/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How wonderful to have a message of hope Isaiah 61: The Spirit of God, the Master, is on me because God anointed me. Through the years of his ministry Isaiah brings a variety of messages to his people. Often, his words are those of warning and condemnation. At other times, his sermons contain wonderful words [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BH_aNhTpPaQ/YBw99ElcDWI/AAAAAAABIaA/1llJadP2sx8I1yRDenrZ6qfU068KzNILQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Smoky-mountains-national-park-Elkmont-Campground%2B5-18-2008%2B5-34-19%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1278" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; Elkmont Campground</figcaption></figure><br />
How wonderful to have a message of hope<br />
Isaiah 61: The Spirit of God, the Master, is on me because God anointed me.<br />
Through the years of his ministry Isaiah brings a variety of messages to his people.  Often, his words are those of warning and condemnation.  At other times, his sermons contain wonderful words of hope and comfort.  That’s the kind of message we hear from him in this passage.  Isaiah considers it an honor to be commissioned and empowered to preach good news to a people who are living as captives in Babylon.  His message is one of encouragement to the poor and heartbroken; to those who mourn and wilt under the burden they carry.  This message is so powerful that hundreds of years later Jesus selects Isaiah&#8217;s words to describe his own ministry.  The message of hope is Isaiah&#8217;s and then it’s Jesus&#8217; and now, well, now it’s mine.  The proclamation of God&#8217;s favor, his healing mercy and grace, isn’t just Isaiah&#8217;s and, while it uniquely belongs to Jesus, I can lay claim on it too.  For those in Babylonian captivity and for those today that are bound by sin, this is good news.<br />
Take Away: In Christ, we have Good News for people desperately in need of some Good News.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-188/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greater grace Isaiah 64: We&#8217;re all sin-infected, sin-contaminated. My hope isn’t that God will look beyond all my failures and decide I’m still basically a good person. I’m not the victim of circumstances and my problem isn’t that I’ve been mistaken about a few things. Isaiah&#8217;s words point to the core problem: I’m a sinner. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5Y0A0HIftT0/YCQahn4-SGI/AAAAAAABIfI/Uj03E8wAI4UP8gLhmLKr5cIIsaFxGPeMwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5133622.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Blue Ridge Parkway</figcaption></figure><br />
Greater grace<br />
Isaiah 64: We&#8217;re all sin-infected, sin-contaminated.<br />
My hope isn’t that God will look beyond all my failures and decide I’m still basically a good person.  I’m not the victim of circumstances and my problem isn’t that I’ve been mistaken about a few things.  Isaiah&#8217;s words point to the core problem: I’m a sinner.  Beyond that, I’m not just a sinner by action; rather I’m a sinner by nature.  I’m not a traveler who somehow wandered onto the wrong road; I’m a rebel who rejected God&#8217;s way because I preferred mine instead.  Even when I try to do my best I’m a failure at it.  The picture Isaiah paints is of a human race that’s rebellious, stained, and lost.  Any possible hope must come from the outside.  That&#8217;s where God comes in.  This God specializes in mercy and hope.  He doesn&#8217;t patch up my messed up life; instead he makes it brand new.  Isaiah does a frightfully good job of describing my perilous condition, but he doesn&#8217;t leave me there.  As great as my sin is, Isaiah reminds me of the greater grace of the Lord.<br />
Take Away: The Lord specializes in mercy and hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-189/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 16:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Better pay attention Isaiah 65: I reached out day after day to a people who turned their backs on me. Sometimes I think we read passages about the merciful patience of God and conclude that we can get away with about anything; that in the end, God will still be there, willing to forgive and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zXb0n5ovlCE/YCVbDxPnQtI/AAAAAAABIf0/zYAJ_-R5W8ggVJmxTejCqXhk5xo5pVhRACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5133614.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; at Biltmore Estate, NC</figcaption></figure><br />
Better pay attention<br />
Isaiah 65: I reached out day after day to a people who turned their backs on me.<br />
Sometimes I think we read passages about the merciful patience of God and conclude that we can get away with about anything; that in the end, God will still be there, willing to forgive and forget our sins.  Isaiah&#8217;s picture of the Lord isn&#8217;t quite as comforting.  Things start off that way though.  God says, &#8220;I&#8217;m available, ready to be found and reaching out day after day to even those who turn their backs and walk away.&#8221;  Know what? We&#8217;d better keep reading.  In that same message the Lord says he’s sick of them and their home made religion.  Even while God has been waiting he’s been watching and as he watches he takes note of all the rebellion that’s going on.  It may be that the most important words in this message aren’t that God has continued to reach out to them even in their sin.  Rather, the words that arrest our attention ought to be, &#8220;I&#8217;m not putting up with this any longer.&#8221;  It’s one thing for a person to have honest doubts and even honest misconceptions about the Lord and how he works in this world.  It is something else to take the patience of mercy of God for granted.<br />
Take Away: Don’t take for granted the mercy and patience of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-190/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking the truth in humility Isaiah 65: There are still plenty of good apples left. Even as Isaiah reports that the Lord’s running out of patience with the stubborn resistance of many, he reminds us that God’s very aware of those who live obedient, faithful lives. The nation of Israel is about to go through [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0ir6mnPhELk/YCb8VjNQYlI/AAAAAAABIhA/a86PhVkDfKE5nKJQq8lBsysRZqH-9jHvgCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5133610.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Biltmore Estate, NC</figcaption></figure><br />
Speaking the truth in humility<br />
Isaiah 65: There are still plenty of good apples left.<br />
Even as Isaiah reports that the Lord’s running out of patience with the stubborn resistance of many, he reminds us that God’s very aware of those who live obedient, faithful lives.  The nation of Israel is about to go through a culling.  Many will face the wrath of God but others will be preserved by his grace.  Frankly, from the devotional side of things I&#8217;m not sure what to do with passages like this.  Am I to be somewhat frightened and spend a few moments doing a personal spiritual inventory?  Am I to take on Isaiah&#8217;s role and start warning those &#8220;sinners&#8221; that the clock on God&#8217;s mercy is running out?  I guess the answer is somewhere in the middle.  I never arrive at the place where I’m above consideration of my own spiritual condition.   Just a quick of reading the gospels reminds me that it’s spiritual pride that’s the downfall of the religious people of Jesus’ day. On the other hand, if I’m going to be effective in both warning and inviting the “outsiders” to come to the Lord I must do so in a sense of humility. Otherwise, I’ll drive them away from both myself and their Savior.<br />
Take Away: Always deal with lost people with a strong sense of personal humility.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-97/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 19:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A big two-letter word: IF Jeremiah 26: If you refuse to listen to me and live by my teaching&#8230;. On one side of the coin Jeremiah tells what’s coming, and it isn&#8217;t good. Soon his nation will fall to Babylon and with that fall terrible things will happen. Later on, Babylon itself will be judged. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_I22fXsgcV4/YFyx6ndKO3I/AAAAAAABJpU/mQtuPgFAHDAqEgmyKqrMcTUFP68dQrp0ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B5-22-33%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
A big two-letter word: IF<br />
Jeremiah 26: If you refuse to listen to me and live by my teaching&#8230;.<br />
On one side of the coin Jeremiah tells what’s coming, and it isn&#8217;t good.  Soon his nation will fall to Babylon and with that fall terrible things will happen.  Later on, Babylon itself will be judged.  Even as Jeremiah preaches this message the flow of events has begun, bringing it all to pass.  On the other side of the coin is God&#8217;s hope that Jeremiah&#8217;s message will cause people to consider their ways and repent.  The message of the Almighty contains the powerful word &#8220;if.&#8221;  What a huge word it is.  It indicates a fork in the road; an opportunity to decide.  It’s also a word of mercy, hope, and grace.  So here we have it all before us.  God intends to bring disaster but IF they listen and IF they repent he will, even at this late stage, relent.  Frankly, he doesn&#8217;t expect it to happen.  The Lord says, &#8220;You&#8217;ve never listened! Why would you start now?&#8221;  The Lord doesn&#8217;t expect things to change, but he offers them a different path.  Two thousand years ago the Lord personally came to this world to offer all humans a choice.  He didn&#8217;t come to condemn, we’re already condemned even as were those people of Jeremiah&#8217;s day.  Through Jesus we’re offered hope.  Once again &#8220;if&#8221; becomes the operative word.  He says: &#8220;I tell you the truth, if anyone keeps my word, he will never see death.&#8221; (John 8:51)<br />
Take Away: The little word “if” becomes a big offer of hope, mercy, and grace when the Lord speaks it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-102/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 19:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Lord, reaching out Jeremiah 31: Everything in me cries out for him. Softly and tenderly I wait for him. In this passage the tribe of Ephraim represents the people of Israel. Jeremiah imagines Israel humbly coming to the Lord, asking if it&#8217;s too late and wondering if the Lord can ever embrace her again. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mRicpu7MJYo/YGNa2lelAEI/AAAAAAABJrw/d-hmbPwaSO0eCaKzcl7MDIVh5nt4ZVkyQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B4-06-34%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
The Lord, reaching out<br />
Jeremiah 31: Everything in me cries out for him. Softly and tenderly I wait for him.<br />
In this passage the tribe of Ephraim represents the people of Israel.  Jeremiah imagines Israel humbly coming to the Lord, asking if it&#8217;s too late and wondering if the Lord can ever embrace her again.  God&#8217;s answer is immediate and compassionate.  The Lord says that that’s all he’s wanted to hear all along and that the strong medicine was administered not because he had stopped loving Israel but preciously because of his love.  This great God of love has longed for his people to return to him and with great tenderness he waits to receive them back to himself.  I can’t help but respond to this passage in a personal way.  I’m moved by God&#8217;s compassion on, not only ancient Israel, but on the lost people of my day.  When I’m in rebellion against God he longs for my return; reaching out to me, crying out in love.  Today, I stand in awe of the mercy, grace, and compassion of God for a lost human race.<br />
Take Away: God is love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
