<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>stubbornness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/stubbornness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:07:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>stubbornness &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's sovereignty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plagues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stubbornness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The stubbornness of Pharaoh Exodus 9: But for one reason only I’ve kept you on your feet&#8230; Things continue to go downhill for mighty Egypt. Dead animals and a plague of miserable boils have struck the land. As Goliath will stager before falling many years in the future, Egypt is near the end. All the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9bcbOOBJsdE/XPrRFh9g6jI/AAAAAAAA8Bs/aURQptozP7IGTrFQB_eesAg7CDRXGQrqgCKgBGAs/s1600/100_2648.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Arches National Park, Utah</figcaption></figure><br />
The stubbornness of Pharaoh<br />
Exodus 9: But for one reason only I’ve kept you on your feet&#8230;<br />
Things continue to go downhill for mighty Egypt.  Dead animals and a plague of miserable boils have struck the land.  As Goliath will stager before falling many years in the future, Egypt is near the end.  All the wealth and power Joseph brought to Egypt is draining away.  One has to believe that the people of Egypt and even the advisors of the king are practically begging him to end this by surrendering to the demand from God that the people of Israel be set free.  As Moses promises yet another massive display of God’s power, he explains the absurd stubbornness of Pharaoh.  This is God’s doing.  Pharaoh hasn’t given in because he can’t give in.   After centuries of seeming silence God is making himself known once again.  When he’s finished with Pharaoh the whole world will know about the God of the Israelites.  On one hand I squirm a bit in my spirit as I see Pharaoh stripped of his free will, suffering the consequences of his earlier stubbornness.  On the other hand, though, I’m reminded that it’s the Almighty who’s doing it.  Who has a right to question what the Creator of all things does?  Pharaoh’s life is going to bring glory to God, not only throughout the world of his day, but throughout history as well.  As I read about the plagues I’m reminded that every life will, sooner or later, bring glory to God.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately, God is sovereign and ultimately, every life will yield to that truth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:13:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stubbornness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bigger grace Deuteronomy 9: You&#8217;re stubborn as mules. I doubt the congregation is shouting out, &#8220;Amen!&#8221; in agreement with Moses&#8217; declaration of their stubbornness, but they know it’s true. Just in case they need reminding, Moses is about to list all the failures of this nation…failures so great that at one point God is ready [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1195px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-3EsHw3YTTW4/XW3X7RrBhMI/AAAAAAABA0Y/mvdipkpFhMM1MQKF7X5qm7Jb6TLqPE98gCKgBGAs/s1600/IMG_2599.JPG" width="1195" height="1600" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Meares, OR</figcaption></figure><br />
Bigger grace<br />
Deuteronomy 9: You&#8217;re stubborn as mules.<br />
I doubt the congregation is shouting out, &#8220;Amen!&#8221; in agreement with Moses&#8217; declaration of their stubbornness, but they know it’s true.  Just in case they need reminding, Moses is about to list all the failures of this nation…failures so great that at one point God is ready to just wipe them off the face of the earth.   However, this portion of the sermon is more about God&#8217;s grace than about their stubbornness.  In fact, it might be said that as great as their stubbornness is, God&#8217;s grace is greater.  This is a story of &#8220;big failures but bigger grace.&#8221;  By the way, the reason I can think about their stubbornness in particularly vivid ways is that I’m no stranger to stubbornness myself.  However, that isn&#8217;t the end of the story for them or for me because I can also tell you that I am no stranger to grace.   Any time grace is given a chance it wins.<br />
Take Away: Amazing grace, how sweet the sound!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rehoboam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stubbornness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Visiting the graveyard, looking at tombstones 2 Chronicles 12: God was not important to him. Here’s a story of the man who, because of pure stubbornness, split Israel into two Kingdoms. Under his grandfather, David (a man after God’s own heart), Israel became a united and successful nation. Under his father, Solomon (a man who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dKGbLquN_Vg/XsCm0HzfZeI/AAAAAAABFC8/L-pPMAtqN7sQIkhGDL3J6XDNhY2O1vCmACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_7252.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; High Falls, NY</figcaption></figure><br />
Visiting the graveyard, looking at tombstones<br />
2 Chronicles 12: God was not important to him.<br />
Here’s a story of the man who, because of pure stubbornness, split Israel into two Kingdoms. Under his grandfather, David (a man after God’s own heart), Israel became a united and successful nation. Under his father, Solomon (a man who asked God for wisdom), great things were accomplished and prosperity came to the land. Under Rehoboam (a man who thinks God is unimportant) there is civil war, invasion from Egypt, and spiritual decline. As his obituary is written this phrase stands out: “God was not important to him.” Such a charge states volumes. In fact, when the final story of any life is told, how a person responded to God is the most important fact about them. It remains true today. How I respond to God matters and honestly, God won’t be ignored. In every life, God has the last word.<br />
Take Away: What will be the Lord’s last word on my life?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
