<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Acts &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-acts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 21:06:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Acts &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the Lord says to wait&#8230;. Acts 1: Judas must now be replaced. The story of the resurrection doesn’t conclude the story of Jesus. This is no “and they lived happily ever after” kind of story. Now we learn about the response to the Gospel and how it, empowered by the Spirit of Jesus, begins [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15881" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15881" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15881" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/P6199506.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15881" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>When the Lord says to wait&#8230;. </p>
<p>Acts 1: Judas must now be replaced.</p>
<p>The story of the resurrection doesn’t conclude the story of Jesus.  This is no “and they lived happily ever after” kind of story.  Now we learn about the response to the Gospel and how it, empowered by the Spirit of Jesus, begins its spread across the face of the earth.  That journey, though, gets off to a rather poor start.  Jesus told his followers to wait in the Upper Room for “power from on high.”  Peter, though, (bless his heart) thinks that while they’re waiting they can conduct some business.  He has some scripture to quote and some logic to apply as he suggests that they make good use of this waiting period to select a replacement for the fallen and now dead Judas.  Criteria are laid out and people are nominated.  Then, using an ancient method, they select a good man, Matthias.  Since hindsight is 20/20 we know that this isn’t the Lord’s intention.  Matthias, good man that he is, isn’t intended to be the replacement disciple.  The criteria, as Biblical as they are, aren’t going to be applied.  The man God has selected is, right now, a Pharisee of the Pharisees.  He’ll soon be the greatest enemy of Christ on the face of the earth.  The lesson to be learned here is simple: when the Lord says to wait, just wait.</p>
<p>Take Away: The best of disciples must guard against running ahead of the Lord.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentecost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do we do now? Acts 2: Get out of this sick and stupid culture! It’s the Day of Pentecost.  Those in the Upper Room have received the Promise of the Father.  The power of the Holy Spirit flows out of them and they proclaim the Good News of Jesus with authority they’ve never had [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15883" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15883" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-640x1024.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15883" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-640x1024.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-188x300.jpg 188w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-768x1229.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935-960x1536.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2935.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15883" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>What do we do now?</p>
<p>Acts 2: Get out of this sick and stupid culture!</p>
<p>It’s the Day of Pentecost.  Those in the Upper Room have received the Promise of the Father.  The power of the Holy Spirit flows out of them and they proclaim the Good News of Jesus with authority they’ve never had before and in languages they’ve never spoken before.  Thousands come running to see what’s happening and Peter preaches his Pentecost sermon.  Good people hear this message and are alarmed that the Messiah has come, been executed, and has risen from the grave.  Is it too late for them?  Has the long awaited Messiah come and they missed the boat?  Pleading, they ask, “So now what do we do?”  Peter’s answer is this: “Change your life&#8230;turn to God&#8230;be baptized&#8230;receive the gift of the Holy Spirit.”  A corrupt, Christ-denying culture has brought them to the brink of disaster.  Their only hope, Peter says with Spirit-filled confidence, is to “get out of this sick and stupid culture.”  This message of both warning and hope is still the one people need to hear today.  Our culture of self and materialism is destroying our souls.  We’re on the brink of eternal disaster.  Our hope is in the resurrected Savior of the world.  The message of God to this generation is the same as the one Peter gave to his so long ago: “Repent, turn to God, be baptized, receive the Holy Spirit.”</p>
<p>Take Away: There’s a way through to God and that Way is named Jesus</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[witnessing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Giving credit where credit is due Acts 3: Faith and nothing but faith put this man healed and whole right before your eyes. Peter and John are on their way to a prayer meeting when they encounter a pitiful lame man at the Temple gate. Peter has no money but he does have faith in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15885" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15885" style="width: 577px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-577x1024.jpg" alt="" width="577" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15885" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-577x1024.jpg 577w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-169x300.jpg 169w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-768x1364.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939-865x1536.jpg 865w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2939.jpg 1153w" sizes="(max-width: 577px) 100vw, 577px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15885" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Giving credit where credit is due</p>
<p>Acts 3: Faith and nothing but faith put this man healed and whole right before your eyes.</p>
<p>Peter and John are on their way to a prayer meeting when they encounter a pitiful lame man at the Temple gate.  Peter has no money but he does have faith in Jesus’ power to heal.  By that faith the man is wonderfully healed.  This healing causes quite a commotion and a crowd gathers.  It’s now that Peter brings a quick sermon giving Jesus all the glory for the healing and calling on his listeners to put their faith in this Jesus who makes a real difference in people’s lives.  As I watch all this unfold I can’t help but wonder how good a job I do of giving Jesus the credit.  Here’s what I think: Christians do a wonderful job of giving the Lord credit for organized, intentional ministries.  We make sure that people helped through official channels know that we’re ministering to them in Jesus’ name.  On the other hand, I don’t think we do a very good job when we minister in unofficial ways.  I fear that often people just think we’re nice folks because we take it for granted that they know we’re acting as representatives of Jesus.  We need to develop a better strategy along these lines.  I need to come up with a line to say when, for instance, I stop to help my neighbor carry some bit of heavy trash to the curb for pickup.  When he says “thanks” I need to be ready to say something about my being a follower of Jesus and I just try to do stuff I think he’d do.  It may not always be appropriate and it’s probably not a time for me to preach a sermon like Peter does in this passage, but then again, helping carry a worn out clothes dryer to the curb isn’t as big a deal as healing someone like he did.</p>
<p>Take Away: Christians need a strategy for giving Jesus the credit for simple acts of kindness they do it his name.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[witnessing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pentecost 1b Acts 4: Take care of their threats and give your servants fearless confidence in preaching your Message. The “silver and gold have I none” healing of the lame man gets the attention of everyone, including the religious leaders. Peter and John are arrested for starting a riot, but the city has caught “miracle [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15904" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15904" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-640x1024.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-15904" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-640x1024.jpg 640w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-188x300.jpg 188w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-768x1229.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935-960x1536.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/100_2935.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15904" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pentecost 1b</p>
<p>Acts 4: Take care of their threats and give your servants fearless confidence in preaching your Message.</p>
<p>The “silver and gold have I none” healing of the lame man gets the attention of everyone, including the religious leaders.  Peter and John are arrested for starting a riot, but the city has caught “miracle fever” and the leaders are in danger of having a real riot on their hands if they don’t let the “miracle workers” go.  The disciples are seriously warned to stop talking about Jesus and then let go.  Victoriously, they return to the gathering of believers, telling all that has happened.  Knowing that these leaders don’t make idle threats, the Church goes to prayer.  On one hand, they ask the Lord to deal with their threats.  On the other hand, they ask him to fill them with “fearless confidence in preaching.”  If the Lord will, then, they seek an easy path in proclaiming Jesus.  However, easy or not, they ask for boldness in telling about him.  Luke reports that as they pray there’s a “mini-Pentecost” as the ground trembles and the Holy Spirit re-fills them.  Out the doors they go in Pentecostal power to tell the story of Jesus.  It may be that we go about this “telling” business all wrong.  We tend to focus on the “make it easy for me” part rather than the “make me bold” part.   There’s nothing wrong with asking the Lord to open the way, after all, that’s what happens in this passage.  However, we might just see a more powerful display of the Holy Spirit in our lives if we backed it up by praying the “easy or not, make me more bold” part of the prayer.</p>
<p>Take Away: Maybe we lack boldness because we don’t ask for it.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 12:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generosity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Free will offering Acts 5: The money was yours to do with as you wished. As the Church is being established there’s wonderful unity among the believers. These first Christians love and care for one another. If someone is in need, those with resources take care of that need. We first meet Barnabas because he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15909" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15909" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15909" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2946-3.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15909" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Free will offering</p>
<p>Acts 5: The money was yours to do with as you wished.</p>
<p>As the Church is being established there’s wonderful unity among the believers.  These first Christians love and care for one another.  If someone is in need, those with resources take care of that need.  We first meet Barnabas because he sells some land and brings the money to the Church to use in meeting the needs of some of his fellow believers.  Apparently, the action of Barnabas has the unintended result of making him somewhat of a celebrity among the believers.  I say this because immediately following is the story of a couple that attempts to gain favor in the Church without making the same level of sacrifice.  Ananias and Sapphira are part of the Church.  They see what Barnabas does and the reaction of people and decide to follow suit.  However, they don’t want to give all they receive in the sale of their land.  Instead, they scheme together to claim to give it all, but to actually hold back a portion of it.  The result is the condemnation of the Lord and their untimely deaths.  They’re judged by God, not for withholding a portion of the money from the sale of their property, but for doing so and then lying about it.  I find it interesting that Peter, as he realizes what they’ve done, says, “Before you sold it, it was all yours, and after you sold it, the money was yours to do with as you wished.”  Sometimes I read about how the early Church operated, that they “shared everything,” and come away thinking that the preferred model for the Church is communal living in which there’s no private ownership.  I might even go a step farther and think that socialism is more “Christian” than is capitalism.  It’s enlightening to balance the “shared everything” statement against “before you sold it, it was all yours” and “the money was yours to do with as you wished.”  As I make this connection I see that the action of Barnabas and some unnamed others is the real deal.  They don’t give what they have because socialism is God’s preferred mode of operation for the Church.  Rather, they give because they want to.  It’s theirs and there’s nothing wrong with them keeping it.  Instead, though, they see the need of fellow believers and want to meet that need.  </p>
<p>Take Away: Obviously, required generosity isn’t really generosity at all.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clergy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-6/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pastors and their congregations Acts 6: Choose seven men from among you whom everyone trusts. One of the growth pains of the infant church has to do with the distribution of resources among the church’s own needy. Some women, apparently due to a language barrier, aren’t getting a fair share of the food the church [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15912" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15912" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15912" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2956.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15912" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Pastors and their congregations</p>
<p>Acts 6: Choose seven men from among you whom everyone trusts.</p>
<p>One of the growth pains of the infant church has to do with the distribution of resources among the church’s own needy.  Some women, apparently due to a language barrier, aren’t getting a fair share of the food the church is providing.  The disciples realize that this is an important concern and willingly share the leadership responsibilities with seven non-apostles.  The result is that the disciples are able to focus on their role in the church while sharing some responsibilities with those who have gifts for that purpose.  The needs of the people are met and the church continues to advance.  As a pastor I’ve read this account again and again trying to understand it in light of the current pastor/congregation scheme that’s generally in place.   I’ve tried to translate it into the 21st century average Protestant church with an average attendance of 70 to 100.  On one hand, I realize that the church of Acts now numbers in the thousands.  Even if the disciples try to handle it all it simply can’t be.  The question that comes to mind is, is that the only reason for the addition of non-clergy leadership?  I think that a lot of church people think so.  In their smaller situations they’re very pastor-centric.  They want the pastor to be the one who visits them when they’re sick and who makes regular nursing home visits.  They expect the pastor to attend every committee meeting and to pray every public prayer.  Then, if the church grows, they’ll take care of things by hiring an assistant pastor.  I can’t help but think this is mistaken because I have the idea that the division of leadership in the Acts church isn’t all about size and work load.  Rather, I believe the leadership and ministry opportunities need to be shared because it’s healthier for the church.  Had the disciples been perfectly capable of caring for the widows while handling the preaching and teaching responsibilities, I still think they would have done, under the Spirit’s leadership, just what they did.  Some church people need to find a place of ministry and plug in, not always looking to the pastor to do it all.  Some pastors need to quit hogging all the ministry opportunities and give others a chance.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord didn’t come to be served, but to serve and we aren’t his followers unless we follow him into lives of service of others.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 12:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gospel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Temple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How not to win friends and influence people Acts 7: And you continue, so bullheaded. The ragged transition in righteous Stephen’s sermon feels so out of place. He’s been debating with the religious leaders, and winning, so they come up with a scheme to lie about him and get him arrested. The charge is that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15915" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15915" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15915" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_2969.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15915" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>How not to win friends and influence people</p>
<p>Acts 7: And you continue, so bullheaded.  </p>
<p>The ragged transition in righteous Stephen’s sermon feels so out of place.  He’s been debating with the religious leaders, and winning, so they come up with a scheme to lie about him and get him arrested.  The charge is that Stephen claims Jesus of Nazareth is going to destroy the Temple and toss out the customs of Moses.  Stephen’s defense begins innocently enough.  For some reason he decides to recount the history of their people, from Abraham on.  Everything he says is plain vanilla, middle of the road facts that every Jew knows.  After several minutes of this walk through history Stephen arrives at the story of the building of the Temple.  Now those who have made the charge that Stephen says the Temple is going to be destroyed by Jesus sit up and take notice.  When Stephen reminds them that their own Scriptures state that God doesn’t live in any building made by man they, I think, decide he’s about to say the Temple isn’t important at all.  Although it isn’t recorded in this passage, I believe that people start shouting Stephen down.  That’s when he drops out of his sermon and responds by calling them “bullheaded,” “traitors,” and “murderers.”  His enemies don’t take kindly to being thus accused and the result is that the mob lives down to Stephen’s description of them as murderers.  I know I’m not anything close to being worthy of making a judgment call on this good man who, even as he’s being murdered prays for those doing the horrible deed.  Still, I can’t help but wonder if things might have turned out differently had Stephen responded differently.  It seems to me that when he gets into a shouting match with his adversaries that his opportunity to make any case at all is lost.  Again, I know I’m not in a position to judge here but I think Christians are almost always more effective in spreading the Good News of Jesus when they live servant-lives, humble and kind.  After all, Jesus said that when we’re rejected we’re to shake the dust off our feet and meekly move on.  That feels a lot different to me than telling people they’re bullheaded murderers.</p>
<p>Take Away: Likely the best way to influence people for Christ is to take on the role of a servant while avoiding calling them names! </p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[missions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Philip and the Ethiopian Acts 8: He met an Ethiopian eunuch coming down the road. Philip is deeply involved in a great revival in Samaria. Miracles are taking place, and people are coming to faith in Jesus by the hundreds and, probably, thousands. The Holy Spirit is filling lives and Philip is at the heart [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15918" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15918" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15918" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3021.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15918" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Philip and the Ethiopian </p>
<p>Acts 8: He met an Ethiopian eunuch coming down the road.</p>
<p>Philip is deeply involved in a great revival in Samaria.  Miracles are taking place, and people are coming to faith in Jesus by the hundreds and, probably, thousands.  The Holy Spirit is filling lives and Philip is at the heart of a real move of God.  Then, the Lord speaks to Philip, sending him away from the action and out to the wilderness.  Rather than ministering to thousands, he’s to watch for just one man, the one known in history simply as the Ethiopian eunuch.  This person is more or less a mystery in the Bible.  Here’s an African traveling to Jerusalem to worship.  What’s up with that?  Some think this proves the, mostly fictional, connection between Solomon and the Queen of Sheba and that because of her visit to Solomon hundreds of years earlier that there’s now a pocket of Jehovah worshipers in northern Africa.  Perhaps this man is one of those worshipers and, because of his standing in government, he’s able to make the long journey to Jerusalem to worship.  It’s fun to speculate about stuff like this.  However, for Philip, none of this matters. He’s on a mission from God to tell this mysterious man about Jesus and that’s what he does.  The man believes in Jesus, asks to be baptized, and, as he’s baptized, Philip is whisked away by the Spirit to a town thirty miles away.  As I read this story, I not only enjoy thinking of the mystery of the Ethiopian, but of Philip’s obedience to the seeming unreasonable orders of the Lord.  If I’m in the middle of a great revival and the Lord tells me to leave it all and head out to the wilderness to find one person, I might be a bit hesitant, wondering if I’m hearing the Lord’s command correctly.  Philip, though, just obeys and the result is this incident.  Why this Ethiopian?  My guess is that he becomes the first missionary for Jesus in Africa, boosting the spread of the Gospel in the direction opposite from Rome, which will soon be Paul and Silas’ territory.  I may be wrong here, but it’s fun to think about stuff like this.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord’s definition of success is often quite different than ours.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 12:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-9/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From persecutor to follower Acts 9: Things calmed down after that and the church had smooth sailing for awhile. From the Day of Pentecost on there’s tension between the followers of Jesus and the religious leaders in Jerusalem. Obviously, the murder of Stephen is the primary example of that. Now, Saul, who was there as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15923" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15923" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15923" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3025.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15923" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>From persecutor to follower </p>
<p>Acts 9: Things calmed down after that and the church had smooth sailing for awhile.</p>
<p>From the Day of Pentecost on there’s tension between the followers of Jesus and the religious leaders in Jerusalem.  Obviously, the murder of Stephen is the primary example of that.  Now, Saul, who was there as Stephen’s last words were addressed to Jesus, becomes the main enemy of the believers.  He terrorizes them, showing no mercy.  Then, on the way to Damascus to root out even more Jesus followers, he encounters Jesus, himself.  It’s a dramatic turnaround.  The greatest enemy of Jesus and his people is now one of them.  Saul is as zealous for Jesus as he had been zealous against him.  Following the martyred Stephen’s approach Saul debates the enemies of Jesus in Damascus.  Then, when opposition is stirred to murderous proportions he returns to Jerusalem.  Thanks to Barnabas, Saul is welcomed into the Church there.  Soon he’s debating with the Hellenists of that city.  Before long they decide to deal with Saul as they dealt with Stephen.  Saul is hustled out of town and soon is sent to his distant home town, Tarsus.  It’s only then that things calm down for the infant Church.  As I read of these events, I once again wonder if debate is the best way to advance Christianity.  It’s Stephen’s use of this approach that touches off the firestorm of opposition and it’s when Saul, with his debate style is moved from the mix that things calm down and the Church advances under a banner of peace.  Also, I can’t help but wonder if Saul’s conversion doesn’t frighten the enemies of the Church.  Saul was one of them, in fact, the most zealous of the lot.  If attacking followers of Jesus can somehow make a person into one of “them” maybe it’s best to just leave them alone!  No real application here but there’s plenty to think about as I consider this chain of events. </p>
<p>Take Away: Debate probably isn’t the best way to influence people for Jesus.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Acts</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-acts-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Acts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cornelius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-acts-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Revival! Acts 10: No sooner were these words out of Peter’s mouth than the Holy Spirit came on the listeners. The story of Cornelius is such a wonderful story. Here’s a good man, a Gentile, who cares for the needy and who makes time to pray. He’s such a good man that he gets the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15925" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15925" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15925" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/100_3029.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15925" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Revival! </p>
<p>Acts 10: No sooner were these words out of Peter’s mouth than the Holy Spirit came on the listeners.</p>
<p>The story of Cornelius is such a wonderful story.  Here’s a good man, a Gentile, who cares for the needy and who makes time to pray.  He’s such a good man that he gets the attention of the Lord who wants to do something more in his life.  Then, miles away, we see another good man, a Jew, who loves the Lord and is a Spirit-filled follower of Jesus.  God’s intention is to bring these two men together.  Connecting this Gentile and Jew at the level the Lord wants takes some doing involving an angelic visitation and a vision from God.  It works!  As Cornelius gathers a house full of expectant friends Peter arrives and soon begins telling them the story of Jesus.  The sermon has barely begun before it becomes unnecessary.  This gathering of people are already on the verge of faith and all it takes is a gentle nudge from Peter to open the way for the Holy Spirit to take command of the service and their lives.  How wonderful it is to experience such a move of God!  It’s a blessing that both satisfies and causes hunger for more.  Once we have such an experience we’re not likely to be fooled by some counterfeit!  </p>
<p>Take Away: Sometimes the Lord has prepared the way for revival and all it takes is one or two acts of obedience to put that revival into full motion.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
