<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>King Saul &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/king-saul/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 16:18:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>King Saul &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 01:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Self-sabotage 1 Samuel 9: He had a son, Saul, a most handsome young man&#8230;he literally stood head and shoulders above the crowd! Since I know where this story’s headed I tend to brush past the way the Bible introduces Saul. Here’s a good man. In spite of his physical domination and naturally handsome good looks [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1E7Pd_1jT3w/XdHmgjWKTkI/AAAAAAABC2g/Ro7K5xefmkYxKjsUfEK4Di_jLmHh2JKNwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3542.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Davis Mountains State Park, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Self-sabotage<br />
1 Samuel 9: He had a son, Saul, a most handsome young man&#8230;he literally stood head and shoulders above the crowd!<br />
Since I know where this story’s headed I tend to brush past the way the Bible introduces Saul. Here’s a good man. In spite of his physical domination and naturally handsome good looks he’s humble. We meet him taking care of his father’s business, looking for some lost donkeys, but also concerned that his father might be worried about him. When it’s suggested that he visit the man of God, Samuel, and ask for help in locating the animals, he goes with offering in hand. When I read this introduction to Saul I’m impressed with him. He has the potential of being a terrific leader of Israel who’ll guide the people to a close, faithful walk with the Lord. As I begin reading the story of Saul I find no reason to expect failure on his part. Instead, everything’s in place for success at every level of his life. In choosing him, the Lord isn’t setting him up for failure. Instead, Saul’s being set up for success. That’s true, too, I think, in the lives of followers of Jesus. No one is saved to ultimately fail. In fact, success is guaranteed by the blood of Jesus. The only way my spiritual journey can end badly is if I sabotage it myself. Sorry to say we’re about to see an illustration of that from this capable young man.<br />
Take Away: The Lord gives us everything we need to live for him and then live with him in eternity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 01:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Transformed 1 Samuel 10: The Spirit of God will come on you&#8230;and you&#8217;ll be transformed. You&#8217;ll be a new person. Beyond Saul’s natural advantages is the stated intention of God Almighty to make him into one of the heroes of the Bible. This big man is humble and practical and will be used by God [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9NmLcZw_FGU/XdMZgd1v8uI/AAAAAAABC3I/avN8SfWIfYkUBpidkF3cUl8HKXR7KRIFgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3545.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Davis Mountains State Park, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Transformed<br />
1 Samuel 10: The Spirit of God will come on you&#8230;and you&#8217;ll be transformed. You&#8217;ll be a new person.<br />
Beyond Saul’s natural advantages is the stated intention of God Almighty to make him into one of the heroes of the Bible. This big man is humble and practical and will be used by God in wonderful ways. What Saul lacks, his shyness and his inexperience as a spiritual leader, is recognized by the Lord so right off the Lord goes to work there. Samuel says that before the day is out Saul will be transformed into a man who openly worships God, one who can be numbered among the prophets. Failure is coming to Saul, but not because God just tossed him into the water to sink or swim. The same God who chooses him also enables him for the task. That’s still true today. What the Lord calls me to be enables me to be. There’s clearly more to be said about that, but this is a truth that’s made real in the lives of all that hear God&#8217;s call.<br />
Take Away: Those the Lord calls he also equips.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 01:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Heavenly surprises 1 Samuel 10: Saul among the prophets! Who would have guessed?! The young man Saul is not a leader and he isn&#8217;t especially known for his spirituality. On this day, after his meeting with Samuel, Saul is headed home when he encounters a group of prophets on their way to worship. Before he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-y9A_f2JUM8w/XdRV5q_8eOI/AAAAAAABC3k/_44qktaU3_M-U_rU5YwL2I_YHLlAbLenACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3311.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Davis Mountains State Park, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Heavenly surprises<br />
1 Samuel 10: Saul among the prophets! Who would have guessed?!<br />
The young man Saul is not a leader and he isn&#8217;t especially known for his spirituality. On this day, after his meeting with Samuel, Saul is headed home when he encounters a group of prophets on their way to worship. Before he knows it, Saul falls in with them, and then to everyone&#8217;s surprise he joins them in their religious expression. This is an unlikely event and word of it spreads throughout his family and friends. People are surprised at &#8220;Saul among the prophets.&#8221; After he becomes king a saying based on this incident becomes common. Anytime a person is surprised at something they shake their heads in wonder and say, &#8220;Saul among the prophets! Who would have guessed!&#8221; I&#8217;ve seen God do some surprising things in people&#8217;s lives. When I was a kid I knew a man who had been the town drunk. He was wonderfully converted and became the Sunday School Superintendent in the church where I grew up. &#8220;Saul among the prophets! Who would have guessed!&#8221; Another man, who was raised in the church, got away from God. His mother never stopped praying for him, but for years he seemed distant. One night he came to revival and responded to the invitation. A few years later he was a terrific youth leader in the church. &#8220;Saul among the prophets!&#8221; I love it when God does stuff like that and look forward to more &#8220;Saul among the prophets!&#8221; events in the days to come.<br />
Take Away: The Lord does wonderfully surprising things in the lives of those who cooperate with his purposes for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 01:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luggage compartment 1 Samuel 10: He&#8217;s right over there &#8212; hidden in that pile of baggage. Things are moving too fast for young Saul. Not long ago the old man of God, Samuel, floored him with the announcement that he has been picked by God to be the first king of Israel. Then there’s the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ASjnWn5spfA/XdXOGZS2_eI/AAAAAAABC3w/xw40xNUDaegmiXFjdRDuIeC0bnG5ER2_wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3557.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; South Llano State Park &#8211; Junction, TX</figcaption></figure>
<p>Luggage compartment<br />
1 Samuel 10: He&#8217;s right over there &#8212; hidden in that pile of baggage.<br />
Things are moving too fast for young Saul. Not long ago the old man of God, Samuel, floored him with the announcement that he has been picked by God to be the first king of Israel. Then there’s the surprising episode with the prophets; he still hasn&#8217;t figured that one out. Now, he finds himself at the big gathering to announce the new king. He already knows the outcome; Samuel let him in on God&#8217;s plan and the prospect of being king both terrifies and thrills him. This big man dislikes being noticed &#8212; something that can hardly be avoided. After all, just his standing up gets him plenty of attention. Almost by instinct he slips out of the main gathering to find a comfortable, out of sight place among the baggage. Here he sits, wondering what he will do when his name is announced. The answer to the question is known soon enough: he does nothing. Frozen in fear and indecision he sits there until someone finds him. Like it or not, he is the man picked by God to be king and the Lord won&#8217;t take &#8220;no&#8221; for an answer. I feel kind of sorry for Saul in this incident. In fact, I identify with both his hesitation and thrill at what the Lord’s doing in his life. Often I find myself feeling unworthy and incapable of doing what the Lord places before me. The greatest source of hope in such times is the knowledge that when God calls to some task he also provides the strength necessary to accomplish that task. Still, it would sometimes be easier to hide among the baggage.<br />
Take Away: If the Lord calls you to it, he’ll enable you to do it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disobedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The bigger they come&#8230; 1 Samuel 13: God is out looking for your replacement right now. On the surface, Saul&#8217;s failure seems minor. All he’s doing is offering his own sacrifice instead of waiting for Samuel to do it for him. Beneath that, though, is a fault line that means catastrophe. Any king of Israel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZqYKCZO0RKE/Xdv1e8rBBPI/AAAAAAABC6A/GRPXDRk8K6g4LaYz8ipaTEEK5FLnJfcuwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3634.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Pinnacle Mtn State Park, AR</figcaption></figure>
<p>The bigger they come&#8230;<br />
1 Samuel 13: God is out looking for your replacement right now.<br />
On the surface, Saul&#8217;s failure seems minor. All he’s doing is offering his own sacrifice instead of waiting for Samuel to do it for him. Beneath that, though, is a fault line that means catastrophe. Any king of Israel must rule only as a servant of God. Things are to be done God&#8217;s way. From the beginning of Saul&#8217;s story his position has been clearly defined. Samuel is the man chosen by God to provide spiritual leadership and that includes making ritual sacrifices. Saul has crossed that line, claiming authority that’s not his. Because of that God is rejecting him as king. Since he doesn’t accept God&#8217;s way of doing things another king will be found. I need to remember here that Saul isn&#8217;t making a mistake in this incident. Rather, he’s acting with full knowledge of what he’s doing. Simply put, he’s pushing God&#8217;s will to the side and taking what he thinks is a better course of action. While it’s true that God is testing him with the circumstance of Samuel&#8217;s late arrival it’s also true that he miserably fails the test. The Lord seeks another king because Saul, by his own decision, makes himself unworthy to be king. As I apply this to my life, I see that I must never forget that he is Lord. I&#8217;m not free to do whatever I want to do. While I know God is gracious and merciful, I also know that, in my own free will, I can push God too far. It doesn’t have to be that way, but I know that it remains a tragic possibility.<br />
Take Away: If I’m to be God’s man I have to do things God’s way. He’ll have it no other way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 02:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being spiritual about things 1 Samuel 14: Saul did something really foolish that day. It’s war. Saul&#8217;s army is in battle with the hated Philistines. Saul&#8217;s son Jonathan leads the way. Single handedly he&#8217;s killed about 20 of the enemy. God&#8217;s working here, bringing confusion to the enemy army. In addition to the damage Saul&#8217;s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sHuBqOk8r-w/Xd1p3yWDW8I/AAAAAAABC6c/t6731MXtYNoPbZEm5JgJ9jAo9ySAwgD7gCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3633.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Pinnacle Mtn State Park, AR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Being spiritual about things<br />
1 Samuel 14: Saul did something really foolish that day.<br />
It’s war. Saul&#8217;s army is in battle with the hated Philistines. Saul&#8217;s son Jonathan leads the way. Single handedly he&#8217;s killed about 20 of the enemy. God&#8217;s working here, bringing confusion to the enemy army. In addition to the damage Saul&#8217;s army is doing them they seem to be at war with one another. It’s now that Saul does a &#8220;really foolish&#8221; thing. He commands his army to fast while they fight. His men are in hand-to-hand combat all day but eat nothing. When the battle ends at the end of the day they’re so hungry that they’re eating raw meat, meat with the blood still in it, which is contrary to God&#8217;s Law. The writer tells us that it’s all Saul&#8217;s fault. He’s in charge and they depend on his leadership. He’s let them down by adding to their burden in an attempt to make their effort seem &#8220;more spiritual.&#8221; It’s important that leaders be spiritually sensitive. We’re not to dress things up to make them seem more spiritual than they already are, but at the same time, we’re to take the lead in recognizing God&#8217;s work in even supposed &#8220;non-spiritual&#8221; efforts. Saul overplays his hand here and the result is near disaster. I pray that God will help me to be sensitive to spiritual things and to be a leader who &#8220;is&#8221; spiritually minded rather than a person who is foolishly, like Saul, merely &#8220;acting&#8221; spiritually minded.<br />
Take Away: Spiritual leaders don’t play the role of someone who is spiritually minded; rather, they ARE spiritually minded.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 02:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thinking about leadership 1 Samuel 14: Wherever he turned, he came up with a victory. He became invincible! Saul is a terrific military leader: brave, capable, and resourceful. My first instinct upon reading Samuel&#8217;s pronouncement of God&#8217;s rejection of Saul as king is to think that everything’s going to fall apart for him. It simply [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-VAvBxawuzHU/Xd7Ey4p0IgI/AAAAAAABC6o/LVTOjwe918kaaSMicrSrgjLhUKjCkBYFACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_3639.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Pinnacle Mtn State Park, AR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Thinking about leadership<br />
1 Samuel 14: Wherever he turned, he came up with a victory. He became invincible!<br />
Saul is a terrific military leader: brave, capable, and resourceful. My first instinct upon reading Samuel&#8217;s pronouncement of God&#8217;s rejection of Saul as king is to think that everything’s going to fall apart for him. It simply doesn&#8217;t happen. Saul builds a great army, extends his rule by taking more territory, and keeps the hated Philistines on the defense. For decades he successfully leads Israel. Whether I like it or not, sometimes godless people are very capable people. For instance, all it takes is watching the innovative, yet profane commercials during a Super Bowl to see that some of the brightest, most outstanding people in advertising are those who have anything but Christian values. So, as I read his story, I see that at on at least the public level, Saul has it all together. It’s at the private level that things are, indeed, falling apart. Without doubt, living for the Lord is the best way to live. Still, being a follower of Jesus doesn&#8217;t make one smarter or more capable. That ought to at least humble me and make me more dependent on the Lord. It may also make me think twice when I’m picking a professional to help me with my business or getting ready to pull the lever to vote in an important election.<br />
Take Away: Some of the smartest, most capable people we know aren’t Christians – at least, not yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 02:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Future knowledge 1 Samuel 15: Then God spoke to Samuel: &#8220;I’m sorry I ever made Saul king. He&#8217;s turned his back on me. He refuses to do what I tell him.&#8221; God has given Saul explicit orders. He’s to attack Amalek and utterly destroy all life. Saul leads his army into the battle and follows [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vLf5-uPc5MI/XeBtXHVyJhI/AAAAAAABC7M/uzYFb6Ma_ccQbFSs3zsN9FvPpWDsR2-rwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4086.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Beeds Lake State Park &#8211; Hampton, IA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Future knowledge<br />
1 Samuel 15: Then God spoke to Samuel: &#8220;I’m sorry I ever made Saul king. He&#8217;s turned his back on me. He refuses to do what I tell him.&#8221;<br />
God has given Saul explicit orders. He’s to attack Amalek and utterly destroy all life. Saul leads his army into the battle and follows God&#8217;s command. Well, not quite. Agag, king of Amalek, is captured rather than killed. Also, some of the choice animals are brought back alive. Now, I’m troubled by all this killing and I’ve written about it before so I’m going to move on to another important feature of this passage. God says he’s &#8220;sorry&#8221; he made Saul king in the first place. Some say that this is just God speaking in human terms, that he isn&#8217;t &#8220;sorry&#8221; in the sense that he regrets having made Saul king. The reason that they believe this is because taking this statement at face value doesn&#8217;t fit their theology. They see time as somehow pre-existent and that God can see into the future. &#8220;God knows everything,&#8221; they say, &#8220;so he has to know the future.&#8221; I think that such logic contains a fatal error: that the future already exists as something to be known. If time is a &#8220;thing&#8221; then, no doubt, God knows all about it. But if time is simply a measure of the flow of events, and if human beings really have free will, then God doesn&#8217;t know the future. Before you drag me out to be stoned, let me add two things. First, God knows what he’s going to do. Throughout the Bible he says, &#8220;If you do this, I will do that &#8212; if you do that I will do this.&#8221; God knows, because he’s going to act, not because he’s looked into the future and seen what he’s going to do but, instead, because he’s God Almighty and if says he’s going to do something that thing is absolutely certain to happen. Second, God could know the exact future if he wanted to. I am not saying that he somehow &#8220;limits his vision.&#8221; Rather, that if God wanted to force events to flow in a specific way he has the power to do so. However, doing that in the lives of individuals would violate the free will he granted human beings. If you’re still with me, let me conclude by adding that God had every reason to believe Saul would be a terrific leader of Israel and to be disappointed when he isn’t. In fact, that’s what God believed would (or at least &#8220;could&#8221;) happen. Saul&#8217;s failure disappointed the Almighty but it didn&#8217;t ruin his plan. The Lord goes about replacing Saul with another king, giving Israel a second chance.<br />
Take Away: The Lord may not pre-ordain what I’m going to do, but he can handle whatever I do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 03:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Listening, obedience, relationship 1 Samuel 15: Do you think all God wants are sacrifices &#8212; empty rituals just for show? He wants you to listen to him! Saul’s a failure in the eyes of God. His large army and military victories don&#8217;t impress the Lord. Now Saul blames the soldiers; something that doesn’t wash with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Oeu5hZK05rw/XeHHllj1JsI/AAAAAAABC8Y/dofoJejhsf4O8OYra3lBSFtoqWanGROFgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/PHOTO_20150704_124846.jpg" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Beeds Lake State Park &#8211; Hampton, IA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Listening, obedience, relationship<br />
1 Samuel 15: Do you think all God wants are sacrifices &#8212; empty rituals just for show? He wants you to listen to him!<br />
Saul’s a failure in the eyes of God. His large army and military victories don&#8217;t impress the Lord. Now Saul blames the soldiers; something that doesn’t wash with the Almighty. Then, he says he’s going to sacrifice the animals in a worship service. Pitiful! Samuel has a word from the Lord for Saul. God isn&#8217;t interested in how many sacrifices Saul might make. Instead, he’s interested in obedience. Saul said &#8220;no&#8221; to God, now God&#8217;s saying &#8220;no&#8221; to him. Saul will continue in power for some time to come, but, in reality, his leadership has come to a whimpering end. Oswald Chambers says that the greatest hindrance to our relationship to the Lord is the service we do for him. &#8220;Look at all I&#8217;m doing for God” we declare, “Surely he can&#8217;t ask more of me than that.&#8221; He can and he does. Listening, obedience, and relationship: these things define God&#8217;s intentions for me. The Lord doesn’t put out a call for volunteer martyrs. He simply calls us to hear and obey. If that means sacrifice, fine. Otherwise, I listen to his voice and live my life in a relationship with him.<br />
Take Away: We’re called to a daily, genuine relationship with the Lord – that’s what satisfies both us and him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-28/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 03:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Would you like to super-size that order? No thanks. 1 Samuel 16: God judges persons differently than humans do&#8230;God looks into the heart. Saul&#8217;s failure weighs on Samuel. However, the Lord says it’s time to get on with selecting Saul&#8217;s successor. This is potentially dangerous because Saul&#8217;s still in power and certainly doesn&#8217;t want Samuel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-J4vxaYlnHVM/XeLpp01LCPI/AAAAAAABC8k/0bwJivlcZTM6mgd_Y2-Etok2EY0QJ--XwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4207.JPG" width="1600" height="901" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Castle Rock Campground &#8211; Friendship, WI</figcaption></figure>
<p>Would you like to super-size that order? No thanks.<br />
1 Samuel 16: God judges persons differently than humans do&#8230;God looks into the heart.<br />
Saul&#8217;s failure weighs on Samuel. However, the Lord says it’s time to get on with selecting Saul&#8217;s successor. This is potentially dangerous because Saul&#8217;s still in power and certainly doesn&#8217;t want Samuel anointing someone else as king. Still, Samuel obeys the Lord and heads out to the town of Bethlehem to find God&#8217;s choice for second king of Israel. There he finds the young man he’s sure is the right one. It’s Eliab, son of Jesse. Tall and good-looking, in fact, you might say &#8220;regal&#8221; in appearance. But Samuel is mistaken. God reminds him that this isn&#8217;t a beauty contest and that God’s more interested in what is in the heart than he is in outward appearance. Eliab might be a fine fellow but he isn&#8217;t to be the next king of Israel. The search continues as Jessie brings one son after another before the revered man of God. Finally, all but one son has been interviewed. Young David is all that’s left. When Saul was chosen we were told that he stood a head and shoulders above the other men. Now, as David is picked, he’s called the &#8220;runt&#8221; of the family. Thus we gain an insight into how God works. He uses big, nice looking people, but he also uses those that others tend to overlook. Why? It’s because God looks on the heart. I pray that the Lord will find in me a person he can use for his purposes.<br />
Take Away: Since the Lord looks on the heart, let’s do all we can to keep our hearts right with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
