<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Judges &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/book-of-judges/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 21:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Judges &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 19:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consequences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Almost, but not quite Judges 1: When Israel became stronger they put the Canaanites to forced labor, but they never got rid of them. The failure of the army of Israel to purge the land of the Canaanites is mentioned in the Book of Joshua but becomes a major factor as I turn the page [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-tLUUR4SaHZs/XZuVkKzdE6I/AAAAAAABB3I/kmSOEJLHob4R36c9XjoVC5zRRer-sbU1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3407.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Jerome, AZ</figcaption></figure><br />
Almost, but not quite<br />
Judges 1:  When Israel became stronger they put the Canaanites to forced labor, but they never got rid of them.<br />
The failure of the army of Israel to purge the land of the Canaanites is mentioned in the Book of Joshua but becomes a major factor as I turn the page and begin reading the Book of Judges.  Clearly, the army of Joshua has experienced unprecedented success.  They arrive as underdogs in a new land occupied by fierce and evil people who have superior weapons and fortified cities.  This is the home of the warrior-giants of the Bible.  In spite of all that these children of ex-slaves cross the Jordan and win victory after victory to become the dominant force in the land.  All in all, what they accomplish is quite impressive.  It’s just too bad that they don’t do what the Lord told them to do and press on to complete victory.  The book of Judges tells the story of the result of that failure.  This is far from being anyone’s favorite book of the Bible.  It is, though, a book in which the grace of God shines forth against the black background of so much spiritual failure.<br />
Take Away: “Trust and obey, for there’s no other way.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 19:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[testimony]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Generation to generation Judges 2: Eventually that entire generation died…another generation grew up that didn&#8217;t know anything of God…. This is a pitiful situation. How foolish! Here are parents who ate manna, had ever-wear shoes, crossed through the Jordan on dry ground, saw the walls of Jericho fall, and won an amazing dominance in Canaan. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/--ItLZSqJvgA/XZz-Wj2OZlI/AAAAAAABB3o/pHXE0KqLbjAYvlmWin-xviASR5aOFd_FACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3199.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Yosemite National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Generation to generation<br />
Judges 2: Eventually that entire generation died…another generation grew up that didn&#8217;t know anything of God….<br />
This is a pitiful situation.  How foolish!  Here are parents who ate manna, had ever-wear shoes, crossed through the Jordan on dry ground, saw the walls of Jericho fall, and won an amazing dominance in Canaan.  Somehow, those same parents failed to instill the knowledge of God in their children.  What’s wrong with these people?  Years earlier Moses warned them that it would be easy to enjoy their success and forget God.  Now, a generation has passed and the nightmare scenario he described has come true.  Apparently, it’s easier to fail to pass faith from one generation to the next than we might think.  My experience with God might be vivid to me but can mean almost nothing to my children.  I must assume nothing and take nothing for granted.  If those I love are to know God I must be resolutely intentional in instilling that knowledge in their lives.  God help us to reach our children.<br />
Take Away: How can I best pass my faith on to those who are dearest to me?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 20:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's people]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s your call Judges 2: That&#8217;s why God let those nations remain. The Book of Judges is the story of God&#8217;s patiently developing a people he can call his very own. There’s a cycle of failure, repentance, grace, and deliverance that’s repeated again and again. When they fail to completely drive out the people of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-n98YancyclM/XZ5GxWhwdgI/AAAAAAABB4Y/NEb9sgZqzBMgVsm5EOgbSzG8s9K6Fz3xgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3261.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Sightseeing in San Francisco, CA &#8211; Golden Gate Bridge</figcaption></figure><br />
It’s your call<br />
Judges 2: That&#8217;s why God let those nations remain.<br />
The Book of Judges is the story of God&#8217;s patiently developing a people he can call his very own.  There’s a cycle of failure, repentance, grace, and deliverance that’s repeated again and again.  When they fail to completely drive out the people of the land the Lord leaves that pagan culture there and uses it to develop the Israelites into the people he wants them to be.  The remaining Canaanites become the &#8220;alternative choice&#8221; for the Israelites.  I see a parallel in my own culture.  I believe the Lord intends that the Church be the dominant force in society.  Sadly, in many cases it fails.  The result is that there’s a thriving alternative secular culture in the land.  This culture has no place for God (or at least wants God to mind his own business).  Every day God’s people are exposed to the values of this self-oriented, market-driven, materialistic society.  As it was for the Israelites of the Book of Judges the people of God must decide “who I will serve.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: No doubt the popular culture is, well, popular – sometimes God’s people have to journey the less traveled road.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 20:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(Don’t) Make yourself at home Judges 3: But the People of Israel made themselves at home among the Canaanites. It’s their first test and they fail it. They’ve failed to remove the pagan people from the land and now their test is to live near them but not become one of them. They miserably fail. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1407px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Aw-lq8onGIY/XZ_IH0mAaSI/AAAAAAABB7E/hbE27AwBWLQ-9l9Sq4HEhgR2SuaZCoeFQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_2939.JPG" width="1407" height="880" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pinnacles National Park, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
(Don’t) Make yourself at home<br />
Judges 3: But the People of Israel made themselves at home among the Canaanites.<br />
It’s their first test and they fail it.  They’ve failed to remove the pagan people from the land and now their test is to live near them but not become one of them.  They miserably fail.  Before long their young people are getting married to Canaanites and the perverted worship practices of those people is being accepted by them.  Simply put, they feel right at home with these heathen.  In his anger, God turns his back on them and soon everything falls apart.  How at home am I in my society?  Jesus loved sinners.  He ate with them and genuinely liked them.  But he never became one of them. On one hand there’s the example of the Israelites who feel so at home with the Canaanites that they adopt their ways.  On the other hand we have Jesus who loves people and fellowships with them, but in doing so, invites them to be the ones who are changed.  God help me to love the lost without making myself &#8220;at home&#8221; with them in the manner of these Israelites.<br />
Take Away: Is the Church changing the culture or is the culture changing the Church?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 20:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Woman power Judges 4: God will use a woman&#8217;s hand to take care of Sisera. It comes as a surprise that we must journey into what might be called the &#8220;dark ages&#8221; of Israel before we find a genuine woman hero in the Bible. I guess it could be argued that Moses&#8217; sister Miriam qualifies, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WBCcGI4mjjY/XaDSIbEGROI/AAAAAAABB7o/TPXaixXhiQQwki5rlCBFeB4jyW21GFbbACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3320.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterrey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Woman power<br />
Judges 4: God will use a woman&#8217;s hand to take care of Sisera.<br />
It comes as a surprise that we must journey into what might be called the &#8220;dark ages&#8221; of Israel before we find a genuine woman hero in the Bible.  I guess it could be argued that Moses&#8217; sister Miriam qualifies, and maybe she does, but Deborah really shines here.  Sisera is the commander of an occupying army that&#8217;s dominating the Israelites and Deborah is their recognized leader.  She calls for Barak, another well-known Israelite, and tells him that it has become clear to her that God’s going to deliver them from Sisera and his army.  Barak, though, is afraid to proceed without Deborah at his side.  Deborah replies that because of his fear, God will use a woman&#8217;s hand to take care of Sisera, and she, not him, will get the credit.  It all plays out as she said and, not only does Deborah go down in history as the one who leads the way to freedom a woman named Jael finishes Sisera off.  Long before the promise of &#8220;daughters prophesying&#8221; is fulfilled in Acts 2, we find God using women as leaders in his work.  Thank God for women who are willing to be used of God to accomplish his purposes.<br />
Take Away: The Lord uses willing people, and there’s to gender qualification in it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 20:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Generation to generation Judges 5: God chose new leaders, who then fought at the gates. Following the defeat of the oppressor Sisera we hear a duet being sung by Deborah and Barak, the two people instrumental in the victory that has been won. It’s a war song, all about how God fought for them and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IHn-x7PRXPw/XaM42rQciMI/AAAAAAABB_g/Rj9dJBTNvzc2cQMODT_Ie5pMm0oNEI-DwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3321.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterrey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Generation to generation<br />
Judges 5: God chose new leaders, who then fought at the gates.<br />
Following the defeat of the oppressor Sisera we hear a duet being sung by Deborah and Barak, the two people instrumental in the victory that has been won.  It’s a war song, all about how God fought for them and how he empowered them to do what needed to be done.  The book of Judges gives us history in 40 year or so chunks, so, while I earlier walked with Abraham year by year and traveled with the children of Israel in their wilderness journey at a much slower pace, each page of the book of Judges represents the rise and fall of an entire generation.  In this song, I find a description of how “God chose new leaders” to fight for him in their generation.  While there’s a lot of ugly stuff in this book of the Bible, I’m reminded that God continues to be active in Israel.  Even though it’s sometimes hard to spot, I see the golden thread of God’s grace here.  A set of leaders fail and Israel plunges into the darkness of sin.  Then, the Lord graciously reaches down into that darkness and lifts a new leader to call his people back from the brink.  This is far from ideal.  It could and should be so much better.  Still, the grace and faithfulness of God shines like a beacon against this bleak backdrop of sin and failure.<br />
Take Away: God’s grace is seen in dark places.  It fact, it shines there, bringing both light and hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 20:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Asking God hard questions Judges: 6: If God is with us, why has all this happened to us? The startling honesty of Gideon arrests my attention today. Even as he has an extraordinary encounter with the Lord he’s brutally honest about how things are going. Of course, the answer to his question has already been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Si8DuTpv_7Q/XaM5ZF5iU_I/AAAAAAABB_s/0Ln011ltibEDPoBMO0DcgTLyc0fVXTa0QCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3328.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterrey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Asking God hard questions<br />
Judges: 6: If God is with us, why has all this happened to us?<br />
The startling honesty of Gideon arrests my attention today.  Even as he has an extraordinary encounter with the Lord he’s brutally honest about how things are going.  Of course, the answer to his question has already been given.  God didn&#8217;t leave the people.  Rather, they left him: they &#8220;went back to doing evil.&#8221;  God isn&#8217;t going to stay where he’s unwelcome.  The Lord departs and they’re quickly dominated by Midian.  Still, God doesn&#8217;t forget them.  When the time is right, the Lord appears to Gideon and calls this unlikely person a &#8220;mighty warrior.&#8221;  More on Gideon&#8217;s leadership later on, but, again, my attention is drawn to his honesty before God.  If God is so good, if he&#8217;s on our side, if he’s our deliverer then why are things so bad?   There’s power in asking hard questions to God.  In this case Gideon need only look to the pagan practices he and his fellow Israelites have incorporated into their lives for his answer.  God&#8217;s grace is clearly evidenced by, first, the fact that they haven&#8217;t been wiped off the face of the earth, and second, the fact that God is right there carrying on a conversation with him.  The truth is, though, that God isn&#8217;t offended by our asking hard questions.  We aren&#8217;t to take up permanent residence in that house of questions but we almost have to pass through that neighborhood to ever arrive at a meaningful faith.<br />
Take Away: It is okay to ask the Lord hard, honest questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 20:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Putting out a fleece Judges 6: Let me say one more thing. I want to try another time with the fleece. Here we are reading about Gideon and his fleece of wool. Actually, Gideon asks for, and receives, three signs from God. First, the angel of the Lord causes a fire to miraculously appear and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FksG9wPM4nw/XaT4ZH8Ew3I/AAAAAAABCD0/OAZ1TSChxWsV4EMFupKS9OAjPIAPGDt6ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/PHOTO_20140919_142110.jpg" width="1600" height="902" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterrey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Putting out a fleece<br />
Judges 6: Let me say one more thing. I want to try another time with the fleece.<br />
Here we are reading about Gideon and his fleece of wool. Actually, Gideon asks for, and receives, three signs from God. First, the angel of the Lord causes a fire to miraculously appear and consume his offering. Second, his fleece of wool gets wet from the dew while everything else stays dry. Third, the situation is reversed and the fleece stays dry while everything else gets wet from the dew. This is interesting reading, but it isn&#8217;t a lesson in how we’re supposed to deal with God. We’re to be people of faith, trusting in the Lord and learning to hear his voice. We’re not supposed to be sign-seekers and deal-makers. The star of this story isn’t Gideon, a near heathen who keeps getting signs from God confirming what he’s clearly already been told. The Star is God, who is patient even when Gideon keeps asking him to prove his own words. I’m thankful for a patient God who puts up with my shallowness even as he works to produce in me a more mature relationship with himself. Generally speaking though, I need to just do whatever it is God has made clear to me without &#8220;putting out a fleece.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Don’t press God’s patience – just obey in the first place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 20:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God smiling Judges 7: You have too large an army with you. The Lord has such a sense of humor. Gideon’s been rounding up the troops to take on the mighty Midian army and he’s done a pretty good job of it. Now they’re on their way into battle, but first, God has some trimming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-W_dPOMlgRbQ/XaeaLbYydBI/AAAAAAABCHs/yb7UrW89560FDGwwo-2vGJuKCEwEPeY1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259744.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God smiling<br />
Judges 7: You have too large an army with you.<br />
The Lord has such a sense of humor. Gideon’s been rounding up the troops to take on the mighty Midian army and he’s done a pretty good job of it. Now they’re on their way into battle, but first, God has some trimming to do. First, those who are afraid are invited to leave. Two thirds of the army decides this is a good time to go home. Then, as they get a drink of water, the few who show &#8220;battle sense&#8221; are kept while everyone else goes home. Gideon was reluctant enough to take on this fight. He must be beside himself as the Lord keeps whittling down his army. He’s now left with just 300 fighters. Of course, God has a purpose in all this. Even as we see the Lord’s disqualification of almost all of Gideon&#8217;s army, we see that the Lord is quite intentional here. If Gideon&#8217;s large force wins a victory they’ll take all the credit for it. The Lord wants not only to bring deliverance to Israel, but to restore them to himself as well. I believe proper preparation for things I attempt is wise and reasonable, but I also know that the ultimate Source in my life is, not my plans and resources, but my Lord. Sometimes, he has to whittle down my approach so, when it all works out, I’ll know who it is that gets the credit. And, as he does it, I think he&#8217;s smiling to himself.<br />
Take Away: The Lord loves turning the tables and doing the impossible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 21:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The battle that never was Judges 7: I had this dream: A loaf of barley bread tumbled into the Midianite camp. In preparation for the coming battle the Lord sends Gideon to the outskirts of the camp of the mighty Midian army. As he cautiously scouts the camp he overhears a conversation between two soldiers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rJycMQlJy8Q/Xaea6vNDybI/AAAAAAABCH0/NQC7Fs5WmAQfCxjRywBtlQXVHbRAMyKZwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259745.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The battle that never was<br />
Judges 7: I had this dream: A loaf of barley bread tumbled into the Midianite camp.<br />
In preparation for the coming battle the Lord sends Gideon to the outskirts of the camp of the mighty Midian army. As he cautiously scouts the camp he overhears a conversation between two soldiers. One is telling the other about a dream he&#8217;s had that has nearly scared him to death. In his dream he saw a tent that represented the Midian army. Then, of all things, he saw a giant loaf of barley bread, representing Gideon and the Israelites, tumbling down the hill into the camp and knocking down the tent of Midian. The soldier has concluded that this is a message from his gods that Gideon’s army is going to roll over Midian. Overhearing all this is greatly encouraging to Gideon who concludes that God is preparing the way for his tiny force to defeat this mighty army. That night, when Gideon’s 300 sound the trumpets, light their torches, and break the jars what the skittish Midian army hears and sees causes mass confusion and they begin fighting one another and running for their lives. In no time at all the battle that never was is over. I think stories like this are important to God’s people. We need to tell them to our children and in telling them, instill in our boys and girls a deep faith in a God who takes care of his people in sometimes delightful, unusual ways. As we tell and retell stories like this, we, ourselves, are reminded of God’s power over those things that overwhelm us and his faithfulness to us in all the circumstances of life. Maybe that’s a message you need today.<br />
Take Away: The Lord delights in doing good things for his people and he especially seems to enjoy doing those good things in unexpected ways.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
