<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bravery &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/bravery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:07:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>bravery &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 07:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Song for a funeral 2 Samuel 1: “You asked for it,” David told him. There’s no passage of time between the end of 1 Samuel and the beginning of 2 Samuel. We simply turn the page and keep on reading. David returns to Ziklag after rescuing those who were taken captive and is, I guess, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WLlzK8dS8w0/XgE_ekBMp1I/AAAAAAABDEc/SKZhioqywTwygT-sze_YLyKa9Rqzr1pBgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129883.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Song for a funeral<br />
2 Samuel 1: “You asked for it,” David told him.<br />
There’s no passage of time between the end of 1 Samuel and the beginning of 2 Samuel. We simply turn the page and keep on reading. David returns to Ziklag after rescuing those who were taken captive and is, I guess, rebuilding the destroyed town. An Amalekite shows up in camp with what he thinks will be received as good news. Saul and Jonathan are dead. In fact, he claims (apparently a lie) that he personally finished Saul off. This fellow was probably robbing the dead on the battle field and came upon Saul’s body. He thinks that having David indebted to him will be worth more than the royal headband and bracelet he took off of Saul’s body. Clearly this guy doesn&#8217;t know David. After all, David has more reason to kill Saul than anyone, yet he has twice passed up the opportunity to do so. The bearer of bad news goes out to meet his Maker soon thereafter. David composes a song of lament over the death of Saul and Jonathan. He could have sung of disappointing failure and lost opportunities. Instead, he remembers the bravery of these two men and the security and prosperity they brought to Israel. As the Amalekite learned the hard way, cheering the death of even a deeply flawed individual isn’t David’s way. It’s not God’s way either.<br />
Take Away: As the Lord is gracious and merciful to us, so should we be to all, even those who don’t measure up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 07:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King Saul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uncommon valor 2 Samuel 2: God bless you for this &#8212; for honoring your master, Saul, with a funeral. David mourns the passing of Saul and his good friend Jonathan and prepares to end his self-chosen exile from Israel by moving to Hebron in Judah. He also hears of the bravery and sacrifice of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-c-LJ09kPUNw/XgJ_0OnVUpI/AAAAAAABDEw/oCEu-HhUDqsiL5oN4AXh9NLqPylIdwf2ACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129884.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Uncommon valor<br />
2 Samuel 2: God bless you for this &#8212; for honoring your master, Saul, with a funeral.<br />
David mourns the passing of Saul and his good friend Jonathan and prepares to end his self-chosen exile from Israel by moving to Hebron in Judah. He also hears of the bravery and sacrifice of the men of Jabesh Gilead who took their lives in their hands to retrieve the bodies of Saul and his sons from where they were on display in Philistine territory. They brought the bodies back to Israel for a decent funeral. On one hand we have the story of the man who claimed to have finished Saul off, now we have the story of these valiant men who went into enemy territory following a devastating defeat to show proper respect for their dead king. David knows valor when he sees it and honors those men for what they did. Times of crisis define us. We may be able to put on an act that convinces about everyone, but when the pressure is on the real person is seen, for good or for bad.<br />
Take Away: Challenging times have the potential to bring out the best in each of us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-samuel-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 11:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living water]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Water from the well 2 Samuel 23: There is no way, God, that I&#8217;ll drink this. As David&#8217;s life is being summed up, we find a listing of significant warriors who served him. Three warriors are especially outstanding: Josheb-Basshebeth, Elazar, and Shammah. These three men were the most fearsome of all the fighters in Israel. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oZxO4St8vc0/Xid4ka7r7jI/AAAAAAABDn4/S30OaHaU7yIUL85Rumq7WUexxUCKj6aUwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P8129988.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 -Pictured Rocks Cruise &#8211;  Munising, MI</figcaption></figure><br />
Water from the well<br />
2 Samuel 23: There is no way, God, that I&#8217;ll drink this.<br />
As David&#8217;s life is being summed up, we find a listing of significant warriors who served him. Three warriors are especially outstanding: Josheb-Basshebeth, Elazar, and Shammah. These three men were the most fearsome of all the fighters in Israel. As an example of their ability and faithfulness to David, we hear one of their stories. David and his men are holed up in a cave while the Philistines occupy nearby Bethlehem. David remarks that a drink of water from the well there would taste very good to him. The Three decide to get him that drink. They fight their way through enemy lines to that particular well, draw water out of it, and then fight their way back out of the town. The Philistine soldiers must have been very confused by all this! When the three return to camp, they offer David water from the well. At this point, the focus turns from the Three to David. He pours the water out as an offering to God, remarking that the water in that container is like the blood of these brave men. To drink it would be to take their lives too lightly. I’m thankful today for the bravery of another Warrior. His life started in that very town, but, when the time was right he fought his way to the very gates of Hell to provide me living water. The blood of that brave Warrior is precious to me too.<br />
Take Away: Life is mine by the precious blood of Jesus.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-chronicles-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bravery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Water from the well 1 Chronicles 11: He refused to drink it. Included in the genealogy of the Chronicles are the names and sample exploits of great warriors who serve under David. &#8220;The Thirty,&#8221; is a band of brave and capable fighters. This group has an awesome leader and some especially outstanding men called the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-fyyTloP8keM/Xpxsk3snOZI/AAAAAAABExA/SOCr0DEjsy8jmv83fDNabbNfLxxgrdU6gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/20170905_175843.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Custer State Park, SD</figcaption></figure><br />
Water from the well<br />
1 Chronicles 11: He refused to drink it.<br />
Included in the genealogy of the Chronicles are the names and sample exploits of great warriors who serve under David.  &#8220;The Thirty,&#8221; is a band of brave and capable fighters.  This group has an awesome leader and some especially outstanding men called the &#8220;Big Three.&#8221;  At one point David, who’s on the run from Saul, comments that he’d love a drink of water from the well at Bethlehem.  However, Bethlehem’s under Philistine rule at the time.  That detail doesn&#8217;t stop the &#8220;Big Three&#8221; from fighting their way into Bethlehem, drawing water from the well there, and then withdrawing to bring it to David.  David’s overwhelmed by this gift and refuses to drink it.  To him, this is a gift too precious to be received as a common thing so instead of drinking the water he pours it out as an offering to God.   I&#8217;ve never had anyone go to battle to bring me a drink of water but I’ve had some people do some wonderful things for me.  When that happens I don&#8217;t want to treat their sacrifice as a common thing.  Some gifts that are intended for me are so valuable that I know they’re too good for me.  When that happens, I can take the example of David, and make it an offering to the Lord.<br />
Take Away: Kindnesses done to us ought to be appreciated.  They should also humble us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
