<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Noah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/noah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 09:35:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Noah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 09:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One man Genesis 6: God was sorry that he had made the human race in the first place; it broke his heart. Human beings have been removed from the Garden but they take their sin with them. Immediately, grace begins to flow, an unending river of good will toward these broken creatures. Sadly, the response [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/sJSNqAWQ6ZZAWDkv0OjV6TvuLOP5YyAGihUfGJEjBOUnFBiYhhLE20gEmcqb2o66WG6r48q9ckGb0U9_EDZSoSp2-W1uGDUr8MUyUIDCi1T2AkuwIH9NBlEAuyQcTXgxfNYQrPeVyf4=w2400" width="2048" height="1536" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Niagara Falls</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="color: #444444;">One man</span></p>
<p>Genesis 6: God was sorry that he had made the human race in the first place; it broke his heart.<br />
Human beings have been removed from the Garden but they take their sin with them. Immediately, grace begins to flow, an unending river of good will toward these broken creatures. Sadly, the response is to reject the grace and push the Grace-Giver away. The crowning achievement of all God made has degenerated into a self-absorbed, God-ignoring shadow of what might have been. This “free-will” business isn’t working out and like radical surgery is sometimes needed to battle cancer, the Lord makes the painful decision to prune away all the foulness so that humanity will get another chance. For centuries the number of people who chose to respond to God’s grace has dwindled. Now, one righteousness man is left. If humanity is to be saved, it&#8217;ll be through him. The focus of the universe is on righteous Noah. We won’t see everything depending on just one man again until the Lord unleashes the eternal solution to the fallen condition of humanity. That will involve a willingness, not to build an ark, but to go to a cross.<br />
Take away: The story of Noah is more about humanity getting a second chance than it is about judgment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 09:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; Fighting the right battle Genesis 6: Noah did everything God commanded him to do. We Christians sometimes rush out to fight the wrong battles. When I read the story of Noah and the flood I’m not supposed to come away with a scientific understanding of how the flood happened. I’m not supposed to whip [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HS-RwUkKsfsP9toR0ibtgtLYm5ySzivjCp-ZqiBkoiocBbDfqgXWczxXlutR6E_n9YHE1-5RNQdCw51rAjMlE6ITrQNJHm1VpY7N9NwskVZm9oUGcO_o5RMdGPtkGGny9Bjiie0hrio=w2400" width="2048" height="1155" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Tompkins Campground &#8211; ACoE &#8211; Lawrenceville, PA</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="color: #444444;">Fighting the right battle</span></p>
<p>Genesis 6: Noah did everything God commanded him to do.<br />
We Christians sometimes rush out to fight the wrong battles. When I read the story of Noah and the flood I’m not supposed to come away with a scientific understanding of how the flood happened. I’m not supposed to whip out my calculator and try to figure out how many animals and provisions the ark would carry or study geology to prove there was really such a flood. Instead, I’m to see that God has a plan to redeem humanity and that he&#8217;ll go to whatever extreme is necessary to get that done. I’m also to appreciate Noah’s obedience in spite of the seeming unreasonableness of his task and his being alone in accomplishing it. Now, that isn’t to say this event is to be filed under the heading of “parable.” Just the details of the construction of the ark and the clear references to locale mark this as a historical event. The take away, though, isn’t my charging off to prove the story is true or sharpening my debate skills so I can conquer the “unbelievers” with stories of gopher wood on Mount Ararat. Instead, I’m to see God at work, redeeming humanity. I’m to be impressed at what the Lord can do with just one obedient person and be challenged to obedience in areas of my life that are beyond my understanding. Rather than fighting battles on the scientific front, a wiser use of my energy is to deal with the eternal spiritual issues of this event.<br />
Take away: It’s easy to get caught up in battles and miss the main points.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 09:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s promise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/2011/09/21/devotional-on-genesis-13/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s promise Genesis 8: I&#8217;ll never again kill off everything living as I&#8217;ve just done. The flood abates and Noah, his family, and the animals depart the ark. Life on earth gets a fresh start. God’s promise that this will never be repeated is intended to be a source of comfort to us when disasters [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-lqjLKGHd_iI/XLo8ddRp7yI/AAAAAAAA6qI/4XcRcRMc2twzpX2m5bhiyU6cujU4oOnbgCKgBGAs/s1600/2013-08-24%2B19.07.34.jpg" width="1600" height="902" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Chesapeake Bay Thousand Trails &#8211; GLoucester, VA</figcaption></figure>
<p>God’s promise<br />
Genesis 8: I&#8217;ll never again kill off everything living as I&#8217;ve just done.<br />
The flood abates and Noah, his family, and the animals depart the ark. Life on earth gets a fresh start. God’s promise that this will never be repeated is intended to be a source of comfort to us when disasters come our way. God caused the flood with the express purpose of purging the earth. The deaths are his doing, according to his plan. Now, the Giver of Life certainly has the authority to be the Taker of Life, so I have no argument at this point. However, the Almighty knows that unless he assures us otherwise every major disaster will cause people to fearfully look to heaven, wondering if this is the beginning of another purge. After all, it’s not as though we don’t deserve whatever God sends our way. In mercy the Lord promises that the Flood is a once-in-history event that will never be repeated. Because of this promise, we understand that other big disasters are simply the result of living in a world where bad things sometimes happen. The Lord doesn’t want human beings fearing that this is “another end of the world” in the face of every hurricane or volcano eruption or earthquake. Instead, he wants us to live in fellowship with him, trusting him to be with us even in the disasters of life.<br />
Take away: Don’t treat every unwelcome event with a fresh round of self-doubt.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
