<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Gideon &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/gideon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 21:13:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Gideon &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 20:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Asking God hard questions Judges: 6: If God is with us, why has all this happened to us? The startling honesty of Gideon arrests my attention today. Even as he has an extraordinary encounter with the Lord he’s brutally honest about how things are going. Of course, the answer to his question has already been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Si8DuTpv_7Q/XaM5ZF5iU_I/AAAAAAABB_s/0Ln011ltibEDPoBMO0DcgTLyc0fVXTa0QCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_3328.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Monterrey Peninsula, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Asking God hard questions<br />
Judges: 6: If God is with us, why has all this happened to us?<br />
The startling honesty of Gideon arrests my attention today.  Even as he has an extraordinary encounter with the Lord he’s brutally honest about how things are going.  Of course, the answer to his question has already been given.  God didn&#8217;t leave the people.  Rather, they left him: they &#8220;went back to doing evil.&#8221;  God isn&#8217;t going to stay where he’s unwelcome.  The Lord departs and they’re quickly dominated by Midian.  Still, God doesn&#8217;t forget them.  When the time is right, the Lord appears to Gideon and calls this unlikely person a &#8220;mighty warrior.&#8221;  More on Gideon&#8217;s leadership later on, but, again, my attention is drawn to his honesty before God.  If God is so good, if he&#8217;s on our side, if he’s our deliverer then why are things so bad?   There’s power in asking hard questions to God.  In this case Gideon need only look to the pagan practices he and his fellow Israelites have incorporated into their lives for his answer.  God&#8217;s grace is clearly evidenced by, first, the fact that they haven&#8217;t been wiped off the face of the earth, and second, the fact that God is right there carrying on a conversation with him.  The truth is, though, that God isn&#8217;t offended by our asking hard questions.  We aren&#8217;t to take up permanent residence in that house of questions but we almost have to pass through that neighborhood to ever arrive at a meaningful faith.<br />
Take Away: It is okay to ask the Lord hard, honest questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 20:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deliverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God smiling Judges 7: You have too large an army with you. The Lord has such a sense of humor. Gideon’s been rounding up the troops to take on the mighty Midian army and he’s done a pretty good job of it. Now they’re on their way into battle, but first, God has some trimming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-W_dPOMlgRbQ/XaeaLbYydBI/AAAAAAABCHs/yb7UrW89560FDGwwo-2vGJuKCEwEPeY1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259744.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>God smiling<br />
Judges 7: You have too large an army with you.<br />
The Lord has such a sense of humor. Gideon’s been rounding up the troops to take on the mighty Midian army and he’s done a pretty good job of it. Now they’re on their way into battle, but first, God has some trimming to do. First, those who are afraid are invited to leave. Two thirds of the army decides this is a good time to go home. Then, as they get a drink of water, the few who show &#8220;battle sense&#8221; are kept while everyone else goes home. Gideon was reluctant enough to take on this fight. He must be beside himself as the Lord keeps whittling down his army. He’s now left with just 300 fighters. Of course, God has a purpose in all this. Even as we see the Lord’s disqualification of almost all of Gideon&#8217;s army, we see that the Lord is quite intentional here. If Gideon&#8217;s large force wins a victory they’ll take all the credit for it. The Lord wants not only to bring deliverance to Israel, but to restore them to himself as well. I believe proper preparation for things I attempt is wise and reasonable, but I also know that the ultimate Source in my life is, not my plans and resources, but my Lord. Sometimes, he has to whittle down my approach so, when it all works out, I’ll know who it is that gets the credit. And, as he does it, I think he&#8217;s smiling to himself.<br />
Take Away: The Lord loves turning the tables and doing the impossible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 21:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The battle that never was Judges 7: I had this dream: A loaf of barley bread tumbled into the Midianite camp. In preparation for the coming battle the Lord sends Gideon to the outskirts of the camp of the mighty Midian army. As he cautiously scouts the camp he overhears a conversation between two soldiers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rJycMQlJy8Q/Xaea6vNDybI/AAAAAAABCH0/NQC7Fs5WmAQfCxjRywBtlQXVHbRAMyKZwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259745.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The battle that never was<br />
Judges 7: I had this dream: A loaf of barley bread tumbled into the Midianite camp.<br />
In preparation for the coming battle the Lord sends Gideon to the outskirts of the camp of the mighty Midian army. As he cautiously scouts the camp he overhears a conversation between two soldiers. One is telling the other about a dream he&#8217;s had that has nearly scared him to death. In his dream he saw a tent that represented the Midian army. Then, of all things, he saw a giant loaf of barley bread, representing Gideon and the Israelites, tumbling down the hill into the camp and knocking down the tent of Midian. The soldier has concluded that this is a message from his gods that Gideon’s army is going to roll over Midian. Overhearing all this is greatly encouraging to Gideon who concludes that God is preparing the way for his tiny force to defeat this mighty army. That night, when Gideon’s 300 sound the trumpets, light their torches, and break the jars what the skittish Midian army hears and sees causes mass confusion and they begin fighting one another and running for their lives. In no time at all the battle that never was is over. I think stories like this are important to God’s people. We need to tell them to our children and in telling them, instill in our boys and girls a deep faith in a God who takes care of his people in sometimes delightful, unusual ways. As we tell and retell stories like this, we, ourselves, are reminded of God’s power over those things that overwhelm us and his faithfulness to us in all the circumstances of life. Maybe that’s a message you need today.<br />
Take Away: The Lord delights in doing good things for his people and he especially seems to enjoy doing those good things in unexpected ways.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-judges-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 21:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Judges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gideon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Golden Ephod Judges 8: Gideon made the gold into a sacred ephod and put it on display in his hometown. Gideon and his army have won a great series of victories and now he returns home to a hero’s welcome. When the people want to honor him he asks for some of the gold [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1V1nFp-X7L4/Xai9P5hZqpI/AAAAAAABCJE/rPIUqhP6S5866v5iupUNE33f4MMf_mkEQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/P9259748.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Golden Ephod<br />
Judges 8: Gideon made the gold into a sacred ephod and put it on display in his hometown.<br />
Gideon and his army have won a great series of victories and now he returns home to a hero’s welcome. When the people want to honor him he asks for some of the gold earrings that were taken from the slain enemy. One has to read between the lines a bit but it seems Gideon’s intentions are good. He takes that gold and uses it in making a priestly garment called an “ephod.” In the history of the Israelites the ephod was worn by the high priest. It appears that this ephod isn’t intended to be worn; after all, it weighs around 100 pounds. Instead, it’s put on display as a reminder of all the Lord has done for them through Gideon. If this understanding is accurate this fancy “reminder” isn’t all that bad. However, it isn’t long before this object of remembrance becomes an object of worship. In fact, Gideon, himself, leads the way in bowing down before the Golden Ephod. How easy it is for us to elevate things to supreme importance while overlooking that which really matters. We church people debate music styles or building plans and worry about who will clean up after the potluck dinner (none of which are bad in themselves) while forgetting why we came to church in the first place. All the while, God is calling out to us, “Here I am, over here.” We miss his call for attention because we’re busy buffing our Golden Ephod.<br />
Take Away: Ultimately, it’s all about the Lord and our relationship with him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
