<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>diet &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/diet/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 23:56:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>diet &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-23/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commitment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winning in little ways first Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food. The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation. There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lJE1XjaSU48/YLQVqR4_jqI/AAAAAAABKVk/CYDNktkWgasEd-apehJEqrnPTJjj-OCJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B%2B9-29-2011%2B12-19-09%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Hyde Park &#8211; the Serpentine &#8211; London, UK</figcaption></figure><br />
Winning in little ways first<br />
Daniel 1: Daniel determined that he would not defile himself by eating the king&#8217;s food.<br />
The hardest time for me to stay on a diet is when I&#8217;m on vacation.  There are so many nice places to eat, we&#8217;re out of our routine, and there&#8217;s the strange notion that &#8220;what happens on vacation stays on vacation.&#8221;  One &#8220;off diet&#8221; meal leads to another and I end up bringing home, not just pleasant memories and photos of all the places we saw, but a few extra pounds too.  Of course, Daniel and his companions aren&#8217;t on vacation.  They&#8217;ve been taken against their will to a distant land with little hope of returning home.  Even if they could go back, things are very different than when they left.  Still, they&#8217;re in very pleasant surroundings.  They&#8217;re part of the household of the most powerful king on earth and they&#8217;re being groomed to serve in the royal court.  Their rations aren’t bread and water but, instead, are the richest of foods and the finest of wines.  The thing is that their religion has strict dietary rules.  That pork chop might look quite tasty, but it&#8217;s forbidden to them by their God.  If we struggle with our diets just because we’re a few hundred miles from home, think of their struggle.  The Temple, Jerusalem, and their family ties are all in their past.  Do the rules even apply anymore?  If they do just go along with what is being asked of them where will it take them next?  Does saying &#8220;yes&#8221; here mean they&#8217;ll be expected to say &#8220;yes&#8221; somewhere else, like, for instance, the worship of an idol?  Daniel decides to draw the line right where he is.  He&#8217;s a follower of God and God has given him some dietary rules.  He&#8217;ll be respectful, but he&#8217;ll hold steady at this minor point.  If he never starts down the path away from God he&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.  I don&#8217;t know if this passage will help me stay on my diet or not, but it certainly can help me remember that spiritual failure doesn&#8217;t start with my rejecting God in some big way.  Rather, it starts with little things.  If I win there, I&#8217;m much more likely to conquer the &#8220;biggie&#8221; when it shows up.<br />
Take Away: If we never start down the path away from God we&#8217;ll never end up where that path leads.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Malachi</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-malachi-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Malachi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steadiness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The challenge of living in the level ground days Malachi 1: Worship of God is no longer a priority. Anyone who’s gone through significant weight loss will tell you that the hard part of a diet isn&#8217;t the “cut-back-on-the-calories” weight loss phase. Instead, it’s the maintenance phase. At that time, the individual moves from trying [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15596" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15596" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15596" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/100_2595.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15596" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along the road to Moab, UT</figcaption></figure><br />
The challenge of living in the level ground days<br />
Malachi 1: Worship of God is no longer a priority.<br />
Anyone who’s gone through significant weight loss will tell you that the hard part of a diet isn&#8217;t the “cut-back-on-the-calories” weight loss phase.  Instead, it’s the maintenance phase.  At that time, the individual moves from trying to lose weight to living a healthy lifestyle that doesn’t result in regaining the weight that was lost.  The problem is that there are constant temptations to give in a little here and a little there.  Once one starts down that road the end result is a return to the former state of things.  The people Malachi speaks to are at a cross roads.  They’re secure and comfortable.  The work of rebuilding the Temple was finished by their parents and grandparents.  Now, it falls on them to live a spiritually healthy lifestyle as an every day people of God.  Frankly, they aren’t doing a very good job of it.  When they bring an animal to offer to the Lord, they&#8217;ve fallen into the habit of bringing one that they don’t want anyway.  Worship, in general, is drifting to a lower and lower priority in their lives.  They aren’t back at the stage of their idol-worshiping, baby-sacrificing ancestors, but, without even recognizing it, they’re gradually drifting away from God.  It doesn’t take a big effort to connect the dots from this to my own life.  I don’t hope a crisis will come to my life to remind me of my priorities, but, here on the level ground of life, I want to live a healthy, day-to-day spiritual lifestyle.<br />
Take Away: Living for the Lord on the common days of life has challenges of its own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
