<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sacrifice &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/sacrifice/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:35:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>sacrifice &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Return on investment Ecclesiastes 11: Be generous: Invest in acts of charity. Charity yields high returns. The Lord is wonderfully generous to us. He’s given us the world and all its beauty and life itself. His greatest gift to us is salvation. This gift cost him everything as is seen at the cross. This is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TWUm43NL6v0/X6RoskaJ8pI/AAAAAAABHfc/ju3WLSkLKPMtZXDgJDML7FihZfPWjak9QCPcBGAsYHg/s400/16rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Return on investment<br />
Ecclesiastes 11: Be generous: Invest in acts of charity.  Charity yields high returns.<br />
The Lord is wonderfully generous to us.  He’s given us the world and all its beauty and life itself.  His greatest gift to us is salvation.  This gift cost him everything as is seen at the cross.  This is God&#8217;s investment in us and his charity toward us.  Solomon says &#8220;charity yields high returns.&#8221;  God gave everything and he has every right to expect big returns on his investment.  What is the return he expects?  He expects human beings to respond to his great act of charity by giving their hearts to him in loving devotion.  From the very beginning God has desired willing fellowship from us.  That relationship is so valuable to the Lord that he gave everything (invested everything) that that relationship might be restored.  It&#8217;s my positive response to that sacrifice; my responding in love and thanksgiving, and my walking in continued fellowship with the Lord that he considers to be a &#8220;high return.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Am I giving the Lord a “high return” on his investment in me?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Song of Songs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-song-of-songs-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 01:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Solomon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Song of Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of love Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love! Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kcF20kAoXS4/X62rvAEuytI/AAAAAAABHls/P8eM6_KmFEM7VfaEIMzvY5K5TvOXHV4JgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/11garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure>
<p>The power of love<br />
Song of Songs 4: You looked at me, and I fell in love. One look my way and I was hopelessly in love!<br />
Previously I mentioned that some Christians have made this book into an allegory of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. As I said then, I&#8217;m not all that convinced, although passages like this do remind me of scriptures like Ephesians 4 where I’m told that: &#8220;Christ loved the church and gave himself up for her to make her holy&#8230;and to present her to himself as a radiant church&#8230; holy and blameless.&#8221; That passage describes Christ&#8217;s passionate love for the Church, a love that takes him to the cross. In the portion of Song of Songs that&#8217;s before me today, the man describes the power of his love for the woman. In Ephesians I see the power of Christ&#8217;s love for the Church. Whether or not Song of Songs is intended to connect me to Christ and his love for us, I’m reminded in this passage of the power of love and the sacrifice one who loves is willing to make for his beloved.<br />
Take Away: “Love” is, ultimately, an action word…real love takes action on behalf of the one who is loved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Follow the leader Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following. There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers. The Bible has several stories of leadership. Moses led for 40 years. David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GKWZD23715U/X3iy3gUoO3I/AAAAAAABGzw/7uTOofCwLGcYE-Eo4mTLHOuMCXf6CN9CACPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Follow the leader<br />
Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.<br />
There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers.  The Bible has several stories of leadership.  Moses led for 40 years.  David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as well.  His son Solomon led to prosperity.  Here are three things that come to mind when I read about these leaders.  First, each of these men is not only a leader, but is also a follower who accepts the authority of the Lord and spends time with him getting his marching orders.  Second, these men know how to share leadership and to train leaders.  They don&#8217;t try to do everything themselves and surround themselves with capable people to help carry the leadership load.  Third, they lead people to meaningful goals.  These men have God given visions that gives their leadership real purpose.  People believe in them and they believe the goal set out for them is worth their sacrifice.  Leaders such as these have no problem attracting followers.<br />
Take Away: God-called leaders lead with purpose in a God-chosen direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-166/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Messiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God’s plan: my hope Isaiah 53: We&#8217;re all like sheep who&#8217;ve wandered off and gotten lost. No one has to convince Isaiah that his people are sinners. There’s ample evidence of that. Also, no one has to convince him that sin brings death; it&#8217;s everywhere. What he needs help with is a way back out [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2u2QPZRA_6I/YAewTukVWoI/AAAAAAABIO0/Czk-Osoly9AUWmNYou1GTdTrO7Qg4Jf_gCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9032133.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
God’s plan: my hope<br />
Isaiah 53: We&#8217;re all like sheep who&#8217;ve wandered off and gotten lost.<br />
No one has to convince Isaiah that his people are sinners.  There’s ample evidence of that.  Also, no one has to convince him that sin brings death; it&#8217;s everywhere.  What he needs help with is a way back out of this mess.  They’re lost to the point of having no hope of returning.  The way back has to be provided by God, Himself.  So how can a righteous God redeem an unrighteous people?  The answer is in this powerful chapter of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy.  The horrible sins of his nation will be gathered up and put on the shoulders of the holy Suffering Servant.  Their sins will become his sins and as the meek lamb being sacrificed in their rituals symbolically dies for their sins, he’ll literally give his all to restore them to God.  God&#8217;s plan: my hope.  The message of salvation was desperately needed by those of Isaiah&#8217;s day and it’s just as necessary today.  The wonderful thing is that it&#8217;s all true.  In spite of my sin, my rebellion, and my &#8220;wandering off&#8221; God is providing a way back through Jesus Christ.<br />
Take Away: God&#8217;s plan: my hope.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-193/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A given life Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say. I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus. The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones. Beyond those [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7ly2NAezS9s/YCrg7H5D4oI/AAAAAAABImc/oAPwqqgH9ngaXn1QXNFEwMtEI9o-rhQhACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PC034534.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Enchanted Rock &#8211; near Llano, TX</figcaption></figure><br />
A given life<br />
Isaiah 66: But there is something I&#8217;m looking for: a person simple and plain, reverently responsive to what I say.<br />
I don&#8217;t know much about the wise men in the Christmas story, but I do know that they come to Jesus.  The gifts they bring are, I understand, expensive ones.  Beyond those material things, though, the important thing is that they bring themselves.  In this passage Isaiah reminds me that God made it all and he owns it all.  He&#8217;s not depending on me to bring him gold, frankincense, and myrrh or anything else for that matter.  He is, though, counting on me to bring him my reverent obedience.  I believe a person ought to practice their faith in Christ in practical ways, including being a good steward of all that has been placed in his or her hands.  However, the offering I give is simply an outflow of a given life.  That&#8217;s a gift that’s guaranteed to please the Lord.<br />
Take Away: Our offerings are an outflow of our given lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Malachi</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-malachi-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 11:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Malachi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How to get a better preacher for your church Malachi 1: You say “I’m bored – this doesn’t do anything for me.” The people of Malachi’s day have lost the edge off of their religion. Worship services are a burden rather than a blessing. For them, righteous living is more about “have to” than “want [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15598" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15598" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15598" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/100_2601.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15598" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along the road to Moab, UT</figcaption></figure><br />
How to get a better preacher for your church<br />
Malachi 1: You say “I’m bored – this doesn’t do anything for me.”<br />
The people of Malachi’s day have lost the edge off of their religion.  Worship services are a burden rather than a blessing.  For them, righteous living is more about “have to” than “want to.”  What should be the most satisfying part of life has become just another burden for them to bear.  Malachi tells them why it’s like this: they’ve settled for a cheap religion.  When they bring an animal to the Lord they don’t pick the finest they have.  Instead, they pick one that’s probably going to die anyway.  Even when they brag that they’re going to make some significant offering, at the last minute they just can’t bring themselves to do it and settle for a mere token offering instead.  The result, according to Malachi, is a dull, boring religion.  The less they put into their relationship with God the less they get out of it.  Here’s the real kicker: God isn’t satisfied with their religion either.  He says, “If this is how it’s going to be just lock the Temple doors.”  Apparently, the Lord isn’t into playing church.  I don’t think this concept gives us preachers a license to preach dull, sloppy, poorly prepared sermons or for singers and others to sleep walk through church.  However, from years of experience I can affirm that the people who get the most out of worship services are the ones who put the most into them.  Why not give it a try?  Get up early enough to pray for the services and for yourself, arrive ahead of time, focus on the Lord, and give 100% to worship.  Who knows?  You might have a better preacher at your church than you think you do!<br />
Take Away: The people who get the most out of worship services are the ones who put the most into them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 12:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the cross]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Broken body, shed blood Mark 14: Take, this is my body. They’ve eaten the Passover all their lives so they know the ritual well. Now, as they gather in the upper room Jesus takes his place as “father” and the meal begins. To their surprise, he doesn’t follow the well-known script and, instead, comes up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15741" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15741" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15741" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2819.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15741" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Point Whitehorn Marine Reserve &#8211; near Birch Bay, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Broken body, shed blood</p>
<p>Mark 14: Take, this is my body.</p>
<p>They’ve eaten the Passover all their lives so they know the ritual well.  Now, as they gather in the upper room Jesus takes his place as “father” and the meal begins.  To their surprise, he doesn’t follow the well-known script and, instead, comes up with his own version, the now familiar words of the Communion ritual Christians have used for 2000 years now.  The bread and wine become, in this new ritual, symbols of the broken body and shed blood of our Lord.  These things, in turn, represent the New Covenant God has made with the human race.  Under this covenant, salvation is dependent on faith in the Son of God who willingly gives himself for us.  The Gospel of Mark moves quickly through the Last Supper and I immediately find myself at Gethsemane where Jesus wrestles with the reality of “broken body and shed blood.”  Every time I receive Communion I’m taken back to the New Covenant and the sacrifice that seals it with blood.  This ritual is rich with meaning but it all starts with broken body, shed blood.</p>
<p>Take Away: My hope of salvation is bound in what is remembered each time I receive communion.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 12:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discipleship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-14/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The carried cross Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple. Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel. Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd. On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15789" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15789" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15789" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/100_2889.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15789" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Day trip to Vancouver, BC</figcaption></figure>
<p>The carried cross</p>
<p>Luke 14: Anyone who won’t shoulder his own cross and follow behind me can’t be my disciple.</p>
<p>Jesus is now one of the most famous people in all of Israel.  Everywhere he goes he’s accompanied by a large crowd.  On this day, to everyone’s surprise he stops, turns, and addresses them all.  There’s nothing gentle about what he says to them.  If they want to really follow him and not just be tagalongs they have to let go of all else.   Family ties have to be loosed.  Claims to self-sovereignty have to be renounced.  These are hard enough words, but then he adds, “If you won’t shoulder your own cross you can’t be my disciple.”  These Jewish people absolutely hate the cross.  It’s not only the instrument of cruel execution but it’s the symbol of their humiliation under Roman rule.  The cross not only means death for the one who is so unfortunate as to be hung on it, but it’s also the means of grinding to dust the pride of the entire nation.  Those who are following Jesus in hopes of seeing a miracle or at least getting a free meal need to rethink their discipleship.  To this day the decision to follow Jesus should be a thoughtful one.  Long after the memory of seeing a “miracle” fades and the meal has been digested the cross remains.  The occupied cross becomes for Christians the symbol of God’s love for us.  The empty cross becomes the symbol of resurrection and hope.  The carried cross is the mark of our continued sacrifice and commitment to Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: Am I a tagalong or a genuine follower of Jesus?  The answer is found in my willingness or unwillingness to take up the cross.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-8/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Giving up a free meal 1Corinthians 8: When you hurt your friend, you hurt Christ. You’d think that today a discussion about eating meat that&#8217;s been offered to an idol can be safely skipped. However, to do so is a mistake. While the literal situation is foreign to me, the principle Paul teaches here is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16051" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16051" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16051" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/100_3130.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16051" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Pacific City, OR</figcaption></figure>
<p>Giving up a free meal</p>
<p>1Corinthians 8: When you hurt your friend, you hurt Christ.</p>
<p>You’d think that today a discussion about eating meat that&#8217;s been offered to an idol can be safely skipped. However, to do so is a mistake. While the literal situation is foreign to me, the principle Paul teaches here is invaluable. In Corinth there’s lots of idol worship. Often people share a meal with their god, offering some to the idol and then having a party in the god’s honor with the rest of it. A Christian might receive a friendly invitation to the party. That’s where there’s a problem. Some Christians think it is fine to attend, that meat is meat and an idol is nothing anyway. Other Christians are just coming out of that idol worshiping culture. Not too long ago they were the ones dining with the idols and to them eating the idol’s meat is a step backwards into the old way of life. The church at Corinth has been debating this issue and now Paul weighs in on the subject. He tells them that the issue in play isn’t about meat and idols at all. Rather it’s about Christians loving one another. Even if the more mature believer knows that idols are nothing but wood or stone he or she has the responsibility to love their fellow believer who&#8217;s still working through the issue. The principle, then, is that I’m to be willing to give up some of my “rights” for the good of my brothers and sisters in Christ. Now, I can’t resist adding here that if you know enough about this that you use this principle as a way to control me (“oh, you can’t do that because it’s against my convictions”) then you’re just trying to manipulate me. Thus, you become the one who’s guilty of disregarding this same principle. When all is said and done, I’m still left with the truth that I’m to love you enough to be willing to sacrifice a bit rather than cause you pain. If I fail here, I not only hurt you but I hurt the Lord we both serve.</p>
<p>Take Away: Love is the guiding principle of Christianity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Exodus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-exodus-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 01:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Exodus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enthusiasm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The power of enthusiasm Exodus 35: Then they came back, every one whose heart was roused, whose spirit was freely responsive, bringing offerings to God for building the Tent of Meeting. God gave Moses the plans for the Tabernacle and now Moses has passed them on to the people. A one-of-a-kind of worship center will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-A6msaTYf-Wg/XRrI2WA4lJI/AAAAAAAA8r8/iqZIU55Dx-w7vMt24W3-oLXcx8-udUlBACKgBGAs/s1600/flowers-006.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; In and around the Skagit Valley of Washington</figcaption></figure><br />
The power of enthusiasm<br />
Exodus 35: Then they came back, every one whose heart was roused, whose spirit was freely responsive, bringing offerings to God for building the Tent of Meeting.<br />
God gave Moses the plans for the Tabernacle and now Moses has passed them on to the people.  A one-of-a-kind of worship center will be constructed.  It will be portable but in spite of its portability it will be an elaborate structure, a place reflective of the God they worship.  When Moses tells them what God requires it sparks excitement throughout the congregation.  Now, without any pressure, the people freely give so that the Tent of Meeting can be constructed according to God’s plans.  As I look at the people coming with their gifts, my attention is drawn to those “roused hearts.”  Enthusiasm is a powerful emotion.  As it does for them, it stirs me to action and makes me willing to make sacrifices.  I want to have a “heart that is roused” when it comes to my relationship with God and his Church. There are many things that demand my attention and my support.  Those things may or may not be worthy.  However, doing God’s work is always worth the effort.  Stir my heart, O God, that I might be “roused” to enthusiastic, sacrificial service of you.<br />
Take Away: I serve the Lord, not because I must, but because I may.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
