<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Faith &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/faith/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:45:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Faith &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-64/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 07:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysteries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5266</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good old Agur Ben Yakeh Proverbs 30: There is no God&#8230;I can do anything I want! Some of the final pages of Proverbs are attributed to Agur Ben Yakeh. Aside from the name and that he is from a town or country called Massa we’re pretty much in the dark about him. The name, I’m [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hhe6n2E-J0w/X5CYQSfj0_I/AAAAAAABHCk/-zicBgIjoQMEYqkEO39hd4z3URUZ1rcfwCPcBGAsYHg/s400/mountians08G.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; Mountains east of San Diego, CA</figcaption></figure><br />
Good old Agur Ben Yakeh<br />
Proverbs 30: There is no God&#8230;I can do anything I want!<br />
Some of the final pages of Proverbs are attributed to Agur Ben Yakeh.  Aside from the name and that he is from a town or country called Massa we’re pretty much in the dark about him.  The name, I’m told, doesn’t appear to be Israelite, but is more Arab sounding.  Of course, Solomon rules a vast empire and has friendly relations with many countries.  It may be that Agur Ben Yakeh is considered to be a very wise man in his home country and that Solomon agrees, collecting his sayings and including him in his book of Proverbs.  However, there’s a bit of a problem with this idea because the nation of Israel alone worships Jehovah God at this time.  Clearly, the words of Agur Ben Yakeh are those of a worshiper of God.  I know these little things are often of more interest to me than to others, but it is kind of fun to think about this ancient mystery.  If the identity of Ben Yakeh is mysterious, his opening proverb is pretty straight forward.  He isn’t impressed by people who doubt the existence of God.  They may think they can ignore God and his commandments but when they do it isn&#8217;t the commandments that get broken!  The wise man says &#8220;every promise of God proves true.&#8221;  He warns those who doubt that to reconsider, warning, &#8220;he might take you to task and show up your lies.&#8221;  The day’s coming when everyone will believe in God.  After all, we’ll stand before him in Judgment.  Those who doubt will be convinced, but for them, it will be too late.  The One they have doubted and ignored, will &#8220;take them to task.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Sooner or later everyone will believe in God – it’s better to be part of the “sooner” crowd.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-154/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 11:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s plans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5436</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not blind trust Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open. Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion. The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic. In his message, Isaiah includes the words of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-v_vbCZKM80o/X_cokt1xWaI/AAAAAAABIJo/KmflYienVpoWJnL9TvIE3zAktpeMgUoJwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P9052229.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Near Estes Park in RMNP, CO</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Not blind trust<br />
Isaiah 45: I am God. I work out in the open.<br />
Isaiah speaks to people who have incorporated idol worship into their religion.  The religions of other nations have greatly influenced them, causing their view of God to include lots of mystery and magic.   In his message, Isaiah includes the words of the Lord who reminds them that he’s never told them to, &#8220;Seek me in emptiness, in dark nothingness.&#8221;  In fact, the Lord has done just the opposite.  He’s told them his plans ahead of time.  He’s even offered them choices: &#8220;do this and I will do that, or do that, and I will do this.&#8221;  This God doesn&#8217;t work in the darkness and serving him doesn&#8217;t involve a bunch of mumbo-jumbo.  Serving God certainly requires faith on our part.  There’s much about that Almighty that’s transcendent, beyond our understanding.  However, his desires for us are an open book.  As Isaiah says it, &#8220;Turn to me and be helped &#8212;saved! &#8212; everyone, whoever and wherever you are!&#8221;  Living in a relationship with God isn’t an exercise in ignorance.  This God partners with us, directing our lives, but, at the same time, allows us to operate freely within his purposes.  This God prefers light to darkness and is, in fact, the Creator of Light (both physical and spiritual).  We serve him in absolute trust, but, since his purposes for us have already been clearly stated, it isn&#8217;t blind trust.<br />
Take Away: Living in a relationship with the Lord isn’t an exercise in ignorance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-80/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t sweat the little stuff Jeremiah 12: What&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose? The whole question is: &#8220;If you can&#8217;t keep your wits during times of calm, what&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose like the Jordan in flood?&#8221; God&#8217;s question to Jeremiah is attention getting. My first response is that &#8220;calm&#8221; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ngJ8MYq2dB4/YEZtX3DR7HI/AAAAAAABI-A/wPdr6_Xo_3YxzyefZtOkh8QSPEMJnLrHwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/aboard%2Brhapsody%2B-%2Bseattle%2B-%2B%2B8-14-2009%2B5-53-33%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; View from Rhapsody of the Seas &#8211; Seattle, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Don’t sweat the little stuff<br />
Jeremiah 12: What&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose?<br />
The whole question is: &#8220;If you can&#8217;t keep your wits during times of calm, what&#8217;s going to happen when troubles break loose like the Jordan in flood?&#8221;  God&#8217;s question to Jeremiah is attention getting.  My first response is that &#8220;calm&#8221; is a relative term.  At almost any time I can find something unsettling to think about.  Just watching the evening news provides me plenty of “troublesome” thought ammunition.  Frankly, of course, I don&#8217;t have to reach that far.  Like everyone else I always have something going on: family concerns, finances, and health spring to mind.  Again, calm is a relative term because much of this is just part of living.  No one has confused my neighborhood with the Garden of Eden and the same can be said of yours.  So, I must learn to take life in stride.  I&#8217;m not saying that life is always easy.  For everyone there are times of &#8220;flooding Jordan&#8221; that knock the props out of everything in our lives.  Even in that, though, the Lord isn&#8217;t giving me the permission to fall apart.  Through Jeremiah he tells me to stop making big deals out of little deals in my life; to learn to trust him in those common problems and then, when the &#8220;biggie&#8221; comes, to apply what I&#8217;ve learned about trust even as the flood waters really are sweeping through my life.  I know, I know, it&#8217;s easier said than done.  Then again, that&#8217;s why I have to practice keeping my wits about me in the little stuff first.<br />
Take Away: As we learn to trust the Lord with the little things of life we lay the foundation for trusting him with the big ones when they come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-114/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 20:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking the “rest of the story” by faith Jeremiah 39: I&#8217;ll most certainly save you. The hero who rescued Jeremiah from the muddy prison is Ebed-melek. Now, as Jerusalem totters on the brink of destruction Jeremiah seeks him out. The Lord has a message specifically for this hero, and it’s a good one. The Lord [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1636px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gW4LDVEO4AI/YHHhlIWsSlI/AAAAAAABJzA/3TJ-jyh_wqglAbrvr-pUNUfFybC3h4dNQCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/100_1279.JPG" width="1636" height="2048" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Iowa fall colors</figcaption></figure><br />
Taking the “rest of the story” by faith<br />
Jeremiah 39: I&#8217;ll most certainly save you.<br />
The hero who rescued Jeremiah from the muddy prison is Ebed-melek.  Now, as Jerusalem totters on the brink of destruction Jeremiah seeks him out.  The Lord has a message specifically for this hero, and it’s a good one.  The Lord has taken note of this good man&#8217;s courage and faithfulness.  Things are going to get really bad very soon but Ebed-melek is going to be spared because God&#8217;s going to see to it.  In a sense, we see here God&#8217;s message to all those who are faithful to him.  There&#8217;s no promise for any of us of an easy life in which bad things never come, but there is the promise of God&#8217;s watch care over us.  It must have been, at the same time, welcome and unbelievable news for Ebed-melek.  Of course, he&#8217;s happy to hear such a message from Jeremiah, God&#8217;s prophet.  At the same time, he, and all Jerusalem, is very aware of the mighty army that&#8217;s poised on their doorstep.  The reality of it all nearly overwhelms the message of assurance from Jeremiah.  It&#8217;s the same for you and me.  The hard facts of pain and disappointment and disaster can nearly obliterate the promise of God&#8217;s presence.  Still, none of that negates it.  Interestingly, the writer of the sacred text doesn&#8217;t follow up on the story.  Jeremiah promises Ebed-melek that God will save him and that&#8217;s it.  Maybe there&#8217;s a lesson for us in what isn&#8217;t included here.  We&#8217;re to read this promise and conclude that, even though we don&#8217;t know the details, God keeps his word.  In the same way, I, right in the middle of life without any specific knowledge of what&#8217;s coming, must conclude that God will &#8220;most certainly save&#8221; me too.<br />
Take Away: Even we don’t know how he’s going to do it we can rest assured that the Lord will, indeed, keep his promises.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-117/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 20:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gedaliah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johanan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7377</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some things are easier said than done Jeremiah 42: I&#8217;m on your side, ready to save and deliver you from anything he might do. Johanan and other Judean leaders know that the murder of Gedaliah is a very big deal. The Babylonian king is not known for his forgiving nature. Gedaliah was the person he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 763px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ifWL1aacC80/YHYBOwSz4hI/AAAAAAABJ1E/BR8pK3r9GXwKVNdBMxXSi5Dv04rdDJXzwCPcBGAsYHg/s763/PB285806.JPG" width="763" height="608" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Brazos Bend State Park &#8211; TX</figcaption></figure><br />
Some things are easier said than done<br />
Jeremiah 42: I&#8217;m on your side, ready to save and deliver you from anything he might do.<br />
Johanan and other Judean leaders know that the murder of Gedaliah is a very big deal.  The Babylonian king is not known for his forgiving nature.  Gedaliah was the person he left in charge and his murder will be seen as an uprising against his rule.  There’s sure to be devastating punishment.  Their solution is to prepare for exile by running in the opposite direction to Egypt, the other major power in the region.  Johanan and others ask Jeremiah to pray for God&#8217;s direction in this, promising to do whatever the Lord says.  However, the message from the Lord isn’t what they expect to hear.  The Lord says to stay put and trust him.  Again, this is totally unexpected and, from a human point of view, very unreasonable.  They&#8217;ve already seen the wrath of the Babylonians.  Thousands have been killed, multiplied thousands have been carried off into exile never to return, and devastation is all around them.  For civic leaders to stick around, waiting for word of the governor&#8217;s murder to reach Babylonia is, in their eyes, an almost criminal inaction.  Jeremiah says, &#8220;Just trust God and everything will be okay.&#8221;  That&#8217;s one of those &#8220;easier said than done&#8221; statements.  Happily, such extreme, life and death situations don&#8217;t come our way very often, if ever.  For me to find applications in life I have to dial things back considerably.  Still, there are times when we, too, are to stand still and trust God rather than take matters into our own hands.  For instance, things down at the church may not be going well and several are jumping ship for the latest and greatest program down the road.  We&#8217;re tempted to follow suit, but when we pray, we simply can&#8217;t feel free to do it.  Others say, &#8220;Come on in, the water&#8217;s fine!&#8221;  God seems to say, &#8220;Stay right where you are, I&#8217;ll take care of you and your family.&#8221;  As a pastor it always concerns me when church people from other congregations show up at our door on a Sunday morning.  I&#8217;m not saying there&#8217;s never a time to go, but I don&#8217;t want to be someone&#8217;s &#8220;Egypt&#8221; when the Lord wants them to stay put and be a part of the turning of the tide right where they are.<br />
Take Away: If the Lord says “stay put” the only thing to do is, well, to stay put!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ezekiel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ezekiel-33/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 21:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ezekiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Basics Ezekiel 3: Get all these words that I&#8217;m giving you inside you. Ezekiel&#8217;s vision is intended to prepare him for the ministry God has for him. At one point in his vision he&#8217;s given a scroll and told to eat it. He reports that it tastes like honey. When the Lord applies the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-o1rBvFslmWU/YImL5i1EsxI/AAAAAAABKBM/S1MANeQRayYnf6YtikDzKxi7wIt7hAM1gCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/around%2Bcolorado%2Bsprings%2B-%2B%2B7-7-2010%2B5-04-55%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2010 &#8211; Garden of the Gods &#8211; Colorado Springs, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
The Basics<br />
Ezekiel 3: Get all these words that I&#8217;m giving you inside you.<br />
Ezekiel&#8217;s vision is intended to prepare him for the ministry God has for him.  At one point in his vision he&#8217;s given a scroll and told to eat it.  He reports that it tastes like honey.  When the Lord applies the vision he tells Ezekiel that he needs to fully digest the message he has for the exiles.  God&#8217;s message needs to become part of him to the point that even if people disagree or simply refuse to listen to him that he&#8217;ll have absolute confidence in what he says.  While I don&#8217;t enjoy arguing religion, I certainly enjoy talking about it.  I love dealing with the finer points of the faith, especially the more difficult to understand passages.  However, there are some things that ought not to be subject to debate.  I&#8217;ve learned that there are a few, very few, absolute basics that need to be swallowed hook, line, and sinker.  They&#8217;re to become as much a part of me as are my heart and lungs.  It&#8217;s not that I refuse to discuss them, but that they are at the core of my existence.  Without diving off into the deep end of the pool here, I think I can name them off the top of my head.  First, God is.  Second, Jesus is the Son of God who died for my sins and was resurrected to life.  Third, as I trust in Jesus as my Savior I have the hope of eternal life in him.  These truths not only &#8220;taste like honey,&#8221; they also make me who I am today and for eternity.<br />
Take Away: Some things are debatable and a few, just a few, aren&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-28/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 16:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God trusting us to trust him Daniel 3: The God we serve can rescue us&#8230;but even if he doesn&#8217;t&#8230;. I love this story! The pagan king orders the three Hebrew men to worship his statue; it&#8217;s either worship or die in the furnace. Their response is one for the ages: &#8220;The God we serve can [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1050px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-OIVO6Bb4QCo/YLuxsj4UCNI/AAAAAAABKY4/pbCbKGEyB0MRh4MqhM3sUxUv_z1NeMMdwCPcBGAsYHg/s1270/2011%2B-%2BLondon%2B-%2B-45.JPG" width="1050" height="1270" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; London &#8211; Westminster Abbey</figcaption></figure><br />
God trusting us to trust him<br />
Daniel 3: The God we serve can rescue us&#8230;but even if he doesn&#8217;t&#8230;.<br />
I love this story!  The pagan king orders the three Hebrew men to worship his statue; it&#8217;s either worship or die in the furnace.  Their response is one for the ages: &#8220;The God we serve can rescue us from your roaring furnace&#8230;but even if he doesn&#8217;t&#8230;we still wouldn&#8217;t serve your gods or worship the gold statue you set up.&#8221;  Now, that&#8217;s trusting faith!  I&#8217;ve never been where they are and I hope I never am.  However, if such a day comes I pray that I&#8217;ll have the same backbone they did.  At a much less intense level, I&#8217;m taken by their &#8220;even if he doesn&#8217;t&#8221; statement.  They knew what God &#8220;could&#8221; do but they weren&#8217;t sure of what he &#8220;would&#8221; do.  If they&#8217;re given a choice, they&#8217;ll vote for divine rescue, but, obviously they aren&#8217;t the ones choosing.  If they have to, they&#8217;ll go with option two: obedience even to death.  I, too, believe the Lord knows how to rescue his people.  However, there are times when it seems God has something bigger going on and my predicament isn’t at the core of what&#8217;s happening.  At times like that the Lord trusts me to trust him.  So, &#8220;even if he doesn&#8217;t&#8221; do what I want, I declare my allegiance to him and then hold fast to it.<br />
Take Away: The great test of faith isn’t believing for a miracle.  Rather, it’s believing when the miracle never comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Hosea</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-hosea-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Hosea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shopping for religion Hosea 7: They turn&#8230;here, then there, like a weather vane. &#8220;Welcome to WorshipMart, your one stop shop for religion. Please keep an eye out for our blue light specials, you may find a very nice accessory to your faith for a low price.&#8221; You head over to the New Age aisle. Maybe [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vpozPUqf4Kw/YNtTAXNHppI/AAAAAAABKoI/lU9eeq15p-MxM7ABTguuytxwwLDzHsgowCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/2013-05-28%2B20.27.46.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Saylorville Lake &#8211; near Des Moines, IA</figcaption></figure><br />
Shopping for religion<br />
Hosea 7: They turn&#8230;here, then there, like a weather vane.<br />
&#8220;Welcome to WorshipMart, your one stop shop for religion.  Please keep an eye out for our blue light specials, you may find a very nice accessory to your faith for a low price.&#8221;  You head over to the New Age aisle.  Maybe a new crystal will help you pray better.  The Politically Correct section has some interesting items, some of that &#8220;what works for you may not work for me&#8221; might come in handy when dealing with some of the more narrow people you know.  The Hedonism section makes you feel somewhat uncomfortable but you can&#8217;t resist some of the &#8220;it can&#8217;t be all that bad if it feels right.&#8221;  And then you head over to the staples section.  After all, when all else fails you might just want some help from God Almighty.  At the checkout counter the salesperson asks if you found everything you wanted.  You answer &#8220;yes&#8221; but you think, &#8220;I&#8217;ll probably be back in here before long, somehow this stuff doesn&#8217;t seem to last like it should.&#8221;  As you check out, you can&#8217;t find the last item.  That&#8217;s happened before.  Everything else is there though; you&#8217;ll just have to make it without God.  Anyway, your religion is no one&#8217;s business but your own.  Right?<br />
Take Away: He’ll either be Lord of all or he won’t be Lord at all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jonah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jonah-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jonah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[belief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Bible]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The biggest fish story ever Jonah 1: One day long ago, God’s Word came to Jonah. As I finish my quick read of little-known Obadiah, I turn the page to find myself on very familiar ground. After all, everybody has heard of Jonah and the “whale.” This is surely one of the top five stories [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xGm3J6JHVX0/YPmsr6_8WmI/AAAAAAABKzc/uQwN2cr8P8YvPmFUL_wxXxp7O5i01l7iwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/IMG_20130729_200659_908.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Tompkins Campground &#8211; Lawrenceville, PA</figcaption></figure><br />
The biggest fish story ever<br />
Jonah 1: One day long ago, God’s Word came to Jonah.<br />
As I finish my quick read of little-known Obadiah, I turn the page to find myself on very familiar ground.  After all, everybody has heard of Jonah and the “whale.”   This is surely one of the top five stories of the Old Testament and people who&#8217;ve never read the Bible or attended church know about this “fish story.”   A few years ago I was teaching a church membership class and this story came up.  The teens in the class wanted to know if Christians have to believe as literally true stories like Noah and the Ark and Jonah and the “whale.”  Had the question been asked by some fine fundamentalists I&#8217;ve known I would have thought I was being set up for the old trap that sounds something like this: “If you don’t believe in a literal six day creation how can you believe in a literal resurrection of Jesus?”   That question, by the way, ignores the clear teachings of the Bible which says, “If you confess with your mouth, ‘Jesus is Lord,’ and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved.” (Romans 10:9).  Note that Paul doesn’t add, “Also, you have to believe every statement in the Old Testament is literal.”  I’m not required to believe in a literal six day Creation to be saved, but I do have to believe “God raised him from the dead.”  Anyway, back to the teens in the membership class.  I told them that I believe the Lord created all things and that sending a big flood or making a big fish capable of doing what the book of Jonah says it did would be a simple thing for such a Creator.  However, the purpose of stores like this is to tell us something about God and ourselves and that it’s a bigger mistake to read the story, believing every word while missing the lesson than it is to read the story and “get it” while doubting that it&#8217;s literal.  So, “big fish” or not, I’m supposed to come away from the Book of Jonah knowing more about God and his work in this world than I knew before.  That’s still my goal as I start through this story once again.<br />
Take Away: The Bible tells us the story of God and us.  It has no interest in answering every scientific question or providing for us fodder for religious debates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Micah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-micah-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Micah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sitting on the front row Micah 7: I’m sticking around to see what God will do. Micah says things are going downhill fast. He’s learned that he can’t trust his neighbor and that “neighborhoods and families are falling to pieces.” Clearly his day is a treacherous, difficult one. In the face of such perilous times [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tn8xF2oe-MU/YRA4IqEZTWI/AAAAAAABK_k/EwwJwfi02WsuTAsadAiJa4FrJqwwCMj5QCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P9179093.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains</figcaption></figure><br />
Sitting on the front row<br />
Micah 7: I’m sticking around to see what God will do.<br />
Micah says things are going downhill fast.  He’s learned that he can’t trust his neighbor and that “neighborhoods and families are falling to pieces.”  Clearly his day is a treacherous, difficult one.  In the face of such perilous times Micah might be tempted to run for the hills or at least withdraw from society.  As anyone knows, Micah isn’t the only one who has faced difficult days.  Through the centuries godly men and women have gone through unbelievable hardship.  Often that hardship has been on a national or even worldwide scale.  At other times the hardship is close to home: a family or even personal struggle that fills our days with exhausting darkness.  In this passage, Micah is no “Pollyanna” who insists everything’s always “just fine.”  However, he is a man of faith.  As tempting as it might be to run and get away from all the wrong and uncertainty he sees, Micah declares he’s staying put.  Why?  It’s because he wants a front row seat to God’s redemption!  Today, we believers aren’t blind to the problems of life.  When things take a downturn we become anxious like everyone else.  However, in it all there’s a thread of optimism.  We believe God is still God and that he’s working in and through it all.  The end result is salvation.  We want a front row seat when that happens!<br />
Take Away: The people of the Lord are an optimistic people – and, for good reason!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
