<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 2Kings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-2kings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 22:56:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 2Kings &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 21:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ahaziah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual giants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marching to the beat of their own drummer 2Kings1: That has to be Elijah the Tishbite! Elijah has come a long way in the years since he fled from Jezebel. He now has a faithful assistant, Elisha, and a band of disciples. Generally, he stays out of sight. However, he remains a household name in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ARSuxi2ZHvw/Xl_Vq40MmpI/AAAAAAABD9k/RAh51qHlT6wxznvQXTN94HoUo01uRx-KACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170404_181859.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Gunter Hill Campground &#8211; Montgomery, AL</figcaption></figure><br />
Marching to the beat of their own drummer<br />
2Kings1: That has to be Elijah the Tishbite!<br />
Elijah has come a long way in the years since he fled from Jezebel. He now has a faithful assistant, Elisha, and a band of disciples. Generally, he stays out of sight. However, he remains a household name in Israel. You might say he’s bigger than life. Now that Ahab is dead, his son, Ahaziah rules Israel. However, things aren&#8217;t going well for him. Moab has rebelled against the rule of Israel and, to top it off, Ahaziah has taken a nasty fall and been injured. The ailing king sends messengers to seek a remedy for his injuries, not to Jehovah God, but to the idol Baal. It’s as they travel to Ekron to visit the Baal shrine that they encounter the old man Elijah, shaggy hair, leather belt and all. The Lord, he says, is angry with Ahaziah for turning to Baal as though he doesn&#8217;t exist and because of that Ahaziah is on what will become his deathbed. When they return with the message and describe the man who gave it, Ahaziah knows that Elijah has stepped out onto the public stage once again. Repeated attempts to arrest him result in fire falling from heaven. Clearly, it’s unwise to trifle with this man of God! Aside from his unusual appearance (and, come to think of it, the lightning strikes on his enemies), Elijah reminds me of some spiritual giants I’ve known. These are people who don&#8217;t make a big deal of themselves, who seem out of step with what most of us think of as &#8220;normal,&#8221; but spend a lot of time in the presence of God. When they have something to say, we’re wise to listen.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes people who seem out of step with the world are very much in step with the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 21:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual giants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spiritual role models 2Kings2: Your life repeated in my life. I want to be a holy man just like you. There’s no one on earth as powerful as is Elijah. As he lives his last day in this world it seems he already has one foot in heaven and spiritual power and authority radiate from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-PlIeRWESSlc/XmE2SN3PdJI/AAAAAAABD94/uU8wHHPt1RArwSA83yinV3GuuW_1FM7GACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170405_172957.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Gunter Hill Campground &#8211; Montgomery, AL</figcaption></figure><br />
Spiritual role models<br />
2Kings2: Your life repeated in my life. I want to be a holy man just like you.<br />
There’s no one on earth as powerful as is Elijah. As he lives his last day in this world it seems he already has one foot in heaven and spiritual power and authority radiate from him. Somehow, probably because Elijah himself has announced it, everyone knows that this is his day. His assistant, Elisha, who has walked with him through the years, is glued to him on this day. More than once the old man of God has told him to stay put but both of them know it isn&#8217;t going to happen. Now, as a moment unique in human history nears, the old prophet asks Elisha what he can do for him before he’s taken. Elisha isn’t shy! He wants to be the man Elijah is. He desires that, even as their names are similar, that their walk with God will also be much the same. I thank God today for the spiritual role models he’s provided in my life. Frankly, it’s easy to fail to recognize them because I’m so close to the situation that I can’t see the big picture of their influence. Because of that I’m sometimes unaware of the spiritual depth of others till they’re gone. A couple of things come to mind as I consider these things. First, I want to open my eyes to spiritual greatness in these special people. Second, I want to allow the Lord to do in me what he’s done in them. &#8220;Your life repeated in my life,&#8221; &#8212; what a powerful phrase!<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for powerful spiritual role models in your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 21:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Swing down sweet chariot stop, and let me ride 2Kings2: Elijah went up in a whirlwind to heaven. As I study the Scriptures I find two accounts of people who leave this world without tasting death. One is Enoch who, the Bible says, is “taken away&#8221; by God. The second is Elijah, who’s taken up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-KSilv6ffF7k/XmKHmwGgeGI/AAAAAAABD-M/lFib67GxM0sB4feCimy-xAxhLmLANQXkgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170407_114150.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; View from Point Park on Lookout Mountain, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Swing down sweet chariot stop, and let me ride<br />
2Kings2: Elijah went up in a whirlwind to heaven.<br />
As I study the Scriptures I find two accounts of people who leave this world without tasting death. One is Enoch who, the Bible says, is “taken away&#8221; by God. The second is Elijah, who’s taken up by a whirlwind into heaven, accompanied by a chariot and horses of fire. I’ve read some interesting explanations of what’s happening on that day including one effort to somehow make this into an alien abduction! While I don&#8217;t have the credentials to take this event on from a scholarly point of view it’s clear to me that this entire passage is intended to convince me of the uniqueness and spiritual power of this man of God. On this day Elijah is overflowing with God&#8217;s power. Nothing like this has been seen on earth. Any understanding of this passage has to start with my recognizing that the intention of the writer is to convince me of the greatness of Elijah, the man of God. Ultimately though, this, and all Scripture, has to be read as a &#8220;God story.&#8221; God has done something in Elijah&#8217;s life. Earlier, I’m given a sobering picture of his humanity. In that account he’s a discouraged, exhausted, and fear-filled man. Now I see what the Lord has done for him and in him. He’s been transformed into the spiritual dynamo I see in this passage. Now, as Elijah disappears into the sky, I don&#8217;t find myself at the end of anything. Instantly God&#8217;s power begins to flow through Elisha. This story continues because God continues to work.<br />
Take Away: The Lord uses some people in wonderful, amazing ways but the story of his work continues long after their story has ended.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual giants]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The God of Elijah 2Kings2: Now where is the God of Elijah? I’ve had the privilege of knowing some spiritual giants in my lifetime. These people walked close to God and, like a motor boat crossing a calm lake, leave a broad, expanding wake that influences people far beyond their experience and even their lifetimes. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NiIhOQETEWY/XmPEqs-UcvI/AAAAAAABD-k/nbX6tkUy44QP26f32Dq8ie-4RAseb4KFwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_5300.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; view from Point Park on Lookout Mountain, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
The God of Elijah<br />
2Kings2: Now where is the God of Elijah?<br />
I’ve had the privilege of knowing some spiritual giants in my lifetime. These people walked close to God and, like a motor boat crossing a calm lake, leave a broad, expanding wake that influences people far beyond their experience and even their lifetimes. They’ve influenced me. If not for them I wouldn’t be the man I am today. In fact, it would be easy for me to just focus on them and let them be my example and inspiration. If I do that that I’ll be a better person. However, as potentially positive as that might be, I’d be mistaken to do it. Elisha has known a great man, a man overflowing with the power of God. Now, though, that man is gone. Elijah&#8217;s disciples want to form a search party to try to find their master. Elisha, though, doesn&#8217;t seek Elijah. Instead, he seeks the God of Elijah. He knows that every good thing about Elijah was because of the God he served. He knows that the great need of his life isn’t more of Elijah. Instead, it’s more of the God of Elijah. Today, I thank God for those spiritual giants of my life. Their influence isn’t taken for granted. However, it’s not them that I need as I pursue spiritual excellence. No, it’s not them; it’s the God they served.<br />
Take Away: Seek, not an “Elijah” but, rather, the God of Elijah.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 21:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elijah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4766</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Micromanaging others 2Kings 2: So there &#8212; didn&#8217;t I tell you? Even as Elisha seeks the God of Elijah, the disciples of Elijah are still looking for Elijah. I can&#8217;t be too hard on these good men, assuming a lack of faith on their part. They’ve literally seen their master picked up by a tornado [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iFZqzEm9ISc/XmVcH2Is3QI/AAAAAAABD_Q/waWZs628se4SPoHCzFuB7_o6ZpCqFfsmgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170407_122507.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Incline Railroad &#8211; Lookout Mountain, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Micromanaging others<br />
2Kings 2: So there &#8212; didn&#8217;t I tell you?<br />
Even as Elisha seeks the God of Elijah, the disciples of Elijah are still looking for Elijah. I can&#8217;t be too hard on these good men, assuming a lack of faith on their part. They’ve literally seen their master picked up by a tornado and carried away. Had I been there I too would have been inclined to view things from a non-spiritual viewpoint. They want to form a search party and try to find Elijah just in case the Lord was merely relocating him and not taking him from earth in a way never seen before or since! Again, I can&#8217;t be too hard on these men. Elisha assures them that Elijah is right where God wants him to be, but, when they insist, he agrees that 50 of them go on a search and rescue mission. Three days later they’re back and reporting that Elijah’s nowhere to be found. Elisha says, &#8220;Told you so.&#8221; Aside from the fact that I would have probably been among those on the search team, I note that sometimes I have to let people do what they want to do. I think I tend to waste energy trying to get people to do things my way when I’d be better off pursuing my vision and letting the Lord straighten them out when he knows they’re ready. Elisha knows without a doubt that the 50 won&#8217;t find Elijah. He also knows that they’ll have to find that out for themselves. Understanding that doesn&#8217;t mean that I shouldn’t ever attempt to influence others. It does mean, though, that I’m free from trying to micromanage the lives of other people.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes leaders have to simply give people permission to find out for themselves what the leader already knows.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mysteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Better think twice before mocking bald men 2Kings 2: Elisha turned, took one look at them, and cursed them. This story makes me uncomfortable. Some children mock Elisha, the man of God, so he curses them resulting in two bears coming out of the woods and killing 42 of them. What’s this all about anyway? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5dHl7Ic0eYg/XmZdSP7BZ4I/AAAAAAABD_g/yNpdvv-1aOQHXQlD7uckjs9ncNqy8ze1wCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_5304.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2016 &#8211; Near Knoxville, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Better think twice before mocking bald men<br />
2Kings 2: Elisha turned, took one look at them, and cursed them.<br />
This story makes me uncomfortable. Some children mock Elisha, the man of God, so he curses them resulting in two bears coming out of the woods and killing 42 of them. What’s this all about anyway? Some Bible scholars I&#8217;ve read say that &#8220;children&#8221; is not the only meaning of the Hebrew word used. It can mean &#8220;servants&#8221; and can refer, not to 7-year-olds, but to young people and even young adults. However, reading that a group of 20-year-old servants mock Elisha and he curses them doesn’t do much to solve my discomfort with this incident. So what do I do with this passage? I think I have to just read it and go on, believing that there’s something happening here that I don&#8217;t get. I have to conclude that I’m missing some vital bit of information that would help me make sense of the passage. It isn&#8217;t unusual to have to deal with life issues that way. For instance, someone tells me that a person for whom I have great respect has done something totally out of character. I can&#8217;t defend what they’ve done but I can conclude that I don&#8217;t know the whole story. Perhaps, if I did, it would make sense to me. So, as I come to this passage I read something that doesn&#8217;t fit in with what I know about God: that &#8220;God is love,&#8221; holy and righteous. I can&#8217;t explain it, but instead of making me doubt God, it just reminds me that I don&#8217;t know the whole story about this or about another million or so issues of life.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes I have to admit I don’t understand things and rely on the character of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 22:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ditch digging for the Lord 2Kings 3: Dig ditches all over this valley. An alliance of three armies has formed to take on the army of Moab. The armies of Edom, Israel, and Judah plan to circle around and attack from an unexpected direction. However, it all backfires. They find themselves a day out of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0SS1bakbsWM/Xme1pcfCpvI/AAAAAAABD_4/WETb8jBSE-006xbgWjHrzaR21pEIZIjQgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170409_182841.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Racoon Valley Escpaees &#8211; trail at campground</figcaption></figure><br />
Ditch digging for the Lord<br />
2Kings 3: Dig ditches all over this valley.<br />
An alliance of three armies has formed to take on the army of Moab. The armies of Edom, Israel, and Judah plan to circle around and attack from an unexpected direction. However, it all backfires. They find themselves a day out of Moab and in the desert having exhausted their supply of water. Jehoshaphat asks for a prophet of God and Elisha &#8220;just happens&#8221; to be nearby. God&#8217;s word through Elisha is that they’re to begin digging ditches in this desert plain because, without a single drop of rain falling on them, God will fill those ditches with water. Many years earlier Elisha&#8217;s predecessor had prayed for rain and, when a cloud &#8220;the size of a man&#8217;s hand&#8221; appeared on the horizon he stopped praying and started running in preparation for the rain storm that was coming. Now, Elisha promises water, but tells them that they need to start preparing for it before they see even the first drop. Obviously there’s a pattern here and in many other instances in God&#8217;s Word. God expects us to act in faith that he’ll keep his word to us. For Elijah that meant he needed to stop praying and start running. For this army it means that out in the arid, dusty desert they’re to prepare for flowing water. How does this principle apply to my life today?<br />
Take Away: Our acts of faith really do have a bearing on what the Lord does for us and through us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 22:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bring your vessels not a few 2Kings 4: He said, &#8220;That&#8217;s it. There are no more jugs.&#8221; Then the oil stopped. Clearly the series of stories in the first part of 2 Kings are examples of what a powerful man of God Elisha is. Still, it seems that, like a symphony, each story is a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-krThhzyvWTw/Xmj3tdrtRhI/AAAAAAABEAM/5kiJ0VMzJrYSNYJNDWea0zFmxb8k2AxfgCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170415_102028.jpg" width="1600" height="1314" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Near Knoxville, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Bring your vessels not a few<br />
2Kings 4: He said, &#8220;That&#8217;s it. There are no more jugs.&#8221; Then the oil stopped.<br />
Clearly the series of stories in the first part of 2 Kings are examples of what a powerful man of God Elisha is. Still, it seems that, like a symphony, each story is a variation on one theme: that when people have faith they act on that faith. These miracles all start with a need and the promise of God. Then, the person has to take action in preparation for God to move. In one story we see soldiers digging ditches in the desert in preparation for water to miraculously flow into them. Now we have a widow with just a little oil being told to go out and borrow jars from everyone she can. When she starts pouring oil out of her meager supply she fills all the jars she collected. It’s only when she runs out of jars that she runs out of oil. So often we take our needs to God and then stand back to watch what he does. However, in this, and the other stories, we see that God invites us to partner with him in what he does for us. No doubt, he does the greater work; after all, anyone can collect jars. Only God can fill them all from such a limited supply. Lord, help me to be a &#8220;jar collector.&#8221; Help me to be a person doing my part in working with you as you accomplish your purposes in my life and in this world.<br />
Take Away: What does the Lord call you to today that will prepare for what he intends to do in your life tomorrow?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 22:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Desperate faith 2Kings 4: &#8220;She said, &#8220;Everything&#8217;s fine.&#8221; This is a surprisingly powerful story. Elisha the man of God promises a woman from the town of Shunem that she’s going to have a son. The child is born the following year. A few years later the little boy becomes suddenly ill and dies. His grieving [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N8w8iYLIjFg/XmpoCnDsQcI/AAAAAAABEAg/7urQyqY3fPMSGHP-2zMg3KJLL0iWlqUmACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170419_131808.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; At old mill &#8211; Pigeon Forge, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Desperate faith<br />
2Kings 4: &#8220;She said, &#8220;Everything&#8217;s fine.&#8221;<br />
This is a surprisingly powerful story. Elisha the man of God promises a woman from the town of Shunem that she’s going to have a son. The child is born the following year. A few years later the little boy becomes suddenly ill and dies. His grieving mother seeks out Elisha. As she’s coming she encounters the servant of Elisha first. Clearly something’s wrong, but when Gehazi asks her how things are, her reply is &#8220;Everything&#8217;s fine.&#8221; It’s only when she gets to Elisha that she pours out her heart. Elisha goes to the lifeless child and performs a miracle, raising him back to life. While I see that this is another story intended to show me how powerfully God is working in the life of the prophet, I’m drawn to the Shunammite woman. If there’s ever an example of desperate faith it’s here. Her heart is broken as she lays her dead son on the bed. The only thought on her mind is to get to the man of God, the miracle worker who promised the son in the first place. She desperately wants to believe he can make things right, but looking into the face of such loss it’s nearly impossible. Knowing that, she realizes she has to get to Elisha as quickly as possible, and, instinctively, she knows that even saying the words, &#8220;my son is dead&#8221; will destroy the mustard seed of faith to which she clings. How is it that &#8220;it is well&#8221; in her life? It’s because she’s holding on to God with her last ounce of spiritual strength. This is miracle-working territory. Without a cross or an empty tomb she believed the impossible. God can do a lot with faith like that.<br />
Take Away: All it takes is faith the size of a mustard seed to see miracles take place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 22:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elisha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's provision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miracles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apples or fish 2Kings 4: They not only ate, but had leftovers. During our Lord&#8217;s ministry some of the people think Jesus is possibly one of the prophets of old, resurrected from the dead. It might be that they’re thinking of this incident. In fact, Luke’s report of the suggestion that Jesus is a resurrected [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vVKt51obZoQ/XmulFzckgsI/AAAAAAABEAw/SKBWTx6fAKY5a5wYF_3Y5srOaDbx33HPwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170425_124128.jpg" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure><br />
Apples or fish<br />
2Kings 4: They not only ate, but had leftovers.<br />
During our Lord&#8217;s ministry some of the people think Jesus is possibly one of the prophets of old, resurrected from the dead. It might be that they’re thinking of this incident. In fact, Luke’s report of the suggestion that Jesus is a resurrected prophet comes right after Jesus feeds the five thousand. In this case Elisha feeds, not thousands, but a hundred; and not with bread and fish but with bread and apples. It’s a different day in which a different man provides and different main course. But it’s the same God. Because of that the lessons are the same. One lesson is that &#8220;little is much when God is in it.&#8221; Another is that I can trust the Lord with my meager resources; he can make better use of them than I can anyway. Whether I&#8217;m thinking about Elisha or Jesus or apples or fish it’s good to be reminded that when I give my all to the Lord he does wonderful things.<br />
Take Away: The Lord takes the little bit that’s our all and does more with it than we ever could.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
