<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of Deuteronomy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-deuteronomy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:54:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of Deuteronomy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 09:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Call to remember Deuteronomy 1: How can I carry, all by myself, your troubles and burdens and quarrels? The book of Deuteronomy is made up of a sermon or series of sermons by Moses, the man of God. In fact, the name of the book can be understood to mean “talks” or “words.” The occasion [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UyrHgFEtpqo/XVsmIpEut0I/AAAAAAABALw/iwhrnJPb0GgUenX6SOa_whuvFT0rTTUdACKgBGAs/s1600/P6239576.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Call to remember<br />
Deuteronomy 1: How can I carry, all by myself, your troubles and burdens and quarrels?<br />
The book of Deuteronomy is made up of a sermon or series of sermons by Moses, the man of God.  In fact, the name of the book can be understood to mean “talks” or “words.”  The occasion is the conclusion of his leadership (and life) and the pending entrance of God&#8217;s people into the Promised Land after 40 years in the wilderness.  Moses wants to remind them of their history so that they will take their story with them into the new land.  He also wants them to remember the mistakes of the past so that they won&#8217;t repeat them.  Most importantly, he wants them to remember the gracious faithfulness of God who has been with them and will continue to be their God.   It shouldn&#8217;t surprise us that this book has a lot of repeat material in it.  After all, Moses is preaching to remind them of these things.  Still, I see a somewhat different emphasis in this sermon as old stories are retold.  In the passage that draws my attention today Moses remembers how he organized the leadership.  It was his father-in-law who first suggested a division of leadership.  Then, later on, it appears the plan had not been carried through and God reminded Moses of this approach.  Now Moses remembers how overwhelmed he was as a solo leader.  Alone, he couldn&#8217;t carry their burdens.  This makes perfect sense.  A leader who tries to do it all will do a poor job of all of it.  It may make that leader feel important, even indispensable, but in the long run, his or her leadership will be a failed effort.  The solution is to select the right people to help, to empower them, to continue to enhance their abilities, to keep them connected to the primary leadership, and to always remember that the Lord is our ultimate Leader.  At 120 years of age and after 40 years of leadership we can be pretty sure Moses knows what he’s talking about.<br />
Take Away: Leadership doesn’t mean doing everything.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 09:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The distant reach of failure Deuteronomy 1: Don&#8217;t be terrified of them, God, your God, is leading the way; he&#8217;s fighting for you. The &#8220;you&#8221; in this passage isn’t the members of the present congregation. It’s their parents. However, Moses is speaking to them as a nation of people, seen as one with the previous [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kMsGwNFB4Fs/XV204J19aeI/AAAAAAABAPs/CcWBUxzABYoUQ5KXlTqBYCWTEOilDOifwCKgBGAs/s1600/P6309594.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
The distant reach of failure<br />
Deuteronomy 1: Don&#8217;t be terrified of them, God, your God, is leading the way; he&#8217;s fighting for you.<br />
The &#8220;you&#8221; in this passage isn’t the members of the present congregation.  It’s their parents.  However, Moses is speaking to them as a nation of people, seen as one with the previous generation.  This doesn&#8217;t sit well with my Western mindset.  We Westerners are individualists who like to think we make our own decisions apart from others.  In this case it was 40 years earlier that Moses had said these words and &#8220;they&#8221; refused to hear, refused to have faith, and refused to obey.  The penalty was 40 years in the wilderness &#8212; an experience all those in the congregation hearing this sermon did share, at least to some extent.  Soon it will be their turn to hear, believe, and obey.  Moses is preparing them for it by reminding them of their already shared failure in their parents.  Still, God is the God of Second Chances.  Soon they will stand on the banks of the river.  To a great extent they will have the opportunity to erase the failure of those who went before them.  While I’m no expert on &#8220;generational curses&#8221; (or &#8220;generational blessings&#8221; for that matter) I’m reminded that my failure or faithfulness reaches far beyond my individual life.<br />
Take Away: It’s unlikely anyone ever sees the full extent of their influence, be it for good or for evil.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you’ve seen one giant you’ve seen them all Deuteronomy 3: God is going to do the same thing to all the kingdoms over there across the river. Moses reminds his people of the victories they’ve already experienced. By God’s help they defeated the army of Sihon. Then they took on Og of Bashan. Before [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QNsVZv4kPRo/XV2z8jAT6dI/AAAAAAABAPg/OKsXYpN4JgwCKTXqQL1lo5dCWEP3oSLnwCKgBGAs/s1600/P6239572.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt St Helens, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
When you’ve seen one giant you’ve seen them all<br />
Deuteronomy 3: God is going to do the same thing to all the kingdoms over there across the river.<br />
Moses reminds his people of the victories they’ve already experienced.  By God’s help they defeated the army of Sihon.  Then they took on Og of Bashan.  Before we ever meet the giant Goliath we meet Og.  He’s huge.  In fact, after he’s defeated his bed is put on display.  It’s over thirteen feet long!  As they say, “the bigger they come the harder they fall.”  The Lord supercharges the Israelites and down comes Og and his army.  Before long it will be time for this current generation of Israelites to do what their parents refused to do.  They’re to cross the Jordan and take the land of Canaan as their own.  This time, rather than cower in fear they’re to think of Sihon and his army and how, by the strength of the Lord, that army was crushed.  When they see the big guys of Canaan they’re to picture the fallen Og and his big, iron bed that is on display.  The victories of the past are to give them courage and faith to move forward to even greater victories.  That’s how it’s supposed to be for me too.  God has been good to me.  By his grace I’ve come a long way.  I don’t know what the future holds, but I wouldn’t be surprised at all if the biggest challenges of life lie ahead.  I’m to let the work of God in my life in days gone by be a source of strength in my life in the events yet to come.<br />
Take Away: As we remember what the Lord has done for us in the past we’re encouraged to trust in in current and future situations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4338</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intimacy with God Deuteronomy 4: What other great nation has gods that are intimate with them the way God, our God, is with us? I’m tempted to focus on &#8220;national gods&#8221; here. In this distant day each nation has its own gods and it’s unthinkable for anyone to imagine a nation kicking out its gods [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-azbuSsy9Nss/XV7v_ir1TII/AAAAAAABAR0/9Jenhk2miNEx1Nb20gOniR-lBt29grWEwCKgBGAs/s1600/P6309594.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Intimacy with God<br />
Deuteronomy 4: What other great nation has gods that are intimate with them the way God, our God, is with us?<br />
I’m tempted to focus on &#8220;national gods&#8221; here.  In this distant day each nation has its own gods and it’s unthinkable for anyone to imagine a nation kicking out its gods to worship those of another nation.  I’m pretty sure a case could be made that we still have &#8220;national gods.&#8221;  In the instance of my country those gods are named &#8220;Materialism&#8221; and &#8220;Pleasure.&#8221;  However, instead of pursuing that line of thought (come to think of it, I guess I already did!) I’ll focus on what it’s like to worship the true God.  Humans don’t make this God out of some precious metal.  Rather, this God makes human beings out of the dust of the ground.  This God makes no demand of those who serve him that he doesn&#8217;t first make of himself.  For instance, before he calls people to love him he first loves them.  In fact, this God always acts first, moving in grace-full ways in the lives of people.  And, as Moses says, this God seeks intimacy with his Creation.  Moses wants his congregation to realize how blessed they are.  Of all the nations of the earth, they have the God who willingly involves himself at every level of their lives.  Today, this Almighty Being invites me to experience that same level of intimacy, that personal day-to-day relationship with him.<br />
Take Away: What a privilege it is for the creature to have intimate fellowship with the Creator.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 09:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Watch out for the little things Deuteronomy 4: Don&#8217;t let your heart wander off. Moses is familiar with failure. For 40 years he’s struggled to keep this nation on the track God laid out for them. They’ve had both successes and failures. Now, with the end of his life in sight this man of God [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-exqnBPqQPgE/XWBkkB_BOaI/AAAAAAABAUI/ej8pBcMjKzgM9GQoPxuQCToA40wJHTMlQCKgBGAs/s1600/P6309596.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment Lighthouse</figcaption></figure><br />
Watch out for the little things<br />
Deuteronomy 4: Don&#8217;t let your heart wander off.<br />
Moses is familiar with failure.  For 40 years he’s struggled to keep this nation on the track God laid out for them.  They’ve had both successes and failures.  Now, with the end of his life in sight this man of God urges them to stay alert.  He wants them to be aware that spiritual disaster sometimes comes bit by bit rather than all at once.  It’s possible to become dully satisfied, to fail to be alert to negative changes in our attitudes, and to begin to drift spiritually.  The problem isn&#8217;t limited to individuals who temporarily lose sight of their goals.  Instead, such gradual failure can be national in nature.  It can also be generational when parents fail to pass their faith on to their children.  Having a current, connected, committed relationship to God is worth any effort it might take.  For those of us who are wonderfully blessed the danger isn&#8217;t that we’ll wake up tomorrow morning and declare that we aren&#8217;t interested in God anymore.  Nor is it that we’ll decide we aren&#8217;t going to attempt to influence our children to be genuine Christians.  The danger is that we will drift.  Moses says, &#8220;Don&#8217;t let it happen &#8212; be aware of the little things and the big things will take care of themselves.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: While we can’t stay self-focused all the time, once in a while it’s a good idea to do a spiritual checkup.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 10:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Don’t mess with God Deuteronomy 4: God, your God, is not to be trifled with &#8212; he&#8217;s a consuming fire, a jealous God. On one hand, I have the matchless grace of God: his patience, forgiveness, and good will toward me. On the other hand, there’s his justice: a hatred of sin and a love [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-gBaB2-WjEno/XWHGmw2qpZI/AAAAAAABAWY/RUg1u2aF6-wKULAVplRmWw8sSkx4DVZSQCKgBGAs/s1600/P6309601.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment</figcaption></figure><br />
Don’t mess with God<br />
Deuteronomy 4: God, your God, is not to be trifled with &#8212; he&#8217;s a consuming fire, a jealous God.<br />
On one hand, I have the matchless grace of God: his patience, forgiveness, and good will toward me.  On the other hand, there’s his justice: a hatred of sin and a love for righteousness.  I’d better not ever forget God&#8217;s justice.  Ultimately, God will have his way.  To presume on God&#8217;s grace is to ignore his justice.  Moses tells the people to be careful that they don&#8217;t mess with God.  They have made certain commitments that include promising to keep the ground rules God has laid out.  What’s true for them is true for me.  It isn&#8217;t that God requires perfect behavior from me &#8212; that&#8217;s beyond my reach.  However, he does require me to keep faith with him.  He requires me to live my life as a man of God and to be open to his correction and leadership in my life.  This relationship is not only my valued treasure, but is also my greatest responsibility.  It must be held in utmost reverence in my life.<br />
Take Away: Being a follower of God is a wonderful blessing – along with that blessing is an awesome responsibility.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 10:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s a remedy Deuteronomy 4: If you seek God…you&#8217;ll be able to find him if you&#8217;re serious, looking for him with your whole heart and soul. Again, Moses is no stranger to spiritual failure. As the leader of this people he’s seen repeated failure. Even as he warns them against trifling with God, even as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-19LfLsYmCgc/XWLcv-3HKHI/AAAAAAABAZI/_5_IuTsL7jcBQN4yHNv_kPOzPBMnU7EHQCKgBGAs/s1600/P6309601.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment</figcaption></figure><br />
There’s a remedy<br />
Deuteronomy 4: If you seek God…you&#8217;ll be able to find him if you&#8217;re serious, looking for him with your whole heart and soul.<br />
Again, Moses is no stranger to spiritual failure.  As the leader of this people he’s seen repeated failure.   Even as he warns them against trifling with God, even as he cautions them about having wandering hearts &#8212; even then, he knows that they&#8217;ll mess up again.  The thing is, not only is Moses familiar with spiritual failure, he’s also familiar with God&#8217;s grace.  Time after time he’s seen God reach out to these people in mercy, love, and forgiveness.  In this, Moses has learned some important things about the God who called to him from the burning bush decades earlier.  He tells them, &#8220;Before anything else, God is a compassionate God.&#8221;  Even if his warnings to these people go unheeded, God&#8217;s character will be unchanged.  People, even people who have miserably failed, who seek God whole-heartedly, find God.  There’s so much hope here that it takes our breath away.  There’s a remedy for spiritual failure.  There’s hope for the fallen.  There’s a God of Second Chances and if we seek him with all our hearts we’ll find him…and in finding him we’ll find hope and restoration.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Live long and prosper Deuteronomy 4: Obediently live by his rules and commands which I&#8217;m giving you today so that you&#8217;ll live well and your children after you. So how does it work? Is it that God has given me these rules and regulations and will pay me back with blessings if I keep them? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XiL45KfOBm0/XWLdbIFIgnI/AAAAAAABAZQ/HkdvAHb6qiAceg9xYEPYCtnEZaQ35tOKgCKgBGAs/s1600/PHOTO_20140630_145450.jpg" width="1600" height="902" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment</figcaption></figure><br />
Live long and prosper<br />
Deuteronomy 4: Obediently live by his rules and commands which I&#8217;m giving you today so that you&#8217;ll live well and your children after you.<br />
So how does it work?  Is it that God has given me these rules and regulations and will pay me back with blessings if I keep them?  I don&#8217;t think so.  God doesn&#8217;t lay down arbitrary rules just for the purpose of keeping me in line and he doesn’t treat me like a little child who’s rewarded with a stick of candy if I’m good.  His purposes for me are filled with grace and mercy.  If God says, &#8220;Don&#8217;t&#8221; I can be sure that it’s for my benefit and not his.  My Creator, who knows me better than I know myself says, &#8220;When I created you I hardwired some very specific things about you.  If you want your life to function at its best, here’s how you’re to live.&#8221;  Following these guidelines doesn&#8217;t mean life will be trouble free (after all, there’s that ugly business of the fall in the opening pages of my Bible) but it does mean that I’ll live the best, most satisfying and fulfilled life possible.  Not only that, but by living according to God&#8217;s plan, I’ll be teaching my children the best way to live.  The result will be that my kids will be more likely to adopt my approach to living in a relationship with God and their lives will also be better lived.<br />
Take Away: When I live God’s way, not only is my life better, but I also influence my children to live for God, resulting in their lives also being better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inherited blessings and personal decisions Deuteronomy 5: God didn&#8217;t just make this covenant with our parents; he made it also with us, with all of us who are alive right now. Some things are generational. That is, they’re passed along from parents to their children. Some of the promises of God are like that. Such [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pnn3X-4QNJQ/XWRA0FRvbTI/AAAAAAABAaY/ANQbD_D39HoVwR2v8ChqPBzXoSlJ5cDAgCKgBGAs/s1600/PHOTO_20140630_152307.jpg" width="1600" height="902" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment, WA &#8211; North Head Lighthouse</figcaption></figure><br />
Inherited blessings and personal decisions<br />
Deuteronomy 5: God didn&#8217;t just make this covenant with our parents; he made it also with us, with all of us who are alive right now.<br />
Some things are generational.  That is, they’re passed along from parents to their children.  Some of the promises of God are like that.  Such promises are made to a people, a nation.  Because of that it could be said that the children inherit the promise from their parents.  Some generational issues are not exactly the property of the children in the way those big promises are, but because of human nature, they almost seem to be.  Parents have an influence on their children.  If that influence is godly the result is very likely a positive one.  On the other hand, if that influence is negative, it’s very possible that things will begin to unravel more and more with each passing generation.  However, it doesn’t need to be that way.  The reason is that God remains active from one age to the next.  Moses tells his listeners that the relationship God had with their parents, a relationship that was broken by their disobedience, is now offered to them.  They won&#8217;t say, &#8220;We’re God&#8217;s people because our parents were God&#8217;s people.&#8221;  Instead, they’ll be his people because God has called them and they’ve responded to that invitation.  It’s a wonderful thing when parents pass their faith along to their children.  It is even better when the children actively respond making that relationship to God their very own.<br />
Take Away: A person who had godly parents is blessed, indeed.  Still, that person has the responsibility of claiming that blessing – that relationship- as their very own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[invitation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Step into the fire Deuteronomy 5: You were afraid, remember, of the fire and wouldn&#8217;t climb the mountain. It was over 40 years earlier but Moses remembers it like it was yesterday. God called him up to the mountain and in that place he had a powerful encounter with the Almighty. The people of Israel, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-TctZ_6d5UUs/XWWmiwhutyI/AAAAAAABAbM/irGUHywpo6IhXRXF2x7RX9keS7f1T_dVQCKgBGAs/s1600/PHOTO_20140630_153002.jpg" width="1600" height="902" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment, WA</figcaption></figure><br />
Step into the fire<br />
Deuteronomy 5: You were afraid, remember, of the fire and wouldn&#8217;t climb the mountain.<br />
It was over 40 years earlier but Moses remembers it like it was yesterday.  God called him up to the mountain and in that place he had a powerful encounter with the Almighty.  The people of Israel, however, didn&#8217;t want that experience.  They saw the billowing smoke and the fire of God and were afraid.  Because of that, they preferred that Moses be their representative while they stayed safely in the valley.  I wonder how many blessings I miss because it is easier to stay where I am than it is to have a raw, fire-filled encounter with the Lord.  To be fair, there’s more going on in my heart that just my wanting to stay comfortably unchanged.  After all, it’s frightening to come face to face with God.  To get that close to God is to step into the fire.  Intellectually I know it’s a good thing to meet God at that level.  In fact, I hunger for him in my spirit.  Still, I find myself hesitating to abandon myself to the fire of the Almighty.  But I must.  Otherwise, I condemn myself to a life that’s a shadow of what it could be.<br />
Take Away: When the Lord invites you to step into the fire accept that invitation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
