<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>learning &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/learning/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 20:07:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>learning &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 12:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evangelism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holy Spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Starting at the start 1Corinthians 2: God’s Spirit and our spirits in open communion. When Paul begins his ministry in the town of Corinth he knows that he needs to take it easy. These folks have little upon which to build. If he starts off dealing with the deeper things of God (like he does [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16039" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16039" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16039" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/photo.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16039" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Oysterville Historic Church</figcaption></figure>
<p>Starting at the start</p>
<p>1Corinthians 2: God’s Spirit and our spirits in open communion.</p>
<p>When Paul begins his ministry in the town of Corinth he knows that he needs to take it easy. These folks have little upon which to build. If he starts off dealing with the deeper things of God (like he does in his letter to the church at Rome) they’ll get nothing out of it and will likely turn back to their former way of life. Paul wisely sticks to the basics: Jesus died for our sins and is resurrected. This message speaks to their hearts and they give their lives to the Jesus they hear about from Paul. Still, there’s much more to learn about the Christian life. Now, though, they’re better prepared to learn of the things of God. The reason for this is that now the Holy Spirit is working in their lives. The Spirit, you see, isn’t into keeping secrets. Rather, he’s all about teaching us, leading us one step at a time into a better understanding of the things of God. To some extent we all start our spiritual journey by taking baby steps. It’s important that we, God’s people, remember that in dealing with those who haven’t a clue. There’s no need to argue the finer points of our faith with people who don’t yet have a handle on who Jesus is and what he’s done for us. We start our religious talk here: “Let me tell you about Jesus.” Once a person receives Jesus into their life, the Holy Spirit begins to commune with their spirit, helping them begin to grasp the deeper things of God.</p>
<p>Take Away: We need to start with the basics in dealing with people, and then trust the Holy Spirit to move them along at the pace he knows is right for them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-32/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 13:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s blessing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A work in progress Genesis 31: But the God of my father hasn’t changed, he’s still with me. Jacob the “heel grasper” has had the tables turned on him. His uncle, Laban, it seems, has some “use others as a stepping stone” tendencies himself. First, after Jacob has served him for seven years he’s tricked [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6zEMjt1CKOk/XNMxHkid9_I/AAAAAAAA7NE/xzbuxOPZBG0GyqaS07ZH_gGSKK2v1z1kQCKgBGAs/s1600/kohala%2Bmountain.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; Kohala Mountain &#8211; HI</figcaption></figure>
<p>A work in progress<br />
Genesis 31: But the God of my father hasn’t changed, he’s still with me.<br />
Jacob the “heel grasper” has had the tables turned on him. His uncle, Laban, it seems, has some “use others as a stepping stone” tendencies himself. First, after Jacob has served him for seven years he’s tricked into marrying the wrong daughter! He ends up with both of Laban’s daughters as wives in a tension-filled household. The sisters even involve their maids in a sort of pitiful “make babies” contest. Laban then makes a deal with Jacob to work in exchange for livestock. The deal turns into a sweet one for Jacob so Laban just changes the contract – not once, but repeatedly. Meanwhile, God’s at work. When Jacob is treated unfairly God gives him a plan that will keep things fair. It’s at this point that Jacob, thinking of Laban’s changing rules, says “God hasn’t changed – he said he would stand by me and he has.” Jacob hasn’t yet arrived but he’s a work in progress. The Lord’s using the experiences of his life to teach Jacob about his faithfulness. The lesson Jacob is learning is the same one I’m learning. It isn’t that I’m always fairly treated or that things always go as I think they should. The steadying factor in my life is that God never changes and is ever faithful to me.<br />
Take away: Life is often unfair and uncertain but God is always faithful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
