<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>optimism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/optimism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 18:54:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>optimism &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Micah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-micah-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Micah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sitting on the front row Micah 7: I’m sticking around to see what God will do. Micah says things are going downhill fast. He’s learned that he can’t trust his neighbor and that “neighborhoods and families are falling to pieces.” Clearly his day is a treacherous, difficult one. In the face of such perilous times [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-tn8xF2oe-MU/YRA4IqEZTWI/AAAAAAABK_k/EwwJwfi02WsuTAsadAiJa4FrJqwwCMj5QCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/P9179093.JPG" width="2048" height="1536" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Smoky Mountains</figcaption></figure><br />
Sitting on the front row<br />
Micah 7: I’m sticking around to see what God will do.<br />
Micah says things are going downhill fast.  He’s learned that he can’t trust his neighbor and that “neighborhoods and families are falling to pieces.”  Clearly his day is a treacherous, difficult one.  In the face of such perilous times Micah might be tempted to run for the hills or at least withdraw from society.  As anyone knows, Micah isn’t the only one who has faced difficult days.  Through the centuries godly men and women have gone through unbelievable hardship.  Often that hardship has been on a national or even worldwide scale.  At other times the hardship is close to home: a family or even personal struggle that fills our days with exhausting darkness.  In this passage, Micah is no “Pollyanna” who insists everything’s always “just fine.”  However, he is a man of faith.  As tempting as it might be to run and get away from all the wrong and uncertainty he sees, Micah declares he’s staying put.  Why?  It’s because he wants a front row seat to God’s redemption!  Today, we believers aren’t blind to the problems of life.  When things take a downturn we become anxious like everyone else.  However, in it all there’s a thread of optimism.  We believe God is still God and that he’s working in and through it all.  The end result is salvation.  We want a front row seat when that happens!<br />
Take Away: The people of the Lord are an optimistic people – and, for good reason!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can’t we all just get along? 1Corinthians 1: You must get along with each other. As I understand it, Corinth is a lot like the Old West of American movies. It’s a rough and tough place with lots of immorality. Paul comes preaching the Gospel of Jesus and many of these rowdy people become believers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16036" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16036" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16036" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140630_153002.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16036" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Cape Disappointment</figcaption></figure>
<p>Can’t we all just get along?</p>
<p>1Corinthians 1: You must get along with each other.</p>
<p>As I understand it, Corinth is a lot like the Old West of American movies. It’s a rough and tough place with lots of immorality. Paul comes preaching the Gospel of Jesus and many of these rowdy people become believers. For a year and a half (a long time for him) Paul stays, establishing them in the faith, teaching them what it means to be Christians. Now, he’s moved on, but has received word that things aren’t going very well in Corinth. One of the big problems is lack of unity. The Church of Corinth is splitting, not into two parts, but into several. In fact, if there’s an opportunity for discord, they’ve found it. Paul writes to them, saying, “You must get along with each other” and then both reasons with them and shames them into unity. As I consider this passage the call of Jesus to his followers to be one even as he and his Father are one feels quite distant. I share the Apostle’s concern as I look at the state of Christianity today. Sometimes “oneness” seems out of reach and I wonder if Paul was writing to the Church today what he would say. There is, though, a silver lining in these opening words of 1 Corinthians. It’s Paul’s sunny, optimistic approach to all this. He describes the church as “cleaned up by Jesus and set apart for a God filled life” and reminds them that Jesus “will never give up on you.” The Lord has already done a lot in their lives and Paul assures them that he’s going to keep right on working. So, as I read these words today I confess that the state of Christianity today concerns me. At the same time I’m infected by Paul’s optimistic view of the Church. It’s good to remember that God&#8217;s still at work today.</p>
<p>Take Away: The Lord is working inside the Church to make us one, and, as we cooperate with him, that’s just what he’s going to do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
