<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>authority &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/authority/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 14:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>authority &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-90/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 18:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congregations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pastoral responsibilities Jeremiah 23: You&#8217;ve scattered my sheep&#8230;you haven&#8217;t kept your eye on them. This passage is clergy oriented so pastor types like me need to sit up and take notice. The Lord’s displeased with the spiritual leaders of Jeremiah&#8217;s day. He pictures them as shepherds who are given the responsibility of caring for the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sph0CRefvqo/YFOJFHkic_I/AAAAAAABJj4/n4WFGk83q6M9291qcYfVGXOOSgpS5ZufwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Ketchikan%2B-%2B%2B8-18-2009%2B1-42-02%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Ketchikan, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Pastoral responsibilities<br />
Jeremiah 23: You&#8217;ve scattered my sheep&#8230;you haven&#8217;t kept your eye on them.<br />
This passage is clergy oriented so pastor types like me need to sit up and take notice.  The Lord’s displeased with the spiritual leaders of Jeremiah&#8217;s day.  He pictures them as shepherds who are given the responsibility of caring for the Lord’s flock.  These leaders are entrusted with the spiritual welfare of God&#8217;s flock but they’re betraying that confidence.  Instead of loving the flock, leading and caring for it, they&#8217;re taking advantage of things for personal gain.  In some cases they&#8217;re actually harming those they’re supposed to protect.  Otherwise, they&#8217;re neglecting them or even driving them away.  God’s disappointed in these leaders and is angry with them.  Sometimes I think that church people are too pastor oriented, giving way too much authority to the pastor, including letting the pastor do their thinking for them (or, standing on the sidelines and cheering as the pastor works him/herself to death &#8211; but that&#8217;s a subject for another day!).  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that there&#8217;s a strong biblical foundation that supports some having spiritual leadership.  The Lord has wired us in such a way that we look to some as &#8220;shepherds&#8221; acting as God&#8217;s representatives.   These leaders are to be servants who put the interests of those entrusted to their care before their own needs.  In this passage Jeremiah reminds me that as a pastor I&#8217;ve been honored with the position of leadership, but with that position has come accountability, not just to the congregation I serve, but to the Lord, himself.<br />
Take Away: Church leaders are to be good shepherds of the flock of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Obadiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-obadiah-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 21:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Obadiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good news for people who don’t find harp playing especially attractive Obadiah 1: A rule that honors God’s kingdom. The final words of Obadiah’s prophecy describe a coming golden age in which God’s people will be restored to their homeland. Beyond that, they’ll live righteously, in sync with the Lord’s purposes for them. Because of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 2048px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GCmKoeKMDrY/YPieEQhXAcI/AAAAAAABKzI/328QItQFGSAEwTJXcOpVpikl9jMnEJUgwCPcBGAsYHg/s2048/IMG_20130729_103117_189.jpg" width="2048" height="1155" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Tompkins Campground &#8211; Lawrenceville, PA</figcaption></figure><br />
Good news for people who don’t find harp playing especially attractive<br />
Obadiah 1: A rule that honors God’s kingdom.<br />
The final words of Obadiah’s prophecy describe a coming golden age in which God’s people will be restored to their homeland.  Beyond that, they’ll live righteously, in sync with the Lord’s purposes for them.  Because of that they&#8217;ll be put in charge, ruling even over their old enemies of Edom.  Their rule will not be that of a conquering nation, grinding their enemies into the ground, but a fair and just one, representative of their God who loves all human beings.  I find it interesting that the Apostle Paul reflects this concept in his second letter to Timothy.  Paul writes: “If we died with him, we will also live with him; if we endure, we will also reign with him.”  At the very beginning of the Bible I see Adam and Eve who are placed in dominion over the earth.  In this passage from Obadiah, I find a promised brighter day in which God’s people rule justly, throwing off the old animosities.  Then, I see Paul looking forward to the return of Christ and his righteous people ruling with him.  I don’t claim to understand all that might include, but it sounds like God has more in store for his people than merely sitting on a cloud playing a harp.<br />
Take Away: As a people of the Lord we’re to reflect his love for all human beings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not acting like a bully Zechariah 1: &#8230;Godless nations that act as if they own the whole world. About half of this book of Zechariah contains descriptions of visions the prophet is given. In the first vision the Lord tells Zechariah that he’s angry with “godless nations that act as if they own the whole [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15546" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15546" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15546" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/IMG_1788.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15546" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Tombigbee State Park &#8211; Tupelo, MS &#8211; road to the park</figcaption></figure><br />
Not acting like a bully<br />
Zechariah 1: &#8230;Godless nations that act as if they own the whole world.<br />
About half of this book of Zechariah contains descriptions of visions the prophet is given.  In the first vision the Lord tells Zechariah that he’s angry with “godless nations that act as if they own the whole world.”  Not only is the Lord angry, he’s about to do something about it.  The Lord had given the mega-powers of the region authority over Israel but they went too far, crushing that tiny nation without any show of mercy.  The Lord says he was angry with Israel, but now he&#8217;s very angry with these nations that acted without mercy.  The vision is intended to condemn those world powers while comforting powerless Israel.  I’m reminded as I read these words that I live in a nation that is a world power.  We have the economic and military might to dominate others.  The vision of the prophet speaks to me, not as one of the oppressed but instead, as one of the powerful.  God has a history of looking out for the needs of the powerless and of holding the powerful accountable.  We aren’t to go around the world flexing our muscles like a bully who always has to get his own way.  The truth is that we don’t own the whole world and we had better remember who does!<br />
Take Away: It’s God’s world and we’re accountable to him for how we live in his world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on John</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-john-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 12:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of John]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resurrection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-john-11/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Its Jesus verses death John 11: Lazarus, come out! I’ve heard it said that Jesus specified that Lazarus “come out” of the grave because, had he just given the command to “come out” that there would have been a general resurrection. Personally, I think that’s more of a poetical take on this remarkable event than [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15866" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15866" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="600" class="size-large wp-image-15866" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1024x640.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-300x188.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-768x480.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486-1536x960.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/12/P6199486.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15866" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mt Rainier National Park</figcaption></figure>
<p>Its Jesus verses death</p>
<p>John 11: Lazarus, come out!</p>
<p>I’ve heard it said that Jesus specified that Lazarus “come out” of the grave because, had he just given the command to “come out” that there would have been a general resurrection.  Personally, I think that’s more of a poetical take on this remarkable event than a realistic one.  Still, I understand the statement of faith in that concept.  This is an act of absolute authority over death.  Jesus doesn’t even touch the dead body.  He, in fact, never enters the tomb.  From outside, after a public prayer, Jesus merely shouts out the command and Lazarus is resurrected.  I can’t imagine any more powerful demonstration of authority over death than this one.  Well, almost.  Soon, an even more convincing event will take place.  For now though, I’m happy to be reminded of this wonderful truth.  Any time Jesus faces death, Jesus wins.  Glory!</p>
<p>Take Away: One hope of all Christians is the hope of life after death.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-1-corinthians-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stop acting like babies! 1 Corinthians 3: Are you really much different than a babe at the breast, content only when everything’s going your way? Only an enemy or a dear friend can say the things Paul says to the church at Corinth. Their behavior, he says is “infantile” and “unscriptural” and Paul is “completely [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16041" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16041" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16041" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/PHOTO_20140703_211659.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16041" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Long Beach, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Stop acting like babies!</p>
<p>1 Corinthians 3: Are you really much different than a babe at the breast, content only when everything’s going your way?</p>
<p>Only an enemy or a dear friend can say the things Paul says to the church at Corinth. Their behavior, he says is “infantile” and “unscriptural” and Paul is “completely frustrated” by them. The problem is their infighting. People are choosing sides and jockeying for position. They approach every situation from a “me” point of view, judging everything by what they’ll get out of it and whether or not whatever it is in play will suit their tastes. Paul, their friend, tells them to stop acting like babies and get over themselves. He reminds them that it’s all about Jesus, not them. It would be nice to think that the “baby problem” is unique to Corinth but you and I both know it’s not. It’s human nature to measure everything by our own desires and tastes. On one hand, there’s a place for that. After all, we bring unique experiences, knowledge, and insights to life. There’s a place for us to express ourselves and let our preferences be known. I don’t think the problem at Corinth is that some folks like the preaching of Apollos better than they like the preaching of Paul. The problem is that individuals selfishly insist on getting their own way and focus their energies on forming coalitions so they’ll have more say than others. Paul tells them to cut it out and remember that the church isn’t theirs in the first place. When I’m manipulating things behind the scenes or openly demanding my rights I’m dislodging Jesus from his place as the Head of the Church.</p>
<p>Take Away: Like it or not, it’s not all about me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Corinthians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 11:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2 Corinthians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preaching]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-corinthians-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The voice of authority 2Corinthians 10: I write in the gentle but firm spirit of Christ. Paul’s first letter was rather stern and was, in general, well received. Most of the church at Corinth took it to heart and responded positively to it. However, we see here that not everyone received it in the spirit [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16104" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16104" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-16104" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685-768x574.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685-1536x1148.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/IMG_2685.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16104" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along Oregon Hwy 101 &#8211; north of Florence &#8211; Heceta Head Lighthouse</figcaption></figure>
<p>The voice of authority </p>
<p>2Corinthians 10: I write in the gentle but firm spirit of Christ.</p>
<p>Paul’s first letter was rather stern and was, in general, well received.  Most of the church at Corinth took it to heart and responded positively to it.  However, we see here that not everyone received it in the spirit in which it was written.  Some complain that Paul should mind his own business and that “them and God” will work things out.  Others point out that there are leaders aside from Paul in their number who hold different opinions from him.  Yet others say that Paul writes tough, but in person he’s not very impressive and his letters shouldn’t be treated as though they’re the final word on anything.  The Apostle takes all this on in this passage.  He wants them to understand that he’s being as patient with those who oppose him as possible, but that his words aren’t his own, but carry with them the very authority of Christ.  He hasn’t tried to manipulate them and he hasn’t avoided the more sticky points.  He knows that there’s opposition both outside and inside the church.  After all, his teachings are radical and run counter to the world’s way of doing things.  He’s not just putting band aids on severe wounds.  Rather, he’s in a battle to the death with an ungodly culture that still has a foothold in the Church.  All this he does under the direct authority of Christ.  If they want to hear from someone with authority, he’s it!  Paul’s self-assurance here is breathtaking.  In spite of his obvious weaknesses he pulls no punches in claiming authority in this situation.  I’m sure there’s a case to be made for humility and for letting people work things out between them and God.  Here, though, I’m reminded that sometimes God chooses to use unlikely people to state his message.  This, I think, is different than a preacher taking a text and, using its authority, delivering a sermon.  This kind of prophetic voice is seldom heard, but when it happens people tend to recognize it.  Beyond recognizing it, we’d better pay attention to it.</p>
<p>Take Away: It’s the Lord who gives authority to his message.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ephesians</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 10:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ephesians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-ephesians/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Church: Christ at work in the world Ephesians 1: The church, you see, is not peripheral to the world, the world is peripheral to the church. Paul&#8217;s writing is filled with superlatives as he begins his letter to the church at Ephesus. God’s people, he tells us, have within our grasp “the immensity of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16134" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16134" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-16134" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/11/P7209619.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16134" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along Oregon Hwy 101 &#8211; north of Florence</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Church: Christ at work in the world </p>
<p>Ephesians 1: The church, you see, is not peripheral to the world, the world is peripheral to the church.</p>
<p>Paul&#8217;s writing is filled with superlatives as he begins his letter to the church at Ephesus.  God’s people, he tells us, have within our grasp “the immensity of this glorious way of life” and it’s with “utter extravagance” that the Lord bestows his gifts on his people.  He tells us that all this comes from one Source: Jesus Christ.  Jesus makes all the difference in (and out of) the world.  It’s not “here and there” or “them and us.”  The glorious plan and possibility is that in Christ everything comes together.  This great Unifier works through and with a specific group of people who have made him Lord of their lives.  That group, we’re told, is the Church.  Obviously, Paul’s not talking about a denomination here and he’s certainly not thinking of some local body of believers.  This is the “capitol-C” Church.  It’s through this body, “his body,” that Jesus is bringing everything together.  As I look at the Church today, it’s a mistake for me to only focus on its failings.  Jesus sees the Church as his body and as the hope of the world.  Even as I acknowledge its failures, I’d better remember its purpose and the source of its power and authority in the world.</p>
<p>Take Away: God has chosen to work through the Church to bring salvation to the world.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Titus</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-titus-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Titus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-titus-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being the leader God calls one to be Titus 2: You’re in charge. Don’t let anyone put you down. Here in Crete Titus is operating in new territory. He’s been part of Paul’s team, traveling from place to place. Sometimes he’s gone out on special assignment, delivering a message or the like, but still operating [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16238" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16238" style="width: 765px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16238" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753-765x1024.jpg" alt="" width="765" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753-765x1024.jpg 765w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753-224x300.jpg 224w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753-768x1028.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753-1148x1536.jpg 1148w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/IMG_2753.jpg 1530w" sizes="(max-width: 765px) 100vw, 765px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16238" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Redwoods National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Being the leader God calls one to be</p>
<p>Titus 2: You’re in charge. Don’t let anyone put you down.</p>
<p>Here in Crete Titus is operating in new territory. He’s been part of Paul’s team, traveling from place to place. Sometimes he’s gone out on special assignment, delivering a message or the like, but still operating under Paul’s wing. Now, though, things are different. Yes, he’s been appointed by Paul to this task, but, by and large he’s on his own. The Apostle reminds him of what he’s supposed to do, but this time, it’s Titus, by himself, meeting with congregations and organizing their leadership. It may be that Paul knows Titus well enough to know that he’s going to struggle a bit with this assignment. Even as he spells out Titus’ responsibilities Paul makes it a point to tell him that he’s in charge and as he meets with these budding congregations he needs to be ready to stand his ground concerning the kind of leaders they need and the kind of people they’re supposed to be. Here, again, I find myself considering a leadership principle. Humbleness is critical if one is to be the servant-leader Christian leaders are called to be. At the same time though, if one has been called to and granted authority for leadership by the Lord, that individual needs to have a firm grasp on that leadership. Most everyone recognizes God-called leadership. The thing is that while most recognize and appreciate it, a few are threatened by it and will challenge or manipulate it if they think they can get away with it. A Christian leader must recognize this and be ready to stand firm in his or her calling in a Christ-like manner.</p>
<p>Take Away: Christian leaders are servant-leaders, but they do carry with them a sense of authority.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Genesis</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-genesis-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Genesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/2011/09/26/4064/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The mystery man of the Bible Genesis 14: Melchizedek, king of Salem&#8230;blessed him. I’ve always thought of Abraham’s rescue of Lot as a fairly localized situation and that their enemy was a neighboring warlord. However, I’ve just realized that Kedorlaomer and his allies were a big deal: a conquering army from Babylon; a world power. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dVWPC31TshU/XL-QKPUT2vI/AAAAAAAA6xM/_GcGeM9WI18UfIHmvpWJY1ByaFAcjxnzwCKgBGAs/s1600/P7268805.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Watkins Glen State Park, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mystery man of the Bible<br />
Genesis 14: Melchizedek, king of Salem&#8230;blessed him.<br />
I’ve always thought of Abraham’s rescue of Lot as a fairly localized situation and that their enemy was a neighboring warlord. However, I’ve just realized that Kedorlaomer and his allies were a big deal: a conquering army from Babylon; a world power. The Canaanite rulers didn’t have a chance against them. When Abram hears what&#8217;s happened, he mounts a rescue effort with just 318 people. Years before Gideon’s 300 will win a battle against an insurmountable force Abraham mounts an amazing rescue by the authority of God. As he returns from that battle the Canaanite kings salute him and tell him to keep the spoils of his unprecedented victory, but Abraham turns them down, commenting that he doesn’t want people to think it was the Canaanites who made him rich. Then, out of nowhere, the mysterious Melchizedek, King of the town named Peace (or Salem) makes an appearance. He comes to bless Abraham and to praise God for what he&#8217;s done. In turn, Abraham recognizes this hitherto unknown man as a spiritual authority and gives him a tithe of all the plunder. I’m sure we’re talking about wagon loads of stuff here. In centuries to come both the Psalmist and the writer of Hebrews revisit this incident. They remind us that, even for the Jewish people, not all spiritual authority is based on lineage. In fact, the highest authority is when the Lord grants it in a direct way. I’m not ready to get bound up in whether or not Melchizedek is Jesus making an Old Testament appearance, but he does become the poster boy for God’s granting direct authority to the person of his choosing, credentials or not. That’s real important in our understanding how Jesus is the High Priest of Christians through the ages.<br />
Take away: As we read our Old Testaments it isn’t unusual to find God preparing the way for his Son, Jesus, to come to the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Deuteronomy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-deuteronomy-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 14:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Deuteronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prophets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The ultimate Prophet Deuteronomy 18: God, your God, is going to raise up a prophet for you…a prophet like me. It’s the nature of things for people to want a &#8220;word from the Lord.&#8221; Even when all the other aspects of religion are established and operating we want to hear from the Lord. In this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F1maiTFlXOs/XXb-laWnqVI/AAAAAAABBB8/VmCHZgVILiUR9BRFZ35zn1SLRcqymk-vgCKgBGAs/s1600/IMG_2685.JPG" width="1600" height="1195" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Along Oregon Hwy 101 &#8211; north of Florence &#8211; Heceta Head Lighthouse</figcaption></figure><br />
The ultimate Prophet<br />
Deuteronomy 18: God, your God, is going to raise up a prophet for you…a prophet like me.<br />
It’s the nature of things for people to want a &#8220;word from the Lord.&#8221;  Even when all the other aspects of religion are established and operating we want to hear from the Lord.  In this passage Moses addresses this.  The priests are doing their jobs and the Levites are in place but Moses knows that without the &#8220;prophetic voice&#8221; that the people will be tempted to turn to the occult in an effort to touch something, someone, beyond themselves.  In addressing this issue, and as a true prophet himself, Moses speaks beyond his own knowledge.  He understands that the Lord is promising to send someone who will speak with prophetic authority, but he doesn&#8217;t know just how great and complete that Voice will be.  Out of their number God will anoint the ultimate prophet.  In fact, this prophet will be the very Word of God.   Throughout their history, these Hebrew people will hear the message of many prophets, but the ultimate prophet, the One who will proclaim God&#8217;s message with absolute authority, is none other than Jesus, the Son of God.<br />
Take Away: In Jesus we not only hear the Word of God, but we meet the Word of God in the flesh.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
