<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>grace &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/grace/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:54:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>grace &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good theology from Johnny Cash Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom. The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen. At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-E_1VkmdhITE/X6MTYEsK8zI/AAAAAAABHew/MSgFGd12GEQ69iWj9UBv0nsDUHrDw8ehgCPcBGAsYHg/s400/22rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
Good theology from Johnny Cash<br />
Ecclesiastes 10: Dead flies in perfume make it stink, and a little foolishness decomposes much wisdom.<br />
The &#8220;dead flies&#8221; line always struck me as funny, especially when I first read it as a teen.  At that time I didn&#8217;t take time to try to understand the meaning of it so I just smiled and moved on.  A person can say and do a lot of wise things in their life, but one blunder can pretty much ruin it all.  I&#8217;ve seen that happen with presidents and pastors; with CEO&#8217;s and secretaries.  When my son got his first driver&#8217;s license I commented to him that many drivers only make one mistake in their lives, and it&#8217;s their last.  Car wrecks can be unforgiving.  It’s true of other life situations too.  A man can be a good husband and father for 30 years and then get involved with someone for a brief fling that ruins all those years of faithfulness.  While I’m a big believer in second chances and grace I also know that a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; can ruin a lot of godly living.  Johnny Cash wasn&#8217;t singing a hymn when he sang, &#8220;I keep a close watch on this heart of mine&#8230;because you&#8217;re mine I walk the line&#8221; but his words do apply in that sense.  I don&#8217;t want a few &#8220;dead flies&#8221; to ruin a lifetime of faithfulness.<br />
Take Away: Watch out for “dead flies” in your life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-100/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 02:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reason]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No reboot necessary Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white. If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage. Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals. The Lord says [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fOD5LyiXRhA/X7Gv87Av5OI/AAAAAAABHoE/Jjk_2wAXWgwN2cF_RQcN9a5l64zKyU6UACPcBGAsYHg/s400/06garden_of_gods.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
No reboot necessary<br />
Isaiah 1: If your sins are blood-red, they&#8217;ll be snow-white.<br />
If I have the idea that the prophets are all about denunciation and condemnation I need to spend some time with this passage.  Yes, God is fed up with their religious charades; their going-through-the-motions spirituality; their under-the-table shady deals.  The Lord says he’s going to put a stop to it.  However, it doesn&#8217;t have to be with defeat, misery, and destruction.  &#8220;Let&#8217;s be reasonable about this,&#8221; the Almighty says, &#8220;we can fix this, and when I’m finished things will be better than before.&#8221;  All it takes is their being sensible and cooperating with God.  This isn&#8217;t about having a sword hanging over their necks.  It&#8217;s about grace and mercy, not justice.  It&#8217;s still true today.  If God wants to do away with us it’s his right and it’s just what we deserve.  However, rather than hitting the &#8220;delete button&#8221; on humanity he offers restoration.  This passage is filled with sunlight and hope.  Plus that, it&#8217;s a genuine offer from Heaven&#8217;s Throne to each of us.  Come on; let&#8217;s be reasonable about this&#8230;God can fix things, making them right between us and Him.  It&#8217;s too good an offer to refuse.<br />
Take Away: Rather than a re-start of humanity the Lord wants to restore us.  That’s grace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-118/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 05:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Staying connected Isaiah 15: A Message concerning Moab. Lest it appear that Isaiah has it in only for Babylon, we must note that a quick journey through this portion of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy brings to light God&#8217;s displeasure with several other groups. There’s Philistia, Moab, Ethiopia, Egypt, Tyre and others. In other words, not only have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 929px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hofV-wDSOPk/X8lLo-K7oDI/AAAAAAABHwo/GUfwjMwQ6d0aEjEM-8ZgHcb9EAhSWF19gCPcBGAsYHg/s929/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-55-05%2BPM.JPG" width="929" height="743" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
Staying connected<br />
Isaiah 15: A Message concerning Moab.<br />
Lest it appear that Isaiah has it in only for Babylon, we must note that a quick journey through this portion of Isaiah&#8217;s prophecy brings to light God&#8217;s displeasure with several other groups.  There’s Philistia, Moab, Ethiopia, Egypt, Tyre and others.  In other words, not only have God&#8217;s people gotten themselves in trouble with the Lord for their sin, they’re surrounded by sinful nations that would like nothing better than to wipe Israel off the map.  (Somehow that sounds familiar &#8212; oh yes, we heard something like this on the news this morning!)  Across the centuries God&#8217;s people have survived only by the grace of God.  Their own failures have brought judgment and their enemies have posed a very real threat to their existence.  Today, that’s still true for all of God&#8217;s people.  We Christians believe we’ve been &#8220;grafted in&#8221; and are, by faith, children of Abraham.  As his people, God holds us to a high standard and we must not forget that.  Also, as did they, we live in hostile territory.  For some believers, this is literally true and for all believers it’s spiritually true.  We’re surrounded by that which would destroy our life in the Lord.  Israel&#8217;s only hope is to reconnect with God.  Today, our remaining &#8220;in Christ&#8221; is also our only hope.<br />
Take Away: Our journey through life takes us through some dangerous territory, our only security is in the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-122/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face. Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself. I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bVc5ehr8RoQ/X869s_8TVCI/AAAAAAABHyE/YYt3gG1zx3w_7ioz8H5QaHDZA_YqWHBZACPcBGAsYHg/s1280/lost-maples-st-pk-tx%2B11-27-2006%2B3-27-46%2BPM.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Lost Maples State Park, TX &#8211; 2006</figcaption></figure><br />
This prescription works for both the farsighted and the nearsighted<br />
Isaiah 25: And God will wipe the tears from every face.<br />
Isaiah&#8217;s words contain a great deal of condemnation and his target is not only the enemies of Israel, but Israel, herself.  I get lost in it all and am not sure whether the prophet is talking to specific people at a specific moment in history or if he’s slipped into &#8220;prophetic perfect tense&#8221; in which he speaks of the future as though it has already happened.  It may be that he’s speaking on multiple levels of a near future and a distant future with the same words.  At times like this, I take the easy way out and focus on my devotional reading, asking, &#8220;What’s this saying to me right now?&#8221;  As I read this part of Isaiah I can&#8217;t help but think of the book of Revelation which contains almost the exact same words.  In fact, I&#8217;m pretty sure the Revelator is reminded of these words even as he promises the glorious &#8220;no tears&#8221; day.  My conclusion is that whether we’re thinking about the broken people of Isaiah&#8217;s day or persecuted Christians of John&#8217;s day or hurting people today that God&#8217;s message is one of comfort and hope.  Some of that hope is contemporary hope: what God is about to do.  At the same time some of that hope is out there in the uncertain future when the Lord wraps up history and brings a new reality into existence.  I’m not sure about just who it is Isaiah is thinking about in this passage, but I do see here a wonderful theme of God&#8217;s mercy and grace.<br />
Take Away: Yesterday, today, and forever the Lord remains merciful and gracious to his people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-129/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grace as far as the eye can see Isaiah 30: Cry for help and you&#8217;ll find it&#8217;s grace and more grace. Things are a mess for the people of God. They’re living apart from the God who gave them life. Their nation is under considerable threat and they’re looking for help from everywhere but from [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 944px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0sXqhNs4SEQ/X9fPDoe5kxI/AAAAAAABH4Q/MACcFtU8BK8p4lKyL6IzD4RJBFdoiPGiACPcBGAsYHg/s944/P4141689.JPG" width="944" height="676" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; near Brennan, TX</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Grace as far as the eye can see<br />
Isaiah 30: Cry for help and you&#8217;ll find it&#8217;s grace and more grace.<br />
Things are a mess for the people of God. They’re living apart from the God who gave them life. Their nation is under considerable threat and they’re looking for help from everywhere but from the Lord. Things look hopeless and, if they continue as they are, that is just the way it is. Still, through Isaiah, the Almighty reaches out to them. Isaiah says &#8220;He&#8217;s waiting around to be gracious to you.&#8221; This is as powerful a vision of God&#8217;s grace as you&#8217;ll ever find apart from the cross. If the Lord is waiting for me to mess up so he can &#8220;get me&#8221; the wait would be long over. Instead, I see here a picture of God Almighty patiently waiting for me to look his way. When I do that, he doesn&#8217;t tell me I&#8217;ve been bad and that I deserve what I’m about to get. Rather, he tells me he loves me and wants to transform my life in wonderful ways. The only thing that stands between me and the grace of God is, well, me! When I bring my messed up life to him he begins to pour grace out: bucketfuls of it! How about you? Have you been afraid to come to God because you think he’s just waiting to send you to hell? If so, this passage contains some of the best news you&#8217;ll ever find. When you turn to the Lord you find an ocean sized portion of grace just for you.<br />
Take Away: The only thing standing between you and grace is you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-131/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 07:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[righteousness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To do list Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right. The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one. Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda. Who can survive such a purging? How does a person prepare for it? Isaiah has a list for all who will [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z6lieSoE49o/X9pXgBBGPBI/AAAAAAABH48/E9zKMFyWXN8_ama67n-b-yXf2dZap3JqwCPcBGAsYHg/s1280/P5291839.JPG" width="1280" height="960" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Buffalo River, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure><br />
To do list<br />
Isaiah 33: The answer&#8217;s simple: live right.<br />
The picture Isaiah paints isn’t a pleasant one.  Things are going to get bad as a firestorm of God&#8217;s wrath is on the agenda.  Who can survive such a purging?  How does a person prepare for it?  Isaiah has a list for all who will listen: &#8220;live right, speak the truth, despise exploitation, refuse bribes, reject violence, and avoid evil amusements.&#8221;  This, he says, is the way through the storm, the way to stability and satisfaction.  I know that some things about God are complicated and it takes a lifetime of serious study and application to master them.  However, some things are pretty straight forward and this list is an example of that.  The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;  That is, we can drop the excuses and commit ourselves to, as best we can, doing the things we know we should do.  That isn&#8217;t all there is to it, but it’s a pretty good start.  Soon enough we&#8217;ll realize that our best isn&#8217;t good enough, but it does turn us in the right direction and with that done, we&#8217;ll find ourselves aligned with God&#8217;s grace which is freely extended to us.<br />
Take Away: The Lord expects us to &#8220;live right.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-136/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God’s wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hezekiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Extraordinary favors from God Isaiah 38: I&#8217;ll add fifteen years to your life. Hezekiah is one of the good guys who trusts in the Lord; a king who has his priorities right. When he gets sick Isaiah visits him and tells Hezekiah that this is it, he needs to prepare to die. Hezekiah prays a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PSQ9sk2Y90A/X-Dnbm8wv3I/AAAAAAABH8I/3dX3ldncO2EH_vCGsknsQzXJ8T8IbHyaQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/P5281811.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2007 &#8211; Blanchard Caverns, Arkansas</center></figcaption></figure>
<p>Extraordinary favors from God<br />
Isaiah 38: I&#8217;ll add fifteen years to your life.<br />
Hezekiah is one of the good guys who trusts in the Lord; a king who has his priorities right. When he gets sick Isaiah visits him and tells Hezekiah that this is it, he needs to prepare to die. Hezekiah prays a simple, trusting prayer that touches the heart of God who grants the king fifteen more years of life. As I read this story I remember that my life is in the hands of God. He has the final say. In Hezekiah&#8217;s case, the illness that comes to him is a natural one but God trumps it by granting him a supernatural healing. I know that the Lord doesn&#8217;t always do that, even in the lives of people just as good and trusting as Hezekiah. Still, this incident reminds me that I can ask for extraordinary favors from the Lord while trusting him in his wisdom to answer according to his grace.<br />
Take Away: Sometimes, the Lord’s answer is “yes.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-179/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 15:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confession]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal responsibility]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Admitting personal failure Isaiah 59: There&#8217;s nothing wrong with God; the wrong is in you. Ever since Adam blamed Eve, and in reality, blamed God, people have tried to pass the buck for their sin. &#8220;God’s too strict&#8221; or &#8220;the temptation is too great&#8221; or some other lame excuse is used as a defense for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vGIx3Q6GAtU/YBhLIZHubpI/AAAAAAABIY4/cZU9cMnom_gFHFYdUL-eMy53xvjdyXx-QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/GSMNP-Cades-Cove%2B5-23-2008%2B9-47-48%2BAM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><center>2008 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; Cades Cove &#8211; Abrams Falls</center></figcaption></figure><br />
Admitting personal failure<br />
Isaiah 59: There&#8217;s nothing wrong with God; the wrong is in you.<br />
Ever since Adam blamed Eve, and in reality, blamed God, people have tried to pass the buck for their sin.  &#8220;God’s too strict&#8221; or &#8220;the temptation is too great&#8221; or some other lame excuse is used as a defense for spiritual failure.  As a pastor I&#8217;ve probably heard more than most.  I immediately think of lines like: &#8220;I was absent from church for two weeks and no one called me&#8221; or &#8220;the church just isn&#8217;t as spiritual as it ought to be.&#8221;  Isaiah has heard enough and he reacts especially to excuses that place the blame for spiritual failure on the Lord.  He tells his people that the thing that has come between them and God is none other than themselves.  It’s their sin that has messed things up and until they admit that things are only going to get worse.  Listen, I know that the church has a responsibility to reach out to people; even people who know better than what they’re doing.   The church is accountable before God when it fails along this line.  However, Isaiah&#8217;s message places the blame for personal failure directly on the shoulders of the one who willfully sins against God.  Don&#8217;t blame God, the church, your spouse, your boss, or your friends for your sin.  Take responsibility for your own actions, confess, and make it right.   You&#8217;ll find that the grace of God is sufficient and that brings a whole lot more peace than making excuses does!<br />
Take Away: Take responsibility and make things right.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Isaiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-isaiah-182/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Isaiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How wonderful to have a message of hope Isaiah 61: The Spirit of God, the Master, is on me because God anointed me. Through the years of his ministry Isaiah brings a variety of messages to his people. Often, his words are those of warning and condemnation. At other times, his sermons contain wonderful words [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BH_aNhTpPaQ/YBw99ElcDWI/AAAAAAABIaA/1llJadP2sx8I1yRDenrZ6qfU068KzNILQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Smoky-mountains-national-park-Elkmont-Campground%2B5-18-2008%2B5-34-19%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1278" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2008 &#8211; Great Smoky Mountains National Park &#8211; Elkmont Campground</figcaption></figure><br />
How wonderful to have a message of hope<br />
Isaiah 61: The Spirit of God, the Master, is on me because God anointed me.<br />
Through the years of his ministry Isaiah brings a variety of messages to his people.  Often, his words are those of warning and condemnation.  At other times, his sermons contain wonderful words of hope and comfort.  That’s the kind of message we hear from him in this passage.  Isaiah considers it an honor to be commissioned and empowered to preach good news to a people who are living as captives in Babylon.  His message is one of encouragement to the poor and heartbroken; to those who mourn and wilt under the burden they carry.  This message is so powerful that hundreds of years later Jesus selects Isaiah&#8217;s words to describe his own ministry.  The message of hope is Isaiah&#8217;s and then it’s Jesus&#8217; and now, well, now it’s mine.  The proclamation of God&#8217;s favor, his healing mercy and grace, isn’t just Isaiah&#8217;s and, while it uniquely belongs to Jesus, I can lay claim on it too.  For those in Babylonian captivity and for those today that are bound by sin, this is good news.<br />
Take Away: In Christ, we have Good News for people desperately in need of some Good News.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-66/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free will]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have it your way Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running. Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them. They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5hjy4W45ajM/YDQRSicp-ZI/AAAAAAABIs0/KZRzd4xM9PENfeleyEkCY0gkweOPPsSrQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/100_0567.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Big Lagoon State Park, FL</figcaption></figure><br />
Have it your way<br />
Jeremiah 2: When things go badly, they don&#8217;t hesitate to come running.<br />
Jeremiah&#8217;s charge against his people is that they’re addicted to pagan gods and that they run this way and that way in search of something that will satisfy them.  They ignore God until things go wrong, then they don&#8217;t hesitate to run to him for help.  The Lord says, &#8220;You&#8217;ve plenty of gods, let them take care of you; let them save you from the bad times.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve seen it.  I&#8217;ve known people who know God&#8217;s purpose for them but don&#8217;t want any part of it.  When the wheels come off, they “get religion” and want God to rescue them.  I know the Lord is gracious and forgiving and long suffering.  As one of his people I want those qualities to be evident in my life.  At the same time, there’s a fair word of warning in this.  At some point, the Lord yields to our decisions and allows us to have it our way.  We shouldn’t presume on the grace of God.<br />
Take Away: Thank the Lord for his grace – at the same time don’t be so foolish as to see just how far you can push the Almighty.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
