<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>spiritual warfare &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/spiritual-warfare/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 19:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>spiritual warfare &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 1 Samuel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-1-samuel-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 03:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 1Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goliath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[King David]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual warfare]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do I really believe the battle belongs to God? 1 Samuel 17: Everyone gathered here will learn that God doesn&#8217;t save by means of sword or spear. The battle belongs to God. &#8220;This very day God is handing you over to me.&#8221; So says David as he prepares for battle with Goliath. For us this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fqE2XMp3SB0/Xeq_Xd8KLYI/AAAAAAABC-8/r_tKZ0qELt4mmNI03bw9Qcu8Cywzf0mvQCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/100_4230.JPG" width="1600" height="901" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2015 &#8211; Wisconsin Ducks &#8211; Wisconsin Dells, WI</figcaption></figure><br />
Do I really believe the battle belongs to God?<br />
1 Samuel 17: Everyone gathered here will learn that God doesn&#8217;t save by means of sword or spear.  The battle belongs to God.<br />
&#8220;This very day God is handing you over to me.&#8221; So says David as he prepares for battle with Goliath.  For us this is a nifty story, one of the most memorable in the entire Bible.  For David, well, this is the real deal.  Before him stands a giant of a man who intends to disembowel him.  David has chosen a sling and some stones as his weapon of choice but he knows this fight isn&#8217;t really about weapons at all. This is a spiritual event, and he correctly identifies it as such: &#8220;I come to you in the name of God-of-the-Angel-Armies.&#8221;  In spite of the real and material threat, David correctly classifies it as a real and spiritual matter.  As much as I like this story, do I really apply it to my own &#8220;real and material&#8221; life?  Am I good at praying and trusting God only in theory or do I do it into practice, where the &#8220;rubber meets the road&#8221;?  Instead of viewing conflicts as spiritual events, do I rush to defend myself &#8212; or call a meeting to plot a strategy for getting my way &#8212; or throw my weight around &#8212; or manipulate the people involved?  To do so is to view the issue at hand as one of &#8220;swords and spears&#8221; rather than as a spiritual battle that belongs to God.  When I do that kind of stuff, I may get my way in the short run, but it will always come at a price to me and to others.  Then again, I may not get my way at all and the giant may just win, leaving me fatally wounded.<br />
Take Away: It’s a real challenge to retrain oneself to recognize spiritual battles for what they are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nehemiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nehemiah-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 19:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nehemiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opposition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual warfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[threats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When the enemy throws everything at you Nehemiah 6: I prayed, &#8220;Give me strength.&#8221; As the rebuilding project nears completion the enemies of Nehemiah desperately try to stop it. Since Nehemiah doesn&#8217;t fall for their &#8220;let&#8217;s meet&#8221; ploy they try slandering him. Their rumor is that Nehemiah’s about to set up a private kingdom behind [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ecCLldtDks/XvZb2w0q4SI/AAAAAAABFU4/r0atfvrM6GI0ZFw9lf0lIzWYNd03eXdtQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_7673.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Cades Cove &#8211; Smoky Mountains National Park</figcaption></figure>When the enemy throws everything at you<br />
Nehemiah 6: I prayed, &#8220;Give me strength.&#8221;<br />
As the rebuilding project nears completion the enemies of Nehemiah desperately try to stop it. Since Nehemiah doesn&#8217;t fall for their &#8220;let&#8217;s meet&#8221; ploy they try slandering him. Their rumor is that Nehemiah’s about to set up a private kingdom behind the walls of Jerusalem and they threaten to send this word to Artaxerxes, himself. Nehemiah can&#8217;t stop them from their lies, but he can pray. Their next effort is to hire Shemaish son of Delaiah to pose as a prophet of God. Shemaish comes to Nehemiah pretending to be his friend. He’s heard from God that this very night people are coming to take his life. According to Shemaish, Nehemiah&#8217;s only hope is to hide in the part of the Temple reserved only for priests of God. It’s there that he’ll be safe. In spite of the credibility of this warning, Nehemiah decides that this &#8220;prophecy&#8221; doesn&#8217;t add up. For one thing, he’s not a priest and his going into that part of the Temple would be an act of desecration. Nehemiah refuses to cooperate and continues rebuilding the wall. The effort of Tobiah and Sanballat to stop Nehemiah from doing what God called him to do serves as a sort of spiritual warfare field manual for us. The enemy of our souls uses all these ploys to distract us from serving the Lord. First, they mock Nehemiah and his crew, telling them that they’ll never be able to finish what they’ve started. When that fails, they threaten them with personal violence. Next, they pretend compromise. After that there are lies and insinuation. Finally, they pretend to be the Voice of God. Nehemiah&#8217;s defenses are: a firm belief that he’s doing God&#8217;s will, absolute commitment to the task, an abundance of common sense, and lots of prayer. Fifty-two days later, Jerusalem is once again a walled city.<br />
Take Away: The more committed you are to doing the will of the Lord the more committed his enemies will be to stop you from doing just that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
