<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Book of 2Timothy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/book-of-2timothy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 20:09:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Book of 2Timothy &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Timothy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Timothy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arguments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disagreements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fellowship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-2/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mature enough to walk away 2Timothy 2: Refuse to get involved in inane discussions; they always end up in fights. Timothy, a young pastor, is urged by his mentor, Paul, to pursue maturity, focusing on things like righteousness, faith, love, peace, and prayer. He’s told to avoid “inane discussions” because they lead only to fighting. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16228" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16228" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16228" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019678.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16228" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Redwoods National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Mature enough to walk away</p>
<p>2Timothy 2: Refuse to get involved in inane discussions; they always end up in fights.</p>
<p>Timothy, a young pastor, is urged by his mentor, Paul, to pursue maturity, focusing on things like righteousness, faith, love, peace, and prayer. He’s told to avoid “inane discussions” because they lead only to fighting. Obviously, Paul’s not talking about having serious discussions in which people have genuine disagreements and are seeking to understand one another’s positions. Still, the principle here is a good one. Believers need to avoid bickering with one another. The longer it goes on the more the two sides get entrenched. Ultimately, there’s a fracture in their relationship in which one side or both gets hurt. Others, sometimes the most innocent people of all, are drawn in and wounded even more seriously by the immature attitudes shown by people who they love, respect, and need. So, how can this mess be avoided? It’s easy, really. “Refuse to get involved.” Some things are worth the trouble and are, in fact, rather important. Most things aren’t. Paul wants Timothy to focus on the good stuff and walk away from the bad stuff. I’ll like my church better if I do that. In fact, I’ll probably like myself better too.</p>
<p>Take Away: Give your energies to that that really matters, file the other stuff in the “not-that-big-a-deal” file.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Timothy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Timothy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is the Word of the Lord 2Timothy 3: There’s nothing like the written Word of God for showing you the way to salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. Does Paul have any idea that one day people will view his writings as the “written word of God?” There are times when he differentiates between [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16231" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16231" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16231" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019687.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16231" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Redwoods National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>This is the Word of the Lord</p>
<p>2Timothy 3: There’s nothing like the written Word of God for showing you the way to salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.</p>
<p>Does Paul have any idea that one day people will view his writings as the “written word of God?” There are times when he differentiates between his opinion and what he says is the plain direction of the Holy Spirit, so he sees in his own writings the hand of God. Still, I tend to think that Paul didn’t tend to think of his own words in such lofty terms. We do, though. In the years following Paul’s life his letters are painstakingly copied and passed around, church to church. As people gather to worship, his words are read to the congregation, shaping their theology and their faith. Today, I can read this passage to a congregation and no one will give much thought as to whether or not Paul’s words are the “written Word of God.” Beyond all that, Paul tells us that these sacred words have a purpose. That purpose isn’t to answer all my questions about science or culture or history. Rather, it’s to show me “the way to salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.” To use it for other purposes is to abuse it. Rightly used, though, it trains “us to live God’s way.” Today, I’m reminded that this is the Word of the Lord, thanks be to God.</p>
<p>Take Away: Let’s never take God’s Word for granted or use it for purposes for which it was not intended.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Timothy</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 10:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Timothy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ministry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[priorities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-2-timothy-4/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ultimately only one thing matters 2Timothy 4: But you – keep your eye on what you’re doing. The Apostle has been around and he knows the score. He’s had people he counted on let him down. Some couldn’t help it. Sickness and other circumstances beyond their control have thrown a monkey wrench into their commitment [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16234" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16234" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16234" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/12/P8019691.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16234" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Redwoods National Park, CA</figcaption></figure>
<p>Ultimately only one thing matters</p>
<p>2Timothy 4: But you – keep your eye on what you’re doing.</p>
<p>The Apostle has been around and he knows the score. He’s had people he counted on let him down. Some couldn’t help it. Sickness and other circumstances beyond their control have thrown a monkey wrench into their commitment to him. Others could help it but failed anyway, getting caught up in some religious fad or simply finding the going too hard. Timothy needs to be aware of all this. At times, people who should know better will want him to ease up on proclaiming the “take up your cross daily” aspect of the gospel message. Something else will catch their eye and they’ll want him to focus on that instead. Paul, who knows what he’s talking about urges this young pastor to “keep your eye on what you’re doing.” More than being a pastor who wants to get along with people, he’s “God’s servant.” Ultimately, what the congregation thinks is secondary to what God thinks. Even as Paul looks forward to receiving the Lord’s approval he wants Timothy, and all of us, to keep this ultimate truth in mind. From my point of view, I want to please those who call me “pastor.” I don’t want to disappoint them or to bore them with sermons that are somewhat less than timely. However, in the end, there’s only one word of approval that matters. I know you know that this is true for pastors and for everyone else too.</p>
<p>Take Away: We have only one Master and pleasing him is, ultimately, the only thing that really matters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
