<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>golf &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/golf/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 23:44:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>golf &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 22:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Golf lessons Ecclesiastes 3: God made everything beautiful in itself and in its time &#8212; but he&#8217;s left us in the dark. One of the famous parts of Ecclesiastes is his &#8220;a time to plant and another to reap&#8221; section in which he lists all the opposites of life and decides they all have their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cnuWHwdl0dc/X5XTnOuYcbI/AAAAAAABHLE/TQCNgPguL0YEWChlQk_kw5LEEO-fY5EpACPcBGAsYHg/s400/19georgetown.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Golf lessons<br />
Ecclesiastes 3: God made everything beautiful in itself and in its time &#8212; but he&#8217;s left us in the dark.<br />
One of the famous parts of Ecclesiastes is his &#8220;a time to plant and another to reap&#8221; section in which he lists all the opposites of life and decides they all have their proper place.  The writer is impressed by all God has done in the world, but frustrated that he can&#8217;t understand the meaning of it all.  I played golf with a fellow who had a long pre-shot routine that he went through every time he hit the ball.  He shuffled his feet a specific way, waggled the club for what seemed to be an eternity, and then stood frozen over the ball before finally hitting his horrible slice.  I wanted to shout out, &#8220;Just hit the ball!&#8221;  No doubt, he needed some golfing lessons, but even I could see that he was over-thinking his golf swing.  He had himself tied up in knots and it created, not an athletic, fluid golf shot, but a poor shot and a frustrated golfer.  Solomon is frustrated that, after all his thinking and considering, he can&#8217;t understand all God does.  He decides that &#8220;there&#8217;s nothing better to do than go ahead and have a good time and get the most we can out of life.&#8221;  That isn&#8217;t a ticket to living an immoral, God-ignoring life, but it&#8217;s a reminder that life is a gift of God and if we over-think it we, like my golfer friend, will spend way too much time out in the weeds rather than enjoying the beauty that has been freely given to us.<br />
Take Away: Life is a gift meant to be enjoyed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zechariah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zechariah-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zechariah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God, golf, and grace Zechariah 10: They’ll get a fresh start, as if nothing had ever happened. I’m not a golf historian, so I may not have the story right, but I understand that in days of old a golfer who had not had the opportunity to warm up on the driving range was allowed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure id="attachment_15575" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15575" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" class="size-large wp-image-15575" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/05/P4309211.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15575" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Mesa Verde National Park, CO</figcaption></figure><br />
God, golf, and grace<br />
Zechariah 10: They’ll get a fresh start, as if nothing had ever happened.<br />
I’m not a golf historian, so I may not have the story right, but I understand that in days of old a golfer who had not had the opportunity to warm up on the driving range was allowed to declare his first shot off the tee to be a “mulligan.”  That meant it was going to be a practice shot and wouldn’t count.  The “mulligan” morphed into an after-the-fact point of grace, first, for the opening shot only and then to any one tee shot during the round.  I’ve even played golf with some folks who took however many “mulligans” they wanted.  My response has always been, “You can take as many second shots as you want as long as you don’t brag about your score!”  I’m reminded that out in real life we don’t get many mulligans.  Once in a while we do, for instance, when the traffic cop lets us off with a warning.  However, if my poor driving has resulted in a car wreck the clock can’t be turned back and there’s no mulligan for me.  God’s man Zechariah has good news for Israel.  The Lord&#8217;s going to give them another chance.  He’s going to gather this scattered nation from all the places where it&#8217;s landed and give it a fresh start.  We serve a God who graciously gives nations and individuals second chances.  When I confess my sin and failure and return to the Lord, I find that he delights in forgiving me and restoring me to his family.  In golf, the mulligan is just an unofficial part of a game.  With God, it’s the real deal and it happens only because of his grace.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
