<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Josiah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/josiah/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 20:11:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Josiah &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Zephaniah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-zephaniah-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 11:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Zephaniah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hezekiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The least known book of the Bible Zephaniah 1: I’m going to make a clean sweep of the earth. Someone has said that this book of Zephaniah is best known for being the least known book of the Bible. I have to confess that it’s pretty much that way for me. I’ve read through the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15500" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15500" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15500 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/P9279164.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15500" class="wp-caption-text">2013 &#8211; Burgess Falls State Park, TN</figcaption></figure>
<p>The least known book of the Bible<br />
Zephaniah 1: I’m going to make a clean sweep of the earth.<br />
Someone has said that this book of Zephaniah is best known for being the least known book of the Bible. I have to confess that it’s pretty much that way for me. I’ve read through the book a few times, usually as part of a read-the-Bible-in-a-year effort. Its three chapters make it less than one day’s reading in such a program. The introduction of the book is somewhat unique because we&#8217;re given four generations of Zephaniah’s family tree, concluding with Hezekiah, likely the well-known king of Judah. If that’s so, it helps us see that, unlike Amos and other prophets who speak for the common man, Zephaniah’s royal blood gives him a different perspective and audience. He ministers during the reign of Josiah, possibly, then having influence along with Jeremiah on the young king. Zephaniah is especially focused in on the Day of Judgment that&#8217;s coming upon, not only Judah, but upon the whole earth. Why such a day is coming, what will happen when it does, and how to prepare for it is subject matter for his message. Since Zephaniah speaks of not only a contemporary time of judgment but a more distant one as well I can consider his message as not only a historical one, but one that needs to be heard today.<br />
Take Away: Even the most minor of prophets has a major message for us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-36/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 03:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blessings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God taking us seriously 2Kings 22: I&#8217;m taking you seriously. The clock is about to run out on Judah as the nation has drifted farther and farther from God. When the boy-king Josiah comes to power things have eroded to the point that even the priests at the Temple don&#8217;t know God&#8217;s Word to them. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-s-X1xtKCEFo/Xo3fShZJMmI/AAAAAAABEk8/gaqM-59r1QEmgTNSfhA67NqRRtGxBU4qwCKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170831_123749.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills, SD &#8211; Scenic Drives</figcaption></figure><br />
God taking us seriously<br />
2Kings 22: I&#8217;m taking you seriously.<br />
The clock is about to run out on Judah as the nation has drifted farther and farther from God. When the boy-king Josiah comes to power things have eroded to the point that even the priests at the Temple don&#8217;t know God&#8217;s Word to them. As Josiah grows up he wants to do the right thing even though he’s unsure of what the right thing is. Out of respect for God, he decides to renovate the Temple and it’s while that work is being done that Scripture is found. The message is not a pleasant, comforting one. Instead, its words declare the covenant made between God and Josiah&#8217;s ancestors. That covenant contains words of blessing but also states, in graphic terms, what will happen if they break that covenant. As Josiah hears these words the seriousness of the situation dawns upon him. He and his people are clearly candidates for the &#8220;curse&#8221; part of the covenant. He’s heartbroken and he’s frightened. He sends word to a woman of God asking for her intercession. The message she receives from God is both positive and negative. It’s negative in its confirmation that all the curses of the covenant will come true. Simply put, God will keep his word. It’s positive in that God is taking Josiah&#8217;s repentance and commitment to the Almighty seriously. Once again the curse is put on hold. As a result, Josiah will rule in peace throughout his life. Even as the Lord takes Josiah seriously he takes me seriously. That doesn&#8217;t mean my saying &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221; will stop events that are already in motion from happening. It does mean that the Lord’s willing to hear and forgive when I call out to him.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Kings</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-kings-37/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 03:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obedience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The boy-king gets an A+ 2Kings 23: The world would never again see a king like Josiah. When Josiah becomes boy-king of Judah the Temple is not only a place for sacrifices to Jehovah God, but is used for worship of Baal, Ashtoreth, and other pagan gods as well. The country is filled with shrines [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iiY7Gyg35r8/Xo9EqW0K-wI/AAAAAAABEl4/XW7OgiIURlMLuaPeSvNqzfCl0F5YrfCAACKgBGAsYHg/s1600/20170831_124121.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2017 &#8211; Black Hills, SD Scenic Drives</figcaption></figure><br />
The boy-king gets an A+<br />
2Kings 23: The world would never again see a king like Josiah.<br />
When Josiah becomes boy-king of Judah the Temple is not only a place for sacrifices to Jehovah God, but is used for worship of Baal, Ashtoreth, and other pagan gods as well. The country is filled with shrines and altars, some dating back for centuries. Near Jerusalem stands an iron furnace that is used for child sacrifices. Clearly, the spiritual condition of Judah was pitiful, as the commandments of God have been ignored for generations. Josiah&#8217;s discovery of the Law of God shocks him to action. What he does isn’t some cosmetic religious reform. This is all out transformation. Josiah uses the Book as an instruction manual on how to live and worship. He follows it to a letter. For instance, the Book of the Covenant describes observing the Passover, something that hasn&#8217;t been done for centuries. Josiah reads the Book and follows the directions, reestablishing this observance. The result is that God is pleased with him, giving him an &#8220;A+.&#8221; Because of his faithfulness an entire generation is changed. Today, Josiah inspires us to take God seriously and to swim against the tide of popular culture. Josiah&#8217;s story gives us hope of transforming our society.<br />
Take Away: When the Lord is given a chance, wonderful, life-changing things happen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on 2 Chronicles</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-2-chronicles-32/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 15:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of 2Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=4955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking God seriously 2 Chronicles 34: The king stood by his pillar and before God solemnly committed himself to the covenant. Josiah is just a boy when he’s made king of Judah. He’s a “seasoned” king, 26 years old and with 18 years of leadership under his belt when the Book of God’s Law is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WuT8mnm5A90/XtvvJDdb6tI/AAAAAAABFNE/Whmv3Vyl2e8kWPKIzoHGt_x9Zsq2dt7fACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20180802_103919.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Sightseeing Acadia National Park and area</figcaption></figure><br />
Taking God seriously<br />
2 Chronicles 34: The king stood by his pillar and before God solemnly committed himself to the covenant.<br />
Josiah is just a boy when he’s made king of Judah. He’s a “seasoned” king, 26 years old and with 18 years of leadership under his belt when the Book of God’s Law is brought to him. Instantly, he realizes how much trouble his nation is in. They’ve broken all the laws in the book! The covenant his ancestors made with God had plenty of blessings in it but it had some very serious curses in it as well. Having “broken the law” they’re destined to face the consequences. Josiah, we’re told, takes this message seriously. He immediately prepares to approach God to ask for a stay of execution. His plan is simple: he’ll commit himself to the covenant that was made years earlier and broken repeatedly by the generations that went before him. The Lord’s impressed with Josiah and his people. The curse is put on hold and Josiah rules a total of thirty-one years. I’m taken today with the mercy and patience of the Lord. Think of God being so forgotten that the Temple which is to be the glorious center of worship is, instead, in a near state of ruin. Think of obedience to his laws being so neglected that that the book of the Law is simply “discovered” in those ruins. Then, watch as this young king reads, understands, and pleads with the Lord for mercy. Finally, rejoice as the Lord graciously extends that mercy. No matter how we’ve messed up there’s still hope if we repent and return to this gracious God of Second Chances.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Nehemiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-nehemiah-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 20:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Nehemiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ezra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God's Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Second Chances Nehemiah 8: This is a day holy to God. Don&#8217;t feel bad. The joy of God is your strength! Many of those listening to Ezra read and explain the Scripture this day left the land of their birth to return to this land of their ancestors. They left family and friends, security and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-vYPP_UPknqE/XvoueZeXF0I/AAAAAAABFWI/6pJX4A8Raf8tb6vYRfEUDfYBdlcdsQRqQCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20181005_115638.jpg" width="1600" height="900" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2018 &#8211; Seven Points CoE, Hermitage, TN</figcaption></figure><br />
Second Chances<br />
Nehemiah 8: This is a day holy to God. Don&#8217;t feel bad. The joy of God is your strength!<br />
Many of those listening to Ezra read and explain the Scripture this day left the land of their birth to return to this land of their ancestors. They left family and friends, security and comfort to go to an unsecured city that wasn’t a city at all; rather, it was a pile of rubble. They made the hazardous journey to Jerusalem and then braved real opposition as they labored to rebuild the wall and prepared to re-occupy the City of David. As this task is completed, a holy event is planned. Governor Nehemiah and Priest Ezra organize an event centered on the Word of the Lord. However, something unexpected happens as Ezra reads and explains the Scripture to them. These good people begin to weep and wail. The sense of celebration is replaced with a feeling of failure and fear. The leaders have to act quickly or this holy day will turn in to a day of mourning. Why is it that the people react as they do? I think it’s because they begin to grasp the enormity of their sins and that of their forefathers. Generations earlier, King Josiah responds in the same way when the Book of God is found in the Temple. As he hears it read he’s alarmed and responds in humble fear of God. There’s a place for this kind of response to God&#8217;s Word. In fact, I need to be fearful and heartbroken when I realize my sin. However, the story must never end here. The Word of God is not intended to condemn me. Instead, it’s to be for me a wonderful message of hope. I’ve failed God and should stand condemned but God is gracious and offers me hope. The bad news is that I’ve sinned against God. The good news is that he’s the God of Second Chances graciously offering me and you hope and restoration.<br />
Take Away: God is the God of Second Chances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
