<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lamb of God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/lamb-of-god/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 19:20:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>Lamb of God &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 12:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John the Baptist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-3/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One tough man Luke 3: The main character in this drama&#8230;will ignite the kingdom life, a fire, the Holy Spirit within you. John the Baptist storms onto the world stage as “Thunder in the desert.” This is one tough man. He preaches a radical repentance. He calls some of his congregation “snakes” and tells everyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15756" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15756" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1024x765.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="717" class="size-large wp-image-15756" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1024x765.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-300x224.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-768x573.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3-1536x1147.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/photo-3.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15756" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Park at Blaine, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>One tough man </p>
<p>Luke 3: The main character in this drama&#8230;will ignite the kingdom life, a fire, the Holy Spirit within you.</p>
<p>John the Baptist storms onto the world stage as “Thunder in the desert.”  This is one tough man.  He preaches a radical repentance.  He calls some of his congregation “snakes” and tells everyone to straighten out their lives.  When people begin to speculate that he might be the Messiah of God he points to the precious Lamb of God who’s soon to be revealed.  John says that water baptism is the best he can offer.  The coming Messiah, he declares, will baptize with the fire of the Holy Spirit, changing people from the inside out.  John’s approach to life change is to take a hard line against sin.  Those who claim a righteousness of their own he calls “snakes.”  It’s a hard message, one intended to draw attention, and of course it’s true.  However, John’s message is of only limited value.  The tax collector who repents and commits himself to do the right thing is still the same person he was before.  The real need of his life will never be met in this manner.  The need is for him to be changed, transformed into a new person.  John’s method creates skin deep believers.  Jesus’ method creates saints of God.  Any time I’m tempted to come down hard on people, challenging them to straighten up and fly right I need to remember that the finest, most anointed practitioner of that kind of preaching ever says that he’s a mere stage hand compared to the real Star, Jesus.  His method isn’t to “tell it like it is.”  Rather, it’s to be a loving, humble servant of God and man. Lord, make me more like your Son, Jesus.</p>
<p>Take Away: More than reformation people need transformation.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Revelation</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Revelation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prophecy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-revelation-17/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The end is at hand, the end is at hand! Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings. John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_16409" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16409" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-16409" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="720" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/P9259752.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16409" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Grand Canyon, AZ</figcaption></figure>
<p>The end is at hand, the end is at hand!</p>
<p>Revelation 17: The Lamb will defeat them, proof that he is Lord over all lords, King over all kings.</p>
<p>John’s mysterious journey continues with disturbing scenes and promises of divine judgment. He sees a woman riding a beast. She’s branded as Babylon, but he’s told that that, too, is a riddle name, and the city, Rome, is described. In John’s day, seeing Rome as the seat of evil in the world makes a lot of sense. Some continue to take the woman, Babylon, and description of the riddle to add up to the literal Rome, carrying with it lots of religious overtones. Frankly, it’s beyond me (seems I’ve been saying that a lot lately). If it isn’t to be taken literally, it may be that the “Babylon” represents a current world power that dominants the world as Rome did in John’s day. All of this is the set up for the big battle. This world power will rally the nations of the world to battle against the Lamb of God. Then, before the battle is even described, we’re told the outcome of it. The Lamb wins. In the end, there will be no doubt as to his high standing: Lord over all lords, King over all kings. The descriptions of judgment, war, and destruction are soon to give way to victory, worship, and the exaltation of the Lamb of God.</p>
<p>Take Away: We don’t have to understand everything to understand this: in the end, the Lamb reigns.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
