<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>grief &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/grief/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 03:15:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>grief &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Ecclesiastes</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-ecclesiastes-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 23:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Ecclesiastes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investing in painful circumstances Ecclesiastes 7: Sages invest themselves in hurt and grieving. I know it is human nature to want to hurry past the difficulties of life. No one wants to spend the rest of their days dealing with some painful situation. However, I also know that just about everyone has their share of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9YNw7xfoGUg/X5x6BBX13BI/AAAAAAABHOs/Lmj8zdW2u30MGdWKYw5_jewsYXcbuexMQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/25rky_mtn_park.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Rocky Mtn Natl Park, Colorado</figcaption></figure><br />
Investing in painful circumstances<br />
Ecclesiastes 7: Sages invest themselves in hurt and grieving.<br />
I know it is human nature to want to hurry past the difficulties of life.  No one wants to spend the rest of their days dealing with some painful situation.  However, I also know that just about everyone has their share of &#8220;hurt and grieving.&#8221;  In fact, some folks have more than their share of such things.  Some of the finest people I know carry a burden of broken health, broken dreams, and painful loss with them every day.  I’ve noticed that, for some, those difficulties somehow deepen them.  They know how to enjoy life, but there’s an attractive stability and perspective on life in them.  The writer of Ecclesiastes says that we’re wise to invest something of ourselves in those challenging parts of life.  When I make an investment, I give something of value because I expect to get a return on my investment.  When I go through the darkness I tend to rush through it as quickly as possible.  This portion of Ecclesiastes reminds me that there’s something for me even there if I’ll trust the Lord enough to give myself to such difficulties.<br />
Take Away: Obviously, no one wants to go through hard times, but even in such times the Lord can work in our lives, deepening us, making us more like his Son, Jesus.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Luke</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-luke-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 12:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Luke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pharisees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repentance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salvation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-luke-7/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A ruined dinner party Luke 7: I forgive your sins. It’s intended to be a formal dinner in the home of a community leader. However, some of the formality is waved off. After all, Simon thinks Jesus ought to be impressed and humbled that a common person like Jesus is even invited to the home [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15768" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15768" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1024x578.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="542" class="size-large wp-image-15768" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1024x578.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-768x433.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321-1536x866.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/PHOTO_20140528_140321.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15768" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Whatcom Falls Park, Bellingham, WA</figcaption></figure>
<p>A ruined dinner party</p>
<p>Luke 7: I forgive your sins.</p>
<p>It’s intended to be a formal dinner in the home of a community leader.  However, some of the formality is waved off.  After all, Simon thinks Jesus ought to be impressed and humbled that a common person like Jesus is even invited to the home of a Pharisee.  Then, to Simon’s surprise this disgusting woman has managed to slip into the room.  Some servant will pay the price for that!  She ruins Simon’s nice dinner party.  Not only is he scandalized that such a person would dare enter his very house, but she’s dominating the moment.  With all this foolishness going on how can he properly impress his guests?  Jesus is obviously uncomfortable with her groveling at his feet, but he’s clearly moved by her sorrow.  Maybe Jesus doesn’t know her story?  Its then that Jesus speaks first as a teacher and then as a Savior.  This woman is overwhelmed by her sins.  Simon has missed the point because he doesn’t see himself as a sinner.  Jesus then turns his attention to this poor, grieving woman and says the greatest words she’s ever heard: “I forgive your sins.”  Simon hears blasphemy, she hears salvation.  In this story, do I best identify with Simon or with this miserable sinner?</p>
<p>Take Away: We tend to see ourselves as the “good people” in Gospel stories, maybe, though, we’re supposed to recognize ourselves as those who aren’t so good.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Job</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-job-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 03:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Better to say nothing Job 16: What a bunch of miserable comforters! When Job&#8217;s three friends, Eliphaz, Bildad, and Zophar, arrive at his side they’re overwhelmed with what they find. They cry out and rip their clothes in mourning. Then for seven days they sit with him, speechless at the horror of it all. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OVO7euaxB-4/XytWOw_TKaI/AAAAAAABFso/J6icGm-87Hkp8kO3oiFGVsLmxwjD5bFrACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/IMG_20190813_150815.jpg" width="1600" height="913" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2019 &#8211; Niagara Gorge, NY</figcaption></figure><br />
Better to say nothing<br />
Job 16: What a bunch of miserable comforters!<br />
When Job&#8217;s three friends, Eliphaz, Bildad, and Zophar, arrive at his side they’re overwhelmed with what they find.  They cry out and rip their clothes in mourning.  Then for seven days they sit with him, speechless at the horror of it all.  It appears that it’s during these days that they come to a decision to go with the status quo because once they start talking they merely state and restate the &#8220;folk wisdom&#8221; of the day.  As they do that, Job turns his fevered face toward them and denounces them as &#8220;miserable comforters.&#8221;  I think they are better comforters sitting there for a week, broken and speechless at what they see than when they start reasoning with Job about all of this.  There’s a lesson to be learned here.  People who are suffering pain and grief don&#8217;t really need our platitudes or our so-called wisdom.  Even when we don&#8217;t know &#8220;why&#8221; things are as they are our presence matters.  The scriptures tell us to &#8220;mourn with those who mourn.&#8221;  We aren&#8217;t called to explain it all but we are told to care and help the broken-hearted by sharing in their sorrow.<br />
Take Away: When we don’t know what to say or do we don’t need to say or do anything – just be there, sharing in the moment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
