<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>leadership &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/tag/leadership/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Doing ministry on the Internet - Devotionals and Photography</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 02:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/psp.gif</url>
	<title>leadership &#8211; Pastor Scott&#039;s Pages</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-43/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[God and me Proverbs 11: The more wise counsel you follow, the better your chances. Western culture exalts the individual. In the words of the song, &#8220;best of all, I did it my way.&#8221; We like our independence. It&#8217;s true even in our religion. We Protestants don&#8217;t have a pope and we don&#8217;t even want [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 405px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SkHjp9HG2ts/X3Tmtya4QdI/AAAAAAABGsc/Tldg34xiSgMT-E3N6POAmqNUzKrcRABPgCPcBGAsYHg/s507/PA211199.JPG" width="405" height="507" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2006 &#8211; Surfside Beach, TX (one of my all-time favorite pics)</figcaption></figure><br />
God and me<br />
Proverbs 11: The more wise counsel you follow, the better your chances.<br />
Western culture exalts the individual.  In the words of the song, &#8220;best of all, I did it my way.&#8221;  We like our independence.  It&#8217;s true even in our religion.  We Protestants don&#8217;t have a pope and we don&#8217;t even want the church to tell us what to believe.  Instead, we prefer &#8220;us and God&#8221; &#8212; an approach that can often be more truthfully stated, &#8220;Me.&#8221;  We don&#8217;t have a pope, but when we’re honest with ourselves, we like it when we can be our own pope: &#8220;I&#8217;ll get my Bible and decide for myself what it says.&#8221;  Now, I know that there are some positive aspects to this.  After all, the &#8220;protestors&#8221; who became the &#8220;Protestants&#8221; did have something to protest about.  Still, doing religion &#8220;my way&#8221; isn’t necessarily an improvement.  Doing it &#8220;my way&#8221; leads to aberrations of doctrine.  Walking down the &#8220;me&#8221; road isn&#8217;t the road to God.  In fact, it’s the original path away from God that’s described in the opening pages of our Bibles.  Learning to listen to others and even being willing to submit to the authority of those who the larger body of believers has recognized to be uniquely prepared and gifted to lead will, in the words of the proverb &#8220;better your chances&#8221; of staying on the right road to God.<br />
Take Away: “Me and God” quite often is really just “me.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[followers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solomon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Follow the leader Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following. There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers. The Bible has several stories of leadership. Moses led for 40 years. David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 375px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GKWZD23715U/X3iy3gUoO3I/AAAAAAABGzw/7uTOofCwLGcYE-Eo4mTLHOuMCXf6CN9CACPcBGAsYHg/s500/01umauma%2Bfalls.jpg" width="375" height="500" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Follow the leader<br />
Proverbs 14: The mark of a good leader is loyal followers; leadership is nothing without a following.<br />
There&#8217;s no such thing as a leader without followers.  The Bible has several stories of leadership.  Moses led for 40 years.  David led not only in military and affairs of government but in worship as well.  His son Solomon led to prosperity.  Here are three things that come to mind when I read about these leaders.  First, each of these men is not only a leader, but is also a follower who accepts the authority of the Lord and spends time with him getting his marching orders.  Second, these men know how to share leadership and to train leaders.  They don&#8217;t try to do everything themselves and surround themselves with capable people to help carry the leadership load.  Third, they lead people to meaningful goals.  These men have God given visions that gives their leadership real purpose.  People believe in them and they believe the goal set out for them is worth their sacrifice.  Leaders such as these have no problem attracting followers.<br />
Take Away: God-called leaders lead with purpose in a God-chosen direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-49/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 08:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leadership, not dictatorship Proverbs 16: A good leader motivates, doesn&#8217;t mislead, doesn&#8217;t exploit. Solomon knows a lot about leadership. He’s watched his father, David, lead Israel for many years. Then when he becomes King he asks God for wisdom that he might lead His people. In all this he comes to understand leadership dynamics as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HIEuHxbiIXs/X3thIv5jQoI/AAAAAAABG0w/qemQhwX5X2oXmPuwGwLXmJYVrKiSq-HWQCPcBGAsYHg/s400/normal_pe_epe_e%2Bfalls.jpg" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2004 &#8211; Big Island, Hawaii</figcaption></figure><br />
Leadership, not dictatorship<br />
Proverbs 16: A good leader motivates, doesn&#8217;t mislead, doesn&#8217;t exploit.<br />
Solomon knows a lot about leadership.  He’s watched his father, David, lead Israel for many years.  Then when he becomes King he asks God for wisdom that he might lead His people.  In all this he comes to understand leadership dynamics as well as anyone who ever lived.  In the passage before me today I get just a taste of his philosophy of leadership.  The guy who says these things isn’t some pastor with an all-volunteer staff of church people who might just walk off if they don’t like the way things are going.  Rather, he’s King of Israel.  He has &#8220;off with their heads&#8221; authority.  In other words, if he wants he can order the direction and everyone has to follow.  However, Solomon has learned that dictatorship isn’t leadership.  He says his job is to motivate people to move together in positive directions.  He says he isn&#8217;t supposed to promise what can&#8217;t be delivered and he isn&#8217;t to get people to do what he wants just to get something for himself.  Honesty, unselfishness, persuasiveness &#8212; these are leadership qualities Solomon brings to my attention today.<br />
Take Away: Dictatorship isn’t leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Proverbs</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-proverbs-61/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Proverbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Running out of wood can be a good thing Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down. As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church. There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 400px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-MTTFgHdu11I/X4tVOZuVjqI/AAAAAAABG-E/AXU72ikIuKM_0MSgLcTsQdPeK5gCViOxACPcBGAsYHg/s400/11cripple_creek.JPG" width="400" height="300" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2003 &#8211; Cripple Creek, CO</figcaption></figure>Running out of wood can be a good thing<br />
Proverbs 26: When you run out of wood, the fire goes out; when the gossip ends, the quarrel dies down.<br />
As a pastor I have a pretty strong influence on what happens at church.  There is, I suppose, always the chance that someone will attempt to take control of a church service but that&#8217;s unlikely.  I have the main say concerning the order of worship and, of course, what is said in the sermon.  However, what happens &#8220;out there&#8221; during the week is out of my control.  Because of that, all the efforts on Sunday to create a loving, supportive family of God can be derailed if that same crowd spends the week fanning the flames of division.  Knowing this is humbling to me and it reminds me that I’m not nearly as influential in my own church as I think I am.  However, it also reminds me that my greatest resource is not my leadership ability.  Instead, my greatest Resource is the One I serve.  It’s my desire that the Lord will help me to love people even when they’re behaving in ways that cause pain.  I want to personally set an example of how a sanctified Christian conducts himself, to help people who tend to gossip understand that there’s an underlying spiritual issue, and to pray that the Lord will exhaust their supply of &#8220;wood&#8221; sooner and not later that the church might be united in love for Christ and one another.<br />
Take Away: Some issues will simply die out and go away if we stop fanning the flames.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-90/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 18:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congregations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastors]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pastoral responsibilities Jeremiah 23: You&#8217;ve scattered my sheep&#8230;you haven&#8217;t kept your eye on them. This passage is clergy oriented so pastor types like me need to sit up and take notice. The Lord’s displeased with the spiritual leaders of Jeremiah&#8217;s day. He pictures them as shepherds who are given the responsibility of caring for the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sph0CRefvqo/YFOJFHkic_I/AAAAAAABJj4/n4WFGk83q6M9291qcYfVGXOOSgpS5ZufwCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Ketchikan%2B-%2B%2B8-18-2009%2B1-42-02%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Ketchikan, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Pastoral responsibilities<br />
Jeremiah 23: You&#8217;ve scattered my sheep&#8230;you haven&#8217;t kept your eye on them.<br />
This passage is clergy oriented so pastor types like me need to sit up and take notice.  The Lord’s displeased with the spiritual leaders of Jeremiah&#8217;s day.  He pictures them as shepherds who are given the responsibility of caring for the Lord’s flock.  These leaders are entrusted with the spiritual welfare of God&#8217;s flock but they’re betraying that confidence.  Instead of loving the flock, leading and caring for it, they&#8217;re taking advantage of things for personal gain.  In some cases they&#8217;re actually harming those they’re supposed to protect.  Otherwise, they&#8217;re neglecting them or even driving them away.  God’s disappointed in these leaders and is angry with them.  Sometimes I think that church people are too pastor oriented, giving way too much authority to the pastor, including letting the pastor do their thinking for them (or, standing on the sidelines and cheering as the pastor works him/herself to death &#8211; but that&#8217;s a subject for another day!).  Today, I&#8217;m reminded that there&#8217;s a strong biblical foundation that supports some having spiritual leadership.  The Lord has wired us in such a way that we look to some as &#8220;shepherds&#8221; acting as God&#8217;s representatives.   These leaders are to be servants who put the interests of those entrusted to their care before their own needs.  In this passage Jeremiah reminds me that as a pastor I&#8217;ve been honored with the position of leadership, but with that position has come accountability, not just to the congregation I serve, but to the Lord, himself.<br />
Take Away: Church leaders are to be good shepherds of the flock of the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-91/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nazareneblogs.org/pastorscott/?p=5581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Quality leadership Jeremiah 23: This is the name they&#8217;ll give him: &#8220;God-Who-Puts-Everything-Right.&#8221; The religious leaders are a disappointment to God. They could have done a better job; treated people the way good and dedicated shepherds treat the sheep under their care. They haven&#8217;t done that and the Lord’s not only angry with them but he [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-OZsCptGoQl8/YFTO2vUNsJI/AAAAAAABJm4/NbQEBr40w903AV1NCx0uT-ngmJNzrpTnACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B5-49-55%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Endicott Arm, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Quality leadership<br />
Jeremiah 23: This is the name they&#8217;ll give him: &#8220;God-Who-Puts-Everything-Right.&#8221;<br />
The religious leaders are a disappointment to God.  They could have done a better job; treated people the way good and dedicated shepherds treat the sheep under their care.  They haven&#8217;t done that and the Lord’s not only angry with them but he has another approach in mind.  This plan will provide quality leadership to his people.  David is considered the prototype king for Israel and the coming Leader will be cut from the same cloth as was David.  He’ll be a descendant of David.  He’ll also be strong, wise, and dedicated to God.  That kind of man will take care of God&#8217;s people.  In Jeremiah&#8217;s future and in my past that Leader makes his appearance.  He does everything Jeremiah says he will.  He’s a righteous man of justice and he goes to work fixing all that sin has broken.  He’s worthy of the name Jeremiah gives him: &#8220;God-Who-Puts-Everything-Right.&#8221;  The process started by this Leader isn’t yet complete, but we already see that everything he touches is changed for the better.  Well, better put, &#8220;everyone he touches.&#8221;   In fact, I can say that I not only believe in this Leader&#8217;s ability to transform lives &#8212; my own life is an example of his work.  I&#8217;m not all I&#8217;m going to be, but by his grace, I&#8217;m not what I would have been.<br />
Take Away: In Christ we find restoration and transformation. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Jeremiah</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-jeremiah-98/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 19:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Jeremiah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three cheers for Ahikam Jeremiah 26: Ahikam son of Shaphan stepped forward and took his side. All’s not well at the Temple. God&#8217;s man, Jeremiah, already has a reputation for preaching gloom and doom messages and he’s at it again. This time he disrupts events at the Temple by telling the worshipers there that the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iil6GqsI8hw/YF5Nq4oKndI/AAAAAAABJp4/5D1TNkORFm8QiAYmubhhluKWzBoPlSM6wCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/Endicot%2BArm%2B-%2BDawes%2BGlacier%2B-%2B%2B8-17-2009%2B5-01-11%2BPM.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2009 &#8211; Dawes Glacier, AK</figcaption></figure><br />
Three cheers for Ahikam<br />
Jeremiah 26: Ahikam son of Shaphan stepped forward and took his side.<br />
All’s not well at the Temple.  God&#8217;s man, Jeremiah, already has a reputation for preaching gloom and doom messages and he’s at it again.  This time he disrupts events at the Temple by telling the worshipers there that the Lord’s going to destroy both the Temple and them.  It&#8217;s an understatement to say that they don&#8217;t like it.  Jeremiah finds himself the center of a riot.  Soon officials show up and they conduct court right on the spot.  Simply put, Jeremiah’s life isn&#8217;t worth a nickel.  It’s then that a respected man, Ahikam son of Shaphan, steps up.  He reminds the people of another gloom and doom prophet, Micah, who during the reign of Hezekiah preached such messages.  He also had many enemies but he wasn&#8217;t killed. It&#8217;s not that they’re above that sort of thing.  Another prophet, Uriah, was hunted down and murdered because people didn&#8217;t like his message.  On this day, though, Ahikam&#8217;s defense wins Jeremiah his freedom.  Ahikam is an important man and on this day he brings his considerable weight to bear to save Jeremiah&#8217;s life.  His stepping in isn’t likely the prudent thing to do, after all this is a mob we&#8217;re talking about.  However, he has power and he uses it to do the right thing whether or not it’s popular to do so.  Sometimes we have to spend some of our leadership simply because it&#8217;s the right thing to do.  Position and authority are just fine, but only if they&#8217;re used for the right purposes.  I&#8217;m not an important person like Ahikam, but I do have some influence in some limited circumstances.  Am I spending it on things that really matter?<br />
Take Away: Position and authority and leadership skills are to be used in positive ways – not just to get our own way about things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[example]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vision]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Nebuchadnezzar school of leadership Daniel 3: Anyone who does not kneel and worship shall be thrown&#8230;into a&#8230;furnace. Any pollster will agree that an opinion freely given is more valuable than one that starts with, &#8220;If you don&#8217;t say this I&#8217;ll kill you.&#8221; One response of Nebuchadnezzar to his dream is to build a statue [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A5Nx2ikZD1k/YLjpn4ctCxI/AAAAAAABKX4/PbqUKtmktbIKwOLhfMgBK41-qIjfqOd3QCPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA017599.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; In the Cotswolds, UK &#8211; thatched roof</figcaption></figure><br />
The Nebuchadnezzar school of leadership<br />
Daniel 3: Anyone who does not kneel and worship shall be thrown&#8230;into a&#8230;furnace.<br />
Any pollster will agree that an opinion freely given is more valuable than one that starts with, &#8220;If you don&#8217;t say this I&#8217;ll kill you.&#8221;   One response of Nebuchadnezzar to his dream is to build a statue of himself and then command everyone to worship it.  Can&#8217;t you imagine him watching this show and commenting, &#8220;See how they love me!&#8221;  The truth of the matter is that there&#8217;s a lot more self-preservation than love going on in that event.  This is leadership at its worst.  A boss who says, &#8220;Do it or I&#8217;ll fire you&#8221; or a parent who says, &#8220;Do it or I&#8217;ll whip you&#8221; or a pastor who says, &#8220;Do it or God will get you&#8221; is a graduate of Nebuchadnezzar&#8217;s school of leadership.  In this case, what the king wants is wrong in the first place, but even if what he wanted people to do was clearly the right thing he&#8217;s going about it in the wrong way.  Real leaders lead by vision and example.  People follow because they&#8217;ve made that vision their own and believe that the leader is the person who can help them get there.  Jesus doesn&#8217;t say, &#8220;Follow me or you&#8217;re going to hell.&#8221;  Instead, he says, &#8220;Follow me and I&#8217;ll make you fishers of men.&#8221;<br />
Take Away: Real leaders lead by vision and example.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Daniel</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-daniel-34/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 16:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Daniel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At least they know what Daniel stands for Daniel 6: We&#8217;re never going to find anything against this Daniel unless we can cook up something religious. At the end of chapter five we find a simple statement that Darius the Mede is made king. Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of history loaded into that statement. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><figure style="width: 1600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P8hPZkwGH7U/YMJMgreWK-I/AAAAAAABKaY/d5sFwzFtB-U96oYCZwpsUg3SuW-SKPC-ACPcBGAsYHg/s1600/PA057783.JPG" width="1600" height="1200" class="size-large" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">2011 &#8211; Arc de Triomphe, Paris, France</figcaption></figure><br />
At least they know what Daniel stands for<br />
Daniel 6: We&#8217;re never going to find anything against this Daniel unless we can cook up something religious.<br />
At the end of chapter five we find a simple statement that Darius the Mede is made king.  Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of history loaded into that statement.  The handwriting on the wall informed the now dead Belshazzar that his kingdom was going to be handed over to the &#8220;Medes and Persians,&#8221; a confederacy that rose to challenge the power of Babylonia.  Apparently, there&#8217;s a lot of historical push and shove concerning all that happened in that takeover.  Daniel spares us all that, barely mentioning his own rise to authority in the reorganized kingdom, now under the rule of Darius.  This king recognizes leadership capability when he sees it and makes Daniel, first, one of his three vice-regents, and then moves to make Daniel the man in charge.  Of course, there are those who oppose this elevation of Daniel and they scramble to find some way to discredit him.  When they can&#8217;t come up with anything bad about him they focus in on his religion.  They conclude that his devotion to his God is his weakest point and decide to attack there.  I know it isn&#8217;t intended, but what a compliment to Daniel!  After living among the Babylonians for many years he&#8217;s still known for his devotion to the Lord.  It all started many years earlier when he decided to keep the dietary laws of his religion.  Now, we see him untouched by the pagan culture.  Things are about to get dicey for Daniel, but for now, he can say &#8220;thanks&#8221; to his enemies for the compliment.<br />
Take Away: Live in such a way even our enemies recognize our devotion and commitment to the Lord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devotional on Mark</title>
		<link>/index.php/devotional-on-mark-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[GR 'Scott' Cundiff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 11:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book of Mark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Devotionals, Pastor Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/index.php/devotional-on-mark-10/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Me first Mark 10: He came to serve, not to be served. Jesus begins his march to the cross. As he and his disciples begin their journey to Jerusalem he tells them what’s coming, the bad and the good. When James and John ask for favored positions in his kingdom, Jesus tells them that they [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15730" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15730" style="width: 960px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="541" class="size-large wp-image-15730" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663-1024x577.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663-1536x865.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/07/100_2663.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15730" class="wp-caption-text">2014 &#8211; Dead Horse Point State Park, UT</figcaption></figure>
<p>Me first </p>
<p>Mark 10: He came to serve, not to be served.</p>
<p>Jesus begins his march to the cross.  As he and his disciples begin their journey to Jerusalem he tells them what’s coming, the bad and the good.  When James and John ask for favored positions in his kingdom, Jesus tells them that they don’t know what they&#8217;re asking.  Very soon, being on his right and left won’t be very desirable places to be.  He again directs them down the servant path as the route to greatness.  Being the slave of others is the Christian route to leadership and Jesus is about to demonstrate that in a most unexpected way.  He’s going to die, not only that we might be set free from the death penalty, but so that we might learn from him to, ourselves, die.  This lesson isn’t only hard to learn, it’s also unwelcome.  Most of us live our lives trying to get things our own way.  When we somehow achieve position one of the perks is that we can now call the shots to suit ourselves.  It is human nature to view everything from the “me” point of view.  Jesus turns this self-centered world upside down.  He says that in his Kingdom, those in power serve with the needs of others uppermost in their minds.  Frankly, after 2000 years you’d think Christians would have a better grasp on this.  Frankly, after being a Christian most of my life, I’d think I’d have a better grasp on it.</p>
<p>Take Away: Jesus gave his all to, in part, show us how to give our all.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
